Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Seven)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Plan: Grind Them Down
-[X] Void Placement
--[X] Bombardment: 2nd Fleet (Kuru)
--[X] Interdiction: 1st, 4th and 10th Fleets
-[X] Force Placement
--[X] Change Company Deployments For The Planets
---[X] 4th Company with the fleet sans Librarians
---[X] 1st, 2nd and 10th Company to Kuru
-[X] Planetary Ground Target Priority List
--[X] Kuru (Top)
--[X] Avanti (Top)
--[X] Vatsa (Top)
-[X] Planetary Progression
--[X] Kuru, then Avanti, then Vatsa

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

Kuru Death Mark Abuses: 34 vs. 11

Kuru was as the other planets in the system, arid and dusty, its surface and depths overrun by its new masters, its various facilities slowly being transformed and claimed by those that ruled Kuru. By now, it was growing increasingly obvious that the interlopers to the newly claimed territory were nothing like what the Suysh had faced before. They did not falter, they did not retreat, and for all that they were far fewer in number than the so-called Imperial Guard of the New Meat, they managed feats that unsettled and infuriated the Queens. Thus, they unsettled and infuriated the swarms of aliens who marched back and forth in guarded patrols, birthed in ever larger numbers out of unfamiliar fear than anything else. Before, all of this would have been done in preparation for a new invasion force, a new series of armies ready to further invade the feedstock worlds which had been waiting just beyond the confines of the Realm of Queens. Now they were purely made for defense.

“Slither-hunt complete,” clicked and hissed the Clawborn to each other, the impulse and thought circulating through the group-mind at generally the same time.

They had no names, for names were only granted to Queens, who chose them for themselves. They had no need to report their orders directly through the technologies of the New Meat, for the psychic impulses and pheromone trails were more than enough to communicate the completion of their route, as well as the general sense of uneasy pride that no foes had been found. Yet this only lasted for an instant, as the acrid psycho-aromatic stink of one of the unholiest of things entered their receptors as their tongues tasted at the air. In seconds, the Clawborn were shuddering and screaming to themselves as they felt their minds begin to melt beneath the all-powerful rage of a slain Queen. All around them, the appropriated manufactorum’s defenders soon began to feel the same call, a call that was all the worse for its decaying nature which only meant that those who should have followed the Last Command of their Queen had failed!

The Clawborn felt the commands of their own Queen-Mother grow distant in their minds as they charged out, skin splitting and musculature activating with previously inactive supplementary adrenal and chemical glands spread throughout their nervous system.

All that mattered was that which had slain a Queen died!

=========================================

Kuru Initial Infiltrations: 85 vs. 61

The Hungerers of the hive of SnarlslaughterQueenEater hiss-clicked to one another as they readied their equipment and devoured the fallen. The sounds of battle were coming, but unlike the young Clawborn or even more veteran Bloodscales, the Hungerers knew better than to simply charge. Years of maturity, battle, and feasting ensured that even the call of a Queen’s death could not dislodge them nearly as easily as their lesser brethren. Far more strong was the hunger which gave them their names. To feast, to eat meat, all to keep their hyper-focused metabolism going before it devoured them from within, that all-consuming desire for foods had kept them going when others would have fallen from their wounds. Yet they could not feast forever, but they would feast again soon.

The outer defenses had been triggered, open warfare on the scrub-laden wastelands outside of the mountain, and much death was wrought there. The Hungerers, this pack of them at least, knew that soon enough their Queen would order them forward to feast and kill upon the intruders. The burning blades stung the open air with their heat, hazy outlines created around each of the Suysh present while their power packs and thermal cannons were readied. All the better to cook the meat before devouring them. It was as much purposeful as coincidence that the cooking technologies of the Suysh had proven to be effective against the New Meat in all their glorious numbers.

Only one of the Hungerers noticed the intruder in their midst, and that one died to a flechette-based attack out of a stocky non-cooking weapon which had been pushed partially into the open maw of the Suysh as it prepared to take another bite out of the pile of dried and cooked New Meat in front of it. Then there was a flash as a teleportation beacon – not that the Suysh knew what such a thing was – activated and delivered the elites of the Rough Meat right into the chamber. The Hungerers did not pause, did not falter, did not even register surprise or hesitation before they immediately leapt upon the intruders into their feeding area.

Only for the Rough Meat to begin firing with their own non-cooking weaponry, shells flying out of revolving cannons and crackling lightning-clad hammers and shields. The Hungerers were mighty and without hesitation. They died to those mighty and without hesitation. One of them laughed as they grappled and fought in the tight confines of the cavern, a creature of Rough Meat covered in void-black armor and bearing a skull cleaned of meat. Though the Hungerers had tasted the knowledge fed to their mind-hunger, throttled down their throats really by the Queen, they did not understand the Rough Meat’s bellows and near song-like cadence, not truly. And then, very quickly, it did not matter at all for the Hungerers had tasted the most bitter of meats, death.

==================================

Kuru Deeper Infiltrations: 42 vs. 50

The Void Screamer howled, as was their kind’s wont, the tides of the Endless Screaming pounding in their auditory receptors. Long ago the scale flaps which had covered the holes of this Suysh had been clawed away and eaten, all the better to hear the Screaming as it forever screeched. Eyelids too had long been eaten, the dry crackling of moisture-deprived eyeballs providing the most pleasant and distracting of tunes amidst the otherwise largely overwhelming presence of the Endless Screaming. It was only the power, glorious and terrible, of the Queen which could override even that, to guide the screamer to their place of purpose and feasting. The upper caverns of the stolen mine from the New Meat, the new Hive, were charnel pits now, the wafting scent of death and waiting meat to be eaten clogging the nostrils of Clawborn and Hungerers alike. Fang tanks were rolling out now, at the order of the Queen who was only just beginning to learn of the incursion. And so the Void Screamers had been sent out, their ability to scent and see through the Endless Screaming far in excess to the so far useless guards and patrols to defend their new home from the enemy.

Yes…yes! A morsel given grandiose shape, attempting to slip forth through the shadows! The soul within was a sparking golden thing, a cracking piece of machinery that bled light rather than oil. But where the light should have been wholly glorious, it was shot through with darkness. Regret. Self-loathing. All wondrous spices for the meat that only a Void Screamer could consume. An alarm, ah, of course, this one had already begun to shriek for its fellow Suysh to discover the attacker, mind and body forever out of synch. The tunnel wall was shattered by Hungerers, and the morsel was abruptly joined by others, but none so dark. The tide of the Endless Screaming was to be channeled, to let loose the noise within as noise without! There, one of the morsels was thrown back, bone crunching deliciously and armor crumpling as a wave of pure force was conjured forth! Another, this one set aflame to cook! And this one to –

“There, the psyker is stopped.”

“I apologize, Chapter Master, but the psyker managed to see through the veil I was attempting to craft.”

“It is no matter, Epistolary. Apollo, are you injured?”

“…no, Chapter Master.”

================================================

Kuru Queen Assaults: 26 vs. 10/71 vs. 20/49 vs. 36/54 vs. 25/88 vs. 64

Her name was torn asunder from the Endless Screaming and her own experiences. Slaughter-Bringer-Larder-Hoarder. Her Hive was resplendent. In the past, she would surely have been worthy of becoming a Queen Over All, a ruler of a vast number of subordinate broods of her own daughter-queens. But instead, she had been sent forth by the Queen of Queens, and her appetite was filled with the incredible taste of the New Meat, so fresh and divergent from the meat of the Suysh. A glorious time of feasting and birthing, her Hive contributing many fresh troops to the blessed Queens birthed for the Void Above, all to be ferried to new worlds, to New Meat. But that time was done, for now they were under assault once more! The New Meat had tried, of course, repeatedly!

But the Rough Meat were far worse. No Queen had tasted Rough Meat flesh and soul, to devour and digest information and knowledge. Some few lesser births had managed to tear a bite here and there out, but none were Queens, much less Void Screamers, and so there was little gained than the temporary filling of a belly. The lattermost was paramount, of course, and yet the frustration remained! She screeched as more eggs plopped out of her birthing canals, slick with slime already beginning to harden protectively in the open air. Her Royal Guard were all around her, assembled and readied for the incoming assault. It was impossible to miss, now, the Rough Meat that were marching through the tunnels while outside of her mountain even more Rough Meat drew away her defensive troops.

She could, mostly clearly, sight the blazing beacons of the Rough Meat’s poor versions of the Void Screamer, birthed from nowhere and nothing approaching a true Queen. Their might, however, was undeniable. There! She bellowed, and thus the Hive turned towards the intruders. Her mind scattered in a dozen directions, pheromones and psychic impulse commanding their efforts to encircle and entrap the comparatively tiny force which had arrived. But even as her Royal Guard moved, a portion of her vast mind espied small bodies of the Rough Meat leaping upwards through the air, their flight propelled by streams of flame and fuel! Her shields formed instantly, thick and strong and built to withstand things of the Endless Screaming as well as those of the meat-realm. Yet instead of coming straight for her, at the very edge of it, they descended amongst the eggs!

No! The eggs! Her more precious of children and last resort food source! Go, go! She shrieked for her Royal Guard to return, to protect, but – no! The Endless Screaming bent and twisted as new arrivals appeared in flashes of light and pain that were too close, far too close! The leader, the Not-Queen, she could see through the Endless Screaming how skeins of control and loyalty stretched from all the Rough Meat towards this one! Near him, an angry dark star in the Endless Screaming! The threat was too much, already the Hive was turning about, presenting backsides to punishing weapons-fire from the Rough Meat who had come through the cavern’s entrances! The Royal Guard pushed to the fore were battered and beaten by the Not-Queen, its flying soldiers, its own Royal Guard! No! It wasn’t fair!

“I…I will devour you ALL!” She bellowed, rough approximations of the tasteless language of the New Meat erupting from her flaps and speaking orifices.

But even as she roused herself, she felt them slipping past her shields, the dark star creating sliver-thin openings enough for the Rough Meat to penetrate through. Her shields, which could withstand artillery and explosive, the predators of the Endless Screaming, remaining all but intact save for split-second tears. And then she began to feel pain. She attacked with all her fury! But it did not fell the Rough Meat, even if it wounded some. Claws, fangs, psychic blasts and bursts, flames and mind-tearing waves of intent, it staggered all but a few, but not the Not-Queen and one of its Royal Guard! She felt blows upon her flesh, her bones, cracking beneath hammer and gun alike. It should not be! The New Meat had failed to even get past her Hive’s outer defenders, their mountain hers to grow in, their efforts useless! The galaxy was to be a feast! A feast for the Suysh!

In the end, her blind fury and hunger had her self-cannibalizing her own wounded limbs as the Rough Meat tore her apart. The ensuing Death-Mark of her agonized spirit was, to the horror of all those of the Hive, dissolved before it could do anything at all. There would be no final assault, no grand revitalization of the Hive in the name of revenge. The Royal Guard, kept protectively by a Queen more cowardly than most of her peers, were all slain leaving the Hive without even the pretense of leadership.

And she would not be the last Queen killed on Kuru in the next week.

A series of explosions ripped through the underground caverns of Siltway Manufactorum Complex Tertius, deepest of the three powerful manufacturing facilities of the greater Siltway territory. There, Suysh died in vast numbers, some to the collapsing rocks that fell in tons upon their scaled heads, some to their own brethren due to their wounds causing the hunger to overwhelm those nearby, and still others were cut down in bolter fire and flamer bursts. Missile launchers kept back the Suysh tanks at bay, while the assembled Librarius kept back the Queen’s final attempt at retribution for those that had caused her death. Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos of the Blood Ravens would add another of the putrid beings to his tally that day. His terminator armor was covered from top to bottom in gallons and gallons of alien ichor, yet he strode from the corpse of the slain Queen without difficulty, the rest of the 1st Company and Honor Guard around him keeping back even the mutating and frenzied Hungerers and Royal Guards of the Hive.

In the depths of Ruby Mountain, so-called because of the fist-sized precious stones regularly excavated there which added vast amounts of wealth to the Imperial nobles who owned stakes there, a Queen died at range. The combined ranged firepower of nearly the whole of the admittedly depleted Blood Ravens broke through her physic shields without any aid required from the Librarius, the sheer dint of firepower brought to bear by Captain Macharius Sicarius creating, ever so briefly, the near effect of staring directly into the face of a star at close range. Specifically, with the aid of his relic Plasma Cannon, as well as the purposefully equipped dreadnoughts of the chapter. The steaming fields of slain Suysh would continue to burn for hours after the Blood Raven contingent had been evacuated to safety.

Warned enough by the deaths of the other Queens, the ruling Queen who had sequestered herself in the warren-like tunnels of a massive dormitory complex once inhabited by the New Meat birthed a great number of new soldiers. She had returned all patrolling fang tanks and scream claws, dragging even those who guarded lesser manufacturing facilities. After all, it would not matter if they were able to continue producing new weaponry and war machines for the Feasting War if the Queen herself died! But for this Queen, at least, she had miscalculated on the value of her position. It was instinctively tactical behavior from her species, to purposefully inhabit the most valued of positions of the enemy once taken, to ensure a prominent but well protected position. But where the mines and manufactorums were considered of utmost priority for reclamation, dormitories were not even on the list of protected facilities.

She died in an instant of orbital fire once her position was confirmed, as did Suysh across the planet wherever they wandered outside of protected areas.

The last Queen on Kuru was prepared. She had marshalled all of her forces, and was actively exerting her will to maintain control over her Hive, straining herself to ensure that when the Death-Marked came, that her Hive would not lose itself over the matter. It worked, even, though her fury at the mere psychic resonance nearly shattered her control. And so the Rough Meat were forced to invade a fully and forewarned Hive for the first time in quite some time. But despite all possible expectations of the Queen, the Rough Meat did not falter. Stoically, they marched into the tunnels, a multitude of spear-tip assaults that invaded and then returned, puncturing the defenses and then retreating before a surging group of Suysh could catch up to them and kill them. Again and again the Rough Meat pushed deeper and deeper than before, until they finally ceased, allowing the Queen to absolutely flood the tunnels with fresh births, clogging them top to bottom with Clawborn. Her Royal Guard pushed to the front, determined to stop the next assault before it could even get past the first tunnel entrances.

And then the Rough Meat appeared behind them all, teleported safely through the tunnels by means of previously hidden teleporter repeaters and beacons. By the time the Suysh had turned back around, the Queen frantically commanding them to do so, the Rough Meat were practically sprinting down the tunnels, deeper and deeper while cutting their way past the scattered defenders left behind at checkpoints. By the time the Royal Guard had pushed and eaten their way past the throttling newborn horde, the Queen was under direct assault. By the time they had reached the Queen’s birthing chamber, hollowed out and stabilized with all the majesty of Suysh engineering, she was dying. The Royal Guard would witness the Not-Queen of the Rough Meat strike the final blow, and though they waited for the Death-Mark to activate their biological programming…it never came.

Then the Rough Meat were gone once more, and the Royal Guard were left with naught but despair, confusion, and hunger in their wake. The latter of which would soon begin to overwhelm them without the guiding presence of a Queen’s mind.

=====================================================================

High above the planet Avanti, the Blood Ravens assembled. The wounded had been restored by the efforts of the Apothecarium, the forges churning out ammo and the techmarines enacting repair rites upon armor and arms aplenty. For a solid week, the Librarius had worked along with the greatest tactical minds of the chapter, all supplied with reports and recordings aplenty. Enemy strengths and weaknesses, successes and failures on the parts of the astartes, and more were analyzed. The cogitators of the ships were consulted many a time, as was the careful deliberations of the Librarius as they focused on their more esoteric rituals. It was not the same as the foolish and vain predictions of the Eldar Farseers, a thousand branching paths with them prancing about relying purely on the literally unreliable Warp and their own alien thought processes. No, here, the cold logic of the cogitators, the experience of the space marines with centuries of experience up to and including consultations with the venerable minds of the dreadnoughts, all of this buoyed and strengthened the postulations offered by the Librarius.

Imperial Guard+Navy Reports: 50
Inquisitor Reports: 76
Personal Combat Experience: 65
Librarius Rituals: 93

The reports from Imperial Guard and Navy – only somewhat usable – and Inquisition – considerably more informative –had been consumed and analyzed. The more personal reports were useful, but not significantly so. It was obvious that Hannibal would have completely different opinions on how to best deal with the Suysh than Captain Sicarius, the two diametrically opposed on their preferred methods of xeno destruction with their experiences different accordingly. Yet that too was useful in its own way. But truthfully, the greatest aid came from that which had nearly been wiped out by Kyras in his hatred. The Librarius, slowly having grown stronger over time, performed their rituals with full attendance from the lowest of their newest members up to the might of the Chief Librarian. There, they pierced the veil using the psychic act known as ‘Battle Sight’, again and again. All of this was fed to the cogitators, and once that information was collated, it was once more analyzed relentlessly.

This was not the panicked deployment to Tartarus, nor the rushed assembly for the Dark Crusade, much less the Kaurava Campaign, though the lack of heavy Librarius support was suspected to have Kyras behind it with hindsight.

Eventually, however, the plan was set.

All that remained was to follow it.

==================================================================

Avanti Plan Execution: 98 vs. 77

Thus the Blood Ravens deployed to Avanti. Precision and discipline marked their paths. Where the enemy was, the Blood Ravens struck. Where the enemy defended, they were drawn out or circumvented entirely. The scouts proved their worth time and again, guided by the Librarians to plant mines and explosives, to deliver teleporter beacons, to mark enemy positions which only further reinforced certain possible branches of the plan while disabusing others. Such was the point, of course. To assume that everything would go perfectly along a single planned path was the height of foolishness, but by preparing additional possible branching paths. If something did not work, it did not mean that the Blood Ravens had failed, merely that instead of striking a column of fang tanks protecting the outer reaches of a particular Hive’s territory that infiltrators could assault different tunnels and infiltrate in different areas.

Mountains, canyons, mines, manufacturing facilities. Places where weapons and tanks could be made, where raw materials were processed. All of those places granted the highest possible strategic value in the confines of the campaign, these places soon became charnel houses once more. In the past, the PDF had been slaughtered by the invading Suysh, their bodies wholly devoured raw or cooked. Then, the Imperial Guard had come, but there they had faltered, and they had been wholly devoured. But now, the Blood Ravens came, and it was the alien that was ground beneath their boots, shot to pieces with their bolters, vaporized beneath their plasma weaponry, or burned to death with their flamers. A diversion here. An infiltration there. And in those cases where the plan called for it, outright confrontation to ensure total attention of the Hive.

The first Queen to die on Avanti died only three hours before the second, the two having found a divergent amount of care and communal appreciation between the two and thus having placed their Hives uncharacteristically close together. The rest would take longer, more than a week each of hard-fought battles to reach deep into where they had hidden themselves and slay them. Yet it was done. On a handful of occasions, the abilities of the Librarius to examine the near future and watch for enemy movements came into effect, ensuring the avoidance of ambush and catastrophic failure due to the efforts of Void Screamers nearly succeeding in obscuring certain Suysh movements.

It was not the glorious rush of, say, the Blood Angels, or perhaps the lightning speed warfare of the White Scars. If anything, it followed the cold calculus of the Iron Hands, bolstered with the fire and fury that the Blood Ravens possessed and further secured by the careful and vital work of the Librarius. The fear and suspicion that plagued all psykers was not without reason, throughout the Imperium and beyond, but amongst the Blood Ravens those of the purged and purified Librarius there was at least a doctrinal faith and belief. To be sure, Librarians were not without their failings and faults, none knowing this more keenly than the chapter’s brothers due to the betrayal and corruption of Kyras and the tragic fall of Isador for the Chapter Master personally. But here, and now, they succeeded in their efforts.

Queen fell after Queen, and in time, even the Death-Mark placed upon Captain Cyrus began to fade. Something that was, to the Suysh, never before done. Never had one so marked failed to be destroyed, yet the wily Captain had lived with it so long that even the powerful psychic energies of a dying Queen could remain forever. By the time the fighting on Avanti was declared finished, the Hives ruined and without leadership, it had faded entirely due to the simple fact that Captain Cyrus outlived the vengeful act of the alien. Above, the 2nd Company fleet had bombarded massive armies of Suysh who had fallen to infighting without their Queens, while the rest of the Chapter Fleet formed up with the ships of the Scarlet Lions and fought off an incursion of Suysh ships.

This too, had been planned for.

The incursion point was luckily predicted, or rather fifteen possible locations had been chosen with this being the most likely, and so the moment the Suysh ships translated out of the Warp they found themselves bombarded and in some cases boarded by the ships of the space marines. Bombardment cannons and close range weapons arrays blew holes in the alien fleet. Though the Suysh had come expecting battle, and began firing the moment they confirmed the presence of the enemy, the xenos were not prepared enough for those that faced them. These were not the Imperial Navy, nor were those invading their ships void armsmen. These were the Blood Ravens and the Scarlet Lions who – bemused at the plans offered by their peers – raucously joined in. Blood was shed in tandem as they slaughtered the Suysh, and the death of more than one Queen was accomplished due to cooperating gunnery technicians and dual bombardments. By the standards of most void battles, it was short, but the violence enacted in that same span of time was considerable. Worse for the Suysh, the ships were able to retreat to the reclaimed Crown and obtain quick repairs using commandeered resources to better be capable of standing up to the enemy should they invade once more.

=======================================================

Vatsa Plan Execution: 53
Scarlet Lions: 70
Suysh: 55

By the time the Blood Ravens appeared over Vatsa, the battle was nearly won without them. The Scarlet Lions had pushed hard, slaughtering vast numbers of Suysh as they searched for signs left behind by the false lions. Though only two Queens had been added to their tallies, the sheer vigorous effort expended by the Primarch-less marines of lost Lemnos ensured that the other Hives were forced into a concentrated defensive posture. In truth, the plan more than accommodated the Scarlet Lions. It, in fact, worked to ensure their participation and efforts were magnified in success and minimized in failures. Force Commander Bartorius would slay a Queen, aided by Blood Raven-led diversions drawing off defensive forces. Captain Agamat would do the same, the Blood Ravens leading the way into the deeper caverns while letting the Scarlet Lions 3rd Company become a roaring spear-tip to plunge into the heart of the Queen.

Vatsa would be properly dealt with in time, but after a mere week of fighting the lion’s share was more than done with. Without Queens, without almost any remaining Royal Guard, the Suysh were already falling into infighting with no method to replenish their numbers. And so the Scarlet Lions and the Blood Ravens found themselves assembling at the reclaimed and mostly repaired Sacred Crown. It would take the Mechanicus some dedicated effort to fully repair the station, but the tech marines of the Blood Ravens had done as best they could. Of the Chapter’s leadership, only Hannibal was absent, being remanded to the apothecaries due to the wounds he had sustained in battle with his largely broken armor being sent for massive repairs to the tech-marines. Again.

“Though the truth remains verily spoken, I cannot help but be baffled and enraged!” Bartorious shouted as he slammed the table once more, causing the projections of the false lions to flicker.

“My company found no signs,” Captain Agamat says softly, shaking his head, “But I trust you Force Commander.”

“We all do, Agamat,” Kallek huffs, “But forsooth do I despise these…these jackanapeses who hath desecrated the memory of the 8th Company.”

“I not wherefore these false marines come from,” Bartorious growls, “Nor why they pretendeth to beest of the Lion’s sons, but I knoweth yond marines art false Scarlet Lions and yet did pretend to beest so – a death sentence regardless! Yet afore that death, I must know how and why they hath donned such trickery!”

“Yet, our mission given thusly by yon Mistress Tarquindil wast to putteth an endeth to the Suysh in this system, good Bartorius. Can we truly afford to deny her and thus loseth the Chapter her promised rewards?” Agamat speaks up, rubbing at his scarred chin.

“I…,” Bartorius growls, turning on his fellow Scarlet Lion with one finger held high.

A metallic cough brought about by bionic lungs drew attention next.

“If I may,” Gabriel said calmly, “Our Master of the Forge has some news to share.”

Martellus approached the table next, servo-arm twitching slightly over his shoulder.

“I have discovered the location of the Suysh home system, and it is indeed where the false lions departed to. How they discovered it so quickly I do not know, but I suspect that they somehow figured out the coordinates with the aid of what…or whoever they were searching for leaving signs behind. As suspected, it lies just beyond the reach of the Astronomicon, but I firmly believe that with the aid of the Litany of Fury, we can reach that point.”

With that said, he placed several data pads for perusal upon the table. Scoured databanks of the Sacred Crown, carefully investigated xeno technology, reversed astral analysis provided by the Librarius, and information gained through the Omophagea. The latter of which had involved a few tech marines being discreetly transported to corpses of certain slain Queens upon the void ships. All of this had been looked at, reported, analyzed, and then analyzed again. The information was near-irrefutable. The false marines who had departed had traveled in the same direction, leading a worrisome credence to the information. It was no simple matter to track something through the Warp, for the Warp itself could reshape itself and thus muddy any such trail immediately, but for a wonder such had not happened just yet.

At the same time, the orders given were to reclaim the worlds present. Because there had been no information on the Suysh homeworlds, it was likely that the Imperium was planning on reclaiming and then heavily fortifying the system again with the expectation that they would be weathering assaults from then on. It would not be the first time a system had been treated as such, but the materials and manufactorums that the Suysh yet still inhabited were vital to the Sector. While the current stockpiles and rationing procedures could stretch for a considerable period of time, the fact of the matter was that without the Jahal System, the Sector would be greatly weakened in the long run. Without Queens, the Suysh were turning on each other, and there was, admittedly, the possibility of them irreparably destroying the facilities the space marines had been sent to reclaim.

But on the other hand, the possibility of ending the Suysh threat at the source was…tempting, Gabriel had to admit.

Bartorius growled as the Force Commander clearly came to the same conclusion.

“We could leave behind a Company to maintain clearing efforts against the Suysh in the Jahal System,” Cyrus eventually spoke up, the Captain of the 10th Company remaining largely obscured in the shadows of the room.

He leaned forward, hair obscuring much of his face save for his cybernetic eye.

“We had a responsibility to committing as little as possible collateral damage on the worlds of this system. There is no such requirement for the home worlds of the Suysh. Furthermore, as they are outside of the light of the Astronomicon, it is unlikely that the Imperium would ever desire to try colonization. My scouts and I could remain here, Chapter Master. Without the Queens, I doubt we would face too much difficulty.”

Not to mention, without the Death-Mark affecting him anymore, he could personally intervene wherever it was required.

Still, the suggestion was made, and so Cyrus leaned back into the shadows, arms coming up to cross over his chest.

"You speaketh truth, Agamat, yet consider thusly," Bartorius turned to look at Gabriel, "Our orders were to assisteth the Blood Ravens, not merely cleanse yon benighted system."

Hmm. Gabriel could see what Bartorius was asking, even if he had done so obliquely. Yet it was not a decision made lightly. The ships of both chapters were repaired, their wounded for the most part walking and able to fight once more. But to plunge beyond the confines of the Astronomicon was not lightly done, even if the mysterious beacon within the Litany of Fury had aided them in doing so before. But they would be without easy support at the same time, and they had no information whatsoever on what was going on in the home system of the Suysh. At the same time, the false lions had gone there in search of some group of marines or another, and had been willing to lie about their origins to do so. And, if Gabriel was honest with himself, he felt the burning desire to know, to peel apart a mystery, something inherent to most all Blood Ravens. Yet all the while he pondered, the Suysh continued to fight below, and the false lions did who knew what.

And so he came to a decision.

Crisis Point Reached
Phase 5 Concluded! The Queens of the Suysh within the Jahal System have all died. The Suysh have fallen completely into self-cannibalization. The efforts of Martellus and the Librarius have borne fruit, the home system coordinates of the Suysh have been discovered. However, the Suysh infighting may or may not damage infrastructure on the planets of the Jahal System if left unchecked. The False Scarlet Lions are confirmed to have departed in the same direction as the coordinates discovered, all for chasing after some unknown group of marines. No further fatalities were sustained by the Blood Ravens, but the Scarlet Lions took a few while fighting alone on Vatsa. Cyrus suggests that without needing to work to reduce collateral, there would be no need to hold back on the Suysh home system, and furthermore that the 10th Company could remain behind to technically fulfill the Chapter's orders to continue fighting against the Suysh and reclaim facilities that now no longer possess reinforcements. Without the Beacon Psykana upon the Litany of Fury, the journey could not be safely made, thus the true Scarlet Lions are reliant upon the Blood Ravens to discover the truth.

Decision:
[] Onwards And Foe-Wards: The only way to truly end the Suysh threat is to destroy them at the source, to ensure that they cannot continue threatening the sector forever. This will, if only temporarily, take the Blood Ravens beyond the confines of the Imperium along with the Scarlet Lions. But the value cannot be understated. The Imperium would surely look kindly upon removing the Suysh as a continuing threat, including the Inquisition...if successful, of course. [Write-In Forces Allotted] Not Required, Will Mean Blood Ravens do not pursue Suysh Homeworlds if no forces are allotted. ADDITIONAL NOTE: This will pull the Litany of Fury off of its current duties with the 5th Company to make use of the Beacon.
-[] Following The Letter: Some Blood Ravens must stay behind if the rest of the Chapter leaves, if only to ensure that they are perceived as still performing the task asked of them by combating the Suysh in the Jahal System. [Write-In Forces Allotted]
-[] If Some Go, Some Stay: If the Litany of Fury is pulled from its current position, it will need to replaced, if only temporarily. [Write-In Ships Exchanged For Litany of Fury Arrival]
[] Remain And Cleanse: The orders given were to secure the Jahal System. That is precisely what the Blood Ravens are going to do. The Scarlet Lions may not be pleased, but other than suicidally attempting to charge off into the warp, they can only remain here. This is the safest option, surely, and the Imperium would be pleased to see such a space marine concentration working towards common cause. Will remain present until Imperial Reinforcements arrive to secure system fully.

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Eight)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[x] Onwards And Foe-Wards: The only way to truly end the Suysh threat is to destroy them at the source, to ensure that they cannot continue threatening the sector forever. This will, if only temporarily, take the Blood Ravens beyond the confines of the Imperium along with the Scarlet Lions. But the value cannot be understated. The Imperium would surely look kindly upon removing the Suysh as a continuing threat, including the Inquisition...if successful, of course. [Write-In Forces Allotted] Not Required, Will Mean Blood Ravens do not pursue Suysh Homeworlds if no forces are allotted.
-[X] Following The Letter: Some Blood Ravens must stay behind if the rest of the Chapter leaves, if only to ensure that they are perceived as still performing the task asked of them by combating the Suysh in the Jahal System.
--[X] 10th Company+fleet, 4 techmarines, 2 apothecaries, 2 chaplains
-[X] If Some Go, Some Stay: If the Litany of Fury is pulled from its current position, it will need to replaced, if only temporarily. [Write-In Ships Exchanged For Litany of Fury Arrival]
--[X] Exchange Strike Cruiser - Ravenous Spirit (2nd) and Strike Cruiser - Legacy of Polonius (4th)

Moratorium For 3 Hours.

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

No Idle Hands: 68

It was a tense time, waiting for the Litany of Fury to arrive. Unluckily for the Suysh, in the time it takes for the astropathic messages to bounce from the main Chapter Fleet to where the 5th Company is stationed is spent with those Blood Ravens present continuing to execute various portions of the devised plan. The Scarlet Lions too, accepting the explanation for the wait with barely contained frustration, elected to try and kill as many xenos as possible in the meantime. Thus, by the time the venerable battle barge that once served as the flagship of Gabriel Angelos in his time as a Captain of the Blood Ravens had arrived, tens of thousands more Suysh were dead. The 10th Company scouts truly showed their mettle, and worthiness for possible future promotion, in those days of combat. Many a factorum was cleansed and reclaimed, old defenses reactivated and rebuilt, with the Suysh forced out of their misappropriated homes. Without any more Queens to sustain their numbers nor to command them intelligently, the scouts focused their efforts on a top-down approach to the entire affair. The less leadership the Suysh possessed, the more animalistic they became. When the Litany of Fury arrived out of the warp, guided there with the aid of the Librarius acting as a focus point, there were no Royal Guard left in existence in the Jahal System. Bereft of their authority, and purposefully located with Librarian support, the 10th Company also executed the last of the alien psykers who had begun taking on leadership status in the interim. Without Royal Guard or Void Screamers, the next in line were the Hungerers, who were brought down with repeated deep striking by the terminators of both chapters present.

But the time came, as it had to, with the Litany and all other ships receiving maintenance and repairs - especially the battle barge Scion of Honor, which had nearly shattered itself with the daring maneuver to emerge from the Warp without a care for gravimetric concerns. All those wounded had been healed to highest extent by the exceptional abilities of the Apothecarium, the dreadnoughts had been granted time to sleep, and the coordinates were locked in.

"Force Commander Bartorius, assemble your ships as close as possible to the Litany of Fury. When we pass beyond the confines of the Astronomicon, your astropaths and Librarians must focus upon the Beacon Psykana," Gabriel transmitted to the nearby waiting ships. "Should their gaze waver, you may be lost to the Emperor forever."

"I wilt admiteth, Chapter Master Angelos, I has't nev'r hath heard of such a device before. How couldst any device possibly projecteth the Emperor's gaze in such manner?"

Gabriel shifted uncomfortably within his armor at the question. It was one that had burned in the heart of the Blood Ravens for millennia, yet none had truly come to a conclusive answer. Just another question that his chapter might never know the answer to.

"We do not know, for certain, Force Commander. It was forged by the great Azariah Vidya, a great hero of the Chapter past, long ago. Yet it functions, and with it, we may strike both at the Suysh and these false marines who deigned to try and use the name of the Scarlet Lions as masks."

The line went silent for a moment before crackling to life once more.

"...very well, Angelos. Forsooth, mine brother hath fought alongside yours well enough thus far, and hath found their character tempered and fine. I shall trust you in this endeavor."

It was a startlingly rare statement, and one that Gabriel had certainly not expected. The vast majority of all Imperial organizations, even their fellow astartes, had long held suspicions towards the Blood Ravens. For the Scarlet Lions to decide they were trustworthy was...appreciated. There was no other way that Gabriel knew to express it.

"Understood. Then let us depart, and see to the end of these vile aliens!"

Gabriel then nodded up at Hadrian, ensconced as the Master of the Fleet was within the command throne of the Omnis.

"Attention, all ships! Prepare for warp transition!"

The universe shuddered ever so slightly as a hole was torn through it, and the eye-melting colors of the Immaterium were revealed. Slowly, the various ships began to advance, the Litany of Fury in the very center of the formation, until all had passed through the forced entryway and it had closed behind them leaving no immediate sign of their passage at all.

==========================================================

Warp Travel: 84

The transition from being within the bounds of the Astronomicon and being without it was not immediately discernible to those who did not count themselves amongst the ranks of astropaths, navigators, or Librarians. Then came the rumbles and shakes of ship superstructures. The techmarines and their servitors began to rush about as the gellar fields began to strain and spark, the generators pushed alternatively to overdrive and then nearly shut off from lack of activity. There was a particular horror that could not properly be expressed to those who did not understand the technical information provided by the cogitators, the absolute certainty that the stresses upon the gellar fields in certain sections were distinct and targeted. To not only know, but see verifiable evidence of other beings, other intelligences probing the defenses that were all that lied between the ships and being invaded, transformed, or torn apart. Or all three at once. But throughout it all, the Beacon Psykana pulsed, a steady beat of light that was but a pale thing of wan illumination compared to the soul-searing power of the Astronomicon. Yet for all that, a thready candle was better than utter darkness. A week of warp travel, during which there was but relentless training and preparations made, yet to know precisely just when they had left and arrived by the reckoning of proper reality could not be known while within the confines of the Warp.

One day before transitioning back into the Materium, the Omnis Arcanum was rocked by an impact that nearly overwhelmed the systems, followed by a keening screech that infested the dreams of all who lived on the ship and set many serfs to bleeding from the ears no matter where they had slept in the ship. The Librarians, ever seekers of knowledge, consulted the thorough records of the Blood Ravens on such phenomena and found that even in the engrammatic records there existed no precisely congruent source of such things. Thus, they concluded, something within the Warp had attempted entry on the venerable ship, and it had either been very, very new, or very, very old. But it mattered little, for the fleet was able to conclude warp transition. Void shields were raised, weapon arrays readied, bombardment cannons loaded, for the Blood Ravens were plunging into the heart of the enemy, and though they had clearly lost ships trying to retake the Jahal system, it would be the height of folly to assume that there was no home guarding fleet.

The Suysh Home System was a large one, a blazing yellow star at its center. Five worlds, three of them terrestrial, two enormous gas giants, slowly orbited the sun. Most importantly, however, was the incredibly thick asteroid belt on the outermost ring of the system, rather than somewhere within it. It was this asteroid belt that met the ships of the space marines first, rattling against the void shield.

But none of that matters.

What matters is that the two of the worlds of the Suysh have already fallen. The immediate long range scans are clear, they came under assault and were destroyed. A great number of orbital stations are currently burnt wreckage or being crushed by the atmospheres of the gas giants, having been pushed out of orbit and down through one method or another. Those over two of the terrestrial worlds were clearly used against the Suysh, an act Gabriel approved of if one efficiently and without too many casualties. The Blood Raven ships and those of the Scarlet Lions cautiously but swiftly move through the outer reaches of the system, until finally they are sighted over the last of the Suysh homeworlds, the last viable planet in the system at all with defenses and inhabitants. The 'Scarlet Lions', though you now know them not to be, have lost their escort frigates, with no sign of where they've gone. Their ship is heavily battered now, far in excess of the minor damage that had been sighted beforehand. But that, too, is not precisely what matters.

What matters is that they are chasing another ship, rather than doing anything to the Suysh orbital stations firing at them. And that ship is, itself, not of xeno origin. Rather it is of Imperial design. More specifically, of Astartes design. A strike cruiser, bearing no sigil or code - the latter of which is confusing even to the cogitators. You can plainly see it is a strike cruiser, a vanguard variant specifically, but other than that it is impossible to say. Nevertheless, the 'Scarlet Lions' are chasing after the ship with reckless abandon and ruthless aggression, firing every weapon they can at the comparatively weaving and ducking target whose shields generators are clearly damaged. All the while, Suysh orbital weaponry shoots at them both. As your ships continue forward, you watch as the vanguard cruiser is struck on the rear with repeated fire from the bombardment cannon of the 'Scarlet Lion' vessel, and begins crashing down on the last remaining Suysh home planet.

Only then does the vox crackle.

"Chapter Master Angelos, you've...finally arrived," came the sibilant voice of Master Akermian with obvious strain. "Excellent, let join forces once more. We have located-,"

"Blaggards and rapscallions!" Bartorius rants, transmitting solely to the Omnis, "You spoke verily, Angelos! Those ships doth truly bear the signals and sigils of the 8th Company! That vessel be Scarlet Lion, but those who stalk its halls be false!"

"-heretics and traitor space marines," Akermian continues, unaware of the interruption. "Clearly, they are how the Suysh knew to invade our worlds, and thus they are responsible for all the death that the Suysh have brought to the Imperium!"

Yet even as he speaks, the guns of his strike cruiser finally turning on the xeno platforms surrounding them, Gabriel could not will his ships forward fast enough to stop the inevitable. The already heavily damaged and now possibly stolen Scarlet Lion ship was already breaking apart. Its engines flared brightly, but they could not stop the ship as it too began to enter the atmosphere despite the will of those who inhabited it.

"Gah! Angelos, you must aid us, in the name of the Emperor!" Akermian yelled, his channel filled with greater and greater static before the transmission cut out entirely.

"Chapter Master, what do we do?" Martellus asked, turning to him. "We could easily take down those Suysh orbitals, but...afterwards...,"

All of those on the bridge turned slightly to gaze at the stoic Chapter Master, who stood motionless as his eyes studied the tactical screens. Perhaps ironically, perhaps not, the two strike cruisers were crashing down in the same area of the Suysh planet. It possessed only two continents, and towards the colder and more inhospitable northern pole both ships were going down only a few dozen miles away from one another, though whether this was because of intent last-minute adjustments with barely functioning engines or not was hard to tell. If those inhabiting either ship truly were space marines, a number of them would most certainly survive the crash. Whether they would survive the Suysh swarming over them afterwards was another question all together. In his heart, Gabriel was furious at the false lions, for their actions had led directly to the death of Blood Ravens, yet as a Blood Raven he desired greatly to unravel the mystery before him. If they had been able to come earlier, perhaps they might have had different choices, the ships that were currently falling through the Suysh atmosphere showed clear signs of fighting one another for some time now. But there was no point speculating now.

Arrival! The Suysh Home System Has Been Reached!
The Suysh possess one world left in the system that is viable, the other two terrestrial planets destroyed, the orbital habitats elsewhere destroyed. The False Scarlet Lions, led by 'Master Akermian', have succeeded in locating their quarry, shooting them down over the last Suysh Homeworld. Yet, so focused there were on their task that they were soon shot down as well by the remaining ignored Suysh defenses. Both ships are crashing near the north pole of the planet, and long-range scans have confirmed that the majority of the Suysh on the planet live elsewhere, making the location relatively isolated. Yet, there is no doubt that the Suysh will be sending forces to kill the invaders soon enough. Should the Blood Ravens assist the Scarlet Lions, or accost them? There also remains the possibility of communicating with the new and unidentified strike cruiser's inhabitants. Force Commander Bartorius is incensed, as are all of the true Scarlet Lions, and wishes to solve this mystery, possibly to the death of the False Lions. But it is the Blood Ravens, with greater ships and firepower, with greater numbers of troops, who will decide what is to occur in the here and now. Afterwards, the Suysh cannot possibly stop orbital bombardment, regardless of the outcome of the False Lion situation.

Orders, Chapter Master? Voting Moratorium For 3 Hours.
[] Write-In

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Nine)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Plan: We Want Answers
-[X] 4th company and fleets clear the orbitals of enemy presence and then move to position for orbital bombardment.
--[X] Capture at least 1 orbital station intact, and then have Martellus and his techmarines go through its sensor logs and databanks to learn what happened here.
-[X] Have Librarius attempt to scry what they can on the identity of the Unknown Marines
-[X] Chapter Leadership, 2nd company and Scarlet Lions head to secure the Unknown Marines. Attempt to establish communication if scrying doesn't reveal them to be Traitors.
-[X] 1st Company and any elements of the 5th Company moves to support the False Lions.

Moratorium For 3 Hours.

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

"We will have answers, Force Commander, one way or another," Gabriel said with a calm he did not feel. "Hadrian, I want that planet's orbit swept clean. I will leave it to you and the 4th Company to capture at least one orbital station intact so that Martellus might wrench what secrets he may from their foul alien technologies."

"Understood, Chapter Master!"

From the command throne of the Omnis, Hardrian's orders flowed with and without actual speech. Engines burned brightly in the unfamiliar void as the whole of the chapter's fleet thus present began to advance. Where the other ships were but strike cruisers, the ships that led from the forefront now were some of the most heavily armored vessels in the whole of the galaxy, the various battle barges having been fully repaired by the sophisticated tending systems of the Sacred Crown space station. When the Suysh orbital stations began to fire at the newest interlopers, they found the might of their weaponry faltering against not just the Omnis Arcanum, but the Scientia Est Potentia and the Litany of Fury as well. Furthermore, the mighty Scion of Honor rumbled forth as well, having recovered from the reckless but effective maneuver of bypassing traditional gravimetric restrictions in warp travel. Surely, Gabriel suspected based on what he knew of Martellus, the techmarines of the Scarlet Lions were either fully supportive of what their Force Commander asked or screaming in their helmets at all times. It could only be one or the other. Nevertheless, even discounting the various strike cruisers and escort ships, four battle barges assembled for but one task were one of the most powerful concentrations of space-borne power that Gabriel had witnessed in quite some time.

"Justinius, if you can, see what information you might glean about these unknown marines, if they are space marines at all."

The Chief Librarian grimaced before nodding, a motion from his hand and a burst of intent from his soul causing the spines of all Librarians present to stiffen regardless of rank. Silently and as one they began to file out towards the battle barge's librarius. The warp here was unfamiliar, and the Librarius had not had the time to grow used to the local currents of the Immaterium like they had in the Jahal System. Even so, scrying and piercing the veil were a specialty of the Blood Ravens. They would just have to be even more careful than usual, for the psychic might of the Suysh Queens was not to be discounted, even if they were not specifically focusing their efforts on them. No more words needed to be exchanged between them, and Gabriel turned back to the tac-screens and projectors before Justinius was even off of the bridge. Now would come something far more difficult to negotiate, if he did not miss his mark.

"Force Commander Bartorius...I have a proposition for you."

"Speak verily then, we hath some time afore we reach the planet."

"I propose that elements of the Blood Ravens go to both crash sites, and secure the marines at both. However, I would implore you to go with us to the targets of the False Lions first, that we may secure them and learn what we can of them, thus gaining more information about the actions of the False Lions."

There was a moment of silence over the vox.

"I apologize, Angelos, for mine ears surely doth misheard thy words," Bartorius finally responded with a deadly calm in his voice. "For if mine eye do not deceive, verily hath the False Lions fallen from the stars, ready for chastisement, yet you would have the Lions of Lemnos bring not vengeance 'pon their necks but rather go elsewhere?!" By the end of it, the bombastic space marine had escalated to full-throated yelling at such high volume that the vox channel nearly cut out from the strain of transmission.

Gabriel simply closed his eyes and sighed, the rest of the marines on the command deck continuing to stare straight ahead the whole while. Apollo grimaced in subdued anger, ceramite ever so quietly scraping against itself for a brief instant as his armored hands clenched tightly together.

"You did not mishear me," Gabriel spoke steadily, choosing to ignore the angry harrumph which came immediately, "But consider, Force Commander, that we would be ensuring that the False Lions do not succeed in their own mission, or at the very least contained. Do we not deserve answers? Answers that the False Lions may not give, but their quarry might possess."

There was the sound of shouting on the vox channel from a number of Scarlet Lions, their words mixing together into a general frustrated cacophony, yet absent was the voice of the Force Commander. To be fair, Gabriel understood. Here were space marines that had stolen their words, their ships, their codifiers, their very name, and had used them for their own purposes. Who had ensured the death of loyal marines of the Blood Ravens, further maligning the name of the Scarlet Lions, arrived under possibly false pretenses and undeniably had abandoned the Blood Ravens and the efforts of the Imperium in reclaiming the Jahal system. And here, now, the False Lions were in the middle of crash landing, and were thus going to be incapable of fleeing the oncoming hammer of the true Scarlet Lions and the Blood Ravens both. But instead of joining the Scarlet Lions in punishing them, he was asking them to pivot and turn to the unknown marines, their numbers and disposition a mystery. Even so.

"I will be deploying Blood Ravens to the False Lions, Force Commander, and with their aid we will be able to keep a better eye on the False Lions. We outnumber them significantly with our chapters working together, and I trust in my battle brothers and yours to be able to handle themselves should matters come to blows. Before you stated you trusted me in this endeavor. Has this changed?"

Still, Bartorius did not respond, even as it began to sound as if some of the Scarlet Lions on his command deck were edging closer and closer to coming to blows.

Fellowship Test: 74

"Enough!" Bartorius could be heard to bellow, followed shortly by the slamming of a ceramite-clad fist into a console, silencing the angry Scarlet Lions nearby.

Slowly, heavily, the Force Commander breathed before letting out one last long exhale.

"Thee test me and mine brothers most heavily, Chapter Master Angelos," he ground out angrily. "Most...heavily. Were we alone, I would bring the full force of the true Scarlet Lions 'pon the heads of those who bear our banner falsely and tear them asunder with all the fury of lost Lemnos."

Gabriel remained still, eyes closed, mind racing as he considered the battle barge and strike cruisers currently flying alongside the ships of the Blood Ravens.

"But...I see some wisdom in your words."

Immediately, everyone could hear cries of outrage from the marines on Bartorius' command deck.

"We shall speak on this matter again once we reach the planet," was all the Force Commander said before cutting the vox.

Slowly, Gabriel released a single breathe and bowed his head. Violence between space marines was always a distasteful affair, in some aspect or another. Even in combat with those who had fallen to Chaos, there was the ever present knowledge that a number of them were veterans of the Great Crusade, a living and hateful reminder of the collapse of a Golden Age. To view a true veteran Chaos Space Marine was to know that there stood what should have been glorious was instead a twisted mirror. No matter the righteousness of the fight, the satisfaction of putting an end to them, that in the end they should not have been at all were it not for the machinations of Chaos and weak wills was a bitter thing. He did not wish to come to blows with the Scarlet Lions, but knew in that instant that it had been a genuine possibility. The offense in Bartorius' voice was palpable, and even now he was likely being forced to corral his battle brothers in their anger. Still, there was time yet to further convince him. Even at full speed, it took a modicum of time for their ships to make it through the void between planets within a solar system. And unlike before, they did not have a station such as the Sacred Crown to repair their vessels if they went for a close-range warp jump outside of gravimetric constraints.

==========================================================================

Scrying Efforts: 41

The air was simply different within the Librarius. Charged with otheworldly electricity, a quiet humming that seemed to emanate from everywhere and nowhere all at once. The scent of records yellowed with age and freshly created documents, ancient paper and fresh ink, flooded the air and mixed with incense and other unguents. This was not the smoke and spark filled air of the forges, loud and booming, nor was it the sterilized clean of the apothecarium. It was something different all together. Gabriel was exposed to only a bare minimum of this as the doors opened and the Chief Librarian emerged, his face troubled. But a second of exposure, able to see the bright blue and white, before the doors closed. Each Librarius was a sacred place, meant to be trod only by those blessed and cursed to be a psyker. Rare was the occasion on which another might be allowed entry, fellow member of the Chapter or not, Chapter Master or not. He was in this moment far more focused, however, upon the Chief Librarian who frowned despite the power the sometimes visibly flowed from him.

"I suspect you do not bring me good tidings, Justinius," Gabriel eventually said after a moment of silence had passed.

"On the contrary, Chapter Master, I bring you almost no tidings at all," came the dry reply. Seeing Gabriel's unimpressed eyebrow raise, Justinius sighed and continued. "The warp here is full of ghosts, Gabriel. I do not know how long the Suysh have existed, but in that time, a vast number of queens have died. The psychic echoes of their death throes are constantly bouncing back and forth."

Justinius shook his head and turned towards the corridor, the two space marines soon walking in unison through the ship towards the command deck.

"The effect grows only stronger the closer we get to the planet. What little we were able to glean is that they," he gestured to some far off point in the middle distance, "Are space marines."

"Mmm," Gabriel grunted. "Could you at all tell if the False Lions speak truth? Are they traitors? Heretics?"

A marine of the 4th Company saluted them as they passed, one briefly returned before they continued moving.

"All I can say is that they have been touched by Chaos."

Gabriel's head whipped toward Justinius, eyes wide.

"But, so too, could I say the same of almost every living Blood Raven, yourself included, Chapter Master. Chaos touches even those who fight against it."

Bitter memories rose, then. As they often did. Even now, as it likely always would, the fall of Isador stung him. Then would come the unanswerable questions. It took but one campaign, one encounter, and his childhood friend had fallen to the darkest depths. As far as Gabriel knew, he was the only living Blood Raven left that had been recruited from Cyrene. The battles against Kyras had touched the the very soul of the Chapter. Then there were those who spoke of the exiled Aramus, possibly one of the greatest young heroes of the Chapter, for a time at least before he had faltered against the forces of Eliphas and Araghast. Many wondered if he and Thaddeus might have been of aid against Kyras, and in the end, that might have been true. But Aramus had accepted his punishment with stoic grace, knowing just as well as Gabriel had that he had faltered and required punishment. But how could he know the character of these unknown marines, with the Librarius failing to discern any particularly vital truths? There was but one way left, it seemed, that would provide the answers that he sought in a manner he could accept.

"Very well then. It seems that we will have to gather the measure of these marines in a more direct manner. I intend for the Chapter Leadership to accompany when we make planetfall."

Justinius nodded in acknowledgement.

"Has Hannibal been released by Gracchus, then?" He asked curiously.

By now, the increasingly tempestuous relationship between the Master of Sanctity and the Chief Apothecary were quickly becoming legendary throughout the chapter. The former would throw himself into the absolute thickest of the fighting with reckless bravery, often winning major victories and preserving the lives of his brethren. He would, however, repeatedly take grievous wounds in the course of that same bravery which would immediately require his placement under the direct hands of the Chief Apothecary once the fighting was concluded. Neither man was a stranger to battle, but the fact that the exact same patient was remanded to his care so quickly and repeatedly had apparently strained the young prodigy's temper. Noting close enough to make him refuse care, obviously, but the fact remained that there were very few Blood Ravens indeed who had the ability to yell Hannibal Palrun down.

"I believe so, yes," Gabriel smirked. "Martellus tells me that repairing his wargear after battle has become a regular assignment in perpetuity for Daedal and Calus, so by now it should all be functional once more."

The Chief Librarian snorted as they walked.

"By which you mean they have fabricated yet another set of power armor for him to ruin by running directly into the line of fire."

"Thunder Blood seems to never suffer such a fate," Gabriel reminded him mildly.

"Yes, well, the weapon seems to have taken on almost as hardy a nature as its master," Justinius grunted back. "But by this point, and you cannot deny this, there are enough fragments left from previous battles that I do not doubt that Martellus could not construct a set of power armor from them alone."

Thus was Justinius and Justinius alone witness to a rare sight, that of the Chapter Master letting loose a rusted cough of a laugh.

=========================================================================

Techno-Scrying: 35

Soon enough, the combined fleet reached orbit. They had not bothered to even try to disguise their approach. The Suysh had no vessels left to them. The fleets that they had sent out would not be returning. By the time the defensive stations began to fire, Hadrian Priscus had already departed the command throne, trusting to his serfs and crew to keep the ship functioning in the meantime. The 4th Company would be deploying aboard assault rams rather than drop pods, and even as the rest of the fleet had begun to head in the direction of the crash sites, the 4th Company was deploying. Despite all hopes, the Suysh design philosophy was not perfectly known enough for any particular station to be chosen for assault, and the attempts of the tech marines to trace alien signal and transmissions had not been successful. If there was a central station rather than a general network, it was well disguised amongst its brethren. As such, Hadrian had designated a scattershot of targets for boarding, dividing his forces accordingly. As for the rest of the Blood Ravens and the Scarlet Lions, they did not fear the weapons of the enemy, not now. Unlike before, these were battle barges and strike cruisers undamaged, without the issue of firing at one another. As the vessels themselves had been purposefully designed for, they simply shifted into position while weathering enemy fire upon their powerful void shields, readying for deployment in complete defiance of all the desperation of the alien. The threat of aircraft interception or orbital fire rotating to atmospheric targets meant that the usage of thunderhawks was inadvisable.

"Chapter Master, we are deploying to the planet now," Captain Crixus transmitted. "The 1st Company shall see to these False Lions."

"Be cautious, Brother-Captain," Gabriel replied, his tone grim, "And be wary. Do not put your backs to them...and prepare yourselves should this come to violence."

"Understood. They shall not catch us unawares, Chapter Master," Crixus replied just as grimly.

On the planet below, the Suysh were boiling forth. The initial probes towards the crash sites already numbered in the millions of the xenos. This could not be allowed. What was coming would solely be between space marine and space marine. Thus, the cogitators were loaded, the serfs given their orders, the servitors programmed for purpose. As assault rams shot outwards, as drop pods were launched, the bombardment cannons began to fire. Orbital bombardment had but one restriction here, not destroying the entire planet while the matter in the north was concluded. This world lay beyond the bounds of the Imperium, beyond the Astronomicon. It had no purpose but as a home and breeding ground for a xenos race that had proven itself dedicated to the consumption of all life, much like the extra-galactic tyranids. Even if the enemy were able to somewhat disrupt precise firing coordinates in certain locations through technological or psychic means, such was not required. Such was the nature of the millennium's wars. Gone was the golden age of the Imperium, a time when peace and reconciliation was even a possibility. Now there was only the grim dark future of only war. The Suysh could not have possibly known this, true, when they invaded the Imperium. But what they considered a grand invasion and occupation, a whole series of systems under threat, was but one sector. Yet even that was too great a crime, and the Angels of Death would suffer not the alien to live.

4th Company Assaults: 87
Information Ripping: 95

As Captain Priscus favored, the 4th Company was aggressive and swift in their boarding assaults. The Suysh fought with all the crazed fervor their race had been shown to possess, but by now the experiences of the campaign were well integrated into the tactics of the Blood Ravens. Even more so the 4th, who had fought repeated void battle against the enemy. Within an hour, the stations chosen by Hadrian were captured, their foul alien cogitators being examine by the tech marines, the Forge Master calling in from a distance as he accompanied the Chapter Master to the planet below. Though much of the information was garbled, sensor logs showed that the vanguard strike cruiser had emerged from the warp long ago, in fact before the fleets that had been fought at Jahal had even departed. Dangerously, they had chosen to make short warp jumps out of the system when cornered by Suysh ships, returning afterwards once the coast was somewhat more clear. They had been the ones to attack the construction facilities and refueling stations over the gas giants, ensuring a significant reduction in the alien's ability to construct and fuel their fleets. Then they had gone on the attack against the Suysh terrestrial planets though far less successfully, due to the Suysh concentrating their fleets there before - as Martellus is able to extract, the fleets were sent to reclaim the Jahal System.

A dangerous game of cat and mouse, dealing what damage could be done and then jumping away, by this point Martellus expects that the strike cruiser was running dangerously close to burning out its engines and gellar fields at the rate it was going.

When the false Scarlet Lions arrived, however, everything changed. Due to the nature of warp travel stretching and bending time without rhyme or reason, it appears that they arrived shortly after the second fleet departed while in one of the intervals where the other marines had jumped out of system temporarily. As such, they had fallen upon the Suysh planets remaining, scouring two of them before the unknown marines jumped back in system. Thus began the far more laborious fight between the two, weeks and weeks of chasing and exchanging fire, a chase that had ended only as you had arrived. The alien technologies have little more information that, as being non-Imperial they had no communications or understandable transmission logs. In the end, the only conclusion that could be drawn was that both forces opposed the Suysh, but that the false Scarlet Lions had put even that aside to hunt their apparent quarry. However, it was Techmarine Calus that discovered something else entirely. His odd skill with exotic technologies allowed him to retrieve certain data packages alluding to other systems of the Suysh, which expands their threat profile tremendously. Indeed, while this is their home system, this was not their only controlled solar system outside of the bounds of the Astronomicon. Systems that, nonetheless, were recently under attack from ships matching the profile of the unknown marines.

=========================================================================

Crash Landing West: 27

Captain Marcus Crixus felt the incredible g-forces exerted upon his body tugging slightly at the mass of scars that was his head, but for all that, he was calm. The 1st Company was falling in their own drop pods around his own, and they were deploying to the location of a hundred suspect marines, but he remained calm. For his brothers were the veterans of the Chapter, and they were almost all clad in terminator armor. Even when they had last met these so-called Scarlet Lions, there had been no terminators noted amongst their number. Thus, in wargear, there was an edge. In addition, with his authority as captain, he had authorized the awakening of all three of the 1st Company's dreadnought brothers, each of them temporarily equipped in Hellfire-pattern. He did not desire to spill the blood of marines loyal to the Emperor, even if they were misguided like these might be. He was not Aramus Valorun. But he still needed to be prepared for it. Especially if they dared threaten his company, or the two squads of the 5th Company that had accompanied the Litany of Fury, for now temporarily seconded to his command.

"Be wary, battle brothers. We go to aid these marines for now, but the moment they turn treacherous we will exact payment for our dead brothers in the Jahal System."

A communication request clicked in his ear, a flicker of intent and the blink of an eye within his helmet allowing the channel to open.

"Captain, is this truly wise?"

The question came from Uriel Hamul, the Company's Champion, his question thick with angry suspicion.

"We will give them but one chance. And should it be required, I have faith in you and the rest of the company to cut them down before they can draw a single drop more of Blood Raven blood."

The response was non-verbal, a guttural grunt of acknowledgement and approval. Some might bristle at being so constantly challenged in their position of absolute authority over the company, but Marcus found himself appreciating it when Uriel spoke to him as such. It kept him grounded, reminded him that for all that he held the position of captain his youth was extreme, comparatively untested when considering the typical space marine captain of any 1st Company. Better for it to be Apollo Diomedes, or some other veteran with at least another century of experience behind them. It would have been easy for pride to overwhelm him, to think that his position was despite his youth rather than simple expediency in a time of absolute desperation in the Chapter. Easy, were it not for his near death at the hands of the fires which had nearly claimed him, were it not for the voice of Uriel raised in question, forcing him to consider his decisions and positions with care.

A faint chime came from the machine spirit of the drop pod as its link with his helm lit up once more, letting him know that impact was only seconds away. Around him, the rest of his command squad braced themselves. Impact itself was barely even worth noting, the icy northern climate already heavily disrupted by the impact of two different strike cruisers registered the arrival of the drop pods almost not at all. Snow and ice had been flash-melted in considerable amounts, revealing packed and now cracked earth below. The moment the doors slammed down the company was deploying itself defensively, the heavy boots of terminators joined with the rumbling crunch of dreadnoughts. Marcus emerged and winced despite himself at the sight of the smoking and shattered frame of the strike cruiser of the Scarlet Lions. Strike cruisers and battle barges were incredibly durable vessels, and he knew that it was entirely possible for some to crash-landed ships to be painstakingly pulled back into orbit with the aid of the Mechanicus. This would not be one of them, the Scarlet Lions would not be reclaiming a ship today. Even without being knowledgeable in the techno-arcane like a tech priest, Marcus could tell that the ship's spine was broken in three places, the scans from orbit showing that it had landed on its side and dug a two-mile long trench in the earth as it broke apart.

"Captain, speeders approaching," a battle brother on the perimeter reported. "ETA to our drop site one minute and closing."

"Brother Cassius?" Marcus murmured discretely into the vox.

"Worry not, Brother-Captain. My brothers and I are watching," the dreadnought-borne warrior reported solemnly to him and him alone.

All three of the Hellfire dreadnoughts had rotated as one on their legs, assault cannons, lascannons, and missile launchers already locked on.

"Very well then. Command squad, on me," Marcus called out loud. "1st Company, form up!"

Within the next thirty seconds, the whole of the 1st Company had assembled itself with weapons readied, Marcus at the forefront. Those of the 5th Company remained at the rear, both tactical squads equipped with missile launchers and heavy bolters. The three speeders that arrived were clearly of the false Scarlet Lions, but they did not open fire upon the forty odd terminators and trio of dreadnoughts that faced them.

"Blood Ravens, have you come to aid us?" The marine piloting the foremost speeder. "We were expecting...more of you."

"The 1st Company will suffice for this," Marcus called back with a mixture of feigned and true anger in his voice, "You underestimate us at your peril. Others of our chapter are busy removing the enemy orbital stations," he pointed towards the clear skies where the faintest flashes of explosions in the atmosphere could be seen if one squinted. "Now then, are you all that survived the crash?"

The false marine shook his head.

"No, but we did sustain casualties at the hands of the traitors. Master Akermian yet lives, by the Rock. We can escort you to him, but we must move quickly. Who knows what the traitors will get up to the longer we give them."

"Indeed," Marcus replied, his voice giving no sign to narrowed eyes he leveled towards them within his helm. "Lead on, Lions."

It was only a short time later that they arrived at what was clearly a hastily made mustering point. Of the hundred or so false Scarlet Lions that had been reported fighting alongside the Blood Ravens temporarily in the Jahal System, they had at some point lost three squad's worth. Yet Master Akermian stood, gazing to the east where the other strike cruiser had crash landed, his power armor draped in a cloak and hood. At his side was his chaplain, silently observing the 1st Company as they came. Marcus struggled for a brief instant to enact vengeance on the behalf of the 10th Company, but his discipline held as his supposed peer approached. Silently, the two regarded one another.

"Have you faced the forces of Chaos before, Captain?" Akermian abruptly asked.

"Yes," was Marcus' terse reply. "Have you?"

"You-," one of the terminator-clad false Lions growled before a hand raised by Akermian silenced him.

"It is hard to tell, given that in our previous fights with Chaos we have not plainly disregarded those shooting our ships out of orbit," Marcus continued.

"You do not understand our hunt," Akermian replied frostily, "All that matters is that we claim victory over the foe, even should our ships, our weapons, or our very lives be sacrificed."

Or even those not of your brethren was Marcus' unvoiced thought.

"The Chapter Master has ordered us to your aid, Master Akermian, while the 4th Company deals with the stations above, and we shall do so - but do not presume to simply order us about."

Akermian just nodded and jerked his head towards where a tac-screen station had clearly been pulled from the guts of the ruined ship.

"Very well. We do not know the disposition of the enemy, but we cannot afford to wait. I aim to deploy my forces within shortly."

It was a dangerous game of deception they played now. Did the false Lions know what the Blood Ravens suspected, or was their contempt enough to blind them? Was Marcus walking his force alongside his future ambushers, or was it he who was preparing to ambush them? It remained to be seen.

=============================================================

Crash Landing East: 36

Gabriel glanced amongst the rest of the Chapter leadership to confirm their next course of action. Unlike Captain Marcus Crixus, Gabriel was unwilling to test the possible temperament of the unknown marines on landing drop pods directly onto their heads. Instead they had deployed just outside the range of standard defensive implements most commonly utilized by space marines, progressing only once Justinius had judged that they would not suffer for doing so. After that, Gabriel had deployed a single squad of the 2nd Company's assault marines forth as scouts. One did not forget how to do so simply because they had been promoted from the 10th Company after all. The Scarlet Lions were, extremely uncharacteristically, silent as they joined him. The bombastic nature of their Chapter was gone, replaced with a grim seriousness that they had not possessed even in the depths of the Suysh hives. In truth, they had been that way since their last communications in the void. It was a strain on their burgeoning friendship that Gabriel had corralled them so, but still they had come. All of them. In truth, Gabriel was not thoroughly outnumbered, and he knew it. The 2nd Company was strong, but the Scarlet Lions had three whole companies at almost full strength despite the casualties they'd taken previously. All three captains, with all three of their command squads, had deployed alongside their companies. That put three Epistolaries against Justinius, should the worst possibility occur.

Yet despite all of that, when the reports came back from the scouting squad, Gabriel had been quietly confused. As had Justinius, when he had subtly probed the crash sight. There were defenses, yes. Multiple tarantula sentry guns with overlapping fields of fire, enough to make even Martellus nod in appreciation when he heard. But more than that, the scouts had been most clearly spotted by the marines present. Despite the best efforts of the Blood Ravens, it was impossible to mistake the twitching of heads, the pointed fingers, but even then the unknown marines had not opened fire. Why that was, Gabriel simply did not know. As it was, they now had visual confirmation of the unknown marines, currently residing in an oddly relaxed yet noticeably defensive formation upon a hill. Behind them, the broken remains of their strike cruiser still burned and smoked, its spine broken and the two halves of the ship separated from each other by quite a significant distance. A quartet of predator tanks was the most armor they seemed to possess aside from the turrets. As for the unknown marines themselves, it was difficult to discern. Almost all of them bore concealing and hooded grey cloaks and tabards sized for their armor, with no Imperial aquila or other symbol upon them.

But despite being clearly scouted, probed for defenses, they did not respond. And so Gabriel had chosen to go for a dangerously diplomatic gambit, one that Hannibal had protested both vigorously and loudly. Captain Sicarius had simply nodded at his words. Justinus and Gracchus both remained silent, both exchanging nothing more than a simple quiet look at one another. Apollo's heart burned with paranoia and fear that the nature of his Chapter Master would lead to his death, but so tightly bound were the chains of duty in his heart that he gave no hint of outward protest. Instead, the disgraced former member of the Honor Guard took up his position as bodyguard and held his weapon close, the powerfield of the mace in his hands crackling with energy. As for the Scarlet Lions, they seemed far more interested at keeping their forces ready to fall upon the False Lions without hesitation, the majority of their forces lingering towards the rear to be as physically close to those who had stolen their name as possible.

And so Gabriel Angelos emerged from the trees, the leadership of the Chapter and the Captains and Command Squads of the Scarlet Lions accompanying him. Behind them, the rest of their forces slowly emerged as well, weapons at the ready but none pointing towards those who might in seconds become their memory. But then, they were space marines, and as such needed only that much time to let loose a salvo. They stood, just outside of range of the tarantula turrets, and waited. A single moment passed before there was visible shuffling amongst the marines before them, all of them slowly and respectfully making way for one of their number to push to the front. This lone marine approached, apparently fearless of the fact that he had none of his brethren accompanying him as he went to stand only a few feet away from over thirty other space marines. At his side was a power sword and a plasma pistol, both clearly functional if old. Slowly, and carefully, he lifted his hands up to pull away at the hood which hung upon his head to reveal an ancient helmet - one that Martellus recognized almost immediately as a Mark IV - and disengaged the seals of said helmet with a hiss of air. The helmet itself and the gauntlets that removed it were a terribly worn black and extremely faded green, as was what could be seen of the rest of the armor. A significant amount of the paint had simply faded entirely leaving only the base color of ceramite behind.

The space marine that faced them then, face bared freely, was quite possibly one of the most weathered space marines that Gabriel Angelos could possibly have conceived of. Age lined his face in a way that Gabriel had never seen before in a space marine, the thoroughly scarred and brown skin stretched taut against the skull. He was bald for the most part, yet possessed a thick yet short salt and pepper beard. And there was a gulf of weariness in his eyes that surprised Gabriel, a painful exhaustion that mixed oddly with the bemused quirk of his lips. Slowly, amber colored eyes examined Gabriel and then the rest of the marines present, stopping most pointedly upon the symbol of the Scarlet Lions that were so proudly worn before moving on. Eventually, however, he sighed.

"Space marines, as I suspected. But not the space marines I expected," he spoke in tired yet rich voice. "After all this time, it seems I can yet be surprised."

"I am Gabriel Angelos, Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens, and I have come in search of answers," Gabriel responded coolly.

"So it seems," the unknown marine chuckled tonelessly. "Yet you come with the ones who have hunted us so thoroughly," he jerked his chin towards where Bartorius stood.

"Watch yourself, renegade, and hath thy mind feast 'pon mine words," Bartorius yelled, "Those blaggards to the west art naught but impostors that hath stolen our name, our words, and our vessels from us! We be the true Scarlet Lions, not them! Mistake us for those maligned tricksters at your own peril!"

The marine facing them blinked, slowly, and scrutinized the Force Commander as he practically vibrated in his armor with anger. Then, without warning, he pulled his head back and let loose a deep belly laugh. One that echoed throughout the clearing, clearly confusing the other marines who bore his colors and those accompanying Gabriel in equal measure. He laughed hard and long, pausing at one moment to suck in a breath so he could continue in his odd merriment. Eventually, however, he settled himself.

"Oh, the amusements the universe has at our expense," he chuckled to himself again before looking up again at Gabriel. "Well, if you tell the truth, that is. There is little I could do to prove otherwise, and if indeed you are foes nevertheless...," his amusement died a quick death, his voice turning solemn once more. "I have been ready to die for a long time now. Still though, you demand answers...."

He glanced to the west then, and then back to Gabriel, managing a shrug with his armor.

"The answers you seek may be dangerous. It would be much easier for your force to overwhelm mine, then turn upon those who have hunted us, you know?" He said without shame. "Our own task here will be completed one way or the other I suspect, if not by us then you. You may call me Dumah."

"Your task?" Bartorius called suspiciously.

"Destroying the xenos, and rectifying our mistakes with them," Dumah responded calmly.

"And what does that mean?" Gabriel asked, eyebrow raised. "Did you...consort...with the Suysh?"

Dumah slowly shook his head.

"Not willingly. They utilized some of our cogitators and sensor logs to find their way to the Imperium," he spoke seriously. "It was not our intent, but it was our information that they used, this I say without shame."

"And yet you claim you did not consort with them, so how could this be?" asked Kleonoi Agamat, the Captain of the 3rd Company of Scarlet Lions.

"It was given to them without our consent," Dumah answered with narrowed eyes. "Taken from us, and used to inform the Suysh as to a new source of food," he spat the last word, clearly disgusted with the xenos race.

It was then that the vox came to life in Gabriel's ear.

"Chapter Master, we are moving out. At the speed that 'Master' Akermain is pushing, we will be upon the position of the other crashed ship within the hour, his speeders sooner than that," Captain Crixus informed him. "As of yet, we are simply marching alongside them, not behind or ahead."

"Understood Captain. Maintain your pace, but keep me informed of any other developments," Gabriel answered quickly.

Dumah had plainly heard him, and grinned bitterly.

"Ah, and so it appears that things are coming to an end, then. If they are not, as you say," he looked towards Captain Bartorius, "Of your Chapter, then I know their identity not. Still, it may be safer in the long run for you to trust them over us, you know. If that is your choice, you may pull your forces back, and surround us. We will not go without a fight, of course, but still. Or, of course, you could all of you put me down in one go, then advance directly into what remains of my forces. We number about eighty marines, all told."

He spoke of his possible eradication with incredible calm.

"If you have questions now, ask them or forever hold your peace. I cannot promise you will enjoy the answers you receive, or that I will even be wholly truthful, but you may ask nonetheless."

What To Do? Choose 1:
Moratorium For 3 Hours.
[] Ask Questions, If Any: (Write-In) Note, if this option is chosen, we'll do quick light posts that I'll later collect into a single larger and threadmarked update post, as depending on questions/answers decisions might need to be made.
OR
[] Pull Back And Surround, Waiting For the Scarlet Lions
OR
[] Eradicate Here And Now
OR
[] Something Else? (Write-In)

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Ten)

GM Note: This post was built from two temporary threadmarked posts to create a large proper turn post. Just for clarification.
Moratorium For 3 Hours.

Spoiler: Winning Votes

[] Ask Questions, If Any+ making Justinius pull his weight
-[] "To which chapter do you and your marines belong? Your armor bears no Aquila nor any other identification, and your helmet is of an ancient design."
-[] "Why do these false Lions seek your death?"
-[] "They named you as traitors to the Imperium. Can this be dismissed as another of their lies?"
-[] "What were you doing outside the light of the Astronomicon in the first place?"
-[] "Who was it that gave the Suysh your information?"
-[] While this is going on, have Justinius attempt to pierce the veil and figure out who the False Scarlet Lions really are and the root cause of this hunt, as well as how they came to pretend to be Scarlet Lions
-[]1st priority: Chapter,
-[] 2nd priority: How they came to have the 8th companies flagship and pretend to be Scarlet Lions.
-[] 3rd priority: Reason for hunting Unknowns

[] Further Questions
-[] "Our Chapter has suffered enough from secrecy. No more. Whatever harm this knowledge would bring us, we will bear it. And none shall find us wanting."
-[] Ask Force Commander Bartorius what does he think of all this.

[] Pull Back And Surround, Let Scarlet Lions Take Front Positions, Blood Ravens Behind And On Flanks
[] Orders for Hadrian and Chapter Fleet?
-[] Take defensive positions and continue to hail the approaching fleet
-[] Inform them that we are conducting exterminatus against a xenos race presenting a direct threat to the Imperium, and also have brothers planetside rescuing the crews of two downed Strike Cruisers

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

Gabriel glared at Dumah, who seemed perfectly at ease despite the possibility of his impending death and the destruction of his battle brothers. A timer had appeared unseen by all his bionic eye, one provided by the best possible estimations of Captain Crixus at the pace of the false lions he accompanied. Was it feigned, or genuinely truthful that he was uncaring? Already, Dumah had alluded that if he would not be lying, then he would at the very least not be wholly truthful. Yet Gabriel could not deny his interest. At the very least, he felt far more secure with Justinius and Hannibal present, brothers who he trusted to be capable of pulling him out of the depths of information hunger more than any other present. It was an affliction he had rarely ever suffered in his time, but Gabriel had seen those who had fallen to it. The traitor and once-friend he had known as Isador was the most recent of those, and so Gabriel had become intensely vigilant of his own thoughts and impulses, lest he ever falter so.

"You are quite at ease for one in such a position," Hannibal said with rumbling suspicion, breaking the Chapter Master from his musings.

Dumah raises an eyebrow at him, his amusement fading for a brief second.

"And They Shall Know No Fear," he intoned with extreme graveness. "The words of Him-On-Terra. Come now, chaplain, surely you know them?"

"Of course," Hannibal growled.

"If occurs to me, Dumah," Gabriel said calmly, fingers firmly gripped around the shaft of Godsplitter. "That we gave our names, our chapters, and yet you did not do the same."

At that, the unknown marine sighed.

"True enough."

"Then I would ask my questions," Gabriel continued. "Firstly, I know not what Chapter you belong to, if any. You bear no aquila, your wargear is of ancient design. Yet, at the same time, these false Lions desire your death above all else, including their own lives and their ship. I would know why."

Dumah nodded with great seriousness, almost mockingly so, at Gabriel's words. Behind him, another subsystem of the crashed strike cruiser erupted, sending a plume of flame and smoke into high into the air. A small shockwave boomed outwards from the ship, knocking a significant amount of snow off of the trees. None of the space marines present except for Martellus twitched, and even that reaction was kept to a grinding twist to one of his mechadendrites. Justinius, on the other hand, had closed his eyes entirely after receiving a silent message through the twitching of Angelos' fingers at one point. Said message had led to another, this broadcast purely in the mind, Gabriel temporarily relaxing his mind enough for Justinius to wrest the words meant for him and him alone. Now the Chief Librarian cast his senses to the west, quietly summoning forth his power.

"The latter, I couldn't possibly tell you, Chapter Master Angelos," he eventually said, fingers absentmindedly tapping out a pattern on the hilt of his power sword. "It could be any manner of things, we have made many enemies in the course of our exile."

It was the last word that Hannibal seized upon, the fire of his gaze practically penetrating through his helmet.

"Exile?" He growled even deeper than before.

"Penitence," Dumah acknowledged with another grim smile. "But it is a punishment we accept willingly."

"And yet again, you do not give the name of your Chapter," Gabriel said. "Your avoidance tests me, and gives credence to the words of liars that you are traitors to the Imperium-,"

Composure Check: 27

Dumah raised a hand to interrupt, allowing the faintest glimpse at the worn but well-maintained armor within his cloak. His expression was completely level.

"Whatever else I say here on this day, know this, Gabriel Angelos of the Blood Ravens," he said firmly. "We are loyal to the Imperium. That, above all else, is true."

There was a minute shifting amongst the Scarlet Lions, hundreds of marines moving ever so slightly for some reason or another. Unlike his own battle brothers, Gabriel had no access at all to the Scarlet Lion private vox channels.

"Loyal, you say, but you are far beyond the light of of the Astronomicon," Gabriel countered, "Far beyond from Him-On-Terra."

A snort was the response.

"Our duty has carried us far, but it is the way of things. You are here yourself, are you not? Surely you are not traitors yourselves?" Dumah shot back, bemused.

There was an immense amount of barely stifled outrage amongst the Blood Ravens. But then Dumah could not have known that he was targeting a terribly deep-seated issue. To accuse any loyal space marine of being a traitor was insult enough, but it was worse for the Blood Ravens, who knew for a fact that in the all too close past it had at least partially been the truth. Gabriel did not miss how despite Dumah's perpetual bemusement, his stance had shifted ever so slightly as dozens of Blood Ravens gripped their bolters and chainswords that much more tightly.

"No," Gabriel managed to grit out between grinding teeth. "We are not. Our loyalty is not in question."

"Of course, of course. We are the potential renegades, after all," Dumah nodded firmly. "I suspect that few in the Imperium are even aware of any nomad predation fleet, let alone ours."

Chief Librarian: 84

"The Carcharodons," Justinius murmured with his eyes still closed. "A mysterious chapter that emerged in recent history only within the Badab War, which quickly retreated back into the void after its conclusion. Universally described as particularly...vicious."

At that, Dumah let loose a rough bark of a laugh, hands going to his hips.

"So the Sharks crept out from the darkness into the light, eh? They must have been desperate for a tithing. Were the Fangs there too?"

"No," Justinius answered back faintly before blinking and turning to Gabriel in utter confusion. "Akermian genuinely thinks of himself as a Scarlet Lion. He was delivered the ship by the Interrogator-Chaplain Luiz Ulrecht, who has accompanied him since. But the Scarlet Lions of his mind are nothing like the true Scarlet Lions. He believe this hunt, this chance to...do something is more important than anything else. More than that, I cannot say, his mind and that of this supposed chaplain are tightly locked and bound. To push further could possibly give them cause to turn on our brothers."

"Interesting," Dumah murmured before chuckling. "If he thinks that we are the last of our fleet, he will be sorely mistaken when the rest of our ships arrive in the system."

The cold forest around them was beginning to heat, alien trees and flora rustling uncertainly as the arrival of so many brought heat and movement to a land that had been largely without it for quite some time. High above, the remainder of the Suysh orbital stations shattered into fragments that burned up in the atmosphere for the most part. Occasionally, and only with the finely engineered and trained senses of a space marine, could one feel the subtle trembles and vibrations in the earth that came far from the south. If the bombardment continued at current levels, it was possible the entire continental plate would fracture and force a gulf of boiling waters between the different sections of the continent proper.

"You still have not said who you gave the information from your cogitators to the Suysh, granting them the knowledge of the Imperium," Gabriel reminded him.

Dumah's face darkened.

"Ones who sought to harm the Imperium, and destroyed one of our way stations to do so. Had we protected it better, the Suysh would have consumed themselves sooner or later, and our fleet would not have needed to destroy them at all," he growled.

"But who were they," Gabriel insisted.

"Ones willing to consort with the xeno in their cause to bring harm to the Imperium, Chapter Master."

A small blip appeared in Gabriel's bionic eye, an update from Captain Crixus. Akermian had sent his speeders ahead. Their time was growing shorter.

"And yet through all of this, you could have lied or obfuscated. Is any of what you've said thus far true?"

"Of course," Dumah answered without saying anymore.

"Why must you act like this," Gabriel finally growled at him, his bionics in his chest adding a metallic thunder to his voice.

"If you kill me, I can accept that," Dumah shrugged in his armor. "Our ships will be here to reclaim our bodies soon enough if necessary, alive or dead. As to why? To protect you. Ignorance is a powerful shield, Blood Raven, one I offer to you freely. To know more could bring harm to you."

He then shook his head.

"And I would not want that to happen to any loyal sons of the Imperium, not if I can avoid it."

==================================================

Gabriel thought for a moment. The Blood Ravens were a Chapter of secrets. Some would say too many. Even now, no matter the entreaty, Davian Thule would not speak of what he had discovered on Kronus, and with the civil war fought throughout Subsector Aurelia, he was the last of the Blood Ravens from that campaign that had been granted access to the relics there at all. He was no Librarian, and yet he knew some scant amount of information once whispered to him by Isador before his old friend succumbed to Chaos. There was knowledge there, he knew, which could be considered tainted by some. Yet it was that same knowledge which had proved capable of aiding the Blood Ravens many times before in the destruction of their enemies. Some of the rituals that even the Chief Librarian used were formulated using the incredible amounts of esoteric knowledge collected over the course of the Chapter's history. Then there were the Chapter's words, ones that still held even now, despite it all. 'Knowledge is Power, Guard it Well'.

"Our Chapter has suffered enough from secrecy," he eventually said, turning his head towards Justinius who simply crossed his arms. "No more. Whatever harm this knowledge would bring us, we will bear it. And none shall find us wanting."

Dumah's eyebrows drew down pensively, and his lips quirking into sad and pitying look.

"I had hoped otherwise, but very well. Perhaps...you will fare better than others in the past who thought the same," he spoke slowly, shaking his head all the while before locking eyes with Gabriel.

Slowly, with deliberate care, Dumah pulled at the cloak which concealed much of his armor to reveal that there truly existed no Imperial Aquila upon the chest. In fact, there were no identifying points of heraldry whatsoever, no customized etchings or scrollwork, no ornamentation whatsoever besides the utter basic form of a suit of power armor. With the rest of the armor revealed, almost all present recognized the Mk-II or 'Crusade Armor' that he wore. Extremely worn, but still fully functional with no issue beyond the cosmetic. It was rare to see, and even personally speaking Gabriel had only ever seen such armor born by particularly ancient space marines that had fallen to Chaos.

"Tell me, Gabriel Angelos, how many Primarchs were there?" Dumah then said, eyebrow raised.

The non sequitur caught the Chapter Master off guard.

"What?"

"A simple question," Dumah said, letting the cloak fall back into place. "How many? Do you know?"

To the vast majority of the citizenry of the Imperium, such a question could be understood. Many did not even know that the Daemon Primarchs ever existed, that they were ever brothers to those who had remained loyal. Those that knew even that much often knew not of those whose names had been lost to time and fate. But such could not be said of the space marines, of whom almost all could trace their genealogy to one of those mythical beings who had once walked amongst the Imperium in a better age. Space marines learned the bitter lessons of the Primarch like no one else could possibly understand, not even the Inquisition, for who could feel more keenly the betrayal and loss of fellow space marines than the true and loyal astartes? Furthermore, to ask the Blood Ravens, who hoarded knowledge in their desperate search for their own past? Absurd. Of course he knew. Every Blood Raven, Librarian or otherwise, knew. There were sermons from chaplains recorded in the histories for each and every traitorous gene-wrought son of the Emperor, lessons to be taught on each.

"Twenty," Gabriel ground out, rolling his organic eye, "You try my patience once more, and the longer you-,"

"Wrong," Dumah interrupted with a curt shake of his head before pursing his lips and giving a reluctant nod. "And right."

A great many space marines blinked within their helmets. Even Bartorius and the Scarlet Lions, all of whom were beginning to subtly tremble with anger and anticipation for the arrival of the false Lions, paused ever so briefly at the ludicrous words that had come from the one who stood before them all.

"...what?"

"There were twenty one," Dumah spoke softly, carefully, as if the sentence itself were incredibly fragile and to even breathe wrong could somehow destroy it. "A twin. A brother, even closer than any other could possibly be. One soul, two bodies, was what some thought. Twenty one, or twenty, both are right in certain senses."

The Chief Librarian uncrossed his arms, one grabbing almost violently at his force staff where it had temporarily been impaled in the ground.

"You lie," Justinius said incredulously, his expression thunderous. "There were but twenty Primarchs made by the Emperor."

"That is what you know," Dumah replied, "But what one knows and what is may not be the same thing."

The sound of clenching ceramite drew Gabriel's gaze to his left, where the Scarlet Lions stood.

"Bartorius," he said, "What do you think of all this?"

The still helmeted Bartorius whipped his head towards Gabriel.

"This exchange of words doth be absurd," he growled, the snarl evident in his voice. "An unheard of primarch? Forsooth, where pray tell was this new legion in the Horus Heresy then, hmm?"

"Not new, not then," Dumah contested. "But we escape the point, and while I enjoy such wordplay. You demanded one of the most dangerous answers in the galaxy, and you shall have it. Relay unto me the name of the Twentieth oh Librarian who knows so much," he then demanded of Justinius.

To even invoke the name of one of the Traitor Primarchs was to take a vileness into the soul, the absolute truth that those who should have been most true to the Emperor had failed in the worst possible way. A stinging pain especially for those of the Blood Ravens. Yet the answers were so tantalizingly close, and so Justinius answered with only a second of hesitation.

"...Alpharius Omegon," he stated stoically.

"Wrong," Dumah interjected again before pausing. "And also right."

"The longer you delay, the closer the false lions get, and I suspect there will be little time for your word games then, Dumah," Gabriel grunted.

Dumah nodded, and if he were not a space marine then it could almost be described as sheepish.

"The Twentieth's name was indeed Alpharius. His twin was Omegon."

And for just a brief moment, Gabriel Angelos felt the world fall out from beneath his feet. Instantly, his mind rebelled against the concept. A lie, surely. But the Alpha Legion was notorious, known even, for their absolute mastery of secrets and information, of subterfuge in the extreme. Enough to hide the existence of another living Primarch entirely? From the entire galaxy? But at the same time, even the records of the Blood Ravens could contradict one another, the information gained different depending on the source. But to wrap his mind around the existence of another Primarch was something he had never expected to have to manage. Tactically, his mind sought out the possibilities, but the rest of his mind struggled under the weight of what could be truth. If it were a lie, he would crush Dumah's body himself. But...if it were true...what was one even supposed to do with such knowledge?

"And the reason why it is so absolutely dangerous for you to even know that much, is because there are forces aligned against the very existence of such knowledge, both within the Imperium and outside of it," Dumah continued. "To even speak of it is to invite their attention. And they are everywhere," he hissed. "Many do not even know that they serve such a cause."

Gabriel just stared at him. The ever present crackle of psychic energies about Justinius dimmed. The noosphere connected mechadendrites of Martellus had gone slightly limp.

"If they suspect you have even the slightest amount of knowledge of us, they will pursue you with all of their power. Sabotage, infiltration, theft, assassination, all this and more."

"So...what," Hannibal cried out in disbelief. "You are some members of a lost and dogged Legion, scattered to the winds, and you expect us to believe this?"

"I-," He began, eyebrow raised before turning his head to the west.

In truth, all those present did, for every space marine present could hear the familiar whine of speeder engines on the winds.

"If I might make a suggestion?" Dumah then started again, his face cast in seriousness once more. "Let these False Lions close enough, and we shall see what we may all glean from them."

Bartorius stepped forward, hand cutting outwards.

"Nay, and deny ourselves our vengeance?! I aim to tearest yon helm of this 'Master Akermian' off and look him in the eyes as I doth strangle the misbegotten life out of him!"

"I am sure you will do so, brother," Dumah spoke quickly, "And at that point we might all fall upon them once our thirst for answers is quenched. Pull your forces back, surround us, but let them think their vengeance is at hand."

He then returned his helmet upon his head, draping the hood over it once more.

"Unless, of course, you have no taste at all for such things," he added before edging back towards his own troops.

Gabriel's mind whirled, and from the looks of Bartorius glancing towards the west and then towards Dumah, his was as well. But in this case, it was the Scarlet Lion that came to his conclusion first. A burst of private channeled communications and Gabriel watched as the Scarlet Lions forcibly pulled back slightly just out of range of Dumah's turrets, some of them requiring other Scarlet Lions to help them do so rather than simply scream in rage.

"Know this," Bartorius called aloud, "No one but I may confront Akermian!"

Just then, the vox crackled to life, its transmission coming from orbit.

"Chapter Master," came the voice of Captain Hadrian, "A new fleet has just jumped out of the warp at the edge of the system! Two battle barges and twelve strike cruisers, as well as attendant escorts! They have not yet identified themselves! Your orders?"

=========================================================================================================

The Passions of Lions 68

Over a hundred space marines and assorted armored support was not the quietest force in the history of the galaxy, especially when they were making essentially no effort at all for stealth. The whole of their travel had been at a pace that was punishing even for an astartes, to the point that the Blood Raven dreadnoughts had fallen behind the formation out of sheer lack of ability to move as quickly as the False Lions desired. This wasn't the worst thing, in Marcus' eyes, as he had grown increasingly certain that things would be coming to a violent end one way or another. There was no way to easily communicate with the Chapter Master in total stealth, as he had sighted more two different tech marines bearing the colors of the Scarlet Lions that followed Akermian. They had, more than once, mentioned that they were monitoring the signals surrounding the crash site they were heading towards. When he had sent his erstwhile communique to the Chapter Master, they had approached him with questions, but they could not deny that he was simply wishing to know the status of much of his Chapter's leadership. But ignoring the thumping of power armor, the rumble of tanks, the whizzing scream of speeders, it was quiet. The False Lions did not speak to the Blood Ravens, and vice versa. There was a great deal of tension amongst them all, for various reasons.

All of it soon to come to a head. The minute that Akermian announced that his speeders had made contact with the Blood Ravens once more, the tension only grew further. Flickering targeting reticles bloomed into being across the rest of the 1st Company. They did not dare make full target locks, but nevertheless Marcus could see through his command helm that some of the veterans were ghosting their eyes across the sides and backs of the False Lions without a single twitch of their weaponry. Some within the Chapter might have found it it dishonorable to even consider how one might take down column of astartes in anything but honorable combat face to face. But for those who had been able to become veterans, much less reach the vaunted status of the 1st Company, it was simply a matter of course. The ones before them had ensured the deaths of fellow Blood Ravens, had stolen the name and colors of another Chapter entirely, and had proven themselves treacherous in the extreme. The closer they got, the more smoke there was in the air, drifting west from the wreck of the shattered strike cruiser. There was a large forest ahead, or at least a considerable copse of it that the space marines had to pass through, casually battering aside or crushing the old frozen vegetation in their way. The snowfall around the area had only grown thicker, the to the point that even terminators were up to their waists in the stuff. It was little surprise that the quashi-reptilian and insectoid nature of the Suysh prevented them from inhabiting this area of their planet with any concentration. Within minutes, they found a raised hill, the still smoldering wreck behind them an orange and oily black backdrop framing them. Though they possessed no banner, these were most certainly unknown to Marcus.

Like The Red Grasses of Lemnos 86
Chief Librarian 73

Surrounding the hill, at least on one side, were the Blood Ravens of the 2nd Company and much of the Chapter leadership. Marcus personally saw the grim face of Chapter Master Angelos give him the slightest of nods before his gaze turned on the False Lions. Marcus had wondered in the silence of the march up until this point how the matter between the Scarlet Lions and the False Lions would be resolved. Yet despite his expectations for immediate violence, he sighted no Scarlet Lions at all. In fact, he could not even register their presence at all amongst the Blood Ravens, though they remained flanking the arriving False Lions. It was, to be frank, stunning. Yet no sooner than the thought had entered his head than a small blip appeared on the edge of his vision, one not registered by his helmet's sophisticated detection systems at all. It passed in a single second before disappearing entirely, and Marcus could not shake the feeling that it had appeared to him and him alone. But a single second was all a space marine needed to know, to analyze, and so the sight of a raven concealing the glowing red heat of its chest led him to remark on the lack of visible Scarlet Lions not at all.

Akermian, however, seemed not to care. In truth, as far as Marcus knew, their ship had gone down before they could even register the ships of the Scarlet Lions hidden amidst the rest of the Blood Raven fleet. The so-called Master of the 2nd Company practically stomped his way up to the Chapter Master. His silent chaplain remained with the rest of the False Lions, as did the techmarines. Thankfully, the False Lions had possessed no Librarian, so there had been at least that much security for his thoughts.

"Why have you not engaged the enemy, Blood Raven?" Akermian snarled.

Marcus watched, his grip tightening around Wisdom as the Chapter Master looked Akermian square in the eye with no expression on his face.

"Because they are your enemies. There they lay, Master Akermian," Angelos gestured out with his hammer towards the waiting hill.

Though he was helmeted and hooded, Marcus could swear he could sense the marine glaring out from within his helm.

"Did you speak to them?" He asked angrily. "Did you listen to their falsehoods?!"

"I accept less and nothing from their words," the Chapter Master answered back, one eyebrow raising. "I have heard the lies of traitors before."

"You would do well to not listen to their lies, Angelos, they are traitors and heretics besides," he growled, shoving his way back to the rest of the False Lions. "Ephaltes!" He called out to the chaplain who had spent his entire time caressing the rosary beads around his neck. "Are our brothers ready?"

"Of course, Master Akermian," was the sibilant response.

"Very well!" Akermian whirled about, unsheathing the power sword at his side as he marched forward slightly. "Know this, traitors! The true sons of the Emperor have come to punish you, to force you to repent!"

It was at that point that one of the unknown marines called back, to the great surprise of Marcus.

"I have been doing that for a long time, boy!" Called a marine whose lack of heraldry was utterly exposed, leaning forward casually against a scrap metal barricade. "I doubt you will make me more inclined to do so more than I'm already doing!"

The response seemed to catch Akermian off-guard, but in his fury he rallied quickly.

"You are as insane as the rest of your ilk, Dumah. You led us on quite the hunt, but you have failed! In the name of the Lion, I, Akermian, will drag you to the Rock myself!" Akermian roared, brandishing his blade.

At that, the so-named Dumah laughed uproariously. Marcus could not stop himself from looking at the Chapter Master, who if anything seemed grimly resigned to whatever was happening.

"Is that what you think I am?" He cocked his head ever so slightly. "No. That is what you must think I am. Well come on then, oh lion," Dumah drawled the word as he straightened and walked around the side of the barricade. "Come and get me!"

Akermian snarled again before turning to look at Angelos.

"Come, Blood Ravens, let us punish these heretics!"

Paranoid Techmarines 56

He then turned back towards Dumah and began to stride confidently forward as the rest of the False Lions began to marshal behind him. Even the rest of the Blood Ravens began to move, though Marcus noted they were remaining just at the flanks. Yet, it was a very specific kind of flank, Marcus realized in a flash, for the flanking formations and positioning thus required - at least in the Codex - that there be a strong central force to be aided by said flanking forces. It was possible to think they were doing so for the column of Akermian's forces, but something about the exact positioning spoke to something else entirely. No sooner had he come to that conclusion, from first thought to conclusion taking him but a handful of seconds, than had the Chief Librarian snapped his fingers and the slightest of veils was removed from his eyes. The high piled snow did not disappear, but shapes that had been present before yet went unnoticed abruptly regained the slightest of distinctive outlines.

It was at that point that three hundred roaring Scarlet Lions erupted from the snows, Force Commander Bartorius practically nose to nose with Master Akermian.

Bartorius Surprise 72 vs. 24

"Greetings...brother," Bartorius growled deeply while somehow simultaneously yelling, one hand flying forward to clamp around Akermian's own, squeezing tightly enough to ensure that the power sword would not be moving.

The other slammed onto the front of Akermian's helmet, and then with a wrenching of ceramite and the shattering of lenses as two fingers punctured them, Bartorius ripped Akermian's helm clean off of his head and threw it to the side. The Scarlet Lions brandished bolters and blades aplenty, while the Blood Ravens had turned about and squarely pointed their weapons at the False Lions. Marcus noted without losing focus that he had received target lock confirmations from the honored dreadnoughts of his company. Yet not a single bolter was fired as Bartorius recoiled in shock, eyes wide as he stared at the one known as Akermian. Massive scars covered the man's head, though nothing compared to what the phosphex had left of Marcus' own, with a great gleam of bionics around the totality of his throat. But few could mistake the utter confusion in Bartorius' voice, even whispered as they were.

"Brother-Captain Notos?"

At his words, a great many of the Scarlet Lions halted in confusion.

Akermian? Surprise 28 vs. 84

Akermian grit his teeth and violently threw Bartorius backwards with an incredible display of strength with one arm, the other which bore his power sword flying upwards to score deeply into the Force Commander's chest armor. It was deep enough to penetrate the ceramite fully, leaving a small spray of blood to freeze almost immediately upon reaching open air. Yet that was all, for Akermian too appeared shocked as he stared out at the marines in between him and his original quarry. That they all bore the same colors as he, if not with the hoods and cloaks, seemed to stun him momentarily.

"What is this?!" He bellowed, eyes moving between Dumah and Bartorius. "What...what trickery is this?!"

"I, Bartorius, shalt say the same pon you villain, for that be the face of honored Brother-Captain Notos, who fell at Armageddon!" Bartorius bellowed back. "Not satisfied enough to steal our colors, our name, our words, but the very faces of our slain brothers?!"

Fellowship of Lions 90

Akermian stumbled, clutching at his head with his free hand. The rage that had infused his expression became mired with bewilderment.

"I...you...Bartorius?"

"Akermian, focus!" Ephaltes called out, raising his crozius high, the power field behind it sparking brightly. "The traitors!"

Fellowship of ?Lions? 64

But Akermian simply clutched harder at his head.

"What is...happening to me!?" He finally screamed.

The supposed chaplain-interrogator of the False Lions approached him and clapped a hand to Akermian's shoulder as he grimaced.

"Remember who you are, Akermian! You are Master of the 2nd Company!"

"He holds no such position within mine chapter," Bartorius growled.

Out of the corner of his eye, Marcus watched as the rest of the Blood Ravens began to form up on them.

"It seems your puppet might be a bit confused," Dumah called out sardonically, and Marcus noted he was pointing his own power sword at Ephaltes. "Your ploy has failed."

Ephaltes slowly reached up to grasp one of the black pearls on his rosary before tearing it away with a growl.

"Perhaps," he nodded. "Perhaps not."

Then he clenched his fist around the pearl and threw it upwards just as Dumah shouted in surprise, whereupon it emitted a very specific burst of auditory and visual signals. Marcus could hear several of the noises on registers that only a space marine could hear, the colors and patterns similarly just beyond the immediate abilities of mundane humanity. Dumah's shout had not yet even finished before a great number of the Scarlet Lions appeared to freeze in place. Not all of them, but there were members of each of the three present Scarlet Lion companies who seemed strangely affected by whatever had been done to them. Bartorius turned slightly, noticing the odd condition of his troops, while Marcus felt a terrible foreboding as Captain Kleonoi Agamat of the 3rd Company raised his bolt pistol and pointed it straight at the Force Commander. All the while, Akermian collapsed to his knees, screaming into himself as he lost his grip on his power sword. In that same instant, Ephalte's rushed forward, crozius raised high.

Chief Librarian 78

"Some of their minds are gone!" Shouted the Chief Librarian, eyes brimming with psychic power. "A light smothered by darkness - but the others-!"

"Kleonoi?" Bartorius asked warily. "What art thee doing?"

"Trying to salvage an idiot's ambitions," Kleonoi answered with tinges of faint annoyance in his voice, the traces of a Lemnan accent to his Low Gothic still there. "Such as it is."

"Beware!" Dumah cried out. "Defend yourself, Lion!"

"Kleonoi!" Bartorius roared.

"My name," Kleonoi replied calmly, "Is Alpharius."

The Scarlet Lions opened fire on fellow Scarlet Lions, the Blood Ravens, and the unknown marines all at once.

The Blood Ravens unleashed bolter and assault cannon.

The False Lions turned and charged the Blood Ravens.

From the hill, Dumah's marines unfurled previously hidden lascannons and sniper rifles hidden somehow out of sight.

All while Akermian screamed on his knees.

===================================================================

Hadrian Priscus was not the most patient of men. It was not a quality that had well endeared him to many of the elder Blood Ravens. He would not wait about while they formulated plans, letting the enemy overrun defenses and Imperial Guard positions while they studied. He was not against it, not by any means, it had brought too much success in the name of the Chapter for him to deny the utility. But most often he found himself requesting to be part of those few astartes dedicated to the first few strikes. Information gathering through violence, pushing and assaulting the enemy, studying their response and capabilities as he and fellow Blood Ravens fell upon them. It was a position that he, at least, appreciated at the time. But then, those who had looked down on him so for his aggression had turned out to be heretics and traitors, so it hardly should have mattered what the hell they thought. Yet since he had become Captain, he had found it far beyond his allowed duties to perform as he sometimes wished. He was responsible for far more than a single squad now. Indeed, it was a considerable irony indeed that he had been forced to learn far more patience than any of his teachers had tried to push on him.

All that said, however, he was finding that the obstinately silent fleet which was even now still burning their engines towards the last Suysh world was doing a wonderful job of fraying at that carefully self-trained patience.

"Send the message again," he finally grit out through his teeth, fingers tapping a rapid staccato upon the arms of his command throne.

"Sending, captain," the serf at the vox station called out.

Neither Hadrian nor the serf commented on the fact that they had been doing the same exact thing for half an hour. They simply waited out the next few minutes in silence. By now the rest of the 4th Company were once more safely ensconced on the ships, and Hadrian had managed to occupy himself for a full ten minutes ordering them about to optimal protective positions in the case of boarding. But it would be some time yet before they arrived within a distance for such things, and even then it was not as if Hadrian desired conflict with these space marines in particular. This time, however, after another solid ten minutes, the serf turned slightly in their chair to look up at him.

"Captain Priscus! We are receiving a response!"

Hadrian nodded.

"Let us hear it."

The serf scrunched up their face as they fiddled about on the console.

"Apologies, Captain, the transmission is rough."

Even so, a voice did finally come through. It was deep and gravelled in a manner suggestive of clear injuries to the throat or lungs.

"We are the Midnight Fangs, the ever questing Maw of the Emperor," rasped the speaker. "You will cease Exterminatus operations immediately. We require the salvage that this world will provide, salvage that you would see destroyed."

Hadrian blinked.

"Even if we do not launch Exterminatus munitions, we are currently in the midst of a rescue operation, and numerous members of our Chapter are on the planet. We cannot withdraw."

There was no immediate response. Given that time, however, Hadrian instead called up maps taken of the system by long range scans. The Exterminatus munitions used on the two other terrestrial Suysh planets in the system had been of the Cyclonic variety, not Virus Bombs, the plates cracked and broken. Major Suysh settlements and manufacturing facilities were currently being destroyed outright by massive tectonic activity as the dead worlds crumbled further. Much of what had been in orbit over the gas giants were also descending due to the immense gravity exerted. The thought of salvaging xenos materials for any purpose was cause for faint disgust, but at the same time Hadrian considered the ships before him. He had never heard of them before, and if they had operated outside the confines of the Imperium for some time, they might require raw materials such as what the planet could provide them out of desperation. On the other hand, he had never heard of them before, and the treacherous ways of Chaos were well known. It would not be beyond them - nothing was - to simply ape the outer appearance of loyal marines.

"You will withdraw your ships to the specific sector of the planet you are operating on. You will not interfere with our own operations."

"You are giving me a lot of orders for a marine not of the Blood Ravens," Hadrian growled back. "You are neither my Chapter Master nor the Emperor."

Once again, there as a lengthy pause before the formation of the Midnight Fang vessels altered into a significantly more aggressive one.

"You will withdraw your ships to the specific sector of the planet you are operating on. You will not interfere with our own operations."

Hadrian nearly snapped at them, but managed to restrain himself at the last instant. It would not serve the Chapter when he could merely withdraw his ships slightly, and destroy the Suysh entirely once the Midnight Fangs had finished with them. It still rankled at him, however, to meekly turn tail after being so insulted. Were he but a marine, he would have demanded satisfaction. But he could not. He was a Captain. And the damned responsibility he had to the Chapter forced him to do otherwise.

"Attention all ships. We will maneuver to provide better support to the Chapter Master should he require it. Ships committing to orbital bombardment, focus your fire on larger concentrations of Suysh, do not crack the continental plate."

======================================================

Blood Ravens: 97
Scarlet Lions: 38
Alpha Legion Lions: 93
False Scarlet Lions: 54
Dumah's Forces: 40

In moments, what had begun as two-sided confrontation had turned into absolute anarchy. The 1st Company Terminators had begun firing into the ranks of the False Scarlet Lions as they had charged them, storm bolters and assault cannons reaping terrible damage amongst their number. Marcus would not appreciate the memories of ceramite cracking and splitting open under his order. Whether traitorous or not, the power armor they currently wore at the very least had the appearance of being untainted. Others of the False Lions had leapt forward into the ranks of the true Scarlet Lions, catching them on two fronts as the Alpha Legion revealed itself from amongst their number. Force Commander Bartorius had taken a staggering number of bolter rounds to the chest and head before he could close the distance with Captain Agamat, just before he was struck from behind by the crozius of the false chaplain Ephaltes. Marcus had rushed forwards, Wisdom whirring in his grip as he cut down one of the False Lions in a single stroke. While the Blood Ravens reaped a bloody toll, the true Scarlet Lions suffered terribly. Many of them hesitated too long as their brethren fell upon them with bolter and combat knife, plasma gun and chainsword. All the while, the marines of Dumah waded in around the sides, trying to reach the False Lions. The most difficult issue however was that the crush of fighting was such that in moments it became impossible to precisely tell which Scarlet Lion was which, or which force they had aligned themselves with. Even the False Lions bore the colors of the Scarlet Lions, and it was only the careful work of memorization by the 1st Company which let their targeting reticles recognize which was meant to be which. Marcus quickly found himself engaged with a trio of False Lions, deathly silent even now. Nearby, he watched as Chapter Master Angelos rushed to the fallen Bartorius' side, quickly followed by the rest of the Chapter's major leadership. An enormous blast of psychic energies erupted from the body of the Chief Librarian sending a great number of marines flying whilst scorching them aflame, all while somehow avoiding doing so to the loyalists on the field. The Librarians of the Scarlet Lions had died quickly, unexpectedly, from their own brothers pushing their bolters into their backs and firing.

==========================================================

Hadrian nearly leapt from the command throne when the silently transmitted request came up from the surface for immediate gunship support. He was no tech marine, but in a pinch he was fully capable of piloting a thunderhawk, at the very least down the surface. Whereupon the serf and servitor could work with the machine spirit to provide all the fire support required. Yet he forced himself to stop, and instead relayed orders that had a number of 4th Company running towards the hangars. No, he needed to remain here, in the void, and keep an eye on the rapidly approaching ships of the Midnight Fangs. This close, he could tell by the scanners that while the ships were not specifically damaged by any measure, they were certainly weathered in a manner that the Blood Ravens fleet was not. A vast amount of ornamentation had simply been removed from the ships, the spires and arches typical to Imperial construction had disappeared entirely. This was especially a surprise due to the fact that battle barges of the Midnight Fangs were not purely purpose-built vessels like those of the Blood Ravens. Rather, the battle barges of the Midnight Fangs were clearly retrofitted battleships of the Imperium, both of them almost out-massing even the already large Omnis. It was not wholly uncommon, a great many elder battle barges were the same, but it was still a shock to see in the modern day. Numerous scars existed on the hull of the nearest approaching ship, but not ones big enough to cause any actual structural damage. Thus, they had apparently gone without removal due to not being anything more than a largely aesthetic issue. If the ships of the Imperium were often compared by its common citizenry as glorious cathedrals within the void spreading the Emperor's Word, then the ships of the Midnight Fangs were ugly stones meant for one purpose and one purpose only - destruction of their enemies. The only thing that seemed to retain much care at all were the worn but massive Imperial Aquila on the sides of their vessels.

"I could have told them no," he muttered, "I could have said I did not have the experience or knowledge."

Slowly, very slowly, he sat back into the command throne, chin coming to rest on on his fist.

======================================================

Bartorius vs. Agamat(?)
50 vs. 49

Bartorius spewed blood from his shattered jaw, bone and blood flying freely as he pulled back from the near decapitating strike of his supposed brother-captain, only to be stabbed through the chest by Captain Agamat as he recoiled, the power sword plunging through the ceramite and flesh beneath as if it were cheesecloth. His helmet had been reduced to ruin protecting his head from the traitor's bolter rounds, crumpled to the point that he had been forced to tear it off so that he could still yet see to fight. Yet the Scarlet Lion did not fall, instead he twisted his entire body around with enough force and speed to tear the blade impaling him out of Agamat's grip, one hand rising up with combat knife drawn to slash open Agamat's throat while the other raised his bolt pistol to fire with loud cracks into the other marine's chest. Throughout the fighting, Scarlet Lion battled Scarlet Lion, questions screamed at each other as the entire strike force lost almost all cohesion. More than once, the sheer viciousness of the violence meant that a Lion would scream obscenities in the name of the Emperor at one they were fighting, only to receive the same in turn. At which point both would be shot at by silent marines bearing their own colors. A great many of the 3rd Company had turned with Agamat, and these fought with far more animation than those somehow twisted by the device utilized by Ephaltes, but of the false chaplain there was no sign after he had rushed into the fighting himself.

Another pair of marines arrived at the small cleared space of the duel, chainswords whirring, their pauldrons signifying their allegiance to Agamat. But no sooner than Bartorius had taken note of them than they were taken off their feet by psychic blasts from the staff of Justinius Probalis. In a pair of heartbeats the Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens stood between them, whole body haloed by psychic might. Where Ephaltes had gone, the Force Commander could not see.

"You cannot win, traitor," Justinius called, fingers gripped around his staff. "You and all your ilk shall fall here."

Agamat snorted.

"Whether we live or die matters not. Another head shall take our place," he chuckled condescendingly. "Ephaltes' failure need not be mine."

Bartorius gurgled angrily, it was all he could manage while his physiology struggled to staunch the bleeding.

"Oh, Bartorius. With you and Kallek dead the Hydra can take your places as well as it has Agamat's. In time, perhaps the Scarlet Lions will all become the Hydra."

The Force Commander narrowed his eyes before grunting and with a cry of pained effort tore the power sword in his chest free. He would have stumbled were it not for the light pouring from Justinius taking on a warmer glow, his wounds miraculously beginning to heal over. He wiped futilely at the ruin that had been left of his mouth before pointing a finger at Agamat. With the lower half of his jaw gone, tongue flopping uselessly, he nevertheless managed a single barely understood word.

"Never."

================================================================================

The Blood Ravens 1st Company had been on both sides of the False Lions. Their dreadnoughts had been behind them. The moment they had turned - as the veterans had known they would - thirty storm bolters and ten assault cannons began to fire simultaneously at independently chosen targets. They could not have openly discussed the matter amongst themselves, and thus more than one false lion found himself torn apart by a multitude of concentrated storm bolter bursts directed against him. Ten cyclone missile launchers fired full salvos of krak missiles at the marines directly in front of them. Tomb-Brother Cassius, Tomb-Brother Adrandus, and Tomb-Brother Anchises fired missile launchers directly into the center of the False Lion column where there was absolutely no risk of collateral damage. All three salvos directly impacted against the bodies of numerous traitor marines while the explosions of heat and shrapnel hit far more. With all the precision of a finely tuned dreadnought frame, they then immediately turned to utilizing a heavy melta, twin-linked lascannon, and assault cannon respectively. To some, it would be disquieting to witness the obliteration of so many space marines in the space of seconds, but these were liars, traitors, and possibly even heretics. They had been proven false, had performed utter desecration to the memory of the 8th Company of the Scarlet Lions, and so it was only just and good that they died so painfully. Of the seventy odd False Lions, barely thirty lived beyond the ten seconds of engagement, though for some it would take longer than that for their bodies to accept it. It was ironic, perhaps, that those near the edges had higher odds of survival due to the volume of fire pushed at the center of their force. Unfortunately for the false marines, the terminators of the 1st Company had merely needed to adjust their aim.

There were, however, a handful of terminators amongst the false lions, and it was these that managed to break free. With a resounding crackle and otherworldly thunderous boom their teleporter packs activated, abandoning those left behind with all the cold cruelty that all traitors possessed. Marcus whipped Wisdom through the neck of one of the last of the marines, his eye searching for where they might emerge next, but attempting to detect passage through the warp was plainly impossible for one such as he. If he strained what remained of his ears, he could hear the faint screech of thunderhawk engines being pushed to their absolute limits.

He dearly wished, once again, that hoped that the 1st Company would have an Epistolary amongst their ranks soon, one like Damion Tyrin.

But then there it was, the lightning crack and momentary splitting of reality as the terminators arrived at the hill directly around where Dumah had been standing. Their arrival was followed by shock waves of force emanating outwards as they returned to earth, knocking numerous power armor-clad marines off their feet. At that same moment, the false chaplain Ephaltes burst from the mass of blood and confusion that was the Scarlet Lions covered in viscera.

=====================================================================================

Blood Raven Leadership: 40
Agamat: 64
Bartorius: 100

It could not be denied. The marine that had pretended to be Kleonoi Agamat was undeniably skilled. Even when faced with the Chief Librarian and Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens, he showed no fear. All that mattered to him, apparently, was the death of Bartorius, heedless of his own injuries or wounds. The power sword he bore flashed and danced, ever so barely knocking aside potential blows from Godsplitter and the Talonstaff of Jonah. A blistering burst of lightning that turned the snow and dirt to glass was just barely dodged, while the power sword itself flicked out and scored deeply into the armor of both Blood Ravens facing him. Another bloom of force that could pulverize bones even when kept within ceramite caught only the edge of Agamat's shoulder. All the while, he fought on. Just agile enough to make his way past the defenses of Chapter Master Angelos, willing to take what hits he could of the incredible power of Justinius and dodge what he couldn't, Agamat managed to make his way past to the heavily wounded Bartorius. The Force Commander had taken grievous wounds in his momentary hesitation when the treachery of his own brothers had been revealed, and even a space marine could not easily shrug off what he had thus far sustained.

However.

Bartorius Telemon was no regular battle brother. He had fought in the Third War for Armageddon. He had plunged his forces into the 13th Black Crusade before being recalled. Six centuries he had known as a space marine. And though he had taken bolter rounds to the face and had a power sword thrust through his secondary heart, he had not yet fallen. When Agamat reached him, a previously hidden vortex grenade taken from his belt held in his grasp, he found the still bleeding Force Commander reaching forward to clamp his hand around the hand that held the grenade. With inexorable and terrible strength he clenched down on that hand, cracking the casing of the grenade within, while with his other he pulled forth his own power sword in a reverse grip to slice the arm off at the wrist. Almost casually, he threw the remaining arm high into the air where the vortex grenade would detonate, the explosion pulling nothing but Agamat's arm and snow into the warp with it. As Agamat recoiled, Bartorius grabbed the lip of his helmet and tore it free, casting it aside as well. Beneath the helmet was a face that was familiar, too familiar, but even the eyes themselves, but within them, there was no sign of the true Kleonoi Agamat. Bartorius knew it, and the one who had taken his Brother-Captain's face knew it as well.

"Hydra Domin-,"

There was nothing more than annoyed resignation on the traitor's face when he was decapitated.

Only then did Bartorius let himself collapse to his knees.

"Gracchus! See to him," Gabriel commanded as he moved forwards, "Justinius, do your best to identify the traitors! I go to end this once and for all!"

And so the Chapter Master strode forth to where Dumah was embattled by terminators and Ephaltes all at once. High above, Blood Raven thunderhawks had arrived, short bursts of weapons fire lancing down from them at the targeting coordinates provided by the Master of the Forge.

===========================================================

Dumah: 22
Ephaltes: 46
Gabriel Angelos: 78

Beneath the weight of fire from both traitorous Scarlet Lions and those who had falsely born their colors, a great many had been forced into cover to avoid death. The armor of space marines was mighty, but not utterly infallible. Of the five terminators that had teleported to the hill, all five were dead. On the other hand, Dumah had taken a pair of power fists to the chest and stomach in addition to more than one storm bolter salvo. He had been forced to a knee, yet still strained to rise with the aid of his sword in the ground. His other hand lay twitching on the ground nearby. Half of the helmet had been struck by the crozius, and blood still trickled out of the rents in the helm even now. The inward crush of his own armor had badly punctured his upper torso, and though it could not be seen, there was an audible hissing wheeze in each breath which signified at least one punctured lung. Opposite him, a wounded Ephaltes stood, blood trickling out from the various wounds the false chaplain had taken on the way up until this point. Simply moving through the fighting Scarlet Lions had ended up with him shot and stabbed more than once. But he still stood, fiery and twisted righteousness blazing in his eyes, the lenses of his helmet having cracked and shattered at some point.

"You have lived too long, Dumah," Ephaltes growled as he stood over him. "You have made mistakes in your old age. That ends today."

"All of this for me? My, how standards have slipped." Dumah wheezed wetly. "You don't care, do you? You've ruined whatever that Scarlet Lion's ploy was. As I said when I turned away, the Hydra has become naught but a decaying ouroboros serving entropy itself."

"You will serve as an warning to the rest of your traitorous kin. The Hydra is coming for them all," Ephalte's hissed as he raised his stolen crozius high. "Our numbers only grow, while there are ever less and less of you!"

"You know, you've all been saying that for a long time," Dumah coughed. "And yet, we remain."

"Die, fool!" Ephaltes roared.

And then Godsplitter struck the false chaplain from behind, thrown from the hand of Gabriel Angelos, striking him like a thunderbolt. The strength of any space marine was formidable. Gabriel Angelos' own strength was further improved by his bionics. Furthermore, he had thrown whilst wearing a powerful suit of terminator armor which only increased the power behind it. And so the Daemonhammer had flown forwards, spinning horizontally, such that when it collided with the right side of Ephaltes, its power field erupted and quite simply blew open the torso entirely. The eruption of the power field not only destabilized the molecular bonds of the ceramite, but much of the skin, flesh, and bone beneath in a flash-vaporized spray of shrapnel and gore. Though Godsplitter clattered to the earth some small distance away, the gauntlets of terminator armor were still capable of wielding smaller implements and as such the plasma pistol rose and fired thrice, putting holes in the backs of three more false Scarlet Lions in the time it took Gabriel to reclaim his weapon and help Dumah to his feet. Around him, the rest of the cloaked and hooded marines rose from cover and unleashed a punishing offense on those traitors and liars remaining.

Ephaltes did not even manage to make it to his knees before the two of them reached him.

Gasping for air, the right half of his body mostly crushed and obliterated by powerful strike, he nonetheless writhed on the ground in agony. Not yet dead, but too far from life. It he had been a marine deserving of it, his condition would have quite plainly demanded his placement into a dreadnought to preserve.

Yet neither of those who stood above him had any desire to do so.

"Was it worth it?" Dumah finally asked as he nudged Ephaltes onto his back. "All this? Stealing our cogitators, ensuring an alien invasion of the Imperium using the information? All to pull me out of hiding?"

Ephaltes did not have the saliva left to actually spit, but he made an attempt nonetheless.

"M-more of us will come," the dying marine rasped out proudly, "Until...you...are all dead." Then he grinned through blackened teeth and bleeding gums. "By killing us, you only...tell the Hydra where you've fled. Fool."

Then he lunged for them with the last reserves of his strength, only for both Dumah and Gabriel to stand back a single step, forcing Ephaltes to flop uselessly forward onto the snow.

"H-Hydra Dominatus!" Ephaltes forced out.

"Quod Hydra Est Mortuus," Dumah shook his head before reaching over and carefully plunging the tip of his power sword into Ephaltes' head, silencing him once and for all.

Around them, the fighting was beginning to come to painful and bloody finish. Dumah locked eyes with Gabriel and took off his helm once more, if only to see better. He gave the Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens a grim smile.

"Always a few surprises to be had, it seems. Let us see to the end of this macabre business."

======================================================

"...Captain Hadrian?"

"What is it?"

The serf manning the long range scanning station along with numerous servitors looked up at him, eyes wide.

"There...there is another fleet emerging into the system."

Hadrian stared.

"Excuse me?"

"I checked the cogitators twice, Captain, see for yourself!"

The Captain of the 4th Company watched, bewildered, as the tac-screen lit up brightly, once more showing the fleets present around the planet. The fleet of the Midnight Fangs had already reached the planet and were currently deploying what appeared to be at least seven companies worth of astartes and armored vehicles hundreds of miles south to where the Blood Raven fleet was currently parked in orbit. Then the vision twisted and bloomed outwards in scope, the planet and the ships above it shrinking rapidly as the rest of the solar system came on screen. There, he spied the telltale symbols signifying new warp transitions, the sigils for unknown Imperial contacts blinking insistently. It was close to the same as when the Midnight Fangs arrived. Too close. He spied another two dozen strike cruisers amongst their number, led by a trio of battle barges, the largest among them also a retrofitted battleship of some sort. Unlike the Midnight Fangs, however, this fleet bore clear signs of damage to their ships, all of it clearly sourced from Suysh weaponry.

Also different from the Midnight Fangs was that the vox crackled to life immediately.

"We have an incoming communication captain, from the unknown ships," a serf spoke nervously, looking up at him.

"Let us hear it then," Hadrian quickly decided, hands clenching and unclenching. "And send a notification to the Chapter Master about their arrival."

"Well, you aren't the Midnight Fangs, but I know you not. Which means you are far out of your territory, whoever you are."

Hadrian ground his teeth.

"We are the Blood Ravens and Scarlet Lions, loyal sons of the Emperor and servants of the Imperium. We have torn the Suysh from their beachhead and have followed them here to burn the rest of their mongrel civilization to ash," he almost shouted into the vox. "Our 'territory' is wherever the Imperium's enemies reside!"

A moment of silence followed that before the new arrival spoke again.

"Well said, if you are being truthful," the other speaker said thoughtfully before turning rueful. "Though I fear that we have done most of the work you've set before yourself. A Sector's worth of aliens have fallen before us, and this is the last of the holdings these xenos possess."

Then there was a pause.

"You remain distant from the Feast of Metal, it seems. Yet you do not seem to be doing much at all other than watching it happen."

"Much of our chapter is below," Hadrian answered firmly, "Enacting search and rescue operations on a pair of strike cruisers that were shot down fighting each other."

"...Excuse me?" the voice eventually asked, their bemusement significantly cooled. "I presume neither were your own."

Hadrian narrowed his eyes at the tactical screen. They out-massed the Blood Ravens significantly, and he had absolutely no idea as towards their numbers. But, at that point, he was able to relax ever so slightly as a light lit up out of the corner of his eye.

"No, they were not. One moment, I must speak with my Chapter Master," he nodded to the serf at the vox station to open the channel. "Angelos, I don't like the look of either of these fleets. One of them is ransacking the xenos for war material, and the other...," he trailed off, unable to fully articulate any specific reason for his wariness.

"Understood, Hadrian," Angelos' voice was patchy through the vox, peaking and falling at odd times. "Martellus is will be transmitting a data package to you. Send it to them. Deploy all possible apothecaries to the surface. Now."

Hadrian raised an eyebrow, though it was only the bridge crew that could see it. His curiosity was beginning to burn at him, but he couldn't possibly refuse his Chapter Master. Well, this one at least. He was proud of the fact that he was one of the first to openly question Kyras, one of the first to support Gabriel. It had nearly gotten him killed a dozen times over, but in his opinion it had been well worth it.

"Your will be done, Angelos," he answered stoically before activating the fleet-wide vox channel. "Attention, all non-occupied apothecaries are to make for the surface immediately. Again, all apothecaries to the teleportarium for immediate deployment to the Chapter Master's location."

Within seconds, the data package came through, but while he was somewhat learned he was no tech marine. To his eyes it appeared to be a simple jumble of letters and numbers mixed together with no rhyme or reason. It was over a hundred characters long, and though he scrutinized it heavily he could not detect any pattern whatsoever in any regard. There were even non-Imperial Gothic characters mixed in that even the cogitators of the Omnis flatly refused to translate.

"Vox, transmit the data package to the new fleet."

"Aye, Captain!"

Then he waited, fingers tapping on the armrest of the throne as he continue to examine the copy the ship's systems had automatically taken.

"Ah!" The vox opened once more, the voice now full of amused warmth. "I am glad to know he lives. Worry not, Blood Ravens, we will move to support you. I am Antilochus, and I am glad to know more true sons of the Imperium."

===========================================================================

The field was one of ruin. Craters smoked, the heat of them causing the snow which fell into them to melt into pools of bubbling water. Trees that had been frozen for years had cracked and split, some of them burning merrily into the night. The white snow was speckled with soot and blood. And there were far, far too many bodies of space marines who were meant to be loyal to the Emperor on the ground to ever be comfortable with. From where so many lay on the ground, it was impossible to tell which ones had been traitors, and which ones had not. Thus began the darkest aftermath of battle that Gabriel Angelos had been faced with in many years as the apothecaries of the Scarlet Lions attempted to tally the dead, while his own saw to those who might yet have a chance at living. It was, perhaps, to the credit of the Blood Ravens that while they had taken casualties none were fatalities. The 1st Company had been perfectly primed while the flanking positions of the rest of the Company allowing them to avoid the intensity of the infighting amongst the Scarlet Lions.

"Another. Brother Amphis. Also of the 8th Company," Captain Kallek spoke dully as an apothecary pulled the helmet of the slain marine off. "Or at least he is such in appearance. Study of his gene-seed will tell us if he truly is or not."

The Scarlet Lions, boisterous and proud, had been utterly ravaged by the machinations of the Alpha Legion. Delivered unto the sword and bolter of their own supposed brethren, their hesitation at fighting their own brothers had proven a costly mistake. Kallek lived, but his right arm had been destroyed at the elbow by a too-close plasma gun blast. He had killed the one who had done it, who had nearly slain him in turn, but the fact that his would-be killer had born his own colors had clearly disturbed and shaken him. It was the same for all of the still living Scarlet Lions. Even now, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens had been deployed to peel back their minds, checking to see if a survivor truly was loyal or simply another infiltrator attempting to survive after seeing that the battle was truly lost. That Chief Librarian Justinius had actually found one such marine had only increased the exhaustive nature of the proceedings - the infiltrator in question promptly killing themselves once discovered. Gabriel looked at what had been wrought, and turned away in disgust. He was aware of the sheer infuriating diversity of the Alpha Legion, the Librarium of the Blood Ravens likely had some of the less redacted lore on that infernal legion compared to other Chapters throughout the Imperium. Still, he had perhaps grown too used to them waging open battle, like on Tartarus or in Kaurava.

"I do not know for certain, though I have my suspicions," Dumah was saying as he rested upon an overturned ammo crate that groaned under the weight of his armor. "Tell me, the Scarlet Lions. They are often divided, yes? A fleet borne chapter sending its individual companies far and wide across the Imperium?"

On his back, armor cut open and peeled back out of necessity for Nero Gracchus to treat his wounds as quickly as possible, lay Bartorius who weakly nodded. Even now, the badly wounded Force Commander was struggling to keep his sus-an membrane from activating. He was incapable of speech, the blood of his ruined jaw coagulated into a rough crusted mass to prevent him from dying of total exsanguination. The first time he'd tried to speak Nero had quite plainly put a hand on Bartorius' throat and wrapped the other hand - currently inside the Force Commander's chest cavity - around the Scarlet Lion's primary heart to squeeze ever so slightly. The blood splattered helm of the Master of the Apothecarion had risen into Bartorius' view and remained utterly silent long enough for the message to be properly communicated. Apparently his time being spent so regularly with the Master of Sanctity and a Chaplaincy which quickly followed the example of their leader had shortened Nero's temper significantly.

"Mmm," the elder marine coughed blood into his fist, though he waved off the look that Nero gave him. "I'll live, apothecary. I've had worse." He then turned to look back down at the Scarlet Lion. "It is entirely possible that at any point in the history of Kleonoi Agamat's time in the Chapter that he was replaced. Perhaps there was even a time when he was unaware of it."

Dumah glanced to where Justinius stood, every Codicier in the Chapter behind him creating a localized nimbus of eldritch power.

"It is possible, through substantially powerful hypnotherapy rites, chemical conditioning, and psychic warding to even mask one's self from themselves," he said after looking back to Bartorius. "Enough such that even a Librarian could not tell, were they to dive into one's mind save for the absolute deepest depths. But then, few marines would consent to such an act, the violation it represents."

Bartorius' eyes squeezed shut in impotent anger, and though there was also a sudden spasm and clenching of his fists it was more the result of the ongoing corrective surgery. The worse part was, Gabriel knew, was that Dumah was right. Psykers were a known but barely tolerated mutation for many, their powers boon and blessing in one. Some, like the Black Templars, abhorred their usage all together. There were even records within the Librarium speaking to a past conflict with the Black Templars for that very reason, though it was noted to be possibly apocryphal. But even amongst the Blood Ravens, with their own unique relationship with their Librarians, an in-depth scouring of the mind by any member of the Librarius would not be eagerly accepted. It was not entirely surprising that the Librarians of the Scarlet Lions had done no such thing to their own brothers, for what possible reason had they been given for it?

"But you proclaimed that Agamat was not working with Ephaltes," Gabriel stated as he loomed above Dumah.

"Based on his reactions, I'd say so," Dumah nodded. "From what you've told me, Agamat had a different plan entirely. He wished to work to the subversion of an entire Chapter." He scoffed and shook his head slightly. "Ambitious, but not wholly unattainable. The disconnected nature of a fleet-based Chapter could have allowed for the subversion of one company at a time. It could be a great many years between one company meeting another, plenty of time to learn roles and alter records. Should Bartorius or Kallek have fallen in the course of the campaign, he could have seeded one of his brethren into the position."

It was one of the most vile and underhanded things that Gabriel could have imagined hearing. It was worse because he too could see how it could have happened had the Blood Ravens not been present. The tapping of Bartorius' fingers on the earth brought his attention back to bear, and both Dumah and Gabriel watched as the wounded marine cast his eyes towards where the corpse of Ephaltes lay, the question clear.

"Him? Just the latest in a long line of hunters sent after me," Dumah answered after a moment, his eyes growing haunted and lips thinning. "And when he does not report success, they will send another. And another. As they always have."

"What I don't understand was why he aped the appearance of being successors of the Dark Angels," Gabriel murmured. "Why go through the effort of it all? It surely would have been simpler to claim to be descended from the Ultramarines or Imperial Fists."

Dumah looked up at him and studied his face, lips pursing.

"I suspect it would be because they could have more easily convinced true sons of the Lion to aid in their hunt, and to remain utterly secretive about it to the rest of the Imperium. It just happened to be that it was you Blood Ravens who came along, rather than anyone else."

Gabriel narrowed his eyes. He was growing increasingly aware of just how resistant Dumah and likely his followers were to revealing the full truth of almost anything at all.

"And why would the Dark Angels or their successors do such a thing?"

A low burst of laughter was the immediate response, one tinged in pain but with considerable amusement nonetheless.

"Now that would another considerably dangerous secret, Blood Raven," Dumah shook his head vigorously. "I've already made a target of you for giving you one such secret, I would not place another target on the backs of your Chapter with another."

"Dumah-,"

"Gabriel," Dumah interrupted him, amusement draining into utter seriousness. "There are a great many wars being fought across this galaxy. You do not need to be involved with every single one."

It was at that point that Bartorius slammed a fist down and pointed at Ephaltes, then further down the hill to where Akermian had fallen to his knees. Even now, he lived, with a quartet of Codiciers and a full squad of terminators of the 1st Company watching over him from a safe distance. The only marine who had been willing to get close was Hannibal, the Master of Sanctity even putting aside his mighty crozius as he knelt and spoke quietly with him. A disturbing number of the False Lions had been revealed to not be False at all, merely altered. It had been a terrible discovery, one that had struck yet one more blow to the Scarlet Lions and their dismal morale. Unlike Akermian, however, none of them had stopped, not a single one. It was only after the battle was over and they had begun genetic tests to check that they had discovered the truth given up by their gene-seed.

"Ah," Dumah's expression turned grim. "I suspect a different course all together happened to them. It is what I spoke of before, Force Commander. Your 8th Company was too isolated, and the reports of its demise likely falsified entirely, or at the very least altered." He folded his hands in prayer for a silent moment. "You called him Brother-Captain Notos? He may very well be such. I cannot say what terrible things that might have been done to his mind to transform him into Akermian."

Gabriel looked up and away from the grief and rage of Bartorius, up at the skies above them, still blustering and grey as the snow continued to fall in great piles. In but a few hours, this entire field would be obscured largely from sight, the wounds the battle had inflicted upon the landscape hidden. He had not been pleased when he'd learned that the first incoming fleet had not been Dumah's forces, and he had nearly turned then and there, tired of the constant wordplay and deception, but there had been other events at hand that required more of his attention. That the fleet spoken of before truly had come, these ones actually bearing battle scars from the Suysh, actually added the slightest bit of weight to the admittedly patchy credibility that Dumah had managed to gain.

"I cannot believe this. If the forces of Chaos could subvert us so easily-," Gabriel began before Dumah shook his head again.

"Easily? No, not at all. Tell me, Bartorius, how many decades ago was the 8th Company lost? Each finger a decade," Dumah raised his hands, fingers splayed wide.

At one, Bartorius shook his head, as he would for a number of them until he finally gave a jerky nod.

"Sixty years, or thereabout," Dumah sighed before turning back to Gabriel with a drawn expression. "Up to sixty years under the tender ministrations of those who have mastered the art of sculpting not just body and shape, nor text and data archive, but the mind as well. Unrestricted by rationality or morality, possibly with aid from xeno technologies and expertise, the infernal creations of the Dark Mechanicus, and worse."

Grunting, Dumah finally stood, his body healing itself just enough to allow him to do so. Even then, Gabriel dwarfed him clad in terminator armor.

"I'm not saying he was weak," Dumah grunted as he rolled a shoulder before looking Gabriel in the eye. "I am saying the enemy is strong. Too many forget that, or ignore the truth of the matter. It may be possible for him to recover himself, but in the end, it may not."

He then gestured towards the field of bodies.

"If Ephaltes, or the Alpha Legion in general, knew which worlds the Scarlet Lions recruit from? They could have begun subverting their aspirants before they are even born through any myriad number of ways. That light and noise burst was a very, very specific trigger. It might have been that these marines served the Emperor faithfully for their entire lives and never be 'activated'. It just happened not to be so."

Since the arrival of his fleet, Dumah had become much more conversational than before, Gabriel couldn't help but notice.

"So what happens now, Dumah?"

Dumah did not reply at first, hands simply coming to his hips as he surveyed the carnage. Eventually, however, he did turn back to Gabriel with a raised eyebrow.

"Now? Now we part ways, Gabriel Angelos of the Blood Ravens. You and what remains of the Scarlet Lions will go back into the light, while we remain here to serve in the dark," he told him without hesitation. "There are things in the void, Gabriel. Terrible, terrible things that require fighting lest they encroach." Dumah's voice briefly became a whisper before he brightened again. "The Suysh were slated to implode within a few years if they had not been given new targets. Luckily we retained a few Queen eggs before we committed to ending their threat to the Imperium."

"Luckily?" Gabriel could not help but ask incredulously.

"Of course," Dumah answered plainly. "How did you think we managed to travel without the Light of the Astronomicon?"

"I had assumed you braved the warp like any other must when outside of His Light," Gabriel answered honestly and with a hint of disgust in his voice. "You utilize the xenos?"

Dumah's lips pulled down as he shook his head from side to side.

"Mmm, yes, on occasion we are forced to travel without any light at all. As it is, however, the Queens provide a useful service. Or, at least, the echoes of their deaths do, as do their Death-Marks."

Gabriel just stared.

"Without the Astronomicon, one must make what beacons they can," Dumah shrugged. "I do not know what method the Midnight Fangs use, while the Carcharodons flit in and out of the Astronomicon - as far as I know, at least. They might be closer to ending their exile than anyone else."

Then Dumah paused, as if a new realization had come to him, but Gabriel was beginning to think it most certainly had not.

"I've just had a thought. Instead of us leaving amicably, you could kill me and my brothers, or try to, and then clap the survivors in chains to bring back to the Imperium for the crimes of our forefathers! I suspect our fleet would attempt to stop yours, and the Midnight Fangs might grow...displeased if their feast is unduly interrupted by conflict. The Alpha Legion would be glad for it. I suspect certain portions of the Inquisition would be as well," Dumah rubbed at his chin. "I'd prefer if matters did not go that way, of course, but it is up to you."

"You are not making the former possibility any more likely than the latter, you know," Gabriel ground out.

"I cannot help my nature," Dumah said before quickly adding, "Most of the time. As it is, from this point on, the fleet will need to stick together lest one of us be picked off again, just in case our foes try the same gambit again."

There was a hissing noise of heated sealant rapidly cooling and both marines looked down to Nero Gracchus rise to his feet, flicking his hands to the side to get the excess blood off. A small servo skull appeared and began spraying disinfectants while passing a small sterilization field over the apothecary. He then reached down and pulled Bartorius to his feet, the Force Commander finally ambulatory once more. He remained incapable of speech, but at the very least he was not in danger of dying anymore. A wrist-clasp was offered and accepted before Nero turned away and walked back down the hill to see to other patients. Bartorius glanced at both of them, eyes narrowing on Dumah, before he too walked down the slope to see to the fallen. Dumah watched him go without emotion before turning to Gabriel.

"I must see to my men, we were not without casualties ourselves. I'm sure we'll have time to speak again before my fleet gets here, Angelos. See to your own brothers."

========================================================================================

In the end, most of the 3rd Company had been subverted by the machinations of the one bearing the name of Kleonoi Agamat. Significant portions of the 4th and 2nd had been sleeper agents activated by the false chaplain Ephaltes, and had been cut down even as they'd done the same to their brothers. The totality of the False Lions were dead, with over a third of their number revealed to have been subverted Scarlet Lions with no real way to to discern which ones might have been willing or unwilling. Dumah strongly argued against attempting to make use of the Omophagea in this occasion, not least because of the distasteful act of eating of the flesh of another astartes, and also it being entirely possible that hidden toxins or memetic hazard had been hidden within. The Scarlet Lion apothecaries were strenuously testing the gene-seed being extracted, for even those vital organs were worried to have been changed somehow. Before, it would have been unthinkable, but given recent events they simply could not put it past the Alpha Legion to have done something to the holiest part of their beings. Those few Blood Ravens that had been wounded would be completely combat effective by the time the Chapter returned to the Imperium, what wounds that remained to be healed soon enough after that point. But nevertheless, the Alpha Legion had done a tremendous job at harming the loyalists in this endeavor. The Suysh had slaughtered millions of Imperial citizens and Guardsmen, destroyed dozens of Imperial Navy vessels, and had nearly crippled an entire sector. All of that, brought about through the deaths of Dumah's marines, and the theft of their cogitators. All to bring Dumah's attention to bear, all so that he would directly intervene, all so that they could bring him out of hiding and attempt to kill him at all costs. All separated from an entirely different attempt to subvert the name and status of a loyal Chapter of space marines as a mask for traitorous actions and movement within the Imperium. Actions and efforts wholly different from battling the Alpha Legion in previous encounters, from the efforts of the Black Legion to destroy Subsector Aurelia.

Though much ruin and destruction had been wrought here, Gabriel could at least attempt to content himself with the knowledge that without the Blood Ravens, it could have been much worse.

His musing was interrupted when Captain Macharius approached him. The man had, temporarily at least, relieved himself of carrying about the plasma cannon he was so partial to.

"Brother-Captain," he greeted him politely.

"Chapter Master," Macharius replied with a salute.

"What do you require of me?"

"Chapter Master, I wish to nominate some of the brothers of the 2nd Company for the position of Company Champion. Brothers Jordis and Obasi are the sergeants of the 2nd Company Assault Squads, and both of them have acquitted themselves with great valor and skill throughout this campaign," Macharius began, falling into attention while staring straight ahead. "And wished to ask you for guidance wisdom."

"I see," Gabriel nodded before glancing down at the data pad and scrolling through its contents.

Brother Jordis had proven an adept sergeant since taking the position, possessing all the vigor and aggression demanded by an assault marine but tempered with clear and noted efforts to ensure the best possible effectiveness in the usage of his squad. Adept tactical thinking had ensured that his squad was rarely at a disadvantage against the Suysh, rapidly moving from weak point to weak point amongst the enemy without lingering too long and being surrounded. While it was entirely part of the role of the assault marine to plunge into the depths of the enemy, the bonds of brotherhood that Jordis had fostered amongst his squad had created an intriguing level of closeness in combat for the squad. It had been repeatedly noted that the entire squad often fought as one smooth and connected group with at a level normally only achieved by veterans, blocking and deflecting blows from one another without even turning or looking, to the point that there was even a note from the Librarians that they had checked Sergeant Jordis more than once for nascent psychic abilities only to find none. His own martial abilities were considerable as well. Jordis was credited with a Queen kill, having fought his way through an entire group of Royal Guard alone while the rest of his squad kept other Suysh from stopping him, plunging himself and his chainsword into the Queen's gullet and literally cutting his way back out. Though he had been badly battered and nearly melted into liquid by the incredibly powerful stomach acids present, his power armor's machine spirit had held firm enough to allow him to survive for the apothecaries to reach him.

Brother Obasi, being the other sergeant of the assault marines of the 2nd Company, had by his position alone been at the forefront of the fighting against the Suysh. Unlike Brother Jordis, however, Obasi seemed content to push his brothers to greater heights by virtue of example. He held two Queen kills, the first of them accomplished earlier in the campaign than Jordis, when the Blood Ravens had not yet fully developed their plans and tactics to the fullest extent that they would later on. At the same time, he had also willingly taken part in more armor-targeting missions, dropping melta grenades and bombs from above to hit xeno tanks and buildings in harrying attacks. Obasi appeared to encourage independent thought and action amongst his squad, discussions common even mid-flight about targets and potential places to land and fall upon the enemy. Though he held the final word, he ensured that the voices of his brothers were heard. When there were disagreements, he had proved able to quieting dissent through sheer virtue of victory later on to spite disagreements. In combat with Royal Guard and Hungerers he had proven adept with the chainsword, slaying them despite the tough hide and armor and further despite his lack of bearing a power sword at the time. He was an extensively experienced swordsman.

"The choice is your own, Brother-Captain. I will not be Kyras," in as many ways that were possible, "And I will not micromanage your every decision and appointment. Both of them could be rightly considered veterans after this campaign, each of them has proven skill with the blade. It is up to you how to decide."

Macharius sighed as he took the data slate back.

"I know, I had mostly hoped that you would come to a different conclusion than I. Both of them are worth the promotion, and their position could be filled by another in their squad, with a newly promoted battle brother from the Devastator squads filling in next."

Gabriel chuckled as some honest humor broke the bleakness ever so briefly. This, not the skulking dealings of the Alpha Legion, but this? This he had experience with.

"Brother-Captain, I will tell you this. In my time as the Captain of the 3rd Company I faced many such decisions as you face now. Brothers equal to one another, yet with only one position to fill, who and when and why a brother might be granted veteran laurels, and who might be seconded to other companies," Gabriel clamped a brotherly hand on Macharius' shoulder. "There will be times when there is no 'perfect' choice. You must simply be prepared to deal with the aftermath should one or the other feel slighted. Have you made them aware that you are considering them for such?"

Macharius shook his head rapidly.

"No, not yet. I don't need them butting heads if I can help it," he said, aggrieved.

Gabriel just huffed another laugh.

"I am sure you will make the correct choice, brother."

The brother-captain simply sighed again as he nodded and walked away back towards his company. The smile soon fell from Gabriel's lips as well when he saw Dumah approaching along with the two remaining Captains of the Scarlet Lions. Bartorius would require either extensive reconstructive surgery or bionics, neither of which were immediately possible, while Kallek had gone largely silent simply out of mute horror at what had been done. The snow drifts were almost up to Gabriel's knees in his terminator armor, and it was only the effort of the tallying apothecaries that the bodies of the slain remained uncovered. The temperatures would surely have frozen most Guardsmen solid, though not all of their kind. Those of Vallhalla and the Vostroyan Regiments might have considered it only extremely cold.

"It seems that our time has come to an end, Gabriel Angelos," Dumah bowed ever so slightly at the waist to him. "I must away. I had hoped the Eastern Fringe would be too far for them, but of course, hope is but the first step on the road to disappointment."

"Where will you go, then?"

Dumah just ghosted a smile at Gabriel.

"Away from here," he answered without any further elaboration. "You are an interesting marine. I don't think I've ever met someone like you Blood Ravens before."

"And how much of what you've said are lies or misdirection?" Gabriel answered back sardonically.

"Some," Dumah smiled with his teeth bared. "But I am more here to revisit the question," he placed his hand quite firmly onto the hilt of his power sword.

Kallek and Bartorius tensed just as Gabriel did. Dumah's expression was entirely too casual.

"What are we to do about this? I can swear to my loyalty to the end of my last breath, and it could all be lies. Will we be permitted to leave, or will combat ensue on this day between space marine an space marine once more?"

What To Do?
Moratorium For 3 Hours

[] Let Them Go
OR
[] Attempt To Take Them In
OR
[] Write-In

Additionally
[] Ignore the question of the Dark Angels, whatever Dumah says might be lies or complete misdirection.
[] Push the question on the matter of the Dark Angels, and why in the name of the Golden Throne would Ephaltes think he could manipulate the Sons of the Lion so.

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Eleven)

[] Let Them Go
[] Ignore the question of the Dark Angels, whatever Dumah says might be lies or complete misdirection.
-[] Instead, pointedly ask about the "more immediate" matter of the Midnight Fangs, such as who they are and if it isn't suspicious that they appeared just as the events were unfolding

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

Gabriel just looked at Dumah for a few seconds while the renegade loyalist looked back with an almost disinterested raised eyebrow. Bartorius and Kallek stood watching the two of them, but neither seemed capable of combat at the moment, standing largely only because of the dedicated efforts of the Chief Apothecary. For a moment, the Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens just listened to the sounds of recovery and surgery taking place on so many space marine bodies. He looked away to survey the ruin that had been dealt to this isolated patch of the planet, and just as he had known they would, the snows were quickly coming to bury it all. This far from the light of the Emperor, with damning secrets and impossible histories, he felt the yawning abyss and all it promised and all it threatened threatening to swallow him and his chapter whole.

No.

If it should come to pass that the Blood Ravens would be confronted by whatever secrets the Dark Angels held, then he would chastise himself then. But he would not plunge the Blood Ravens needlessly into yet another cauldron of shadowy danger if he could help it. Already they were faced with potentially becoming greater targets of the Alpha Legion and their esoteric infiltrations, simply for the fateful choice of battling the Suysh rather than dedicating the chapter to other battlefields. For all that Dumah proclaimed to be a loyalist, a proclamation that Gabriel was willing to entertain for now at least, it would certainly not be beyond a descendent of a previously hidden Primarch – a concept that he struggled over even now – to manipulate a potential conflict for his own ends. No, Gabriel saw the offered knowledge for the potential poison it was, and made to pivot.

“Tell me of these Midnight Fangs,” he asked instead. “Is it not suspicious that they have appeared just ahead of your own fleet, setting upon the planet?”

There was a bemused twinkle in Dumah’s eye, for he could immediately tell why Gabriel asked his question, but as the ancient marine considered the topic the twitching of his lips turned into a full frown. The scars on his dark mocha skin stretched unpleasantly with the motion.

“Mmm, another of the banished fleets,” he nodded, gazing up as if he could see their ships in the southern hemisphere. “The Midnight Fangs are supreme scavengers and opportunists…I would not call them cowards,” he said very carefully, “But they rarely commit themselves to battle when they are not certain of victory. Worse, their Feasts are often committed without warning or cooperation with others,” he continued with a faint scowl on his lips. “The Carcharodons at least communicuate with the Mechanicus for the Grey Tithe and the Administratum for the Red, but the Midnight Fangs show up, consume what they will, and move on, all in the name of endlessly persecuting the fight through the Void.”

Dumah then turned back to look Gabriel in the eyes, uncharacteristic seriousness in his eyes.

“I will tell you an unvarnished truth: do not approach or even stand too close to them, lest they find you worth more as salvage to their thirsting resource stores than as fighting sons of the Emperor.”

Gabriel grunted, his lips thinning, but he nodded all the same. He maintained a connection to the command vox lines, and as such could hear occasional reports from Hadrian above in his ships about the conduct with which the Midnight Fangs acted. Most of it would be transcribed by waiting cherub monitors into the cogitators to be recorded later, along with auspex scan records and the like. Already, his mind had seized upon a comparison back within the light of the Astronomicon, specifically with those of the Blood Angels and their successors known as their Death Companies. Only once had Gabriel ever witnessed a Death Company in action, on a battlefield more than three centuries past as a mere initiate, and yet he had watched as more than forty marines had thrown themselves madly into battle and died to a battle-brother against ork lines. Yet it had proven enough for the rest of the Imperial forces to plunge through the created beachhead. Going by long-range auspex, the Midnight Fangs were as fierce and heedless of their own safety, rapidly advancing constantly with unknown patterns of vehicles riding behind that were loaded up with all sorts of taken materials, be they weapons, armor, or outright portions of entire buildings.

“I see.”

“You think you do, but you’ve not seen a predation fleet truly at work, I’d reckon, and if you are very lucky, you won’t,” Dumah shook his head. “The Carcharodons strive to be found worthy enough to be granted a place back within the light. The Midnight Fangs gave up long ago, and that reflects in everything they do.”

“And your kind?”

Dumah smiled.

“We exist to confound the enemies of the Imperium and provide a rebuttal to the insanity of the Hydra.”

The vox crackled to life.

“Chapter Master. All immediate surgeries and procedures are complete,” Chief Apothecary Nero’s voice came through. “The rest that might be required can be completed within the apothecariums of the Scarlet Lions over time, though some might require entombment based on their injuries.”

“Thank you, Brother-Apothecary. Let us return to our ships and to the Imperium,” Gabriel responded quickly.

“It seems our time is done then. Be careful with what you’ve learned, Blood Raven,” Dumah nodded at the Chapter Master before looking over to Bartorius and Kallek. “As for you, I would be cautious, though we’ve extracted a great poison from your Chapter before it could spread, there may yet still be thorns hooked into place.”

Both of the Captains stiffened, but neither spoke, only giving curt nods. The whine of thunderhawks soon filled the air, and all of the marines watched as a squadron of battered craft fought their way down through the atmosphere. None bore much beyond the barest of Imperial iconography, and what of it was there was terribly worn. Also flying down were Blood Raven and Scarlet Lion thunderhawks, these of far better appearance and possibly quality, through all watching knew better than to simply assume based on the outward appearance of either craft. Whatever machine spirits that resided within the craft of Dumah’s forces would have to be hardy and stubborn ones to survive out here in the void without any Mechanicus-held worlds.

“I believe that our time here is done. It is time we go our separate ways,” Dumah coughed and sniffed. “May you find victory under the Emperor’s light once more, Blood Ravens and Scarlet Lions, while we seek it beyond.”

No one was eager to remain on the Suysh planet as the Midnight Fangs picked over it. Within a matter of minutes, the forces of all three loyalists ascended upwards once more towards their respective ships. Frankly, utilizing the teleportariums was a concept that made Gabriel and most other Blood Ravens uneasy. Teleporting was already a dangerous act, every time, even when one was within the chaotic space beyond the regular borders of the Imperium. The comparatively much longer travel times of more mundane transport was quite preferable to losing marines into the Warp. Though the Blood Ravens suffered zero fatalities and quickly treatable casualties, the Scarlet Lions had been utterly savaged. Though the fighting against the Suysh was over, the fight between apothecaries and death itself would continue for some time. The fleets kept closely together, almost huddled, as they pushed out and away back towards the borders of the Imperium, though Dumah’s ships did not follow.

The home system of the Suysh would be left behind, the last bastion of an alien civilization that had chosen to war against the Imperium in order to devour them as food, themselves now being devoured by the scavenger fleets of the Midnight Fangs. If the words of either of these disconnected chapters were worth anything at all, the rest of the Suysh civilization had already fallen in the course of their unrelenting hunger. There yet remained Suysh Queens elsewhere in Imperial space, but without the constant reinforcements from their factories and space stations beyond the grasp of most of the Imperium’s fleets. As far as Gabriel and the rest of the Blood Ravens could tell, with relative certainty, the Suysh would not survive in the long run, save for disturbingly being used by Dumah’s brothers as psychic beacons.

Such was the eventual fate of all who would dare assault the Imperium.

“Chapter Master, we are receiving another communication from Dumah’s forces, from the ship of the one known as Antilochus,” Hadrian called out from the command throne.

All of the Chapter’s leadership was on the command deck of the Omnis, though Justinius appeared to be meditating for the upcoming push through the Immaterium along with many other codiciers. Some still bore their armor, though others, like the Chapter Master himself, had surrendered their wargear to the serfs and tech marines to perform maintenance on. Gabriel still towered, though he was now dressed in a simple robe of cloth with a belt of cord, and nothing else, his bionics gleaming in the lights of the bridge.

“Let it through,” Gabriel commanded, folding his hands behind his back.

“Safe travels, Blood Ravens,” Dumah’s voice bounced in and out, his ships on the far side of the system. “May you find victory within the Emperor’s light.”

“It occurs to me, Dumah, that you still refused to tell us what to call you and your brethren,” Gabriel replied sternly. “The Alpha Legion-,”

“I will stop you there, Angelos,” Dumah interrupted flatly, “There is no Omega Legion, no bright mirror to the Alpha Legion, if that is what you are hoping. We are but a few candles that burn in defiance to a shadow of something once great. It is time for us both to leave to where we must.”

“…I see,” Gabriel eventually said, sharing glances with the rest of his nearby battle brothers.

All looked disturbed, grim, and uncertain in equal measure, which was only to be expected considering the so-called revelations that had come upon them in the course of the campaign.

“Do not be so dour, Blood Raven,” Dumah chuckled over the vox. “I doubt we shall ever see or hear much of each other ever again.”

“Then this is goodbye.”

“Indeed. It bears repeating, Gabriel, but the information you now possess makes you a target, regardless of whether or not you wished to act upon it,” Dumah’s voice shifted then, becoming more grave. “Knowledge is power, wield it well,” he intoned before cutting off the vox call.

It was like a heavy bolter round being fired right next to the ear. Gabriel’s arms unfolded and clamped tightly onto the tactical display, while other nearby Blood Ravens who had heard the words looked about at each other in bewilderment.

“Dumah!”

Not once had the Blood Ravens utilized their old battle cry throughout the fighting, the words damningly spoken by Kyras in the closing days of the Third Aurelian Crusade, by the traitorous Blood Ravens during the Chapter’s civil war. It was a phrase that held true, yes, but only amongst the Librarians and tech marines when regarding their duties, or in quiet and private conversation between the psykers or technologically trained battle brothers.

Not.

Once.

Yet the words that Dumah had just spoken, clearly well-worn and heavy with earnest tradition…!

“Get him back on the vox,” Gabriel cried aloud.

“I am trying, but their ships are not responding to vox hails,” the serf at the nearest vox bank yelled aloud.

“It’s too late,” Hadrian shouted, “They are entering the Warp!”

The Blood Ravens watched, fists clenched, eyes wide and staring, as the accursed fleet of Dumah and his brethren disappeared into the warp. They were left to only think furiously, breathing hard, some immediately beginning to pace shortly. Gabriel, for his part, just growled and bowed his head. He knew that this far from the Imperium, in unfamiliar territory both within the Immaterium and without. He forced the desires down, crushing them beneath his will, and straightened from where he’d leaned forward against the table.

“Just…just lock in coordinates and get us out of here,” he growled, eyes locked ahead into the distance.

“But Chapter Master, they-,”

“Now, Hadrian!”

And so the Blood Ravens, against ingrained instinct and harshly spiking desire for the knowledge that had been abruptly produced, without a chance to analyze or debate, departed.

Warp Travel: 72

The travel through the warp was, somewhat, more smooth than it was on the way there only by the virtue of the fact that there were no impacts or detections of dangerous warp entities. At least any that could be reckoned by the Librarius. Once more, the beacon within the Litany of Fury began to pulse, and as its pulses reached out through the warp, it impacted and collided, repeating backwards and forwards continually. Ever so carefully, the fleet of the Blood Ravens and the Scarlet Lions crept their way back towards where they had begun until the Astronomican began to burn more fully in the eye of the navigators rather than as a distant echo caught and propagated by the beacon. But in time, after more than a month within the Warp, they emerged once more into the Jahal System.

What greeted them was a full fleet of the Imperial Navy, which hung over each of the worlds within, ferrying heavy detachments of the Imperial Guard down to a hundred separate battlefields. Their arrival could not have been missed, not with so many battle barges and strike cruisers at once, and immediately vox hails began to assail their ships from across the system. While Gabriel moved to respond to those that he could, informing the Imperial commanders of their actions and victory, he also scanned the tactical screens and the returns of their auspex scans to locate the 10th Company. Within seconds he found them, spread out across the four main planets. A motion from him to Hadrian had quiet hails put through, and soon enough Captain Cyrus responded.

“Chapter Master, it is good to see you and the Chapter are alive and well,” Cyrus said immediately upon the vox channel opening.

“The same to you, Cyrus. Our ships will require chrono-sync with your ships for the cogitators, but I would have it said from your mouth. How long were we gone?” Gabriel spoke calmly.

“About half a year, Chapter Master,” Cyrus shrugged, his hololith form sparking in and out of proper focus. “I elected to put my company to use aiding the Imperial Guard, they showed up about two months after you left after they confirmed our reports.”

“Ah,” Gabriel nodded, “I’ve see they’ve achieved landings on all major strategic points.”

“Correct. At this point, it’s a foregone conclusion that the Suysh are finished, but I figured that it would not hurt the Chapter to try and aid the Guard in the meantime.”

“Fear not, Captain, I approve of your actions,” Gabriel was quick to say, a smile on his scarred face. “But for now, recall you company and join your fleet to ours, we are making for Sacred Crown station for repairs and maintenance, and we may speak more freely there.”

“Very well, Chapter Master,” Cyrus shallowly inclined his head, “We’ll meet you there.”

A few days later found the Blood Ravens, save for Captain Tarkus and the 5th Company, together once more. The leadership assembled, reporting on and debating what they’d seen and learned of their companies, their allies, and their enemies. The ships of both Blood Raven and Scarlet Lions were being repaired by the automated systems of the station as well as tireless work by the tech marines, and would be finished soon enough. There, Cyrus revealed that he’d managed to maintain if not cordial than at the least functioning relationships with the Generals of the Imperial Guard that had been deployed, one to each planet, without angering the Admiral in charge of the Imperial Navy battlegroup assigned. It helped that the Suysh had been so thoroughly ravaged by the passage of the space marines, their total lack of leadership only ever increasing with the work of the scouts of the Blood Ravens. In the end, the Suysh were being reduced to near mindless and cannibalistic hordes that showed no tactics or planning whatsoever, essentially running themselves into prepared Guardsmen battle lines unto extinction.

Cyrus predicted that the Suysh on all of the worlds within the Jahal system would be dead within a few more weeks if their levels of aggression kept up.

Then, of course, came the inevitable aftermath of a hard fought campaign. The dead required tallying, the lists of living and dead altered once more, and promotions and recognition granted to those who had earned it. It was likely that similar was occurring with the Scarlet Lions, but the normally boisterous marines had become intensely reclusive on their ships, responding to daily update requests but little else. None of the Blood Ravens wished to push it, for many still keenly felt the wounds to the spirit that spilling the blood of those once thought of as brothers could cause. The 2nd Company had suffered heavily, out of the whole of the chapter, losing a full sixteen battle brothers over the course of the campaign. On the other hand, by the reckoning of Cyrus, with an additional six months of proving, a good number of scouts had been promoted to full battle brothers, only aiding in the fighting that the 10th Company had taken part in while the rest of the Chapter was elsewhere.

Afterwards, they simply rested, recovered, and refilled their war material stores with some hefty work on behalf of their forges. The fighting was effectively over, and nothing more required the participation of the Blood Ravens. It was one thing to aid the Guard, another to apply space marines to a situation where the only casualties suffered by the Imperial Guard were from friendly fire or laziness rather than any actual abilities on behalf of the enemy. As such, the Blood Ravens soon prepared themselves to leave, it was time to return to Subsector Aurelia, for a multitude of reasons. But not just yet.

==============================================

It was impossible to describe a space marine, a true space marine, with such a mortal descriptor as ‘bleary’, but the Scarlet Lions came close as they cautiously welcomed the Blood Raven thunderhawk onto their battle barge. Captain Bartorius and Captain Kallek stood waiting with a small honor guard, but the former had yet to regain the ability of speech and the latter was still sans an arm. Nevertheless, the Scarlet Lions stomped their feet and saluted in a loud crash of ceramite on ceramite as Gabriel and Martellus emerged, a small pallet carried by a servitor behind them. Several figures, in fact Scarlet Lions dressed in vibrant purple and crimson togas, were off to the side. They held within their hands a multitude of strange instruments, and began to play them. The song itself was obviously meant to be triumphant, bold, powerful. But for some reason, despite the skill of those who likely spent decades with them, the noises that emerged were undeniably mournful and quiet, the power of music itself as battered as the spirits ones who played it. Yet the Scarlet Lions made a go of it regardless.

“Brothers,” Gabriel looked not just at the Captains but the rest of the Scarlet Lions. “The predations of Chaos have dealt you a weighty blow…but you yet stand. In time, I have faith that the strong sons of Lemnos will rebuild, mightier than ever.”

He watched them, carefully, as a number of spines seemed to straighten. One of the music playing marines, who had freshly inked tattoos beneath on eye in the form of purple-lined teardrops, inhaled deeply and began to blow more clearly. More strongly. More proudly.

“We could not have known what we would face when we dedicated ourselves to this fight, but I am proud to have fought it alongside you. The poison within was torn out before more ruin could be done.”

Kallek merely nodded, while Bartorius looked down.

“But in remembrance of our fighting together, against xenos and treachery alike, the Blood Ravens would give the Scarlet Lions a gift.”

Gabriel stood back, gesturing towards where Martellus stood. The Master of the Forge bowed slightly, stepping to the side, a pre-programmed gesture that had the servitor rolling forward slightly, the pallet held in front of it.

Martellus Roll: 92

Within was a power sword, its destructive field currently inactive. It had once been one held by the Blood Ravens before Martellus altered it. Scarlet Lion iconography had been intricately engraved into the guard and handle, while along the length of the blade the word ‘Lemnos’ had been carved in fine High Gothic script. For the entire month of warp travel back to the Imperium and for many of the days afterwards leading up to now Martellus had worked upon it, to make a worthy gift of friendship for those who had fought alongside the Blood Ravens without hesitation. The center of the hilt, traditionally a skull on an Imperial weapon, was now a snarling lion’s head. All told, it was a magnificent piece of equipment, and Martellus was not shy about expounding about the improvements he’d made to the power field systems, utilizing a bevy of rare materials and what he claimed to be the blessings of the Omnissiah. He ceased, however, when he realized that there were no other tech marines present and that his Chapter Master had coughed for the second time.

“Er, yes. In any case, in honor of our friendship upon the battlefield and our bond as fellow sons of the Emperor,” Martellus carefully handed the weapon to Captain Bartorius, whose eyes widened as he felt its weight and balance. “I call it Truthfang.”

When Bartorius thumbed the activation rune, he jerked slightly as the traditional blue and white of a standard power weapon did not flare to life. Instead, a sparking aura of gold with streaks of white came into being. The letters of the word Lemnos upon its length were somehow colored by the power field’s presence, taking on the white and red color pattern of the Scarlet Lions beneath its semi-transparency.

“This be…a mighty gift,” Kallek spoke, for Bartorius could not. “Thank thee.”

“May it serve the Scarlet Lions well,” Gabriel spoke warmly before bowing his head. “I am glad it was complete in time before our departure,” he then raised it, looking at Kallek as Bartorius seemed entranced by the weapon in his hand. “What will you do now?”

Kallek sighed, slumping slightly.

“We shall lick our wounds, try to calleth pon our brethren for a Council of Grasses, and rebuild out numbers as surely as we might,” he answered simply. “We cannot do any less.”

He set his shoulders, however, and looked up at Gabriel.

“But you saved our lives, and the soul of our companies. If the Blood Ravens had not been there, three whole companies of Scarlet Lions would have fallen into darkness. For that, you have our eternal gratitude. If there should come a time, you may call upon our two companies,” Kallek gestured and another marine with sergeant markings approached with a data slate. “These are our astropathic signatures, with command codes that will prove your messages true.”

“We are honored,” Gabriel began.

“And we are alive because of you,” Kallek interrupted with a small huff. “Our pride is battered, but we are not yet broken.”

“…indeed,” Gabriel smiled, “Indeed. Safe travels, Lions.”

“And to you as well, Blood Ravens,” Kallek nodded back.

With that, the two fleets departed, the Blood Ravens going one way and the Scarlet Lions another. Time would tell if they would ever meet again, for the galaxy was ever at war, and their duties could call them to any of a thousand battlefields at any time.

Time would tell.

Campaign Over: Xenocide of the Suysh Completed

Next post will be a start of turn post. Below are the total fatalities/advancements/found notables that have resulted from the fighting. Front page has been updated.

Total Fatalities Of Campaign

4 Scouts [1st Stage] Killed [8 Gene-Seed Recovered]

5 4th Company Marines Dead [10 Gene-Seed Recovered]

1 Tarantula Sentry Turret Destroyed (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)

16 2nd Company Marines Killed (32 Gene-Seed Recovered)

1 1st Company Marine Killed (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)

25 10th Company Neophytes [2nd Stage] Killed

Total Gene-Seed Recovered: 52

Advancements
Of Starting 28 Lexicanum -> 9 Advancing To Codicier
Of Starting 12 Codicier -> 4 Advance To Epistolary
Of Starting Scouts [2nd Stage] 35 -> 35 Advance To Battle Brothers Awaiting Assignment
Of Starting Scouts [1st Stage]: 142 -> 130 Advance To Scouts [2nd Stage]
12 Scouts [1st Stage] Require More Experience To Advance
5 2nd Company Marines Advance To Veteran Status
6 4th Company Marines Advance To Veteran Status

Neck Progenoids Reclaimed From Advancing Scouts [2nd Stage]: 35

Specialists To Be Found Exemplary In The Course Of Campaign
2nd Company Assault Sergeant Jordis – Skilled leadership and exemplary combat capabilities have ensured that his squad achieves the maximum possible result with the greatest possible efficiency. The bonds of brotherhood he has forged with his squad are amongst the most close-knit in the entire Chapter. Personally showed great valor and skill during combat against the Suysh. Credited with one solo Suysh Queen kill by weathering the alien’s fury at close range in order to slay it. [+Fellowship, +Toughness]

2nd Company Assault Sergeant Obasi – Substantially skilled combatant and leader of an assault marine squad. Leads by valorous example, inspiring those around him to greater heights as he plunged into the xeno lines again and again. Noted to be one of the most skilled swordsmen in the chapter, accomplishing many incredible deeds with only a chainsword and bolt pistol. Oddly indulgent with complaints and discussion amongst squad, but manages them well enough. [+Fellowship, +Weapon Skill]

1st Company Terminator Sergeant Stromahn – Any member of the 1st Company is one of the greatest veterans of the chapter, and Sergeant Stromahn is no different. A terminator under Chapter Master Angelos as far back as Tartarus, Stromahn has proven himself again and again. He has stood against the tide again and again to preserve the lives of his brothers, striking the foe with unrelenting fury while trusting in the artifice of his terminator armor to preserve him. The amount of glories he has won, and the sheer effort he puts into advising his brethren in battle and outside of it marks him as a solid foundation for younger brothers to seek out guidance from. [+Elder Veteran, +Guiding Heart]

1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos – Brother Minos has fought for the Chapter and specifically Chapter Master Angelos for an extensive period of time, always willingly at the forefront either as an assault marine or as an assault terminator. As a part of the 3rd Company, Brother Minos fought the daemon Sindri Myr in person, withstood the ranged techno-sorcery of the Tau while facing a pack of krootox alone to allow his brothers to redeploy at the rear of the enemy formation, and survived the deadly battle of Aurelia that killed so many others. His close combat skills and flat refusal to fall no matter the injury until the battle is done has won many victories for the chapter. [+Elder Veteran, +Duels Like A Mountain]

Techmarine Janos – Techmarine Janos proved himself willing to battle the technologies of the alien Suysh without hesitation, trusting in his skill and the Omnissiah to bring him to victory. During the Suysh campaign, he quickly and often chose to participate openly in battle, all the better to service the vehicles and wargear of his brothers even while under fire. His stoicism is already a growing legend, the steel in his spine quite possibly Omnissiah-given. [+Combat Engineer, +Willpower]

Apothecary Talm – Brother Talm seems almost upset at being as skilled and capable an apothecary that he is, though he has spoken to none other than the Chaplains about such things, if he does at all. He excises this discontent in the most appreciable of means: slaying the enemies of the Emperor whenever possible with a shotgun or plasma pistol while standing over the bodies of his brothers. It has been noted, more than once, that he was destined to be an exemplary devastator marine before being selected as an apothecary. [+Violent Protector, +Ballistic Skill]

Apothcary Ikai – During the battles against the Suysh, on those few occasions where Blood Ravens fell, Brother Ikai was the one who led the charge to retrieve them. Inevitably, his white armor was covered from head to toe in alien gore by the end of it, all to preserve the precious progenoid glands of his brothers. Though bereft of a jump pack, as skilled with the chainsword and as brash as he is, it is unsurprising that he was expected to be a superb assault marine before taken into the ranks of the apothecaries. [+Assault Apothecary, +Weapon Skill]

Chaplain Alastair – Much to the consternation of the Master of the Apothecarion, Chaplain Alistair has readily followed the example of Hannibal Palrun, Master of Sanctity of the Blood Ravens. Alistair has proven a ready member of the Fist of Faith formation, utterly willing to weather the storm of enemy fire with nothing more than his body, and a violent inspiration to his brethren. All of which was done without a rosarius. Even so, his durability is matched perhaps only by the Master of Sanctity himself, with Chaplain Alastair also shielding the wounded with his own body. His battlefield sermons on fury and hatred are held up as examples even amongst his fellow Chaplains, his skill with a crozius and pistol undeniable. [+Toughness, +Thunderous Orator]

Chaplain Galloss – Chaplain Galloss is an eccentric, even amongst the Chaplains, for his incredible quiet outside of battle. In the flames of war, he is just as bombastic and exulting as his fellows, but outside of it he rarely speaks much at all, leaving sermons for his brothers. Even so, his nature has allowed him to be remarkably capable of pinpointing chinks in the spiritual and mental armor of his brethren, speaking to them and buoying their faith and will in the aftermath of battle. By the time Chaplain Galloss has finished counseling any one marine, they are all the stronger for it, their souls tempered and salved with his aid. [+Fellowship, +War Counselor]

Chaplain Tasanor – It has been remarked amongst the Chaplaincy that Brother Tasanor would have been a Company Champion were it not for his position. He has displayed incredible combat ability, even amongst fellow Astartes, and formed a highly effective part of the first Fist of Faith formation during the Suysh campaign. Though he wields a crozius, as is befitting his position, he also carries a multitude of other weapons depending on the enemy he is facing at the time. Displaying a remarkable flexibility in mentality for a chaplain, he encourages the same in his fellows when attached to squads, leading them to victory again and again. [+Encyclopedia of Violence, +Heroic Challenger]

Epistolary Lucan – As a Codicier, Epistolary Lucan unearthed rare and powerful knowledge hidden within the Librarius of the Litany of Fury, left behind by the Librarian Jonah Orion before the fateful battle against Kyras began on the planet Cyrene. He dedicated many years to studying and mastering this knowledge before fully unleashing it in the Suysh campaign. Though not particularly skilled in visibly impressive abilities, Epistolary Lucan is a master at enhancing his brethren, greatly empowering their strength and psychically accelerating their very bodies until the squads he was attached to became little more than blurs amongst the enemy. Should they take wounds, he has proven quite the capable healer as well, albeit with the powers of his mind rather than the tools of the Apothecary, a legacy of Jonah Orion’s lessons. [+Psychic Booster, +Support Specialist]

Epistolary Flekton – Though he is quite a capable Librarian, learned and powerful as befitting an Epistolary of the Blood Ravens, Brother Flekton has proven a true master of defensive psychic abilities, crafting powerful domes and barriers of pure thought that have withstood the most powerful weapons of tyranids, tau, greenskins, Suysh, and more. His wards also protect his brothers from intrusion into their minds and souls, and for those incredibly rare times that something bypasses his defenses he can quickly set about mending flesh with nothing more than his purifying will as the notable Librarian Jonah Orion once could. While providing and fortifying his barriers he is an able shot with pistol or psychic blast. [+Barrier Lord, +Support Specialist]

Epistolary Rasmus – Though he is obviously capable, Rasmus does not often wield the most visible psychic powers known to the Chapter. Rather, he has proven himself to be a master with the unseen. Skilled at piercing the veil to analyze possible futures, tracking the enemy, communicating with fellow Librarians at great distances, Rasmus is no easy foe in combat either. He has proven adept at shattering the minds and shackling the nervous systems of his enemies, or utilizing technomancy to ruin their weapons and armor to allow his brothers to kill with impunity. Brother Rasmus has proven his abilities time and again. [+ Deadly Telepath, +Esoteric Master]

Epistolary Idmon – Fighting within tight confines in the tunnels and caverns of the Suysh, Epistolary Idmon showed a true talent for geomancy and general telekinetic combat in excess of his other codicier level abilities. Whether literally throwing tanks or forming shields of stone and lightning, Idmon proved himself a deadly foe to the enemies of Mankind. He is credited with slaying a Suysh Queen by literally bringing the cavern down around it, manipulating hundreds of tons of rock into spikes that obliterated the foul alien and its Royal Guard at the same time. At other time, he formed new tunnels and entrances that allowed his brothers to move flank the enemy easily. Metal and stone bend and twist with ease before him, and he seems to see through them almost as well. [+Geokiller, +Perception]

Codicier Aeneas – Amongst his brother Librarians, Brother Aeneas has proven a duelist without peer. Such was his skill that the Librarius saw fit to release one of their most valuable relics, the blade of Azariah Moriah, thought lost to those not privy to information on what lies within the vaults of the Librarius. Furthermore, Brother Aeneas has proven an adept at teleporting through the warp into the bodies of his enemies, enhancing his own strength and speed to incredible levels. If his foes are at range, he can step through the veil to reach them. Even the Chief Librarian has voiced his acknowledgement of Brother Aeneas’ abilities, but at the same time Aeneas has not yet mastered some of the abilities required of an Epistolary. It is rumored that this is deliberate, so that Aeneas may be deployed wherever he can rather than being forced to be stationed in any single Company. [+Champion Duelist, +Teleport Specialist] Entrusted with the Relic known as the Blade of the Martyr

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part One)

GM Note: 2 Hour Moratorium

Spoiler: Start Of Turn Stuff

100 Gene-Seed Test-Slaves Complete Growth, Harvesting Yields 2 Gene-Seed Each, +200 Gene-Seed To Total, now 618.
10% Gene-Seed Tithe Enacted By Mechanicus. Gene-Seed Total Reduced To 557.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

Only a day after the newest techmarines of the Blood Ravens returned from Mars and the latest Tithing of Gene-Seed taken away on the departing Mechanicus ships, the docking bay of the Omnis was host to an Inquisitorial retinue once more, and just as the last time it was not a welcome thing. While the Blood Ravens had been aiding in the near total extermination of the Suysh race, the Ordo Malleus had scoured Subsector Aurelia, such as it was. Even the burned worlds of Typhon and Cyrene had felt the Inquisition’s boot upon their surface, the latter especially. Gabriel’s twin hearts, one of which was bionic, both beat with shame at that fact. Cyrene had, after all, been where Kyras had done his most vile rituals, had nearly ascended to complete daemonhood, only to be struck down by those few who had remained loyal. Inquisitor Toth had returned, his perpetually grim countenance magnified by what he had discovered, a full on grimace to his face now. Just as the last time, a pair of Grey Knights had accompanied him.

It still pained Gabriel to know that their bond had been so thoroughly severed by Kyras, and likely would pain Thule as well if the dreadnought were conscious. It did not help that some of the Grey Knights that had accompanied Boreale had fallen not to the forces of Chaos but to greenskins.

“Your suspicions were correct, Angelos,” Inquisitor Toth grunted as he glanced about the docking bay. “Though there have not been any direct daemonic manifestations, this daemon’s influence is growing nonetheless.”

Hope may have been the first step on the road to disappointment, but the confirmation still cast a pall over the assembled battle brothers.

“The seals were broken by the Black Legion,” Justinius replied, rubbing at his chin, “Ulkair was weakened when he was banished back within. Should he grow sufficiently powerful enough, he may well emerge once more.”

Toth nodded, his grimace increasing in scope.

“I agree. Furthermore, I suspect that the planet itself is serving as an anchor, for all that it is also his prison.”

“But to destroy it completely could free him instantly,” Justinius was quick to say, his eyes wide.

“I am aware,” Toth said with a raised eyebrow. “Simply because this subsector had felt the touch of Exterminatus twice does not mean that I am as eager to use it, Librarian.”

Many of the Blood Ravens present wore helms, but their frowns could still be felt.

“So what do you suggest, Inquisitor?” Gabriel spoke up, looming in his terminator armor. “The people of Meridian have suffered from the daemon’s machinations, as well as those that would ally themselves with it before, but they have resisted it as well.”

Toth’s gaze shifted towards his one-time ally, his grimace disappearing as his expression became unreadable.

“That is not your judgement to make, but the Inquisition's,” he said ominously, ignoring how the Blood Ravens shifted about at his word. “However,” he exhaled sharply through his nose, “It has not reached such a point, merely affecting the lowest of menials. The Ordo Malleus shall remain within the Subsector to see what may or must be done, and shall continue to combat the daemons’ influence.”

He folded his arms behind his back once more, having forgone bearing weapons beyond the plasma pistol on his belt.

“However, this will not last forever, Blood Ravens. This daemon is slowly regaining strength, and I do not doubt that we shall face it again, sooner than we would like.”

Sooner, of course, being any time whatsoever. A Greater Daemon, even at its weakest, was one of the deadliest threats in the entire galaxy.

“When we must face Ulkair again, can we count on the Ordo Malleus to aid us?” Gabriel asked after the ensuing silence.

Toth snorted.

“We shall see what aid may come,” he said with a shrug before a curious look came upon his face. It passed so quickly that Gabriel was not even entirely sure that he’d seen it. “For now, I shall leave a number of my Interrogators within the Subsector to continue the fight. I am called elsewhere.”

Gabriel blinked his remaining biological eye. It was a remarkable allotment of effort at all, though he doubted that the actual number of Interrogators, strength of their retinues, or the like would ever be offered. On the other hand, it was a confirmed Greater Daemon, and as such the Ordo Malleus would likely take no chances. There was definite worry that Meridian might have been consigned to the fire, but so long as its people openly resisted such things hopefully the fires of Exterminatus would not reach them. Derosa as well seemed more than able enough as a Governor, and it would be a shame for the Imperium to be deprived of her services.

“Our thanks to the Inquisition then, for aiding us in this matter.”

Toth narrowed his eyes and sniffed.

“A daemon such as this cannot, will not, be ignored. But should its influence grow too strong…,” he trailed off.

Gabriel just nodded. The warning was received.

“As an aside, I have heard that you may have found Vandis,” Toth noted with alarming casualness. “Good luck, but beware. If he so easily aligned his troops with the Black Legion in the past, he may have significant force to bear.”

“How did…,” Apollo spoke up, startled.

“Christina spread her net far and wide,” Toth looked at him with eyebrows still raised. “Your actions against the Suysh earned you that much from her. Die well, Blood Ravens,” he then began marching away into his waiting dropship.

The Grey Knights followed after him, but not before a long searching look at the Blood Ravens.

“That went about as well as could be expected,” Captain Cyrus noted after the ship had left.

“I disagree,” Justinius shook his head, “His tidings were dire enough. Though we do have a rare thing which may be of use to us.”

“Oh?” The sardonic Captain of the 10th Company looked up at the slightly taller Chief Librarian. “A blade hanging over our heads to push us on?”

“No,” Justinius frowned down at him before looking back out at the void beyond the shielding of the docking bay. “Time. We know that Ulkair is attempting to regain his strength, to escape Aurelia. We have warning, this time, we know where and how, just not precisely when.”

“I agree with Justinus,” Gabriel nodded. “Rare is it that we can prepare for a daemon’s machinations, rather than desperately pursue them after they have already begun the final stages of their infernal plans.”

Cyrus just looked between the two, almost repulsed by their hope and determination.

“If you say so,” he huffed before peeling away and heading towards the thunderhawk that would transport him back to the fleet of the 10th Company.

“Cyrus!” Gabriel called after him, causing the marine to turn about slightly. “Razor Squad’s members are being promoted, Sergeant Ankit asks that we send him replacements.”

“I’ll have them picked out by the end of the day, Chapter Master. By your leave?”

Gabriel nodded.

Both knew that Razor Squad’s efforts on Meridian had already been of great use in combatting the slowly growing numbers of cultists there. What had begun as a point of prestige for Derosa had become a significant boon to the Governor’s efforts to protect her planet. There was no chance of the Blood Ravens recalling Razor Squad, not when their work had abruptly become that much more important to keep the opinion of the Ordo Malleus away from turning to their most exacting and permanent of solutions.

Razor Squad’s Scouts Promoted, +9 Battle Brothers Awaiting Assignment to total, now 44. 9 Scouts 2nd Stage seconded to Razor Squad, now 121 2nd Stage Scouts in 10th Company. 3 Techmarines Returned From Mars, Having Completed Training. Ordo Malleus remains with Subsector Aurelia, Grey Knight going to attempt something to help reinforce Aurelia seals of Ulkair, unknown numbers of Interrogators now in Subsector tracking and suppressing Ulkair influence.

========================================================

“In the end,” Macharius winces as Chief Apothecary Nero stabs him particularly hard with a needle full of revitalizing chemicals before he folded the skin and flesh back in place to begin stitching. “Obasi proved himself a most able combatant.”

“So it seems,” Gabriel chuckled as he looked down at his wounded Brother-Captain.

It was not an unexpected result, in the end. Unable to decide, Macharius Sicarius had elected to pull his entire depleted company into a tournament, both to forge stronger bonds of brotherhood after their casualties in the fighting as well as to declare a Chapter Champion. Also unexpected was that both Brother Jordis and Brother Obasi had proven themselves again, both being the final duelists in the tournament. It was a close thing between the two, going by the pict-recordings, but in the end, Obasi had triumphed and was faced with the final fight of the night against his Captain. Despite being exhausted and wounded by his fight with Jordis, Obasi had managed to defeat Macharius as well. A heady feat.

“Brother Jordis was wholly amicable about his loss as well,” Macharius continued, jolting slightly as Nero’s injectors finished their work.

Some days, it seemed like the Chief Apothecary’s manner had grown even more taciturn than before. It made it only the more jarring that he was barely past a century in age, yet still cowed marines many centuries his elder.

“Oh?”

“Aye, Chapter Master. If he continues on as he is, I’d even consider him as a possible captain,” Macharius winced as he stood up from the bed, rolling his shoulders as he did so. “He is a superb fighter, yes, but I find that his true skill is in leadership.”

“Oh?” Gabriel tilted his head. “Truly?”

“Truly,” Macharius nodded as the two began walking out of the apothecarium, “He is mentor not only to his squad, but to younger sergeants as well. When Cyrus wishes to throw his scouts against more seasoned marines to blunt their pride, Jordis is one of those most often on tap…usually because he helps pick them back up and instruct them on why they failed.”

Gabriel could not help the smile at that, for such genuine brotherhood was a welcome balm to the still bleeding wounds in the Chapter’s heart.

“Chief Apothecary!” A desperate cry came from down the hallway, and both Gabriel and Captain Macharius stood aside as a bevy of Chaplains came rushing down the hallway, carrying a groaning Hannibal Palrun on their shoulders as a still living reliquary. “Help! We were training and Master Palrun was-,”

A noise of tearing metal interrupted them, and both Chapter Master and Captain both glanced back into the apothecarium. Nero had torn a metal tray apart in his hands, medical tools on it scattered onto the floor, leaving the fragments on the ground. The young chief apothecary’s hands clutched at the frame of one of the beds in the room, the faintest noise of stressed metal audible as his grip ground into them. The chaplains, somehow, did not seem to notice as they almost threw Hannibal into the bed that Nero was grasping.

“I’m fine,” the profusely bleeding Hannibal protested, “The gravitic field only vaporized some of my-,”

Whatever else he had to say was cut off as the doors to the apothecarium closed.

Gabriel and Macharius shared a look before simultaneously nodding and splitting apart to go their separate ways.

2nd Company Champion Selected By Macharius (and rolls): Brother Obasi

=======================================================

“Brother-Captain Tarkus,” Gabriel greeted warmly. “We are glad to see you return safely.”

Tarkus saluted before relaxing and nodding with a grin.

“It is good to be back amongst our brothers once more, Chapter Master Angelos,” he replied.

Around him, the rest of the 5th Company was busy receiving similarly cheerful greetings from many fellow battle brothers. Tarkus had detached from the mass and headed straight towards his peers in the Chapter, but none would gainsay the fellowship and bonds of brotherhood on display behind him. The bolters of the 5th Company had been sorely missed against the Suysh, but had certainly still seen use. Just as all had suspected, the Eldar had come to Zerann to try and stop the Mechanicus from their study efforts. It was unfortunate that they had run directly into a prepared defense force, and despite apparently incredibly effective psychic massing, harlequins, cloaked infiltrators, and a significant fleet of corsairs and the like, the Eldar had nevertheless been defeated. The 5th Company would fight alongside the forces of the Imperial Navy and Mechanicus in the defense, but Tarkus himself would accomplish a significant deed himself. Past experiences against the Eldar served him well, and so it was he who saved the life of Fabricator-General Phokas, the ruler of Zerann, when communications were temporarily severed during the battle to Phokas’ flagship. Rather than accepting it as a momentary failure from battle damage, as many tech priests asserted, Tarkus and his command squad teleported aboard the vessel to fight off an assassination squad which had nearly slain the Fabricator-General. Doing so could have thrown the Forge World into chaos, as well as kill the one who had masterminded the study in the first place, whose memory banks stored all which had been discovered and not yet disseminated.

Furthermore, the study had been deemed a success. Long had the holo-fields of the xenos confounded Imperial auspex systems and the like, but according to the tech priests of Zerann their study would improve targeting against Eldar vessels by a statistically significant amount. In the future, it might well be the Eldar who would be shocked and surprised as their vaunted defense systems were defeated by the Omnissiah’s blessings. Though it would be quite some time for such improvements to be rolled out across the Imperium, if ever going by conservative tech priests might see it as blasphemy to alter their systems too significantly, the ships of Zerann were not so confined. Neither would the ships of the 5th Company either, as it turned out, no the rest of the Blood Ravens. With the secrets of Zerann’s study completed, they had seen fit to give those secrets over to the Blood Ravens to utilize should they come up against Eldar ships ever again in the future.

Yet that was a reward for helping protect the study and planet as a matter of course. For saving the life of the Fabricator-General of Zerann, the primary Forge World of the entire Sector, there was another.

Said reward was visible through the docking bay shielding, accompanying the fleet of the rest of the 5th Company.

“So…,” Gabriel led, eyes upon it.

Tarkus cleared his throat as he turned to regard it as well.

“Ah, yes,” he nodded. “The Fabricator-General said that we should be the ones to give it its name.”

The new strike cruiser almost seemed to gleam in the light of the stars.

Eldar Ship Study Complete! Eldar attack on Zerann successfully defended against, 5th Company significantly aided in defense. Tarkus personally saves Fabricator-General Phokas.
Immediate Results:
- Improved targeting against Eldar holo-field defenses.
- Improved relations with Imperial Navy of Korianis Sector/Phokas/Basilikon Astra
- For saving his life, Phokas gives a reward: +1 Strike Cruiser to 5th Company Fleet (Unnamed) with full Thunderhawk Compliment and upgraded Forge i.e. +75 BP/Turn.
- 5th Company no longer assigned to Zerann Guarding Effort. 5 5th Company become Veterans.

=======================================================

The ships arrived without fanfare, but immense gravity. Rare were the ships that were dedicated solely to the use of the Astra Telepathica, none were without great importance. Escorted by five separate Lunar-class cruisers, the transport ship at the center of the formation burned with psychic light that even the lexicani could see from within the Librarium. The reply from the Astra Telepathica had been curt, and carried with it something implicit. A demand, in fact, one writ in blood by one of the most powerful living Imperials in the entire galaxy, whose authority was utterly undeniable. The pacts sworn between the Blood Ravens and the Astra Telepathica were written and signed long ago, long before the current Master or any current living Blood Ravens had been in service. Yet both were compelled by that ancient compact. What was granted to the Blood Ravens, delivered by a dour and immensely powerful Alpha Psyker, was valuable enough, of course.

Eleven young subjects, precisely at the perfect age for implantation, had been given over. Genetically pure and utterly compatible with the gene-seed of the Blood Ravens, all of whom were noted for their likely future psychic potency. Minds scrubbed so thoroughly as to be empty vessels ready to be Blood Ravens in every aspect, every form, of their existence. Likely meant to be seconded to other, more prominent chapters or other services throughout the Imperium, but instead given over to a barely living Chapter. This had, evidently enough, irked the current Master of the Adeptus Astra Telepathica, enough that the delivery had come with a writ, a wafer of psycho-reactive material that broadcast his words into the minds of those who held it. There was a price for their request, though obviously there would have to be one in any case. One did not simply make a demand of a High Lord, no matter what.

The service in question was unspecified, for now, but it would hang over the heads of the Blood Ravens for some time yet.

Time would tell if it was worth it.

- Due To Omake, 11 Extremely High Quality Psyker Aspirants Ready For Immediate Implantation To Become Lexicani in the Librarium. It is assured that they will prove quite capable should they survive the implantation process and further psychic studies.
- Asking the Astra Telepathica for recruits has a price! One Unshakeable, Unavoidable Favor For the Astra Telepathica Logged!

=======================================================

In a void between solar systems, yet still within the light of the Astronomicon, the Omnis Arcanum waited patiently. Opposite to them, a squadron of cruisers bearing the symbols of the Inquisition maintained position. A single, if significant, data package was exchanged. No other communication occurred, and the moment the package was confirmed to be received, the ships dipped back into the warp almost immediately on to their next task. The Omnis Arcanum was quick to leave as well, heading towards Subsector Aurelia where much of the Chapter still remained. As it went, the leadership of the Blood Ravens assembled in an auxiliary tactical room connected to the greater strategium. Here, powerful cogitators assembled reports deemed worthy of being seen by the Chapter Master and his Captains, information collated from the various bouncing messages that flew from one end of the galaxy to another. The Deathwatch featured prominently, as did their various campaigns. With much of the Imperium’s strength concentrated against the 13th Black Crusade and other such fights of extreme magnitude, the perfidious xenos continued to take advantage.

Yet none of the Blood Ravens focused much upon that, not even the one amongst their number who had once been a part of said Deathwatch.

Instead, they all gazed upon the coordinates and replicated data packages on another matter entirely.

“System 384A,” Gabriel tasted the name even as he marveled at its significance.

“Vandis,” Tarkus growled.

It had been Tarkus who had discovered the stolen relics of the Chapter, amongst them the terminator armor known as the Aegis of Hurios. Alas, that same returned relic was taken by the Honor Guard later on, then destroyed in the fighting of the civil war. All the while, the rage had simmered that such a man would dare hoard such things as trophies.

“Indeed,” Martellus growled as well, his anger at the mistreatment of holy wargear palpable. “According to the information that Inquisitor Tarquindil has given us, this system was deemed extremely low priority for colonization due to the gravitational anomalies that surround it.”

“What sort of anomalies?” Gabriel looked at him.

“Bends in space that appear unnatural, almost as if scarred into the fabric of space-time, possibly by some ancient xenos weapon. In any case, this…gravity reef…,” Martellus continued, fingers tugging at the holo-lith to display the anomalies in question, “Will tear apart any ship that does not maneuver in precisely the right manner to enter it, regardless of what dimension or angle of approach they would otherwise desire.”

A flick of his fingers sent holographic ‘ships’ towards the reef, only for them to be torn to shreds instantaneously.

“It is little wonder that Vandis fled here,” Martellus shook his head, “It is almost impossible to enter, if one does not know the way.”

“And there is a way?” Gabriel questioned further, his voice hard.

“Yes, Chapter Master,” Martellus nodded, shuffling the images about. “Whatever lies within the system, they apparently need certain goods. Enough that a few unscrupulous Chartist captains were willing to brave it, for rather considerable payments going by the Inquisitor’s report.”

“What goods?”

Martellus sighed.

“Luxury goods, as it turned out. High quality grox meat, thousands of gallons of amasec, and the like.”

There was a long, drawn out pause.

“Not fuel? Weapons?” Tarkus asked with a frown as he perused the data. “That means he has enough of those to not require purchasing more.”

“…you mean to tell me that Vandis could have remained completely hidden…if he didn’t wish to indulge in his vices?” Gabriel asked incredulously.

Martellus shrugged.

“I’m sure Thaddeus, if he were here, would have some rant on the Meridian nobility,” he replied before looking back to the data.

Again, a round of exchanged stares, but this time Gabriel kept his reactions internal. He knew that his decision had been controversial, but he also knew that he had done the right thing. At the time. Doubt was a poison, one he was well familiar with by now, but not one that he had grown immune to just yet. But he hadn’t known that the 13th Black Crusade would erupt, nor just how devastating the Blood Raven Civil War would prove to be. Going by the last scattered reports, a good number of loyal Blood Ravens had died out there, another of the few ships the Chapter had thrown into the fire again and again. But no, Gabriel thought to himself, they fought against the forces of Chaos, there was no better test for ones who had wavered.

“As it is, we shall have to travel into Segmentum Obscurus to this isolated system. It lies within the light of the Astronomicon, but outside of Imperial control. The Imperium was forced out of the Sector more than half a millennium ago, and with the fighting on Cadia…,” Martellus trailed off. “Well, suffice to say we can expect little to no local support, and possibly renegades or aliens as a buffer around Vandis’ hideout.”

“Can our ships even fit through those openings?” Hadrian asked to no one in particular as he maneuvered a holographic example of the Omnis towards the gravity reef. “Hmm. Yes. It will be tight though, extremely tight. We cannot move in sheaf, wedge, nor pod formations. It’ll have to be single file.”

A faint wince came from Hadrian even as he pronounced it. It was potentially a death sentence to whatever ships were first in the formation, as they would be running directly into any possible prepared defenses first. Reversing vessels out of the narrow pathways through the gravity reef would be near impossible to do quickly, especially if enemy ships were coming through the front. No massed fire would be possible in any direction. But to do anything otherwise would be an absolute certain death sentence, due to the fact that the gravity could rip any ship out of the warp and then to pieces. Truly, the gravity reef could not be natural, only the result of some impossible weapon or another.

“If so, we shall sweep them aside regardless,” Gabriel declared. “Return to your duties, brothers, study the information we have received. I shall have orders for you all shortly.”

A round of assent came, from Captain to Chief Librarian to Master of Sanctity. Yet as they left, one by one, Tarkus remained behind, leaning his back against the wall.

“Captain Tarkus, did you need something more?” Gabriel asked, causing Tarkus to straighten and give a curt salute.

“Just a thought, Chapter Master,” Tarkus replied, pursing his lips. “Though there might not be any allies waiting for us in Obscurus, we might yet still have some we can bring with us.”

“Oh?”

“Inquisitor Adrastia was already hunting Vandis while Apollo led our efforts against Kyras, she simply did not have the resources of Tarquindil,” Tarkus supplied, watching his Chapter Master’s face for reactions. “Governor Derosa might also have a considerable grudge against Vandis for abandoning her and the Subsector.”

“Hmm,” Gabriel narrowed his eyes in thought. “Perhaps. Adrastia is a friend to me, but I have no way of knowing what forces she could bring to the fore.”

“But she would aid us?”

Gabriel let loose a short laugh.

“Since I have known her, she has never been one to easily give up a target. Though the same could be said of all of the Ordo Hereticus. Still,” he continued to muse, “Vandis is a known traitor and conspirator with the Black Legion. The Ordo Hereticus would likely be interested in pursuing him, especially if they might get information on any other contacts he might still have within the Imperium. On the other hand,” Gabriel tilted his head from side to side, “I was not present for Vandis’ fleeing, but you and Cyrus were. Would she truly be able to aid us?”

“Before…,” Tarkus’ face fell, causing him to inhale deeply before forging on, “A traitor once noted but a single truth I will still acknowledge.”

Both knew that he spoke of none other than Sergeant Avitus, but Gabriel did not begrudge Tarkus for his lacking of giving voice to that name. Gabriel still struggled to even speak Isidor’s name, for few wounds could penetrate so deep and lastingly as a brother’s.

“Speak, Tarkus.”

“He said that Elena Derosa should not have been a mere adjutant or adept within the Administratum, but a Sister of Battle. We might also consider speaking to the Order of the Lost Rosetta, as well, for they might welcome the chance to put Vandis to the pyre.”

Gabriel stared at Tarkus.

Vandis had stolen from the Chapter, which should have made him the sole issue of the Blood Ravens, but of course things were not so simple. As a heretic who aided the Black Legion, as a traitorous and failure of a Governor of Meridian, Vandis had made himself an enemy of far more than just Gabriel’s Chapter. There was nothing that required they call upon others, however, nothing at all. No guarantee that aid would be give even if there was a request. It burned at the very pride of a space marine to even consider such a thing, to grovel, but even that was perhaps a trap of the mind itself. For the Blood Ravens had been made humble not by Ulkair, nor by Araghast, or even the daemon Ulkair, but by one of their very own.

“Very well. I shall consider your words.”

And consider them he would, along with a great many other things.

Lead The Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Assign Unassigned Battle Brothers (44) To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment)
[] Assign Veterans To 1st Company If Desired (Write-In, If Desired, Not Required)
[] Assign Epistolaries to Companies (Write-In Which Epistolary To Which Company)
[] Assign New Fleet Additions (Write-In Fleet Assignments For Acquired Frigates/Destroyers/Gunships) [IF ANY AVAILABLE]
[] Name New Unnamed Strike Cruiser (Write-In Name)
[] The Hunt For Vandis: Ex-Governor Vandis is a known heretic, having betrayed Meridian to Chaos long before he surrendered it so easily to the tyranids. He was a thief of Chapter Relics, including terminator armor, and a coward besides. His forces bore the colors of none other than the Black Legion, aiding Araghast the Pillager. He fled towards Segmentum Obscurus, to a system that was on no coordinates known to any of the Navigator Houses. Yet the long arm of the Inquisition is quite capable at discovering that which wishes to remain hidden. A series of unique stellar phenomena prevents the system from being approached by most any conventional travel except for a small handful of ‘stable’ routes. Attempting to do otherwise would result in the fleets being torn apart by the gravitational anomalies. Scans indicate the presence of a solar system of some sort, but little else could be specifically told. House Vandis proved capable of considerable armament, and likely still retain it. This will not be a simple matter. However, others may yet have grudges against Vandis, others who might be enticed to join the Blood Ravens in finally bringing Vandis to justice. Vandis has had many years to build up his forces and his defenses, and his previous allegiance to the Black Legion cannot be ignored, nor forgotten. This will surely not be an easy fight, one way or another. (Write-In Blood Raven Forces Dedicated To This Act) (ALSO: Write in who you would contact to help you, i.e. Scarlet Lions/Derosa/Adrastia?/ETC. Be thoughtful about this, there are no guarantees.)
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Deathwatch Campaign Offers: The Deathwatch is being entirely overwhelmed. They are desperate for a great many more soldiers than many chapters are willing to give. They are, even, willing to give out targets to whole chapters that a single or grouping of kill-teams cannot normally defeat on their own. These are no mere minor invasions, but great gulfs of foes of extreme issue. It is highly advised that the Chapter focuses their efforts on only one of these potential targets at a time, else risk being similarly overwhelmed as the Deathwatch has been.
-[] The Saharduin Swells: The monstrous Saharduin have pushed further outward from their original holdings due to the arrival of WAAAGH!! Killmash attacking the forces of the Imperium from behind. Dark Eldar were also reported, though details are nearly nonexistent. The Imperial Navy is in full retreat from the area, forced to abandon the dozens of Imperial Regiments deployed onto the Saharduin ocean worlds due to the destruction of too many transport ships. The Imperial Navy is hoping to rebuild their ships and crew compliments for enacting a new offense within five to ten years. Brave scouts have reported that WAAAAGH!! Killmash is just as eager to fight the Saharduin as the Imperium, and both races have begun fighting each other without any clear advantage.
-[] The Odaken Herd: A new race, quadrupedal, heavily furred, with fully articulated ‘hands’ on each limb. Each is the average size of an ogyrn, and they bear strangely advanced terraforming tech – or at least Odakenning tech. They prefer ice worlds, subsisting on alien consumables and some form of symbiotic algae that grows upon their bodies. The arrival of the Order of the Lost Rosetta pushed them back from all Imperial worlds taken so far, the Sisters of Battle bringing much flame to the cold. The Odaken home system has been located around a slowly dying yellow star, which will erupt in only a century. The Sisters of Battle have sworn to burn every world of the alien to ash before their sun can and have already made considerable progress on that oath.
-[] The Kra Empire: The Kra are a new alien race invading the Imperium in Segmentum Ultima noted for their admittedly advanced technological arsenal on par with the Imperium’s own. Quadrupedal with a humanoid four-armed torso, the Kra have been noted to favor las weaponry developed in an oddly primitive design aesthetic, such as the las-bow. Subsector Tulmis has already fallen, with the rest of Larsa Sector under threat. The Adeptus Mechanicus has responded in extreme force due to the xeno occupation of Forge World Amasca; three separate Mechanicus Fleets carrying full complements of Skitarii as well as the titan legions Legio Vindicatia and Legio Mortidan have thus far entered Larsa and Tulmis.
-[] Hive Fleet Kraken Splinter Invasion: The Helba Sector is under threat from a Splinter Fleet from Hive Fleet Kraken. The tyranid invasion is currently focused upon the Mede Subsector, where the members of the space marines known as the Ebon Claws are currently attempting to fight them off. The Raven Guard successors have been noted by the Deathwatch to have become severely deleted after losing companies sent to the 13th Black Crusade, the War on Armageddon, and the current fighting going on in Ultramar. If they lose their homeworld of Frigandus Cordis, located in the Mede Subsector, their Chapter will surely go extinct. With the demands on resources for fighting elsewhere being so high, it is unlikely they will receive any regular reinforcement from the rest of the Imperium for at least another few years.
[] Terminator Exchange: Theodosia is willing to produce some Terminator Armor for you, having gotten those specialized forges and designs online. But she will, one, require a full squad of marines with at least one psyker amongst them to safeguard the area - not that she doesn't trust the defenses and holy blessings of the Omnissiah, she just wants to ensure protection for your own equipment. And the hexagramic wards of the Blood Ravens should be especially valuable. Second, for each set of five terminator suits you desire built, she will require aid in other things, allowing her to free up production systems for what you desire. [1 Squad+Librarian Required To Help Oversee Production Whenever Selected. 1 Squad Required For Minor Favor Works In Exchange Per 5 Suits]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training For Gabriel
As Apollo's Skill Is No Better, Training Referred To Cyrus For Ballistic Skill, Last Skill To Be Improved Through Training

Ballistic Skill From 4 to 5: 84+??+Cyrus(25)=??/500 <- To Be Rolled

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Only Strength Remains To Be Improved To Return Chapter Average To Pre-Civil War Levels]

[] Select Strength Trainer (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.
- If Ulkair is beginning to rise in power again, much is to be done to prepare for this, whether in numbers, arms, or allies.
- The Deathwatch seem desperate indeed, willing to take scouts, veterans, or even tomb-brothers, should they be sent to them.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest At Start Of Next Turn. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use. [Possess 557 Total Gene-Seed]
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (191 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (13 Total) with Gene-Seed.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.
- We have more than enough Gene-Seed, I do not think that we require more Test-Slave implantations at this point.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (Choose 1):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] The Raven's Talons: Justinius believes that it should be possible to craft weapons that would be highly effective against daemons and the malefic powers of the Warp itself, as Godsplitter is. With five usable shards taken from Wailing Doom of the Unknown Craftworld's Avatar of Khaine from Typhon Primaris, he believes he could make similar weapons. Whether another daemonhammer, a blade, axe, maul, or spear, he thinks it possible. [100 BP Per Raven Talon, Powerful Anti-Daemon Power Weapons, x4 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Weapon. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] The Raven Aegis: The powers of the Warp and the daemons of Chaos are things that you know for a fact the Blood Ravens will face in the future. Creating talismans which would protect against such things would be incredibly valuable indeed. Justinius' successful efforts at using the materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine from Craftworld Ulthwé has made him believe it possible to create such things. [50 BP Per Raven Aegis, Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection Talisman. x6 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Talisman. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] Something Else Entirely - (Write-In)

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.
- If Ulkair is rattling his cage, we need more Librarians, and better weapons to wield against his ilk. Please, Chapter Master, I implore you to seek for ways to increase our numbers.
- The Astra Telepathica are loathe to send us any more recruits so soon, especially given their quality. I would not risk their ire by asking again so quickly, Chapter Master.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (775 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Howling Hatred [0/750] to receive an additional +25 BP/Turn
-[] The Rage of Erudition [0/750] to receive an additional +25 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Ships (Current/Former)
- [] The Ravenous Spirit [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Spiraling Fury [13/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Burning Seeker [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The The Great Father's Fist [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Legacy of Polonius [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [200/????]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- We should probably build more Tarantula turrets.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, to increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We have proven, now, our techmarine cadre to have the ability to properly construct the forges on our ships. We should continue this practice, for the Chapter is dangerously under-equipped compared to the strength it once possessed before the Purge.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Have we considered building more Tarantula turrets? Deploying them to aid our forces in upcoming fighting would be most valuable indeed, all things considered.
- Our Chapter will remain low in number for quite some time yet. I believe that one of the best ways to alleviate such issues is the noble Tarantula turret.
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon All Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.
- The Deathwatch would not ask so desperately if it were not needed. We could, conceivably, send scout marines to them. A number of these scouts would die, but they would die doing the Emperor's work. Those that survive would return with a vast amount of experience as well.

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Two)

Spoiler: Plan Split the Party+Immediate Result Stuff

[] Plan Split the Party
-[] Assign Unassigned Battle Brothers (44) To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment) [] Assign Unassigned Battle Brothers (44) To Companies (2nd Company 22 , 4th company 22 )
-[] Assign Epistolary Lucan to 1st Company
-[] Assign Epistolary Flekton to 2nd Company
-[] Assign Epistolary Rasmus to Honour Guard
-[] Assign 6 Thunderhawks to 10th Company’s Faith’s Horizon (6 Transporters)
-[] Assign 6 Thunderhawks to 2nd Company’s Unnamed Strike Cruiser/Blood and Iron (6 Gunships)
-[] Assign 6 Thunderhawks to 4th Company’s Burning Seeker (3 Gunships, 3 Transporters)
-[] Assign 6 Thunderhawks to 5th Company’s Great Father’s Fist (3 Gunships, 3 Transporters)
-[] Assign 8 Thunderhawks to 8th Company’s Rage of Erudition (8 Gunships)
-[] Name New Unnamed Strike Cruiser Blood and Iron
-[] The Hunt For Vandis: 2 Squads of 1st Company in Terminator Plate led by Chapter Master Gabriel, Honor Guard, Justinius and Apollo. Take 5th Company and fleet along with the Spiraling Fury and 2 escorts (x1 Gladius Frigate and x1 Hunter Destroyer) from 1st Company Fleet. Call in Derosa/Adrastia/Mechanicus if available. Use Minor Favor on Adrastia. Use Major Favor on Mechanicus.
-[] Hive Fleet Kraken Splinter Invasion: Assign Remainder of 1st Company, 2nd, 4th, and 10 Company
-[] Select Strength Trainer (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Apollo
-[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (191 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (13 Total) with Gene-Seed.
-[] Use 191 Total Gene-seed. 191 for Normal. 13 for Psyker.
-[] (Write-in Option) Study Gene-Seed
- [] The Raven Aegis: The powers of the Warp and the daemons of Chaos are things that you know for a fact the Blood Ravens will face in the future. Creating talismans which would protect against such things would be incredibly valuable indeed. Justinius' successful efforts at using the materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine from Craftworld Ulthwé has made him believe it possible to create such things. [50 BP Per Raven Aegis, Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection Talisman. x6 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Talisman. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
-[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Meridian/Junius)
-[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Ravenous Spirit [500/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] Craft Relic Mark VIII 'Errant' Power Armor for Captain Tarkus (25 BP)
-[] Craft Raven's Aegis *NOTED ABOVE* (50 BP)
-[] Craft Psychic Hoods x10 (100 BP)
-[] Craft Force Weapons x6 (90 BP)
-[] Craft Multi-Melta x1 (10 BP)

Forge Work
Improvements and regular crafting completed.
Relic Armor: 1d100-> 95 Great Success!
Raven's Aegis: 1d100->74 Success! +1 Raven's Aegis to Armory (Unassigned)

The Barding of Tarkus: This masterful creation bears the engraved valorous deeds of Captain Tarkus of the Blood Ravens, along with zealous denials of the lies of traitors and madmen. A quirk of its manufacture has somehow further hardened the materials of its make, to the point of conferring greatly improved durability even amongst power armors, while its servos and artificial muscle fibres confer greater strength. Such magnificent armor inspires greater fervor in fellow sons of the Emperor in battle. (+1 Toughness, +1 Strength, Improved Resistance Against Anti-Armor Weaponry) Currently Equipped By 5th Company Captain Tarkus

Implantation+Recruitment Notes
Start of Turn Gene-Seed: 557
Implanting: 191 Neophyte [2nd Stage] / 2 Psyker [2nd Stage] / 11 Telepathica Recruits [2nd Stage]
Advancements: 191 Neophyte [2nd Stage] -> 185 Scouts [1st Stage] / 2 Psyker [2nd Stage] -> 0 Lexicanum / 11 Telepathica Recruits [2nd Stage] -> 11 Lexicanum*
Failures: 6 Neophyte [2nd Stage] / 2 Psyker [2nd Stage]

Meridian*+Junius: 700 Aspirants Recruited [600/100 Split In Recruits]
*Captain Cyrus exercised authority as Master of Recruits, elaborated upon in update.

Training Notes
Strength Training: 369+80+Apollo(30)=479/500
Ballistic Skill From 4 to 5: 84+55+Cyrus(25)=164/500

Armory Notes
775 Available:
- The Ravenous Spirit [500/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn [New Total/Turn = 825!]
- Ravens Aegis Creation: 73/100 Success! 1 Raven’s Aegis Created [50 BP]
- Craft Relic Mark VIII 'Errant' Power Armor for Captain Tarkus (25 BP) [Rolling Attempt Below]
- Craft Psychic Hoods x10 (100 BP)
- Craft Force Weapons x6 (90 BP) Unspecified, But Made Swords
- Craft Multi-Melta x1 (10 BP)

The Hunt For Vandis:
Ground Troops
Specialized Detachment: 20 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chapter Master Gabriel, Honor Guard, Chief Librarian Justinius, Apollo.
5th Company: All
Fleet Elements
1st Company: SC Spiraling Fury + 2 Escorts (1 Gladius/1 Hunter Destroyer)
5th Company: BB Litany of Fury + SC Rage of Erudition + SC The Great Father’s Fist + 7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)
Favors Used
Minor Favor – Adrastia
Major Favor – Mechanicus

Hive Fleet Kraken Splinter Invasion:
Ground Troops
1st Company: 22 1st Company Marines (20 TH Capable)
2nd Company: All
4th Company: All
10th Company: All

Fleet Elements
1st Company: BB Omnis Arcanum + 4 Escorts (2 Gladius, 1 Hunter Destroyer, 1 Nova)
2nd Company: SC The Howling Hatred + SC Ravenous Spirit + SC Blood and Iron + 6 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyer, x1 Nova
4th Company: BB Scientia Est Potentia + SC Burning Seeker + SC Legacy of Polonius + 6 Escorts (x2 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyer, x2 Nova)
10th Company: SC Faith’s Horizon + 3 Escorts (x2 Gladius, x1 Nova)

GM Note: Check spoilers above for forged stuff, recruitment, detachment information, and more. Voting Moratorium For 12 Hours.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

The Fabricator-General was, as it turned out, more than eager to quickly excise what leverage the Blood Ravens could hold over him. To assail a purveyor of Chaos, a known thief and heretic, was pious work besides. As such, when the call came through, and a discussion of the unknown capabilities and status of the system within was had, Zerann made use of their copious shipyards. To lose even a single one of the remaining venerable ships of the Blood Ravens, especially the newly christened Blood and Iron, would of course certainly offend those who worshipped the Omnissiah. After all, the vast majority of the ships helmed by the Blood Ravens and their serfs had been built there. Much as Mars and other worlds with the correct patterns and constructor manufactorums mourned each death of the legendary Baneblades, so too did Zerann mourn the death of the ships they crafted. Out on the Eastern Fringe, every ship was a vital lifeline to the rest of the Imperium, the rest of the galaxy. Or, at least, every Imperial ship was. Other vessels of the vile xeno races were abominations before the Omnissiah’s holy gaze, that they existed at all an insult to the cult of the machine and pursuers of the Motive Force.

Yet, even such vile mockeries of more…pure…interpretations of technology could have their uses.

As such, Phokas delivered unto the Blood Ravens what they had already given to the Mechanicus.

“I recognize those profiles, or at least some of them,” Martellus mused, the Master of the Forge having come up to witness the delivery of the Mechanicus.

“Me too,” Tarkus nodded as he leaned against the projector of the various holographic pict-screens that rotated through the air. “They look like portions of the Judgement of Carrion.”

“Indeed,” the Magos at the head of the delivering Mechanicus fleet nodded, the image flickering slightly as they did so.

Identifying themselves only as Trigan-Delta-14, it was clear that they had been a member of the Mechanicus for quite some time, centuries at the least. Not a hint of their skin or flesh remained visible, and when they shifted their weight it was far more heavy than the shape and size would imply. But of course all was hidden beneath their crimson and bronze robes. Their voice remained flat, completely without emotion, with the occasional flickers of binary emitting from the attendant servo skulls floating by their shoulders that were incomprehensible to all but the Techmarines. But far more important were the various metallic carcasses that they had towed with them from Zerann.

“The space hulk has been fully disassembled, tainted and accursed monolith that it was, with the true gifts of the Omnissiah extracted from within and falsehoods removed,” TD14 announced. “The Fabricator-General has seen fit to use that which was impure as pyres that may redeem their misbegotten existences.”

With that said, the dozen cobbled together craft ignited their engines and pushed across the intervening space between the fleets of the Mechanicus and the Blood Ravens from the former towards the latter. None were of human origin, which only made sense. No doubt whatever reclaimable ships of the now recycled Judgement of Carrion that could be, had been. That which remained were only vile alien vessels and technologies, which were offenses to the Adeptus Mechanicus. None of them were greenskin ships, as those were better used as the scrap they were as fuel for the foundries, but the exact origins of many were unknowable entirely. Perhaps the races that they had come from no longer existed, or hadn’t yet. Such was the nature of the Warp and a space hulk which spent unknowable eons within it between its bursts into the Materium. But nevertheless, the technological mastery of the frontiersmen tech priests of Zerann had managed to get them to work, at least enough for their purposes. Even cursory scans showed the reduced structural integrity of the ships, as well as several notable and easily identifiable items which were packed to the brim. Radiological and chemical warnings burst into being on the pict-screen.

“Fire ships?” Gabriel asked, raising an eyebrow.

“Affirmative, Chapter Master Angelos,” TD14 nodded. “Most are supplied with standard plasma bombs and incendiaries, as per the concepts devised in the Gothic War and past conflicts. Precise cutting methods should ensure that the destruction of their hulls provides further destruction.”

They’ve made a dozen escort ship sized fragmentation explosives.

“You said most,” Martellus spoke up, touching the haptic interface to center the pict-screen’s tactical display on to a trio of ships in particular, cruisers to their peer’s escort tonnages. “But the scans on these have different results than the others. Not to mention the obvious differences in weight and size.”

“…Affirmative,” TD14 nodded again after a short pause. “These ships bear…newly revised explosives based upon the principles of certain forms of Nova Cannon armament and the graviton weaponry recently recovered by Forgeworld Aerus.”

“Gravity-based Nova Cannon warheads,” Martellus summarized before turning to Gabriel. “These should prove…particularly potent, Chapter Master.”

The fact that Forgeworld Zerann was clearly using the grudge of the Blood Ravens against Vandis to test out not-quite-experimental weaponry was not mentioned. It was both obvious and accepted as a matter of course. The three ships carried extremely powerful explosives indeed. They would have to be rationed, if used at all.

“The ex-Governor was not an amicable ally to the Forgeworlds,” TD14 let loose what sounded like a guttural set of grinding gears that Gabriel took a moment to realize was the equivalent of a sniff. “He presumed his ownership over the holy Angel Forge granted him insight into the Omnissiah that he did not have.”

The Magos leaned in, the red and green glow of their cybernetic ocular replacements intensifying slightly.

“It is the hope of Zerann that the Blood Ravens shall prove lasting and significant chastisement.”

“And command of these ship is accomplished…?” Martellus spoke up again.

“With slaved servitor crews,” TD14 leaned back, “The command codes have been transferred to you. They can only follow the most simplistic of commands, but should serve their purposes well enough.”

Shortly afterwards, the ships of the Mechanicus departed, leaving their gifts behind and favor fulfilled. Ordinarily, twelve ships, would be a tremendous investment of effort and work for Zerann. But that would have been for vessels meant for centuries or longer of work. Fire ships were suicide vessels, designed and prepared solely for immediate destruction by way of striking other targets and detonating. The Blood Ravens were, effectively, providing trash disposal and testing new weaponry for the Mechanicus. But Gabriel could easily see their value. Even if not ships of the line, such ships could at the very least provide a screen for more valuable vessels when penetrating the gravity reefs surrounding Vandis’ stronghold. The destruction of defenses or enemy ships if any as well.

Mechanicus Major Favor Utilized: 12 Fire Ships Received, 9 Standard/3 Experimental. Standard Fire Ships are capable of instantly destroying escorts and heavily damaging or even crippling capital ships if successful enough on their detonations. The experimental Fire Ships provided utilize Graviton/Nova Cannon technologies and are cruisers in tonnage compared to the escort tonnage standards. Experimentals are deemed likely to be either completely useless or startlingly potent.

=============================================

“Inquisitor Adrastia,” Gabriel greeted as he loomed over the Inquisitor in question.

“Gabriel,” Adrastia returned with something approaching a smile on her severe face.

It had been a considerable amount of time, all things considered, for those who were not enhanced as the Emperor’s Angels of Death, since Inquisitor Adrastia had last come to Subsector Aurelia. Were it not for the loyalists of the Blood Ravens, it might have been a fatal last time. Yet, at the same time, it had been Adrastia’s power as an Inquisitor which had halted the Exterminatus fleet from destroying Calderis and Meridian. Here, now, she stood within the docking bay of the Litany of Fury with her hands on her armor-clad hips. Behind her was her retinue, made up of a distracted looking Tech-Priest who was busy looking over a plasma gun in their mechadendrites, a Sister of Battle clearly of the Orders Hospitaller that watched them warily, a twitching man with a band of crackling metal over empty eye-sockets and a staff, and a rather familiar man dressed in the manner of an Inquisitorial Storm Trooper.

“Colonel Merrick,” Apollo tilted his chin upwards slightly at the man. “I’d heard you were missing in action.”

“Heh, got found, my lord,” the weathered veteran of the 85th Vendoland grinned back before it slipped into a melancholic frown. “For all the good it did my boys and girls.”

“You have my sympathies, colonel,” Gabriel bowed his head.

The Hrud had seen to the disgraceful end of the 85th Vendoland, years ago. Proud soldiers of the Imperium aged into uselessness, dying in hospice from various age-related difficulties rather than in battle. By now, Colonel Merrick was surely the last of regiment’s old incarnation, as by now the 85th had likely been reconstituted anew. That he stood before the Blood Ravens once more, still appearing as only a middle aged mortal human man despite battling those same Hrud? Was no doubt the result of advanced rejuvenat treatment as befitting a valuable servant of the Inquisition.

“…appreciate it my lord,” he said, holding in well-worn grief with remarkable stoicism.

“Still,” Gabriel then looked back at Adrastia, “I was not…expecting you to come in person.”

“Vandis is a known heretic, as is House Vandis,” Adrastia replied crisply, “They purged their records when they fled Meridian to cover their tracks. Marcus Vandis may be the only connection to other possible heretics spread throughout the Sector and beyond, for we know well enough he had many associate spread throughout the Imperium and beyond.”

The Inquisitor crossed her arms over her chest, one eyebrow raised beneath her hat.

“As such, we will be taking him alive if at all possible.”

There was a sudden stilling amongst the Blood Ravens within the hangar, for now as ever there was a spark of pride in them that burned when ordered by those not their own. Worse, the former Governor was a thief and coward who had dared to take of the Blood Ravens, and as such deserved only a swift death. Tarkus, of them all, visible bristled in his armor. It had been he who had been forced into the warehouse by the greenskins when left to guard it, who had witnessed the revolting trophies within that had terminator armor as pride of place.

But as Gabriel nodded, the tension was choked out of existence by his assent.

“If at all possible, Inquisitor.”

The aid of the Inquisition could be a great boon, their resources and reach often remarkable, yet even that could not be gained without a considerable price. Besides which, Gabriel actually agreed with her. If Vandis had not become some sort of monstrosity or creature otherwise incapable of proper interrogation, then the efforts of the Inquisition could surely extract much valuable information to use against the servants of Chaos. Possibly also even those who had not sworn themselves but remained associates of heretics nonetheless. House Vandis had been startlingly well-connected in the past, and while there had been a great purging of their web of connections, the possibility was strong that others had gone undiscovered.

Another few seconds passed in silence before Adrastia smirked.

“Hopefully we’ll have better success with him than was had with Kyras,” she huffed before turning slightly back towards the Valkyrie that had brought her there and gesturing towards her retinue. “Though you’ve met Merrick,” her lips quirked again, “The rest of my retinue bears introduction.”

Said retinue straightened up slightly at her words, the Tech-Priest placing the gun back within their billowing red robes.

“Enginseer Narchus,” she paused as the Tech-Priest bowed to them before moving on, “Sister Amelia,” the Sister of Battle nodded curtly, “And Savant Militant Tethi,” the psyker twitched a bit more violently at his name.

Gabriel cast his eyes upon them all, though found his vision ever so slightly burning when his gaze alighted squarely on the psyker, the sensation only leaving when his eyes moved on. Their skills were likely beyond doubt, if Adrastia had taken them into her retinue. Then Gabriel looked past them, past their Valkyrie transport, and to the ship beyond. There, hanging in the void, rested a venerable and dangerous looking Vengeance-class Grand Cruiser, whose transponder codes identified it as the Sword of Reckoning. Further auspex scans declared that it had been thoroughly modified, with massively increased armor plating, shielding, and firepower befitting an Avenger-class Grand Cruiser being the most obvious. The Sword of Reckoning, being an Inquisitorial vessel, likely held many more secrets than such outwardly obvious markers. No escort ships had accompanied it, and instead the Grand Cruiser had slipped forth from the warp completely alone.

“You’ve upgraded,” Gabriel then said with a low chuckle. “When we met last, your personal vessel was a Lunar-class.”

“Yes, well,” Adrastia blew some air through her nose sharply, “While I could not capture Kyras alive, my investigation was well-received enough.”

“Course, we also-,” Merrick began to say before Adrastia’s hard eyes landed on him, causing the veteran to snap his jaw shut with a click of teeth.

Adrastia was moving up in the ranks of the Inquisition then, which only made sense. It had been many decades since they had last interacted. One did not survive being an Inquisitor that long without advancing, as the only alternative was quite simply to die or suffer worse fates. No doubt she had done much of the grim work of the Ordo Hereticus in that time. Enough to be granted such a venerable ship, at least.

“As it is, Gabriel, this was all I could bring forth in such a short period of time,” she shrugged. “I do not yet possess more than a single regiment of Inquisitorial Storm Troopers, and they act as my vessel’s void troopers and guards for prisoners,” she then pursed her lips, gazing into the middle distance. “Unfortunately, General Castor is dead, and the Cadian 10th died to a man fighting on Cadia. The Wild Hunt is gone. Cadians across the galaxy are being recalled to their homeworld.”

“It is more than we expected, and any aid at all is appreciated, Inquisitor,” Gabriel inclined his head once more.

“Hmph,” Adrastia shook her head. “Vandis has had almost a century since fleeing Subsector Aurelia to build up his defenses and forces, is known to have willingly collaborated with the Black Legion, and his House who knows how long before that. They could have built up an entire colony or more within the system as a private holdout that they did not have to tithe from,” she looked back up at Gabriel grimly. “And you have only a few more marines than you did when you faced Kyras.”

She very pointedly glanced at the bionics that replaced a considerable portion of Gabriel’s face, the most obvious remnant of his near death at the hands of the daemonic traitorous Chapter Master. A number of the greatest veterans of Gabriel’s forces had died in that climactic fight, many suffering wounds that pushed beyond what the sus-an membrane could manage. Not just battle-brothers, but close friends, who had fought under him even before Cyrene. Jonah Orion among them, who had distinguished himself against the Hive Mind, only for daemons to rend him apart while in suspended animation upon the cracked molten earth.

“Vandis may have allied himself with the dread powers of Chaos, but now he faces Blood Ravens who have survived the crucible. A chapter united, in brotherhood, in loyalty, in purpose. And we are not without our allies this time either.”

Adrastia just raised an eyebrow. She had no doubt seen the waiting Fire Ships when she’d arrived.

“Quite.”

Inquisitorial Forces Added To Vandis Assault Force

=======================================================

“I never thought to see one in person,” Martellus spoke in awe as he stared at the pict-screen, as did everyone else in the strategium.

“I have, in the past, but only rarely,” Gabriel murmured as he leaned forward to more closely examine the small fleet which had emerged into the Materium a short distance away from the Blood Raven ships.

At the center of the new arrivals was the object of the Master of the Forge’s wonder, an increasingly rare pattern of vessel in the Imperium. Its body was weathered and scarred, heavily, a legacy of wounds and wars laid upon its metal hide from thousands of years of service. Yet its reactors still burned strong, its scars cosmetic rather than evidence of major structural damage, and though it bore few weapons at all it was still a massive vessel. The size of it was staggering, which only made sense considering just what it was.

“A Galaxy-class Troop Transport,” Martellus said slowly, shaking his head, eyes wide indeed within his helmet. “That is…remarkable. Each Galaxy-class is capable of hefting four entire regiments of the Imperial Guard, support staff and campaigning supplies included.”

There were other troop transports as well, but all were dwarfed before their ancient cousin. Surrounding them all was the rest of the flotilla. An Emperor-class Battleship sat the forefront, with two smaller Avenger-class Grand Cruisers and a handful of Lunar-class cruisers as well, all with a small cloud of escorts. It was not the mightiest fleet that Gabriel had ever seen in his life as a space marine, but even a single ship could make the difference in times such as these.

“Incoming vox, Chapter Master,” the serf manning the comm station announced. “With vid-cast.”

“Put it through,” Gabriel declared.

Depicted in flickering green by the holo-projector was another familiar face. His upper torso was covered in more medals than the last time that they had met, but other than a few grey streaks upon his head Admiral Graves of Battlefleet Korianis barely seemed to have aged. This time, of course, his pict-cast was not joined by the scowling face of a Sister of Battle to the side.

“Chapter Master Angelos, it seems we have been brought together once more to fight against the enemies of the Emperor,” Graves inclined his head slightly as the connection stabilized.

“Admiral Graves,” Gabriel greeted back, “I am happy to receive the aid of the Imperial Navy once more, though…I certainly was not expecting it. Was the Imperial Navy not preparing to regroup and rebuild to face the Saharduin?”

Graves grimaced, his shoulder slumping slightly before he straightened.

“For the most part, yes, but thankfully my fleet was held in reserve, and thus not committed to that fighting before it all went wrong,” he scowled at the thought of so many destroyed ships and lost crews, before brightening slightly. “But Governor Derosa was able to shake us loose rather than have us sit around for years waiting for the new offensive.”

Gabriel, as well as numerous other Blood Ravens on the bridge, blinked in surprise.

“Governor Derosa?”

“Oh yes,” Graves lifted an eyebrow. “She has been moving heaven and earth to rally against Vandis. One would almost think that she has a grudge against the man. In point of fact…,” he gestured to somewhere off-screen, at which point a brother and sister pair dressed in officer’s uniforms stepped into view. “House Derosa is being represented rather directly.”

“Chapter Master Angelos!” The brother and sister saluted in unison, boots thumping against the earth, before relaxing their stances ever so slightly.

Immediately, Gabriel could tell what Graves had meant. Both of them bore an unmistakable resemblance to none other than Elena Derosa herself. The brother bore a deep scar along his face from forehead to chin, the sister a burst pattern on the left side of her face a clear sign of surviving an explosion at close range. Nor were such scars the cosmetic creations that were often purposefully taken on by certain foolish members of Imperial militaries or nobility to make them appear as veterans or simply as incomprehensible fashion statements. Gabriel could tell, even across the stellar distance, that these were real.

“I am Colonel Gabriel Derosa, Chapter Master,” the brother introduced himself, his voice a clear strident bell, “In command of the 3rd Meridian Consolidated.”

“And I am Colonel Arama Derosa,” the sister spoke in a remarkably gravelly rasp, “In command of the 10th Meridian Consolidated.”

Gabriel very carefully did not wince, nor react openly in any other measure at the very, very obvious legacy behind their names. The name Gabriel was not entirely uncommon, at least upon the planets of Meridian, and once upon Cyrene and Aurelia before those worlds were lost. Arama, however, was a name more common to Calderis, not Meridian at all. More importantly, Gabriel knew exactly how the Colonel of the 10th Meridian had gotten her name, who she was named for, and he earnestly did not wish think any more on it. Aramus had wavered too close to the line, it had to be done!

“You are Governor Derosa’s…,” Gabriel trailed off meaningfully.

“Children,” Arama confirmed with a curt nod. “I assure you, sir, we have served across over a dozen battlefields as part of the Imperial Guard, we are not fresh recruits.”

“The Imperial Guard and House Derosa stands ready to extract vengeance against the traitors of House Vandis,” Colonel Gabriel cleared his throat. “We are prepared to fight and die as necessary.”

“As are we all,” Admiral Graves said calmly, before a motion from him sent the Colonels off-screen once more. “I’m not entirely sure what Governor Derosa promised to Sector Command, but she managed to get my fleet moving and to recall a considerable number of Meridian’s regiments here. I’ll send you the data packet.”

Captain Tarkus, standing nearby, could not help his mind from casting itself backwards to a specific memory. The words of the traitor Avitus, who he had slain, had not all been vile things. Before that fateful day, during the 1st Aurelian Crusade, Tarkus remembered the reactions amongst his fellow battle brothers when they’d learned of just how Elena Derosa had gotten the codes for Angel Forge. She had been nothing more than a foolish and obstructive bureaucrat from a minor noble house of Meridian up until that point. But then she had rallied the PDF of the planet to her side and stormed the manse of House Vandis, literally shooting her way inside with a plasma gun. It had been remarked, then, that she might have better served as a Sister of Battle than a mere Administrator. Though she was now the ruling Governor, Tarkus could see that same spark of ferocity within her bloodline, evident in at least two of her children.

“Very well. Prepare your ships, Admiral. I intend to proceed to 384A as quickly as possible.”

“Lead the way, Blood Raven.”

Imperial Guard and Imperial Navy forces added to Vandis Assault Force.

==============================================================

“Captain Cyrus…is this truly…,”

“It is a cruel galaxy we live in, Sergeant,” Cyrus replied coldly.

Before them, the largest number of recruits ever taken at once in the history of the Blood Ravens were being marshalled up the ramps onto many waiting thunderhawks. Above Meridian, the assembled fleets of the 1st, 2nd, 4th, and 10th Companies waited above. Genetic purity had been determined of course, but charts and scans could only show so much. There was so much more that such scans and test tubes could not yet perfectly determine, such as willpower and the like. By while the standard Blood Trials had begun, by the orders of the Master of Recruits, the only one with such authority, the permanent end of those who failed was forestalled by the apothecaries. Instead, they were being taken up, many who ordinarily simply would not have made the cut given a chance out of desperation. Though some of the Blood Ravens alive today had faced the tyranids of the 1st Aurelian Crusade, none had fought Great Devourer as much as Cyrus Octavius.

And so standards were waived for the simple fact that they would need every pair of hands firing as many weapons as possible as they would get. It was why the armories had been completely emptied, all that was not given over to the Chapter Master and the 5th Company to punish Vandis given over to their own task force. The tyranids assaulting Subsector Mede greatly outnumbered those that had come to the Aurelian Subsector. Plasma guns, missile launchers, sniper rifles, and a truly impressive number of explosives and ammo.

“Most of them will die. But better that they die defending the Imperium from the tyranids than in one of the endless scuffles in the Underhive over rusty scrap metal or drinks of clean water.”

It was cruel, and went against his instincts as steward of the Chapter’s recruits and new blood, but against his centuries of experience in the Deathwatch and personal studies of the 1st Tyrannic War such instincts were easily silenced. In the past, his fellow battle brothers, knowing nothing of the tyranids, had balked at his admission that he would have been willing to let an orkish WAAAGH!! fight freely to stop a splinter fleet. But he was now the Force Commander, no longer just a veteran scout sergeant, but now the Master of Recruits.

“My decision is final,” he eventually said. “It will be a handful of months of travel through the Warp, and in that time they shall undergo intensive hypnotherapy rites. Their training shall be on the battlefields of Mede.”

“…yes, Brother-Captain.”

Captain Cyrus utilized authority as Master of Recruits to lower standards on recruitment in favor of more bodies for combatting tyranids in Mede Subsector.

==============================================

The gravity reefs were distressingly invisible to the naked eye. On the auspex, they showed up quite clearly, warping and twisting about in manners that by all rights should have been impossible according to the laws of physics as they were understood by the Imperium. Yet they remained present nonetheless. As had been stated before, small channels existed of somehow untouched space, or at least comparatively small on a stellar scale. Large enough for battleships and battle barges to move through, at the very least. Large enough for escorts to pass side by side, but not large enough for two cruisers at anything approaching safe distance from one another. Unfortunately, a single winding column was the only possible method of entering the system within.

“Attention all ships,” Gabriel announced onto the fleet-wide vox. “We’re going in.”

Librarius Scrying: 50

Gabriel then turned towards the doors that opened onto the bridge, from which Justinus had just emerged. The Chief Librarian’s body and armor stank of psycho-reactive incense burned in pursuit of scrying rituals within the depths of the Librarium. Condensation dripped from him, as ice that had formed from nothing slowly began to melt. In the depths of the ship, numerous Librarians remained unconscious from the backlash of their ritual, success or no.

“Chapter Master,” Justinius rasped. “I have news.”

“Enlighten me,” Gabriel raised an eyebrow.

“Vandis most definitely has sorcerous defenses,” Justinius wiped his brow, “But we managed as best we could.”

“That is all I could ask of you.”

Spoiler: Ground Assets

Blood Ravens: 2 Squads of 1st Company in Terminator Plate led by Chapter Master Gabriel, Honor Guard, Justinius and Apollo/5th Company
Meridian: 15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) 1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
Inquisition: Inquisitor Adrastia + Retinue of the Ordo Hereticus

Spoiler: Fleet Assets

Blood Ravens: 5th Company Fleet + SC Spiralling Fury + 1 Gladius/1 Hunter Destroyer
Admiral Graves of the Imperial Navy: 1 An Emperor-class Battleship / 2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers / 8 Lunar-class Cruisers as well / 10 Frigates / 20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)
Inquisition: 1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class.
Mechanicus: 9 Fire Ships (Escort Tonnage, Standard Load) / 3 Fire Ships (Cruiser Tonnage, Experimental Gravitic/Nova Explosives)

Approach Method Into System 384A
Note: Gravity reefs mean that ships outside of escort tonnage must proceed single file. Enemy defenses within system unknown. Defensive stations, enemy ships, mines, etc. possible, but potency and numbers if any unknown.
Note: With the bare success of the Librarius in scrying attempts, the following is known: Static defenses present, mobile defenses present. Precise strength unknown. Recommendation, at least 2 fire ships at forefront of formation to take fire, or battle barge, due to expendable nature of former and sheer survivability/toughness of latter. WARNING: Vandis possesses at least moderate sorcerous defenses against psychic scrying/powers.
Note: Unattached Specialists Divided Automatically. Techmarines, Chaplains, and Apothecaries all seconded to Captain Cyrus and Mede Subsector. Master of Sanctity, unvoted on, chooses to join Cyrus. Librarius fully dedicates self to following Chief Librarian Justinius.

[] Write-In Approach Method

EX1: 2 Fire Ships at forefront, Blood Raven ships, then Imperial Navy, then Imperial Troop Transports and rest of Fire Ships.
EX2: Battle Barge at forefront, followed by X # of Fire Ships/Blood Raven Ships/ETC.

Turn 23 Social - 2481

Spoiler: Voting results [*] King Belegar, to try to get some idea of where he's at with his crisis of faith. [*] Algard, reporting the Skaven Civil War in person instead of in writing. [*] Empress 'Heidi', to be present for the birth of her child [*] Princess Edda, on a hunt for weavers across the Empire. [*] Roswita, as she rides out the chaos of the influx of Battle Wizards. A Cleric of Grimnir could be mistaken for a Slayer at a glance, but several things set them apart to those that were familiar with the Dwarves. First, that they had an air of solemn determination instead of a bubbling cauldron of emotions barely contained under a facade of bloodlust that most Slayers possess, and second, that they bear a tattoo of the Rune of Grimnir on their chest, instead of their own personal Runes. In the Hall of Oaths, a silent, solemn gathering watches a Cleric of Grimnir converse quietly with a Dwarf that by his beard can't be older than forty - barely more than a child. The conversation concludes, and in efficient motions, fistfuls of the youth's hair are gripped and sliced off by the razor-sharp handaxe of the Cleric. Tears flow freely down the faces of some of those watching, but though you can see despair, you can also see pride. With his hair hacked down except for a single stripe down the center, the Dwarf will now make the long trip to Karak Kadrin to complete the ceremony that dedicates a Dwarf to the seeking of death in battle. Any Dwarf in the Karaz Ankor would give him food and a night's shelter, and transport if they're going in the direction of the Slayer Keep. It's not necessarily part of the ceremony, as far as you understand. It's more of a symbol of the Oath they intend to take, to show the Clan they think they've dishonoured that they intend to set things right. "There's a concoction of volcanic salammoniac and animal fat," King Belegar says beside you, his voice low enough to not carry to the crowd. "Makes the hair stiff and brittle if you leave it in long enough. Makes this ceremony a minute or two long, rather than a solid fifteen minutes of yanking hair and nicking the scalp. Many a young lad has seen sense and washed it out before they made their way to the local Temple of Grimnir." He lifts his crown and runs a thoughtful hand through his own hair. "Made it once, though I didn't get so far as to put it in, between my father's passing and my first successful raid into... well, into here." "What did he do?" you murmur back, watching the youth. You think you might have seen him a time or two, but even in the smallest and most important Clan in Karak Eight Peaks, you just don't have the time to put a name to every face. "Nothing." He sighs. "Nothing, when he thinks he ought have done something. Battle of Karagril, thinks he didn't step forward fast enough and fix the shieldwall when the Dwarf in front of him fell. Battle of Karag Lhune, he kept his shield raised when he thinks he should have lowered it and swung. Battle of the Eastern Gate, he busied himself dragging to safety a Dwarf he thinks he should have known was dead." You watch the newly-shorn Dwarf embrace who you assume are his parents, accept a freshly-forged axe from a Longbeard you recognize as the Eldest of Clan Angrund, and with a frozen face he walks out of the Hall of Oaths, likely never to return. "Way the Karaz Ankor is, and has been for millennia, every Dwarf must be a warrior, even those least suited to it. He had the deftest hand with a scrimshaw knife I've ever seen, could take a Skaven's fang and engrave into it the name and lineage of the one who slew it. But because he can't face battle, or perhaps because he thinks he's not good enough at facing battle, now he's going to dye his hair orange and get the proper tattoos and when he freezes up in front of a troll, he's going to be eaten. And for all the power of the crown, the most I can do is make sure he'll have easy passage at least as far as Zhufbar." The gathered kin of the now-doomed youth file out of the Hall of Oaths, not one of them casting a single eye your way. King Belegar isn't actually here, not formally. If he was formally here to witness this, properly announced by his Hammerers and acknowledged by the Cleric of Grimnir, it would signify that the youth's shame had been severe enough to shame the entire Kingdom. "Karag Lhune was once a quiet corner of the Karak," he says as the two of you walk out of the now-empty Hall, King Belegar's bodyguard shadowing you as unobtrusively as a fully-armoured Dwarf can be. "Filled with the odds bits-and-pieces that couldn't quite fit in the more-populated Mhonar or Rhyn or Zilfin. Temples, airship docks, the school and apprentice barracks, an overflow vault. Now the entire Dwarven population of Karak Eight Peaks fits into the Chiselwards, and could quadruple before we'd need to start excavating new rooms." You remain silent. If you were honest, you'd have to admit to having had similar thoughts. Only one in four Dwarven children were women, and it was a rare woman that would have more than four children, and she would usually be approaching her hundredth year by the time she does so. That was an awkward fit into a world where greenskins and Skaven and the forces of Chaos and other, more esoteric threats applied a constant attrition. "If I truly cared for the safety and future of my people, I'd have never sought the forces to accomplish this," he says quietly. "Clan Angrund, sure, Clan Angrund never allowed itself to settle down, and would have marched towards extinction if someone didn't find a way to succeed. But the others? The Norgrimlings were comfortable in Zhufbar. Helhein were celebrated in Karak Norn. The Bronzefists had their own mountain in the Vaults - not the biggest mountain, nor the richest, but it was theirs. And a dozen other clans either considering or in the process of uprooting for the home none of their ancestors for three dozen generations has seen. The Karaz Ankor is not hurting for space - the entire lot of us could fit within Karaz-a-Karak these days. So if we don't need the space, and I'm not seeking to expunge Grudges with Dwarven blood, and I'm unable to retake the home of my ancestors without abandoning their ways, what am I accomplishing?" "Karak Azul?" you hazard. He remains silent for a while, and then exhales. "It's true. Their reconnection to the Karaz Ankor might not be possible any other way. But I find it difficult to find satisfaction in their Karak when my own is so diminished, and will never be otherwise in my lifetime." --- The atmosphere in Altdorf is thick with suspense as the birth of the Emperor's heir approaches, and the Colleges are no exception. The Jade College crowd the Palace, fighting for primacy with Priestesses of Rhya and Shallya. The Celestial College crackles with energies as every path into the future is scoured for any hint of possible disaster. Rumours fly that those few Light and Bright Battle Wizards not deployed to Sylvania are lurking throughout the city, waiting for any hint of a possible threat to the Empress or her child. The usually-abandoned entrance of the Amethyst College is filled with the bravest citizens of Altdorf imploring Morr not to cut short any lives. The only Colleges apparently unmoved by the atmosphere are the always-absent Ambers, the unfeeling Golds, and, of course, the ever-enigmatic Greys. Or so any outsiders can tell, anyway. The usually-empty entry hall is filled with Grey Wizards idly reading books or chatting, only for their act to be punctured whenever someone enters and everyone looks to see if there's news. The tidings you bear are not related to the Empress, but they're certainly good. For the second time in a year you make your way into Algard's office, and though his table is as clear as ever, the two added pocket dimensions indicate that paperwork may have been piling up while he was engaged in tower-related business in Eight Peaks. "Trouble with the tower?" he asks distractedly, squinting at a parchment covered in numbers. "Not at all, Lord Patriarch. I bring the best kind of good news." A small smile twitches in the corner of his mouth. "The kind that would have been very bad news, except it ends with 'and you took care of it'?" "Don't know where you'd get that idea." You take a seat across from him. "I speak, of course, of a full-blown Skaven civil war." After a moment of thought, he sets the parchment down, and the dimensions of the desk wrinkle for a heartbeat as the parchment slides in the opposite direction of reality and out of sight. "You have my attention." "I've taken a cooperative Clan Moulder prisoner. He seems to still be loyal to the Clan in general, but he ended up on the wrong side of a leadership dispute so he's got no direct ties, and the rest of Clan Moulder got wiped out that day so there's no mundane way the Skaven would know I have him." "'Mundane'. Good qualifier." "Thank you. He says, and I believe him to be telling the truth as he understands it, that Clan Pestilens and their subordinates made a play for control once more, and this time Clan Mors sided with them. They've failed but there's been no intercession by the one in charge, so the other Clans are scrambling to finish the job and grab what they can in anticipation that when it does, it'll call a halt to hostilities." "Pestilens, the rest of the Brotherhood, and Mors..." he leans back and stares into space, muttering to himself. "Shame we're only hearing about it in the aftermath, but still... Mousillon, Bastonne. The current Ambassador's a good egg, I'll have a word in his ear. As for here... Ubersreik, of course. And Nuln..." He refocuses on you. "This might be worth having a poke at the Conspiracy of Silence. I'll have a little word with people who'll have a little word with people. If it all ends in disaster pray you never hear a word of it again, but if everything goes as it should this might be a nice little feather in your cap. Needless to say, if your guest spills anything else of interest I want to hear about it." "Of course, Lord Patriarch," you say with a smile. He returns it. "You've become quite a credit to the College. Keep it up, young Magister." --- [Rolling...] While there, you take the opportunity to check your pigeonhole to see if there's been any mail - most would know to contact you in Eight Peaks, but apart from the Amber Hills, academia rarely strays beyond the walls of Altdorf. Finding an unexpected bundle of papers and letters, you make your way back to the privacy of your unadorned and rarely-used quarters to go through it. The first piece is a rebuttal to Preliminary Observations on the Eusocial Cave Spider, and you frown at the opinionated Amber with a lot of opinions on where the line is drawn between sociality and eusociality, and is quite firmly convinced that the We must fall short of the latter. You flip through the other pages present, and find a counterrebuttal from Esbern and Seija that quite thoroughly punctures the debate presented on its merits without having to bring the We into it at all, which you imagine would be quite necessary with them being somewhere within the forests of the Empire. [+1 College Favour from further attention to Preliminary Observations on the Eusocial Cave Spider] You flip through a number of reports on attempts at adapting the MAP to other winds, and apart from the Bright College it seems that all attempts were dismal failures, seemingly because their own Winds don't have the natural inclination to flow and pool. But then you flip further and find a sparse few paragraphs in which a Bright College Lord Magister guts your spell, replaces its innards with a few simple flourishes, and sends it on its way, simplified enough for any Apprentice to cast. Following that is eight near-identical letters informing you that your spell has been added to the curricula of all eight Colleges. [+10 College Favour from Mathilde's MAPP being developed and added to the curricula of the Colleges] --- While the Empress is surrounded by a thick swarm of priestesses, midwives, ladies-in-waiting, and various other courtly hangers-on as the projected day of birth approaches, that she greets you like an old friend combines with the reputation of the Grey College to ensure that they all step very lightly around you. The constant internecine status conflicts in the Imperial Court are well known, and you're not here to start fighting in them, you're just here to see that your oldest friend's biggest gamble continues to go smoothly. Though it goes unnoticed by the relatively undeveloped senses of those few Jade Wizards trusted enough to look her over, divine energy dances through both her and her unborn child, engaging in a constant dance that intertwines without ever quite mingling. Shallya's blessings fill them both with vitality, and Ranald's careful oversight seeks to guide them into a comfortable future like a pilot into port. [Rolling...] You don't witness the birth itself, though you're right there with Heidi's hand trying in vain to crush yours through Aethyric Armour; the entire business is genteelly screened off with a series of curtains, some seemingly designed specifically for this. Between Heidi's yells and a Shallyan priestess commenting that five hours wasn't even unusually prolonged, the entire business leaves you feeling quite convinced that the process of reproduction is very poorly designed indeed, no matter the entertainment that the earlier stages might represent. But at long last, a strong set of lungs gives a scream of outrage at his eviction, and the likely future Emperor is placed into Empress Heidi's arms. "He's beautiful," she says dreamily. He's really not. You have a quiet word with a Rhyan priestess, who assures you that it's normal for him to be that colour and for his head to be that shape, and both should be temporary. --- Bells ring, town criers shout, and messengers scatter in all directions as news goes out to every corner of the Empire. Celebrations spill out into the street, partly out of patriotism and partly because canny Luitpold has subsidized the price of wine and ale throughout the city, ensuring that all citizens start their relationship off with the new heir on the right foot. Custom dictates that parents give thanks to Shallya for a healthy birth with a small gift of food, and Luitpold scales up accordingly and turns over the contents of several royal granaries. In the coming days, the newborn will be taken to the first of what is sure to be many holy services at the Grand Temple of Sigmar, but before that lot can get their claws into him, at the nexus of a set of coincidences that see each and every one of the usual swarm distracted elsewhere, the two of you find yourselves alone with the child, who sure enough has adopted more traditional colouring and skull shape. "They say it's bad luck to pick a child's name in advance," Heidi murmurs, her eyes locked on the sleeping child's face. "Luitpold had one chosen for the previous one. Two, I suppose. Karl Franz." She smiles at the babe. "He doesn't look like a Karl, though. Could we get away with calling him Ranald, do you think?" "Probably not," you admit reluctantly. "Magnus, perhaps?" "No, the Todbringers are kin to the original and they make enough hay out of it as it is. Wilhelm?" You screw up your nose. "After the one that tried to purge wizards because some entirely non-magical thespian tricksters looted his treasury?" "He did? Oh, terribly sorry, I didn't realize he'd do anything of the sort." You narrow your eyes at her, not entirely sure if she's messing with you, but after the amount of times you've deployed that same act you can't really criticize. But you can fire back. "Dieter?" She fakes a gag. "Perish the thought. But I'm liking the theme. Leopold's out, not giving the Unfähigers a foothold. Probably be a bit too on-the-nose to go with Sigmar, wouldn't it?" "I'd say so." You smile as a thought occurs to you. "How about Mandred?" She bites her lip. "The Skavenslayer? Saved and united the Empire... I like it." The child stirs slightly as his tiny shirt is unbuttoned, and you prick a forefinger with a shadowchisel and draw a cross in blood above his heart. "Ranald greets you, Mandred. May this world bring you joy, and may you bring joy to this world." --- [Rolling...] Princess Edda is originally of Karak Izor, which has more ties with Tilea and the Border Princes than it does the Empire, but the Young Holds have close ties and introductions to the Elector Counts of Averland and Wissenland are hers for the asking. It makes some sense that she'd capitalize on those relationships and linger there rather than pushing deeper into the Empire, but you follow a hunch and arrive unannounced at an awkward hour, and when sunrise and cock-crow arrives and a sleepy Princess returns to her guest quarters, she finds an unexpected Grey Wizard awaiting her. "Good morning, fellow Councillor," you say with a smile. "I applaud your dedication, to be getting to bed this early in the morning." "Ah," she says, brain trying to go from zero to a sprint in an instant. "Magister Weber." "I must also applaud Prince Kazrik for providing such prolonged assistance to you." "Yes," she says. "Assistance. We were-" "Grungen? Developing bokkul? Adgalazgandit?" Though Khazalid doesn't have Reikspiel's breadth of creative euphemisms, it does have a lot of abusable mining terminology, and Edda blushes deeply. And that only worsens as you exercise your grasp of the language. Unfortunately you didn't come all the way to Nuln just to see how much you could make the Princess blush, so after fishing for as many juicy details as she's willing to give, you take her on a jaunt across the border and up the road to Blutdorf. Sadly you've other business elsewhere and can't linger long enough to properly catch up to Anton, but you can make introductions. As the ruler of Blutdorf, he can spread word and vouch for the offer, and as a well-liked figure in local nobility, he can make even further introductions to spread an even further net. And not least of all, he can act as the local node of the EIC to funnel the actually rather stupendous amount of underworked, underpaid, or adventurous weavers within the EIC's sphere of influence that they've gathered the information of. And while you make that introduction, you have an opportunity to watch Princess Edda as she does her best to operate among humans. And the result is obvious: she doesn't. Oh, she operates fine as an ambassador, a representative speaking on behalf of a Dwarven Kingdom, but she doesn't seem to understand how humans operate on every level, and seems limited to speaking her request and seeing what happens, and if she gets any result but acquiescence she's lost. It's not a matter of any sort of dislike, as far as you can tell - you and her get on fine, and you're not just a human but a wizard. It's just that as an administrator, she's used to Dwarves, who can almost always be predicted and when something goes wrong, it's usually in a fairly predictable way. You imagine it must be something like a champion sheepdog being expected to run herd on a cat farm. Normally it would never be a problem for a Dwarven Princess, but Karak Izor's gambit to put her within marrying range of King Belegar had put her in control of a sizeable and growing human population. Troubling. You tuck away your newly-won insights and move on. --- [Rolling...] You open the neck of the sack dubiously and peer in, and are presented with the sight of a great many simultaneous grins. "Ah." "They're like cats!" Roswita shouts, waving her arms out the window of the briefing room in the general direction of the battlefields of Sylvania. "Every day, someone with fire instead of hair or surrounded by birds or a skull instead of a face wanders in and drops off a Vampire skull or the head of some forest mutant or a cartload of bones and I say thank you and they act like I've thrown a party and named my firstborn after them, and they go off to find something even worse to drag back! Look what they did to my table!" You consider the small sapling protruding from the wood of the table, its small green leaves stretching towards the window. "I see." "One of them walked off with my wall sconce stuck to her, I had to send a footman after her to get it back! She didn't even notice! Another made all the candles flare up, and one set fire to the curtains! One of them I had to tell only visit in the morning, because if he comes too late in the evening all the staff start nodding off!" "It..." You search for words. "Could be worse?" "I was expecting, I don't know, fire, floods, plague, having to repopulate Sylvania from scratch. Not this... weirdness! Part of Tempelhof got destroyed, and some of them rebuilt it, but refused to rebuild the roofs because 'why would they want the stars obstructed?' and they had to be led away to go bother the Strigoi." "So Tempelhof is sorted?" She subsides and scowls before admitting it. "Yes, and their Primar came all the way here and said if we keep away the Vampires and the wizards, they'll pay taxes and accept whatever authority I put over them. Still got Strigoi and Lahmians to deal with, and it's a stalemate on both fronts so far, but so far there's been nothing unexpected." "So everyone's magic is remaining cooperative?" She shrugs. "Magister Patriarch Feldmann says that Sylvania puts everyone on edge, so they're double-checking everything. He's at least sensible, and we've been working together to sort out proper deployments to keep everyone useful and intact. Worst of it is a hill near Egling that apparently will remain magnetized for the next three hundred years or so." You pull one of the skulls from the sack, considering it, and she waves a hand at you. "Take it. Please. I'm going to have to fund an expansion to the Siegfriedhof monitored ossuary as it is." --- In your recently-furnished sitting room, you cast an eye over the gathered wizards. "In the past six months, I have weaponized the Hellfire of another race's Hell." Thoughtful silence greets you. "You can do that?" Adela finally asks, intrigued. You grin at her. "Apparently! Ask Gunnars nicely if you're curious. Now that I've set the bar, how have the rest of you kept yourselves busy? Adela, impress me." She scowls. "Dwarves are really cagey about mechanics." "No kidding. Did you really spend six months banging your head on that wall?" "I've been working on getting my Flaming Sword cast time down. Shaved about a second and a half off." "Could make all the difference. Hubert?" He smiles. "I killed a troll." You consider that. "...why?" He stares at you. "Okay, let me unroll that. While sorting out the trolls in Kvinn-Wyr is definitely an entry on the long-term list, there's a lot of things above it. What made you seek out a troll?" He seems to be considering it. "My great-great grandfather killed a troll," he says finally. "I used to play with its club when I was young. I wanted to see if I could do the same." "That's fair. How was it?" "It was more work than I expected." "Trolls are. When it is time to move against Kvinn-Wyr, it will probably be because we've got a whole bunch of ways to deliver fire on hand. And the rest of your time?" He probes his side with a wince. "...healing." "Let this be a lesson in proper prioritization and time management. Gretel, I gave the others a chance and none have managed to dethrone you. What have you been up to?" Looking quite pleased with herself, she takes out a sack of coins and slides one across the table for you to examine. You rub a finger across the gold, then look into a face only a mother could love. "Eugh. Malekith. Where'd you find these?" "Picking through the ruins of Clan Moulder," she says, without a hint of self-consciousness. "That'd explain it. Anything beyond monetary wealth, which I as a Grey Wizard am immune to the allure of?" "Just a bunch of uncooperative Skaven and their ridiculous wyrdstone money. And yes, I used gloves and turned it over to Dreng and burned the bag they were in afterwards." "Way to extend the lead." You slide the coin back across the table at her. "Edda would give you a fair rate, but the smelters here are already working overtime on loot from the Orcs. Tell the EIC you work for me and they'll take it at full weight value, or let me know when you're headed to Barak Varr and I'll come with and make an introduction to the Royal Mint's acquisitions guy." You turn to Max, who's still sulking, and skip right to Johann, who's got one of the wolf-rat pups sitting on his shoulder and grooming his hair and another asleep in his palm. "Johann, apart from our favourite puppies, what's been happening?" "Still stalled on the damn ra- uh, the you-know-what, but I've been working with Panoramia with the ooze we found. It can digest just about anything organic and turn it into... well, more of itself. We're feeding it to some of the cattle and they seem to like it okay, we're up to three months without ill effects at half their diet." "That's," you pause, consider. "Possibly a really big deal." You consider further. "And might answer some questions about Skaven logistics." "It's a matter of how far we can scale without running into deficiencies," Panoramia says. "The Halflings have agreed to scale up tests, so we'll be starting sample groups of goats and sheep on 10%, 25%, and 50%. That seems to be as much as they're willing to eat without becoming upset and uncooperative. If they're still doing okay at one year in, we'll start draft cows, milk cows and horses at Ulrikadrin. After five years, we slaughter and do full autopsies." "I take it you've properly quarantined the test animals?" "Of course, Magister. They're penned up in one of the valleys between the Lhune and Nar foothills." "Good. Keep on it. Any other use of your times, when you haven't been threatening to revolutionize agriculture?" "Apart from punching?" "Yes." Johann shrugs, so you turn your gaze to Panoramia. "With all the water we could need, I've set up some ponds up against Lhune for the Black Lotuses." She frowns. "Loti?" "Lotuses," Johann says. "Loti," Maximilian disagrees. "Old Reikspiel root, so it pluralizes as loti," Adela says with a satisfied smile. "Black Loti, for the Rangers. I taught the Halflings how to tend it, but the Rangers have a thing about wanting to grow it wild where they range so I taught them as well." "Armaments for our friends, food for the livestock, riches for us, and death and mayhem to our foes. Productive few months for most, and lessons learned for the rest. Let's continue the trend for the rest of the year. Now, before you all run off to go get up to mischief, with my abode finally taking a proper shape, my library is not just theoretically available to you if it occurs to me that a specific book might be useful, it is now entirely available to you. If I'm not around, find Wolf and ask him to let you in. It's on this floor, other end of the hallway, to get into the Collegiate section Dispel the lock and replace it on your way out - you all know Dispel and Magic Lock?" Five yes, one no. Oh, Celestial College. Why must you- well, actually, that one makes sense. No need for locks with prognostication enchantments to prevent thievery. "You've got a one-month grace period where I let you in and out, Hubert. Scrolls are under Sevir, take what you need with you when you leave but return it in good condition or I'm sending a stern letter to your Master." You'd made a little key enchanted with Dispel for Johann and gave it to him earlier. It's nowhere near strong enough to be useful, but it will get him in and out of the Magic section. --- As your next council meeting approaches, you consider the matter of your Tower project. There's no question that what's been constructed over the past six months is a formidable weapon, but there remain limitations and imperfections that more time could perfect. You've still got another six months before even a normal success would be expected, let alone the fantastic over-achievement you've accomplished, so the time is there if you want it, but if you're convinced you'd be more useful elsewhere it might be better to report it complete and move on. [ ] [TOWER] Complete [ ] [TOWER] Ongoing There's also the matter of your purchases. With the Karak reasonably secure and freshly-mined silver to begin rolling in soon, your budget has been extended, and beyond the expenses in construction it has already covered, there's also an allotment for research materials that will be just perfect for expanding your library. Library Purchases Budget: 300gc, 2 Dwarf Favour. Anything not spent will not accumulate. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. Dwarf Favour Purchases [ ] [DWARF] No purchase. [ ] [DWARF] Write-in. College Favour Purchases [ ] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [ ] [COLLEGE] Write-in. Other Purchases [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. - If the Tower vote is to call it Complete, I'll have to have a second vote to sort out what Projects you'll put forward. In the future, this vote will be held before the social turn to prevent this problem. - There will be a four hour moratorium. Remember to keep all your votes in one post. - The 'research materials' budget cannot be applied to anything but books. Yes, it technically could be used for things like flasks and alembics and whatnot, but you already have those. Please don't try to find creative reinterpretations of what may or may not be considered a research material.

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Four)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[] Write-In: Send in the Litany of Fury and whatever ships Graves can spare right behind them to serve as the Anvil to lock the enemy fleet in place. Once the Fire Ships have detonated or been destroyed, engage with the Anvil. The Strike Cruisers will attempt to flank the fleet and target the Hades Cruisers to deny the enemy their heavy firepower while the Litany of Fury challenges the enemy Battle Barge, all the while the Librarius attempts to deny teleport assaults upon the ship. Priority to boarding assault will be all long ranged traitor cruisers, starting with the Hades and going down. Secondary Priority will be keeping enemy Strike Cruisers from reaching the fleet. While the enemy fleet is engaged, get the Troop Transports clear of the Gravity Reef and allow the remaining ships to join the fray. One Cruiser Fire Ship will hit a flank while allied ships disengage while remaining escort-tonnage Fire Ships will go straight for the Battle Barge.

GM NOTE: Well, at least I still had an outline with some notes on actual paper.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

In an age of unending war, void combat often devolved into two distinct paths. The first was the duel. Hours, days, perhaps even weeks of maneuvering at long range, dancing in and out of enemy reticles and attacking them from afar before pulling back. A dreadful dance of a thousand cuts interspersed with intermissions in the form of minor recuperation in asteroid belts or nebulae, or perhaps the dark side of particularly large planets or planetoids. Steadily, slowly, the supplies dwindled, repairs became ever more threadbare before ceasing entirely as nothing remained to patch the holes with. Reactors began to stutter-stop as they were strained for long periods of time. Each blast, scar, tearing of hull and ship hard points was a glorious hard-fought victory or heartrending defeat, all leading up to moment when only one victor remained. The second was the immediate clash, an eruption of sheer violence and destruction that saw the ending of thousands of years of survival, of work, of machinery in but minutes. A conflict of such ferocity that for all the years of experience and generations of expertise in building warship and wargear alike would end in less than a single day.

The Black Legion under Lord Mortirex, who had had their bloodlust stifled and unsated for decades at a time, only ever able to raid the furthest reaches and return on rare occasion, preferred the second.

As the tainted vessel of Chaos flung themselves forward, frantic and terse communications flew between the ships of the Imperium. The pride of Admiral Graves was great, that of his Captains as well, and yet in this instance, he saw the wisdom of the course offered by the Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens. Grimly accepting their duty, the Avenger-class Grand Cruisers Glorious Repentance and Illumination of the Emperor drove forwards alongside the Litany of Fury. Three vessels, venerable and mighty, against the bloody and hooked fist of the enemy, an anvil to withstand what could be. Haphazard and barely targeted volleys flew from the closest Chaos ships, while behind the lances of the Imperium fired back. A moment passed as engines flared and gun ports opened, before at a single fleet-wide command a concentrated and deadly spread of torpedoes erupted from all ships capable of firing them. Concentrated lance salvoes struck at pre-determined targets, popping void shields like bubbles and shearing through vital components.

The first howling Chaos ships, their crews long melded into their stations or shambling through their corridors, barely had enough time to contemplate the void itself as they were struck head on by the torpedo volley. Great holes were torn through them, two enemy cruisers disappearing entirely in explosions that seared the eye and sent static rippling through auspex sensors. But still the ships of Mortirex came on, some even laughing at the deaths of their comrades for their weakness. Those that had been damaged but not destroyed were only incensed by the damage dealt to them, the thought of retreat or even pausing for momentary repairs passing through exactly none of their minds. The daemons that cavorted across the vox proclaimed the names of their chosen ships, screaming in a choir of inviting damnation into the ears of all who dared listen to any but the protected channels.

And yet.

Engines burning at full power, weapons purposefully depowered and other non-essential subsystems momentarily disabled, the strike cruisers of the Blood Ravens flew above and below the incoming thrust of the enemy. A few particularly sharp-eyed gunnery crews, or in a handful of cases of the daemons inside the turrets on the broadsides, spied them. But before they could do more than a feeble volley or two, they had moved out of proper firing arcs and range, such was the speed demanded by the Chaos ships to close and get to grips with the enemy. As such, they soared through the void unhindered and untouched, until they began to reach their targets, at least. At the absolute rear sat the Hades-class Heavy Cruisers, known well in the records to be capable of terrible devastation at extreme range. Their reach was long and vicious, yet at the same time they had been left behind by the rest of the Black Legion – both to allow them to pick and choose their targets as they wished as well as ensure they could not interfere with the closest fighting. Point defenses began firing immediately, but by then it was too late, each strike cruiser striking as hammers into the enemy ships, spinning them slightly while their salvoes momentarily broke through void shields. Within seconds they would return, of course, but the shock was enough for boarding parties to get through.

=======================================================

In a flash of discharged light and sound, they appeared. Metal and ropey rust-red flesh intermingled openly, making up the walls and floors equally, and therefore both crunched and squished as ceramite boots crushed downwards atop them. Lighting was poor, the winking red emergency lights which had been activated centuries ago as the Warp crept over the ship being the only mechanical source of it in the immediate area. No sooner had the space marines appeared than did pustules erupt to release screaming creations that were once servitors melded with daemons, doors twisting open like undulating esophagi being cut open to release hordes of mutants that had descended from the original crewmen. Some bore a semblance of flak armor, others were covered in chitinous plate, still others bone and scrap metal tied with dried intestines.

The Blood Ravens opened fire immediately, bolters booming, directly into the horde.

At the center of their formation, Tarkus, Captain of the 5th Company, raised his voice as he accessed the vox which bounced its signals across all three enemy ships into the comm systems of his fellow Blood Ravens.

“Proceed to your targets, brothers, and advance!”

===============================================================

Sergeant Stromahn’s fingers depressed the firing stud of his assault cannon the moment the auto-senses of his helmet detected non-friendly movement, before the light of the teleportation had even begun to properly fade. The rest of his fellow terminators did the same. An approaching target on the left was crushed into pulp with his power fist, and as the last contrails of energy faded from sight he was able to see that it had been some sort of mutated crewman who’d come at him with a rusty pipe. The one he’d fired at – that the assault cannon had torn apart – had wielded a far more dangerous plasma gun. One that had exploded violently, taking his target and those near him out at the same time. Fortuitous, that. Stromahn paused as Captain Tarkus spoke, then immediately moved on, battle brothers of the 5th Company appearing nearby as well.

“Follow me, brothers, to victory,” he intoned calmly despite literal hell breaking loose around them as the ship itself came alive to defend itself from the invaders.

It was all that needed to be said for all nearby Blood Ravens to assemble behind them before the small battle group advanced as one.

============================================================

Glorious Repentance was dead in the void. It bled atmosphere, metal, and bodies from dozens of wounds. A pair of torpedos had struck its strategium dead on, the first slaughtering the crew instantly, the second flooding the corridors of over a third of the ship in incendiary death. The anvil cracked and splintered, and more than a third of the Black Legion ships flooded through the opened gap. The Imperial Navy fought back, for that was all they could do, their backs up against the gravity reef preventing full maneuvering. Fighter craft swarmed out on both sides, clouds of gnats amidst titans of adamantium and warp-borne flesh alike. Bombing runs, dogfights, boarding rams and transports, the lives of hundreds ending beneath the attentions of those who commanded them in the first place. More gun batteries fired, some ships on both sides now able to turn sideways to present broadsides to more fully fill the emptiness of space with sound, light, and fury. Void shields rose, and void shields fell. Hulls cracked, weapon emplacements were blown apart, and crews ran back and forth to repair what they could. The Litany of Fury, once the flagship of Gabriel Angelos as the Captain of the 3rd Company, was not immune nor inviolable to the conflict.

Its shields had fallen more than once from the sheer volume of fire levied upon it, of course. But this time, something was different. A codicier deep within the Librarium cried out as his portion of a great winding shield within the Immaterium was finally pierced through, unclean technology and daemonic will helping propel force through it. Though the sphere of ritual and psychic energies had repulsed multiple attempts, in this one instance, the gap was enough. A serf cried a warning on the strategium at the top of his lungs only a handful of seconds before a flash of light and noise that sent many other serfs to the ground bleeding from their eyes and ears burst into being. Stepping forth from the Warp strode none other than Chaos Space Marines, horns sprouting from their helmets, bodies noticeably mutated and bulked into deadlier forms, and accursed weaponry held in their hands. Sibilant whispering in languages unknowable by mortals drifted from their swords and bolters. An entire squad’s worth of traitor marines stepped into the Materium with only one purpose, one act on their minds.

Instead, they met Apollo Diomedes.

In half a heartbeat of a primary heart, two veterans of the Long War were dead, the power mace known as Rogal’s Fist crashing down in an overhead swing that obliterated the head and upper torso of one and then sweeping horizontally across the face of the second. The latter strike was not a complete one, the wind-up halved by the close distance, and yet it left only spatters of flash-vaporized gore and shattered fragments of ceramite flying. As the primary heart completed its pulse, a switched grip had the power mace thrust forward directly into the armpit of another marine up through and into the temple, leaving the body to only just barely begin collapsing. A free hand slammed the barrel of a bolt pistol directly into the hardened photolenses of a traitor marine’s helmet and fired once, putting a bolter round right through a bloodshot eye and into the brain within, the explosion turning all within the helmet into a slurry of organic matter and old cybernetics. As the traitor marine’s upper half twitched violently backwards, it took the bolt pistol with it, at which point Apollo’s hand flashed down and then up again with a combat knife that dug deep into the throat of another marine, stabbing and cutting with such violence as to decapitate the foe. Only then did the secondary heart complete its own pulse.

At which point Godsplitter flew forward, slung in a single driving forward thrust without wobble or flipping, and struck one of the traitor marines in the groin, the explosion of its energy field turning the impact site into shrapnel of metal and bone and detaching the legs from the body entirely. The torso flew backwards into one of the traitors just as they’d begun to try and fire at their initial target, sending the bolter rounds into the ceiling instead. Apollo stepped forward quickly, slamming the power mace down through a power sword, shattering the blade, the hand holding it, and then the chest of the marine beneath. The twisted and malefic machine spirit of the armor, long warped by the acts and treatment of its bearer, ceased to be as the power mace pushed through the chest and out of the back. By then, the other traitors responded to the immediate threat, firing their bolters instead at Apollo rather than their initial target. Bolter rounds cracked against his breastplate and helmet, and still he advanced, one arm coming up to protect the photolenses of his helmet before swiping low with his power mace to kill the legless marine. One boot landed atop that of another traitor marine, preventing them from pulling out of range, and there his knife found his target through their chin and into their brains while Rogal’s Fist fell like a comet atop the head of another. Only then did the corpse of the traitor who had been shot through the eye fell backwards far enough for Apollo to reach back and pull his bolt pistol free and repeat his last act with it. To the traitor’s credit, they managed to get both of their hands around Apollo’s wrist before he could finish, posthuman strength straining against posthuman strength. At least until a finger squeeze sent multiple rounds through the photolenses and into the head within.

In the time of less than ten seconds, a combined thousands of years of war experience were ended.

Apollo breathed hard as he cleaned his wargear while Gabriel stepped forward and pulled Godsplitter free from the small crater in the deck it had made.

“It seems that I shall require my terminator armor after all,” Gabriel said as he stepped back up to the command throne with a frown on his face.

“Additional incursions reported,” a servitor slaved to the internal sensor cogitator bank stated calmly. “Honor Guard responding. Warning, an assault party is heading to bombardment cannon ammunition store A4.”

“Apollo,” Gabriel barked.

“Of course, Chapter Master,” Apollo bowed his head and sprinted into the depths of the ship on his lonesome towards another squad of the enemy.

By then, the void shields had regenerated once more, though their generators were beginning to strain under the effort. For that moment, at least, there would be no more incursions just yet.

===============================================================

Reactor-hearts pulsed and throbbed, metal and flesh twisted long ago by possession and transformation through the vagaries of the Immaterium acting with impunity. Until melta charges tore them apart, at least. Red and black armored space marines throttled the veins of the ships, cutting off systems one by one. Engines flickered and died, as did shields, and thus were the Hades cruisers attacked from without and within. Even as slivers of flesh began to creep back towards one another, the ships attempting to heal themselves in manners most unholy and aided by mass sacrifice of slaves and crew, the Blood Ravens were relentless. A target may have survived or regenerated after a squad had passed, but how many times could it do so? Twice? Thrice? How many more? Heavy flamers roared and assault cannons thundered, tearing and burning as they willed. Onslaughts of cultists and mutants and lesser daemon-things swept against the tightly packed space marines, howling their insane cries to their Dark Gods, and yet they died all the same for it.

In the end, so too did their ships. Machine spirits, or daemons, it did not matter which, for they howled impotently all the same as their existence within the system came to an end. But by then, the Blood Ravens had already teleported back to their ships or boarded the thunderhawks that were only then able to approach due to the amount of destroyed point defenses that had kept them back beforehand. The strike cruisers left the drifting corpses behind, firing at them as they turned about to ensure as much damage as possible while adjusting to newly set courses. Complete destruction was no longer the goal, however, for the battle had continued elsewhere without them.

For the Illumination of the Emperor had just been split in twain by the Joyous Lament and Rex Magnifica.

===================================================================

Both of the Avenger-class Grand Cruisers were gone, their value as little more than physical barriers that could easily be swept past by even the most incompetent of captains and crews.

The Litany of Fury stood alone, a rock against the tide that flowed around and past it.

Behind, the Imperial Navy was no longer of capable remaining as static as before, forced to maneuver in and out of optimal firing patterns due to the shoal of Chaos-held ships in and amongst their number. While the escort tonnage ships had suffered terribly at the hands of Imperial bombers, more than one Imperial cruiser was venting atmosphere from the blows they were taking. In the middle of it all, Admiral Graves continued to command his fleet with tireless focus. For behind them, in an act of incredible daring and danger both, the troop ships had skulked out of the gravity reef’s tunnel. They spread themselves out as close to the gravity reef as they dared, knowing that the merest protrusion of their hulls touching the anomalies might spell their doom and all they carried, yet maneuver they did. From within, the fire ships freed themselves, and with the Litany so embattled it fell to Graves to transmit the command codes to their servitor-slaved crews. So, too, did the vessel of Inquisitor Adrastia emerge, and immediately acted as a shield behind which the troop ships could retreat once more into the comparative safety of the gravity reef.

On the Litany, however, matters were more dire. She had weathered the enemy for too long without relief, and despite the fact that a number of the Chaos ships had flown past to get to grips with the vessels of the Imperial Navy, some remained, their hate overriding tactical sense enough to have them concentrate solely on the ship before them. On the bridge of the Litany, Gabriel grimaced as twin impacts slammed into the battle barge’s frame as the Joyous Lament and Rex Magnifica crashed into it like wolves biting at a prey’s heel. Looming ominously above, the alpha predator to its lesser kin, the Ruination of Purity slowed to a stop. A single salvo from its bombardment weaponry, twisted mirrors that they were to the implements of the Litany of Fury, shattered the void shields once more. This time, however, there was no cough and whine from the generators as they sought to regenerate the shielding, but rather a metallic scream accompanied by the sparks, pops, and minor explosions that accompanied the components of too many generators overloading with fatal finality.

“So…,” Gabriel bowed his head until it almost touched Godsplitter, the daemonhammer held firmly in his hands. “It begins.”

“BLLLLLOOOOOOOOD RAAAAAAAAVEEEEENS!!!” Lord Mortirex bellowed across the general vox, his voice no doubt reaching from one end of the system to the other. “Are you prepared, loyalist scum?! I have prayed to Khorne that you might provide at least one appreciable skull to pile before his throne, to Slaanesh that you inept children might possess some measure of skill enough to be worthy sport, to Nurgle that you survive us long enough to entertain us, and to Tzeentch that your porous toe-sized brains might actually conceive of plans capable of not faltering at the lightest puff of air!”

Warp-tainted plasma projectors and ballistic projectiles turned even more of the point defenses on the Litany of Fury into smoking slag.

“Warning, multiple enemy boarding craft incoming,” a servitor chimed in. “Dreadclaws and assault rams detected.”

Gabriel scrutinized the actuality sphere in the center of the strategium, the holographic orb shrinking in its view to display the Litany at the center. Numerous jagged red arrows appeared, beginning from the Black Legion ships and terminating at several points across the battle barge. There was no longer any need to waste troops attempting to teleport, not when the psychic defenses of the Librarians prevented easy movement through the Immaterium. The Litany of Fury had sustained so much damage to its weapon systems and shield generators that they could be boarded with impunity. To his surprise, however, none of them were targeted specifically at the strategium, though they certainly were striking towards numerous strategic targets. A decapitation strike would have been easy, at this point. Unless…

“But worry not, Blood Ravens,” Mortirex guffawed harshly, “Even when you fail to exceed my lowest expectations, pathetic creatures that you are, your vessels shall serve well enough as trophies, at the absolute least!”

Gabriel grit his teeth as the Chaos Lord announced his intentions. Tearing apart the strategium with the melta cutters of boarding craft would be counter-intuitive if he genuinely believed he could claim it.

There was nothing for it, he knew, and so he activated his connection to the command vox channel.

“Justinius,” he said gravely.

“I know, Gabriel,” the Chief Librarian said curtly. “I have already departed the Librarium, as have numerous others. Some must remain behind to defend the Librarium, but the rest of us…shall fight.”

“Very well,” Gabriel nodded, though he knew the Chief Librarian could not see it. “We shall hold our ground, here and now. There is nothing else we can do to affect the void battle. May None Find Us Wanting,” he intoned before stepping away from the command throne towards the doors.

“May None Find Us Wanting,” Justinius echoed.

Thus came into being a microcosm of old hatred and spurned bonds of brotherhood within an embattled vessel in fierce void combat, a dark and smudged mirror to titanic confrontations of the past.

=====================================================

Pavus sneered as he and the rest of his squad stomped their way through the corridors. The symbols of the Corpse were everywhere, the lights were far too bright on their pallid and mutated frames, and it was all he could do to prevent not only his squad but himself from turning to deface all that they saw. That would come in time, surely, once they claimed the whole of the ship, but for the moment he despised the quiet screaming tinny little voice somewhere within him that was left…uncomfortable…by the sigils and regalia on display all around him. The serfs and combat servitors had provided little help, fleeing after a mere half of their number had been slaughtered. It wasn’t enough, not even close, to satisfy his hatred for the Imperium and its lackeys. But he was no Word Bearer to convert the blind idiots to the truth, no.

His truth was delivered at the end of his bolter and on the edges of his growling chainsword, and the acceptance of that truth was signified by the enemy being dead.

“Our target is up ahead,” he gnashed through his oversized incisors, his latest mutation inflicting upon him glorious shredding fangs capable of biting even through adamantium. “Ready yourselves.”

“Why,” Peric sneered from behind him, his claw-arm snapping with his agitation. “All these Blood Ravens seem capable of is running away.”

Snarling, Pavus whirled about and slammed the other marine up against the wall, pleasingly cracking an Imperial skull sigil on the wall with the force of it. He glared all five of his insectoid eyes into the photolenses of Peric’s helmet and into the bloodshot eyes beneath.

“Because I’ll not be gutted by Lord Mortirex because the grox pups he stuck me with could not exercise basic tactical consideration,” he snarled, hooking his teeth upon the fool’s helmet and crunching down slightly.

Not enough to kill, or to tear the helmet apart, but enough to peel it slightly with nothing more than his teeth. Peric had been a bur in his boots since the moment he’d arrived. It was obvious that he was attempting to jockey for Pavus’ position, and any weakness at all could be seized upon by any of the others in the squad. Unfortunately for Peric, Pavus had done the exact same thing to usurp command of the squad, and he was not about to let himself be overtaken by some centuries younger pup.

“Now fall into line, Peric!” He slammed his fist into the side of Peric’s helmet before stepping away, all while making sure to keep himself pointed towards him.

Peric growled back, and the rest of the squad slowed, hands and weapons twitching without outright pointing towards one or the other. This early on, it would be foolish to declare even a mockery of loyalty. Slowly the formed a circle facing inwards, stepping carelessly atop the bodies of fallen servitors that had attempted to trundle away from them without any sense of urgency.

“Grox pup?! I’ve slaughtered thousands for the Dark Gods, I have fought for them for a thousand years!”

Pavus laughed, the noise an ugly slurred sound through his sprouted fangs.

“A thousand years of war are nothing, child, I have fought in Black Crusades!”

Peric had had enough, as Pavus knew he would, and yet rather than leaping forward towards him, he remained where he was. Pavus had planned on gutting him mid-leap, yet as he attempted to strike the fool down with his chainsword, he realized the motor had stilled. When he tried to pull his gun, his armor refused to contribute itself to the action. In seconds, the rest of his squad had realized something was wrong, only to discover the effect had carried itself out across the rest of them. Soon enough, cursing and straining was heard from all of them as they attempted to move, to rise, to do anything at all. But they could not even move their heads, their helmets as locked into position as their armor.

Then Zsask died, head disappearing into a small fountain of brackish gore and shattered adamantium.

“What-,”

On and on it went. They raged. They cursed. They roared. But Pavus could do nothing but watch as marine after marine fell, each with their heads utterly removed until it was only him and Peric left. By then, he had recognized the method of killing, the weapon by which they were being picked off. Someone was firing at them with a sniper rifle, and yet he could not even shift his gaze to search for the shooter.

“Face me, coward!” Pavus howled aloud, shaking with anger in his own armor. “You wretched-,”

And then Pavus of the Black Legion, and before that point the destroyed Scorpions of Wrath Chapter, died.

Only then did Epistolary Rasmus sigh as the last of the traitors fell to the ground, racking his sniper rifle one more time. He had spent barely any time at all as a neophyte before joining the ranks of the Librarians, his trials focusing less on his capability with wargear and more on his mind and soul. Yet only now did he wonder how else he might have contributed to the efforts of the Chapter, what he might have achieved if he had not been born without the psyker mutation. Alas, he could not contemplate for long, sustaining a complete lockdown of ten separate sets of power armor had strained him more than he had thought, even with him firing the rifle as quickly as he could. As it was, he could hear further reports of contact elsewhere in the ship. But he had pierced the veil well enough to know that this position was not truly secure. More would come. First, he needed to dispose of the bodies, or at least move them out of sight. Personally, he disagreed with his Captain’s insistence that he separate from the rest of the Honor Guard to protect the flashpoints from his visions, but he was under orders. Everyone was spread out, after all. The Litany of Fury was a battle barge, and they were far too few.

===================================================================

It was just like the tunnels.

Only instead of being formed of crudely punched through rock or dusty abandoned Imperial architecture, it was the corridors of the Litany itself. No doubt the tech priests would howl when they came upon what he had done, but then the vast majority of them had gone to fight against xenos rather than traitors. Whether it was because he was even more familiar with the ship, or it was practice, anger, or desperation, he didn’t know. In the end, it didn’t matter. The enemy had come charging in, heedless of his concealed presence until it was too late. To their credit, the chaos space marines had reacted immediately as he’d begun, attempting to retreat, even pushing others down to ease their way, but it hadn’t been enough. Now the corridor was a nightmarish mishmash of barely Euclidian geometries.

The walls, the floor, the ceiling itself had bent and twisted, forming spikes and blades, crushing and grasping in the form of momentarily molten tentacles of material. Some had been sheared into halves, others crushed long enough for thinner spikes to punch through photolenses or damaged rebreathers. Some had mutated so heavily as to have been forced to long ago disdain their helmets, and for them there was little they could to in order to survive. That was not to say that it had been easy, of course, as he’d fallen onto his knees and wept tears of blood as the nerves of his entire body were set aflame with the psychosomatic response towards his efforts. Yet he was alive to say it was worth it, and that would have to be enough.

As such, Epistolary Idmon staggered to his feet and beheld the results of his actions.

One squad of dead heretics, their bodies and body parts strewn about the corridor. It was to his surprise that one was somehow still alive, even with half of the wall melted around their body and forcibly melted into their flesh. Moving closer, he watched as the traitor spied him and immediately began trying to reach the grenade on their belt, their other arm having been twisted into organo-metallic abomination by his own actions. Before they could finish their act, he’d placed a plasma pistol into their head and fired twice.

Idmon slumped slightly against the wall, breathing heavily.

===========================================================================

More of them were coming. It felt like the enemy had poured an entire army into this. For all they knew, the enemy had done just that. There were reports across the ship of chaos space marines, small daemonic incursions, cultist swarms bearing weaponry spanning from regular lasguns to more esoteric and deadly things. More worrisome was the fact that there were reports of khornate berserkers, plague marines, and noise marines. For the warband to feature such diverse devotees meant that either a great deal had been promised and delivered or the sheer force of personality of Mortirex was enough to keep them in line and not killing each other. Likely both, and possibly some other thing as well. But he didn’t have the time or mind to spare anymore. Not right now. Not here.

“Aeneas!” One cried as he remained back behind the hastily made barricades.

Fifteen Lexicanum were with him, all of them having suffered painful wounds in the course of their defense. That none had died yet was solely attributed to the skill of Aeneas, despite the violence of the enemy. Many bore weapons they had never expected to need to wield themselves, many with plasma guns and even a few teams of two with heavy bolters. On the opposite side were hundreds of corpses. Scattered amongst them were a bare handful of chaos space marines. Behind them, however, rested the still thrumming main reactor for the Litany of Fury. It was, quite literally, the beating heart of the battle barge. Secondary and tertiary generators and reactors rested throughout the ship, but this was the grandest and most potent of them all. The enemy knew it, and the Blood Ravens knew that the knew it. To take this position was to take hold of the ship’s heart, either to safeguard it or to tear it out.

“I’m fine, brother,” the Codicier lied as he straightened.

He had been granted the honor, privilege, and responsibility of bearing none other than the blade of Azariah Moriah himself, he who had sealed the Great Unclean One Ulkair in the past. He refused to dishonor himself and the blade with failure.

“There! See the scum!” Laughed a howling Khornate as they rounded the corridor, uncaring of the fusillade immediately levied upon him. “The reactor is ours, loyalists! We will wash your presence from it with your own blood!”

And there were others behind him. Hulking cybernetic monstrosities bulked with Warp-aided mad science stood amongst other Khornates, as well as accursed mortals whose flak armor and helmets had been sewn into their skin. There were various other chaos space marines as well, all of them bearing chain and power weapons, some of them clearly well on their way into devolving into true berserkers.

“Kill the ones that get past me,” Aeneas announced loudly and then gripped the Blade of the Martyr in a two-handed grip. “Emperor gird my soul, and may none find me wanting,” he whispered.

Then he stepped forward through time, space, and out of the Materium.

Immediately, the screaming began, the whispers, the taunts, the promises and lies thundering into his ears. The grasp of an infinity of idiot godlings tugging on his every cell, his every molecule, trying to tear him apart for the temerity of his unsanctioned and insulting method of passage. He had to look forward twice, mind struggling to overlay the images of one atop the other with accuracy. It was the most excruciating thing that he had ever experienced, every time. There was never a point where it seemed to get easier, only a matter of how well he could stay focused, how well-guarded his mind was, how well his soul rebuffed the attempts to devour it. Ordinarily, all that was required was a step forward, to push through the murky depths, and to reappear. Safer, as much as one could ever apply the term to teleportation.

But there were too many for that. As such, he began moving forward, legs and arms pumping in only the vaguest recognition of the laws of physics that quite simply no longer fully applied.

The foremost berserker was halfway through the word ‘skull’ when he was bisected from head to groin in a straight line while an expanding ripple of destructive energies pulsed outwards as Aeneas momentarily reappeared. He could have forced the normally destructive reaction of the Immaterium and Materium’s forced interaction into dissipating if he’d been teleporting amongst the ranks of his brothers. As he was not, he let it erupt freely. But before he could do more than flicker into sight for less than a second, he was gone again, moving on to the next. This time it was one of the abominations, this one thrice-skulled with the appearance of gross surgical ‘overimprovement’ by the mad mind of some heretic or another. Thick slabs of metal had been literally bolted into place with an industrial nail gun, and yet the sword passed through them as well.

Then the next.

And the one after that.

“For-,”

“Skull-,”

“What-,”

“MAIM-,”

“KILL-,”

“BURN!”

Faster, faster, and faster still Aeneas moved. His body began to scream at him, signals and neurons firing confusedly as he began to occupy more locations in the space-time continuum than he should have near-simultaneously. Too much conflicting aural input in the Materium joined with the screams of the daemons of the Warp. His lungs began to twitch and burn as he burned more oxygen than he possessed, moving too quickly to even inhale safely. At one point he came face to face with himself as he plunged the Blade of the Martyr through a chaos space marine’s chest while his opposite was stabbing the marine through the head. He couldn’t tell if it was an afterimage or if he was, and never would know for certain. The strain grew further, and he grew slower. The enemy began reacting before he could act or fade away. Bolter shells skated across his armor, a chainaxe bit into a gauntlet, a grasping mass of spiked tentacles grasped and latched on to him, only for its bearer to scream as their mutated arm disappeared into the warp and was severed from them. His bolt pistol boomed again and again, rounds appearing amidst the carnage from seemingly nowhere and striking targets in trios.

Meanwhile, the rest of his fellow Librarians had not been idle, firing into the morass with psychically guided shots. Though they were but Lexicanum, aided by their innate psyker abilities even bursts of the heavy bolter found purchase and fatal accuracy.

It ended almost as soon as it began, forty seconds at most.

Aeneas slipped out of the Warp as if emerging from a pool of sewage, each movement slow and jerky as he collapsed to his knees, gore splattered liberally across his body from psychic hood down to his boots. Blood-flecked bile spewed out of his mouth while steady streams of already thickening and coagulating blood poured out of his nose, his eyes, and his ears. His skull pounded with the pressures he’d subjected it to, his psychic hood crackling with the energies he’d forced through the device. Aeneas gasped and gagged until he could cough up everything that he needed to before shakily standing, forced to use the noble Blade of the Martyr as a crutch to help him manage it, even as he holstered his bolt pistol to wipe off the trails of increasingly dried blood. Every iota of his being screamed in agony from the forces it had been made to both enact and withstand.

But it had been worth it, for the enemy were all dead.

Ah, but he could hear it.

More of them were coming.

“Aeneas?!” A Lexicani cried aloud.

He would never make Epistolary. To do so required skill and ability in a generalized spread to ensure adaptability for whatever Company they were assigned to, and Aeneas had already accepted his deficiencies in that direction. He would never possess the required potency in all that was demanded of an Epistolary, and so a Codicier he would remain. Never mind that he was the most skilled teleporter in the entire Chapter, save perhaps for the Chief Librarian himself, or that he could channel with a force sword with superlative skill. He was but a blade, much like the one he wielded. Specific and specialized. He would not ever be able to accomplish all that his fellow Librarians could, but he could at the least become the best possible at what few talents he did possess. The evidence of that lay all around him.

Twenty-two dead chaos space marines, eight dead khornate berserkers, five ogryn-sized cybernetic abominations, all dead by his hand, the rest taken care of by the Lexicanum and the Epistolary behind him.

It was an accomplishment worthy of song and story, of honors and engraving into steel and stone.

But there was no time to consider it.

“I’m fine, brother,” the Codicier lied as he straightened.

He held the flat of the Blade of the Martyr up, gazing first upon the image of himself reflected upon its glowing surface and then to the enemy that marched into view. Immediate heavy bolter fire sent them into a brief retreat that lasted a bare second before a massive surge burst forward. He inhaled deeply through sickly lungs, and felt his twin hearts beat erratically in his chest. Interspersed throughout their number were chaos space marines, champions with control of entire groups through some method or another. Threat, fear, promises of future power, and more were likely. The cultist troopers were well equipped – too well equipped, with hellguns and plasma guns firing directly at him.

“Kill the ones that get past me,” he shouted amidst the screaming of the heretics before his voice fell into a whisper. “Emperor gird my soul…and may none find me wanting.”

Then Aeneas stepped forward, his adamantium boot not even hitting the ground before he flickered out of sight, out of reality itself if only for a moment.

And the killing began anew.

=================================================================

“Ah…there you are,” the sorcerer crowed as they walked into the training chapel. “One last prayer for salvation before I end you, hmm?”

Justinius rose from where he’d knelt before a statue of the Emperor, summoning his staff to his hand as he turned about to face his foe. The Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens had an enormous cabal of Codiciers behind him, nearly the entire compliment save for one. Against him, the Black Legion sorcerer was followed dutifully by a large cadre of acolytes. Many of them bore the signs of psykers upon them, others had grasped the darkness of sorcery with both hands and souls wide open. They possessed other troops as well, guardians and slaves alike whose minds and souls had long ago been scoured clean of anything but obedience.

The Blood Ravens were well out numbered.

“Only through the destruction of the Emperor’s enemies may we earn our salvation,” Justinius said with deadly calm. “I knew you would seek me out, if only to see the one who had stymied your paltry attempts at accessing this vessel with your own eyes.”

The sorcerer snarled, the daemon in their staff hissing in tandem with their irritation.

“Paltry…!?” The sorcerer cut themselves off and slammed their staff down, corruptive powers rusting and bending the metal unnaturally around it. “Arrogant blind loyalist fool! I had thought to offer you a place at my side, where you could truly make use of your talents rather than slave away for the Corpse-On-Terra!”

“Instead as a slave under you?” Justinius said with a raised eyebrow. “I think not.”

“You…you…,” the sorcerer shuddered in anger, “KILL THEM!”

Lightning flashed, columns of flame the size of tanks flew, whips of pure kinetic force snapped down, and Justinius Probalis walked forward through it all, the psychic light pouring from his eyes so bright as to obscure the rest of his face. The Talonstaff of Jonah slammed down, unleashing a wave of cleansing psychic power that washed over the forces of Chaos. The purity set warp-mutated flesh aflame, tainted wargear sputtered out as their machine spirits ever so briefly reasserted themselves, and many found themselves wholly blinded as their multitudes of eyes melted out of their sockets. The daemons bound within the sorcerer’s staff screamed as they were dissolved and dissipated. Then the physical shockwave that came in the wake of those purifying energies struck, bowling cultists and chaos space marines alike over.

"Alas, poor creature, I cannot spare the time to truly chastise you," Justinius boomed. "I have had enough of your warping and cloying of the veil, the pall and fog you cast over our sight. It will end, here and now!"

And then, hopefully, Justinius would figure out just why a chill had entered his blood.

=============================================================

Gabriel moved as swiftly as he could, coordinating the defense as best he could despite jamming on the vox channels. A garbled call using Honor Guard codes had him moving as swiftly as possible towards the aft of the ship, joined on the way by none other than Apollo. The two of them had seen to the deaths of more than a few cultists boarders, yet they were pebbles before an ocean. The Litany was surrounded, a prize clutched at the center of the greater mass of the Chaos fleet as it advanced. There was no way for them to know how the void battle proceeded, not now, not with their systems so damaged and communication arrays deliberately targeted. All they could do now was attempt to defend their ship, but going by the reports that had passed between the Librarians they were facing a strong warband indeed, one that had focused itself solely for this purpose while letting other ships strike against the Imperial Navy.

The two of them arrived at a gruesome scene.

Over two dozen chaos space marines and dozens more cultists lay where they had been struck down but interspersed throughout their number were the distinct bodies of Blood Ravens. Or, at least, portions of them. Some had been killed so violently that more than half of their bodies had simply ceased to be discernable amongst the bodies. Chaplain Uther Volkoss’s upper torso lay slumped against a wall, having been slammed so heavily into it that his head and helmet had been crushed flat against the bulkhead. Falkor Ryll, the veteran apothecary, lay facedown in a pile of corpses of cultists that had hacked him to pieces, only the white of his armor giving him away. Only Epistolary Rasmus was missing, having been sent to coordinate with the rest of the Librarians across the ship.

Gabriel and Apollo came to a sudden halt as they beheld not just the carnage before them, but the ones behind it. Ten obliterators stood in eerie silence. In the past, every obliterator ever encountered had never ceased screaming in pain or rage as the obliterator virus endlessly mutated their bodies, twisting and forcing their appendages into various sorts of weapons. Yet while the crunching of shifting bone and spurting of twisting meat was audible, they were silent. All instead remained in compete deference to their leader, their master, having knelt in subservience without rising even as the two Blood Ravens arrived. Aside from their eyes flicking towards them and away, they were almost able to be mistaken for statues. It was to that master that Gabriel looked to now.

By contrast to the obliterators, the behemothic space marine clad in black adamantium did not even deign to look in their direction. Three horns speared upwards from the left of their head, actual warp-borne bone rather than a portion of their helmet, punching out of the adamantium and ceramite and stabbing upwards. A thick cloak of chains fell from their shoulders, the metal itself rusted into near black from the sheer amount of blood spilled upon it for centuries and centuries. Their panoply was clearly customized to fit their frame, their body already nearly equaling that of terminator armor. Their legs had become amalgamations of armor and dark pulsating flesh covered in mutated chitin plates with clutching talons that scraped and peeled at the metal of the floor. A power axe befitting their size had been slammed into the ground blade-first, its power field a fell dark red that burned to look upon, three bloodshot eyes having grown along the upper haft of it. In one hand, they held Doukas Laskaris aloft, the Captain of the Honor Guard struggling to fight despite Bloodtalon laying broken in pieces beneath him along with his helmet.

Yet as Gabriel and Apollo arrived, the chaos space marine reached up and casually closed a fist around Doukas’ head, crushing it to pulp in an instant.

“NO!” Gabriel roared in tandem with Apollo.

Only then did they turn their head to gaze upon them with eyes that quite literally burned with malefic light to the point of being outright flames that visible burned within the helmet.

“Blood Ravens,” Lord Mortirex sneered. “Mewling babes, crying out at the slightest inconvenience,” he snorted as he tossed the still twitching corpse of Doukas over his shoulder in another expression of casual strength. “I had thought to face something of worth in your malign line,” he wrapped his fingers around his power axe and wrenched it free of the floor as he turned to face them more fully. “But even your precious ‘Honor Guard’,” he pitched his voice high in mockery, “Was little more than a waste of time!”

“Traitorous scum,” Apollo growled.

The Chaos Lord paused, head tilting slightly before he let out a laugh of genuine astonishment that had long grown rusted with disuse.

“’Traitorous scum’,” Mortirex echoed with dark amusement, “Is that the best you can do? Really? Pathetic.”

“It is all that needs to be said, for that is all that you are,” Gabriel declared, Godsplitter raised in his grip.

“Hmph. Better, but in the end just as worthless as the rest of your kind,” Mortirex chuckled. “Araghast should have just killed you all rather than play games. But worry not,” he hefted his axe into a two-handed grip as he stomped one foot down atop another Honor Guard’s chest, depressing deeply enough to get a squelch. “I shall rectify his mistake and end your misbegotten lives here and now!”

Behind him, all ten of the obliterators rose to their feet, whirring in their ballistic mutations growing louder as the glows from their las-weaponry protrusions increased in intensity.

Chapter Master, Your Decision?
Note: Success Is Not Guaranteed Either Way. This Is Merely A Choice Of What Is Initially Attempted.
Note Note: Moratorium For 12 Hours.

[] Focus: Lord Mortirex may be one of the most dangerous foes Gabriel has ever encountered. Working with Apollo, however, it may just be possible to bring him down or at least force him to withdraw temporarily. The obliterators are a considerable threat, but not an insurmountable one with skill and luck.
[] Divide: Obliterators cannot be allowed to interfere with this. Ten of them could concentrate enough firepower to end Gabriel or Apollo in an instant. One of the pair must break away get into close range with them and hope that the one left behind can survive long enough without them.

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll
Chaplain Uther Volkoss
3 Honor Guard
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Five)

[] Divide: Obliterators cannot be allowed to interfere with this. Ten of them could concentrate enough firepower to end Gabriel or Apollo in an instant. One of the pair must break away get into close range with them and hope that the one left behind can survive long enough without them.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

To call what occurred in the next few seconds could not be rightly considered a duel. A duel, at its core, was fought between two parties. A series of blows with some weapon or another by one party or the other. Sometimes simultaneously, sometimes not. But most importantly was the chance, the opportunity for retaliation, a joint if diametrically opposed effort. The blow struck by Lord Mortirex did not afford for that, the speed and strength behind it outright denying that such a concept was even fractionally existent throughout the myriad infinite possibilities of the universe and Immaterium both. He spun and swung his axe down in a single downward stroke despite his distance from Gabriel and Apollo, and yet nearly managed to slay them regardless. For while the head of his oversized axe struck the plating of the deck, a mono-shaded blade of energy rapidly continued onwards with a shriek of reality momentarily splitting apart. What started as a blade, a projection, practically became a wall that nearly bisected Gabriel if he had not turned aside, whose height stretched from floor to ceiling and seared its way through metal and wire alike as if it were naught but air. Where it touched the air, it ignited it, the smooth pane of energy effectively causing the air to its sides to explode in a ship’s wake of daemonic inferno. The force of that wake of explosions threw Gabriel, clad in terminator armor and with more than half of his body replaced by bionics, off his feet and a foot deep into a nearby wall.

By the time that Gabriel had extracted himself with a wrench of his shoulders, the energy had only just begun to dissipate. There was no time for hesitation, and as such he turned and began to run as quickly as his armor could allow towards Mortirex, only to have to throw himself forwards onto his knees to avoid a horizontal slash which caused a similar effect, battering his back and legs with another wake of explosions. From that position, Gabriel saw Apollo – who had somehow previously managed to stay on his feet – take a running leap which let the explosions that tore through the air propel him higher and further. Even then, Mortirex reversed the grip on his axe and swung it, single-handed, upwards at the passing and rapidly accelerated hero of the Chapter as he flew past without any ability to properly dodge. Gabriel grit his teeth and forced himself upright as Apollo howled in pain as the blade of the axe tore across his chest and let loose a massive gout of blood that quickly flicked through the air to melt away onto the axe. The force of that blow sent Apollo crashing into the ceiling before landing while set aflame, behind Mortirex and closer to the Obliterators. His reward for his getting past the Chaos Lord was all ten of them spinning up their weaponry mutations that twisted into the shape of plasma guns and heavy bolter barrels that began firing before he could even begin to try and get to his feet.

“There, that is your proper posture, Blood Raven. On. Your. Knees.”

Gabriel did not respond with words, but instead with a furious battle cry as he rushed forwards, Godsplitter gripped tightly in his hands. Mortirex’s next words cut off as he grunted in mild surprise as Gabriel swung the daemonhammer forwards, crashing against the shaft of the daemonically tainted power axe that the Chaos Lord bore, the discharging energy field sending a bright crackle of blue electricity spreading outwards. The Chapter Master did not relent, shifting his grip and flipping it about to try and strike the Chaos Lord once more. This close, Gabriel could see the awful weapon up close in all its terrible glory. The blade itself was tinged with black pulsating veins; its head etched with glowing runes of Chaos that burned at the eye to look upon. More disturbingly, the three bloodshot eyes along the upper half twitched violently, pus bleeding from around their ‘sockets’ along the metal. One of them began to glow, brighter and brighter, its iris swiveling about before focusing unerringly on Gabriel. His instincts had him twist about to the side, nearly turning a hundred and eighty degrees and dangerously exposing much of his back to Mortirex as nothing less than a wrist-thick column of blazing warp energies shot out from the eye. Metal was vaporized at the direct impact site and boiled away around it in a manner distinctly like that of a lascannon being fired at close range.

“Hmm,” was Mortirex’s only reaction to Gabriel’s feat as both reset their grips on their weapons.

The Chaos Lord was not, despite his prodigious height and size, clad in terminator armor as Gabriel was. Rather, he was as large as Gabriel was without it, his own custom war panoply closer to that of ‘regular’ power armor, though obviously thoroughly modified by the devilish expertise of the Dark Mechanicus and transmutative powers of the Warp. His reach was longer, his dexterity greater, and based on the few clashes that Gabriel had had against him, his strength exceeded the Blood Raven’s, even when factoring in bionic reinforcement. For all of that, however, the eruption of the Godsplitter’s disruption field had not been wholly without success, and one of the three eyes upon the axe was fused shut by caked over and rapidly dried blood and pus. A guttural scream from behind Mortirex was accompanied by multiple weapons and types firing in silent tandem.

“Come then, Blood Raven. ENTERTAIN ME!” Mortirex bellowed as he rushed forward, his very boot prints leaving scorched and red-hot impressions in the deck plating.

======================================================================

The strategium of the Spiraling Fury was quiet and somber in great contrast to the violence in the void outside.

“We have no choice. The last reports were of the Litany being boarded with overwhelming numbers,” Tarkus said bitterly as he leaned against the actuality sphere’s console and glared up at the battle’s projection.

The Chaos Fleet had advanced relentlessly past the silent and unmoving Litany, engaging the Imperial Navy at close range. The fire ships were still advancing, but one had fallen to enemy fire before it could properly act or provide anything more than temporary stellar phenomena. The captains and crews of the enemy were insane, corrupted, but not wholly tactically inept. It was not as if the enemy battle barge and strike cruisers were defenseless, that there were no ships nearby that were favoring middling range broadsides rather than trying to outright ram the remaining Imperial ships. If they approached close enough for even emergency range teleportation, they would be close enough to be struck by the enemy.

But to do otherwise, to remain back, would be both cowardly and treasonous.

“We must advance! To the Litany!”

Upon his order, the three strike cruisers flared their engines and plunged forwards. Immediately, some of the Chaos ships turned about, fully cognizant and wary of their danger after they had scuttled the Hades-class ships. It was not the worst bombardment that any had suffered in their lifetimes, in terms of concentration of fire, but it still battered relentlessly at their void shields. The closer they got, the more ships that turned about, which in turn exposed them to fire from the remaining Navy ships. More importantly, however, was the forward push by one of the cruiser-tonnage fire ships. Its mindless servitor crew pushed it further towards its original target, set early in the fight after they had emerged from the gravity reef. The target, ironically, was one of the Chaos-held Avenger-class Grand Cruisers near the center of the Chaos formation. The ship, trailing atmosphere and fires freely, accelerated at the last instant, redlining their engines at the expense of all other systems such as shielding or life support to ensure impact.

The result, as all present discovered, was a temporarily created gravimetric anomaly which crumpled the entire Grand Cruiser into a sphere of metal and pulverized flesh a mere hundred meters across. Shockwaves of rippling graviton explosives pushed up against all ships present regardless of size and faction. Some escort ships nearly ran into one another, several weapon batteries on the ships close to the destroyed ship were crushed and broken, and formations on both sides were shifted out of place. For a brief second, all stopped and marveled at what the Adeptus Mechanicus had created, before returning to the fight once more. Following that point, however, it was impossible to miss how the remaining cruiser-tonnage fire ships were thoroughly targeted. Despite Admiral Graves’ best efforts, the slowness of the servitor crews in responsiveness meant that they could not disengage quickly enough, falling to enemy fire with rapidity even at the cost of more than one Chaos cruiser. The resulting two gravimetric explosions tore through the air, each yield differing from the others in distance and strength.

However. Such maniacal focus on the experimental payloads did, however, ensure that the remaining escort-class fire ships, their threat considerably lesser, were able to move on to their own target. The point defense weapon arrays of the Ruination of Purity were powerful, its thunderhawks and storm eagles sent outward as it hovered protectively over its prospective prize. Such an effort could have unnerved a great many crews, but the servitors slaved to the consoles no longer had the capacity for such things. Even as one of their own was destroyed in a great conflagration, they pushed forward. Then a second. But they could not stop the third, nor the fourth. One struck the bombardment cannon of the Ruination of Purity, sending purifying flames cascading throughout the nearby ammo storage bays as they were triggered within their berths, the second struck the battle barge directly in one of its own hangar bays, flooding three decks with flames that continued to eagerly consume the oxygen within its fetid halls.

All the while, the Blood Ravens raced forward.

==============================================================================

“Metal, metal, metal, I thought I was fighting Blood Ravens, not Iron Hands!” Mortirex roared angrily as bludgeoned Gabriel across the face with his own crumpled left arm with enough force to send him reeling within his armor and to shatter the remains of the bionic limb into splinters of metal.

Blood poured down Gabriel’s face, the left half of his face crushed inward, the skull fractured in multiple locations. His Larraman’s Organ worked to clot his cranial wounds, but his arm only spurted hydraulic fluids and other unguents in discolored spatters across the ground. The horns on the side of Mortirex’s helmet had been shattered by one blow from Godsplitter that had further damaged the Chaos Lord’s helm and head within, at least Gabriel hoped given that one of the twin baleful spheres of fire that burned in the visor’s slit had winked out. In comparison, however, Gabriel felt the internal bionics of his body scraping and screeching against one another from the concussive forces that had been inacted upon them. His terminator armor all along the left side was partially melted slag, though his leg remained moderately functional. Which was more than he could say for his right, of which the forward third had been cut off entirely. One quasi-lascannon blast from the eyes on Mortirex’s daemonic power axe had torn through his side, and still burned where it had nearly cored his armor and body in one blow. The third he had managed to dodge entirely, and now all three eyes remained crusted shut.

“You were not as pathetic as I feared, but still manage to disappoint-,”

“HrraaaaAAAAAAGH!” Apollo’s guttural wheezing bellow caused Mortirex to turn, but for once the Chaos Lord was not fast enough to stop a smoking ruin of a space marine to leap atop his shoulders from behind.

Gabriel stared in abject horror at the burnt and punctured revenant that Apollo Diomedes had become. His armor had collapsed in fragments more akin to Hannibal Palrun’s state while fighting the Suysh. The Obliterators had not gone down easily, though Gabriel had been so consumed with his own fight that he could not spare an iota of any of his senses towards the other fight. Wounds riddled Apollo’s body, some seared shut by plasma weaponry or heavy flamer bursts, others were holes punched through him by smaller rapid-firing lasweaponry. Chainweapons of some kind or another had torn across his body, tearing through skin, flesh, and bone in more than one place. Only deliberate and willful suppression of the sus-an membrane could have kept him conscious. Even now, Apollo was still afire, warp-tainted flames still consuming parts of him as he swung his power mace down upon the Chaos Lord’s head.

“What is-?!,”

Gone was the noble warrior and storied hero, gone was the measured expertise of centuries of warfare. What remained was practically a savage and frenzied beast, snarling and clawing and swinging while gnashing their teeth.

More astonishingly, for a wonder, it worked. In the next few seconds as Gabriel marshalled what remained of his strength, grit his teeth, and pushed forward, Apollo struck regularly and mercilessly with Rogal’s Fist. The power mace almost seemed to sing as it cracked against Mortirex’s head, neck, shoulders, and back. One of the eyes upon the Chaos Lord’s axe began to writhe and twitch, protective crust of pus and dried blood flaking away as it blinked before being struck with the power mace, causing a monstrous yet ethereal screech to emit from the weapon that seemed to cause more pain to Mortirex than either Apollo or Gabriel. Distracted as Mortirex was, he could not stop Gabriel from rearing back and slamming Godsplitter squarely into his chest, and for the very first time in the fight, forced the Chaos Lord to stumble slightly. Dark, sludge-like fluids burst out from the minute number of cracks impressed into the breastplate, the closest equivalent to what blood the traitor possessed.

“ENOUGH!” Mortirex roared as he reached up and grabbed Apollo by the forearm bearing Rogal’s Fist mid-swing and tore the marine off of his shoulders and slammed him down into the ground with enough force to snap the bones of his arm instantly.

But he did not let go, and instead maintained his grip as he turned Apollo into a bludgeon against Gabriel, cracking even more of the bones within Apollo’s body against the venerable terminator plate that the Chapter Master bore and then against the deck plating, whichever was closest as the Chaos Lord advanced. Again, and again, and again, until with a sickening squelch Apollo’s entire right arm tore from his shoulder like a bloodied drumstick, hand still clutching the power mace. The very second the detachment occurred, Mortirex lashed out with his boot and struck Apollo directly in the center of his chest, his reward the rare but unmistakable sound of the solidified mass of a space marine’s ribcage shattering as Apollo was sent flying. The entire time, Gabriel could not properly retaliate, but as Apollo bounced off of the deck he took advantage of the opening to slam Godsplitter with all his might against the wrist that still held said arm, the thunderous crack of its energy field cracking apart armor and cratering the wrist deeply. With a pained roar, Mortirex was forced to let go of Apollo’s arm as the matter of his wrist was abruptly reduced by a third. Which, in turn, left him open for Gabriel to reverse his grip and slam the head of his hammer directly into the exact same point on Mortirex’s chest that he had beforehand. This time, full gouts of black blood sprayed outwards as a fist-sized portion of the armor crumpled inwards leaving a sizzling hole with a cloud of blue sparks. As Mortirex took a step back, Gabriel stepped forward and struck the same point a third time, forcing his foe back.

“Heh.”

This time, Mortirex did not stumble. He did not fall back. He instead accepted the pain of those three blows with a grunt before striking down with his axe at a diagonal angle. This close, his eagerness in finally managing to deal some true damage pushing him forward, Gabriel could finally not dodge. He had managed a considerable amount of dexterity in his terminator armor, to its very limits in fact. But finally, his luck in doing so ran out. For a moment, Gabriel did not quite comprehend how Mortirex was rising in his vision until he realized that he was in fact the one falling, his legs cut out from beneath him leaving his torso to collapse onto the deck with a heavy thud that set his head to ringing. He could not do more than stare as Mortirex pressed his boot against his chest and pressed down hard enough to hold him in place. The other boot stomped down on Gabriel’s remaining limb at the elbow, crunching down audibly. Small dribbles of sludge-like blood dripped out of Mortirex’s chest down onto Gabriel’s. The orbs of infernal flame that were his eyes flickered slightly, the previously disappeared one flickering back into existence.

“You should be proud, Blood Raven. You managed to bleed me. Araghast was the last to accomplish such a feat.”

A faint crackling joined in the chorus of creaking metal and cracked bone that assaulted his ears, and it took Gabriel a few seconds of effort to realize it for what it was. He strained, futilely, against Mortirex and consequently clanged his head to the side against his own armor against his implants.

“And to think, you were out there this entire time, waiting for me to whet Soulsplitter upon you. I think…yes,” Mortirex nodded slowly, tone at first conversational before growing more ominous, “Vandis has served his purpose. Abbadon is consumed with Cadia. This anchorage…shall be mine. A Black Crusade of my own shall set this entire Segmentum aflame. Perhaps…heh, I might even go to Ultramar. Face true space marines in battle, rather than you limp-wristed thin-blooded paltry pretenders to the legacy of the Legions!” He snarled at the end and pressed his boot further into Gabriel’s chest.

The same burning effects of his very feet were beginning to heat the ceramite coating and the adamantine beneath with an almost cheerful red and white glow.

“Vox origin signal confirmed. Initiating teleport!” A small, tinny voice announced in Gabriel’s ear from where he had activated his implant.

“Mmm?” Mortirex cocked his head to the side.

The Immaterium split open, briefly, only to snap away in a brief flash and burst of displaced air. Left in its place stood twenty terminator-clad Blood Ravens of the 1st Company and three squads of the 5th. At their head was none other than Brother-Captain Tarkus Varianus, whose eyes widened as he beheld the scene before him.

“You-,”

“FIRE!” Tarkus bellowed, and all loyalists present obeyed.

Five storm bolters, two heavy flamers, and three assault cannons proceeded to do so immediately. As did twenty bolters, five heavy bolters, two plasma guns, the relic bolter known as Deathdealer, and the flamer known as the Gift of the Seraphim. Epistolary Damion Tyrin let loose with five thin spears of blinding lighting from atop his staff that punched directly into the Chaos Lord’s chest where he had been struck thrice with Godsplitter and out of his back. While also firing his plasma pistol with his other hand. The assault terminators rushed forward, though ahead of them all came Chaplain Tarion, screaming a litany of hatred while firing his bolt pistol and swinging his crozius simultaneously. The reward for all of this was a pained bellow erupting out of Mortirex’s mouth as he was struck from all directions for a long pair of heartbeats before the melee attackers reached him.

Which, in turn, proved to be a mistake.

Though Mortirex had been pumped full of holes, set aflame and smoking from holes shot through his formerly mostly untouched armor, he had not fallen. Indeed, Tarion’s righteous assault came to a sudden end as the Chaos Lord shattered his crozius with a single swing of his axe that let loose another coruscating cutting energy field. Two assault terminators grunted as they were buffeted, one having to abandon his storm shield entirely as the explosive wake followed behind. Chaplain Tarion was not so lucky and was instead thrown closer to Mortirex rather than pushed away. To his credit, the chaplain managed one more impactful strike against the Chaos Lord’s knee before he was split down the middle, the infernal flames burning his progenoid glands and internal organs into burnt organic slag.

“Ranged only!” Tarkus bellowed to the assault terminators, who immediately acquiesced and retreated.

The moment they were out of immediate danger of being caught in the crossfire, all present with ranged weapons began firing again. Mortirex roared in pain at this, preparing to swing his axe once more in a potentially devastating horizontal slash, the fell energies gathering about the head of his power axe, only to grunt in abject surprise as he found himself unable to. Looking down, Mortirex stared as Gabriel glared up at him, his sole remaining arm, flexing and pulling against the Chaos Lord’s wrist. Similarly one-armed, Apollo Diomedes added his sole remaining hand to the effort, his face completely half-broken inwards and chest openly concave. Both should have been dead by then, or at the least forced into suspended animation, yet both openly spat defiance at him.

“Get…off!” Mortirex roared, only to for once somehow find that his strength was not as inexorable as it had been previously.

All the while, he was fired upon. By then, the other Blood Ravens had realized what still might happen. A non-verbal order by the veteran terminator sergeant Stromahn redirected all storm bolters and assault cannons squarely onto that arm. Aided by their own years of experience, supernatural skill and reflexes, and the auto-senses of their helmets, they threw more than half a hundred rounds to the exact same targeted point of the upper arm. Mortirex was forced to pull back and shield one half of his body with the other simply to prevent his limb from being severed by pure concentrated ranged firepower. Which, by necessity, dragged Apollo and Gabriel along, meaning that his side was exposed, and they were not. At which point sergeant Stromahn triggered the cyclone missile launcher he had deployed with, firing the last of its payload directly into the Chaos Lord’s back for the single second that it was exposed as he attempted to shake Apollo and Gabriel off.

And finally, finally, finally was Mortirex thrown fully off his feet and thrown to the ground in a crashing roll that bounced further. Whereupon he was struck by krak grenades thrown overhand to fly practically as missiles themselves in as straight and direct a path as possible. Another pained scream tore out of the Chaos Lord’s throat as anti-tank weaponry was deployed directly against him, as well as another concentrated blast of vicious lightning out of the Epistolary’s staff. Yet he rose despite the sheer volume of death being fired at him and slammed his axe into the ground. This time, the pane of opaque energies erupted into being not as an attacking blade but as a curved shield which stretched from ceiling to floor and from wall to wall. It took only a few more seconds of fire to realize that even assault cannons and grenades could not scratch it.

“Hah…hah….ahahah….AHAHAHAHA!” Mortirex’s breathless and noticeably pained breaths twisted into full-blown guffaws from behind the shield. “Yes…YES! This is what I was waiting for! A real test, a true fight! What a blessed day this is!”

“Show yourself, heretic!” Tarkus yelled as he reloaded his bolter. “Face us!”

“Oh, but I have, little loyalist,” Mortirex answered with a laugh, audibly straightening with a clunk of armor and whine of servos. “And what I thought to be a disappointing waste of time has proven so much more! Yes…we shall face one another again.”

The field expanded outwards rapidly without warning with enough explosive and violent force as to throw all the terminators present flying along with everyone else. Only Tarkus remained upright, having dug in his heels and clamped his hand against a torn panel of floor to do so. Mortirex bled from head to toe, leaving sizzling acidic black sludge against the ground from his various wounds. He was bent at the waist slightly, over a dozen fist-sized chunks were missing from his armor, and certain portions of his armor were covered in smoking craters left behind by plasma gun blasts. But even as Tarkus watched, some of those holes and craters almost seemed to wriggle at the edges, small tendrils and fibers so thin that they were nigh invisible stretching out across them. Seared and exposed pale flesh was rapidly scabbing over, mottling, and twisting into scrunched scar tissue as they healed.

“You are worth more than simply grinding into the dirt and executing here and now,” Mortirex said with only a slight wheeze. “No. I refuse to let this end so soon. Not when it is the best fight I have had in decades! Come, Blood Raven. This…shall be a contest for the ages!”

Then the Chaos Lord shifted his stance.

“All of you mongrels still alive, get to the ships! Release the gene-hounds to cover you,” he said, now speaking without any difficulty at all to an unseen target. Only then did he lower his gaze to look at the Blood Ravens once more as they struggled to their feet. “I shall see you on the battlefield, space marines. Do not disappoint me!” He finished with a laugh as a hellish light enveloped him.

With a crackle of Warp-tainted lightning and a scream of defiance turned pained gurgle from the Epistolary, the Chaos Lord disappeared to the shock of the Blood Ravens present.

“Chapter Master! Diomedes!” Apothecary Medici cried aloud, causing Tarkus to turn about.

Already, Apollo had clearly fallen into suspended animation, but Gabriel somehow managed to hold on.

“Tarkus…,”

In an instant, the Captain of the 5th Company had rushed over, falling to one knee by the Chapter Master’s side.

“Hold on, Angelos. Medici will-,”

“Tarkus,” Gabriel growled, his remaining hand gripping Tarkus’ own tightly. “You have…you have command.”

Only then did he go limp, unable to hold back from falling into suspended animation any longer. Tarkus stared numbly as Medici went about his frantic work and rose slowly. The thunder of boots caused him and many others to whirl about, only to find them pointing their weapons at the bloodied and shocked faces of a great number of Librarians. The Chief Librarian led them, his normally sage and calm visage pale and horrified as he gazed upon the tableau.

“Gabriel!”

“He may live,” Medici said tersely as his tools whirled to life. “Much of his wounds were to his bionics, a matter of repair and reattachment. If Apollo lives through the next hour, he will either require immediate interment into a dreadnought or extensive surgical work and bionic reinforcement to his skeletal structure.”

Justinius only stared in shocked silence, as did the other psykers, as they stared at two of the greatest heroes of the Chapter lay prone with only a few threads connecting them to the mortal coil. Tarkus looked at them all and sighed before connecting to the command vox line and input his codes.

“This is Captain Tarkus. Chapter Master Angelos has been incapacitated, but his last words beforehand were to give me command,” he announced to the entire Chapter. “I intend to honor his wishes and the Chapter both. I require status reports from all command elements immediately.”

Tarkus lowered his finger from his ear as he glanced at Justinius, who was now scrutinizing him. The briefest feathery touch graced Tarkus’ mind as the Chief Librarian scanned his memories for surety. It would have been a violation in any other instance, but against the forces of Chaos, he could not fault the Chief Librarian’s concerns. In turn, Justinius favored him with a respectful nod as he confirmed the truth of the matter, bringing both hands together around his staff as he planted it before himself.

“What are your orders, Captain Tarkus?”

“We cleanse the Litany and finish this battle,” Tarkus began before pausing as the vox squawked in his ear.

“Captain Tarkus,” the serf manning the vox station on the strategium of the Spiraling Fury, “The heretic battle barge! It’s…it’s leaving! And the two strike cruisers with it! Should we try and pur-we’re under attack, enemy cruiser screen, heading right towards us!”

Silently, Tarkus cursed.

“Defend yourselves, we shall have to finish those particular traitors off later. For now, we have a battle to win,” he said unhappily before glancing about at the rest of the Blood Ravens with him. “The Honor Guard are dead,” he said grimly, having recognized the corpses strewn about the area, “But some must guard Medici and aid in the transport of both Angelos and Diomedes to the Apothecarium.”

“I shall do it,” Sergeant Minos announced, the veteran assault terminator clutched at his thunder hammer so tightly that for a moment Tarkus wondered if he would break it. “Me and my squad shall do it.”

“Very well,” Tarkus nodded, “To the rest of you…move out!”

=====================================================================

As it turned out, ‘gene-hounds’ were abominations of cursed genetics work. Their lifespans were, according to the apothecary, surely less than a single decade due to the forces wrought upon their bodies. Enhanced thrice, with cybernetics, chemicals, and genetic treatments, they were practically biological versions of combat servitors with minds pumped full of hyper-adrenal stimulants to create near matchless aggression with an ogryn’s strength. Their durability was comparable as well, and as such it was the gene-hounds that survived longer than anything else. All remaining living Chaos Space Marines had teleported away, leaving their cultists servants behind with no recourse other than to go down fighting alongside the gene-hounds who were remarkably capable of using high-caliber weaponry and chainaxes literally welded to their arm, to the fatal surprise of more than one serf and at least two marines.

The damage dealt to the Litany of Fury was extensive, both on the inside and the out. It’s bombardment cannon had been heavily damaged, and would not be repairable without a visit to a Forge World, and more than half of its void shield generators had been shorted out and would take more than a week to patch repair. Other than that, its hull and superstructure had taken most of the damage. Ironically, the intent of the enemy to take it as a prize meant that it had taken little damage to most of its core systems. Most importantly damaged was the communication arrays, but those could at the least be swiftly repaired. The same could not be said of the two Avenger-class Grand Cruisers that the Imperial Navy had brought, which were complete and total lost causes. The strike cruisers too had taken little overall damage considering they had managed to cleanly reach the rear of the enemy formation and then had struck from behind the rest of the time while the Chaos Fleet was overcommitted. As for the Imperial Navy itself...

“Chapter Master I-, wait, who- Captain Tarkus?” Admiral Graves cut himself off in surprise as his image was holographically projected in the strategium.

The battle had taken its toll, the man’s uniform now sweat-stained and hair thoroughly unkempt. Large bags had appeared underneath his eyes as the exhaustion of an hours-long running battle for his life had extracted its price.

“Affirmative, Admiral Graves. If you would hold a moment,” Tarkus said as he shifted his eyes over to the other projector as it flickered to life.

“Gabriel! What the hell was-,” Inquisitor Adrastia similarly cut herself off as she was faced not with her old friend but with another. “Captain Tarkus,” she said in a far less familiar tone.

“I unfortunately have grim news to share with the two of you,” Tarkus began immediately before either could begin speaking further. “During the closing moments of the battle, the Chaos Lord in charge of the fleet boarded the Litany of Fury personally. He was confronted by Chapter Master Angelos and a number of other marines, Apollo Diomedes included.”

“Does Angelos live?” The Inquisitor cut in immediately, her normal expression somehow increasing in severity.

“He does,” Tarkus nodded, lips thinned, “But both he and Apollo are no longer in a condition to command, and it was the Chapter Master’s wish that I take command until he recovers.”

“By the throne,” Graves swore as he clapped a hand to his temple and rubbed at his face.

“Damn them,” Adrastia growled.

“In the meantime, damage was dealt to our auspex and communication systems, and other major and minor weapons emplacements,” Tarkus continued stoically. “What is the status of your ships?”

It was not the best possible report to have received.

But neither was it the worst.

The enemy had been so driven to get to grips with their foes that they had left behind optimal firing ranges and firing rates as well, clustering into closer range such that some ships could not fire at all lest their strike only their ‘allies’ at the same time. Surprisingly, only a small number of the Chaos ships proceeded to do just that, others simply forced to wait and rotate about in the void to try and reach a point where they could shoot the ships of the Imperium and the ships of the Imperium only. The initial torpedo salvo had done more damage than initially assumed, and the subsequent slugging match that had occurred had favored the Imperial Navy more than was feared. Which meant that they had only lost some of their eight Lunar-class cruisers and ten frigates rather than all of them. Though, in truth, the reason that they had taken such damage and losses was amplified by their need to protect the troop transports, which were far less capable of defending themselves. In truth, the only ship that was wholly without damage was the Vengeance-class Grand Cruiser of Inquisitor Adrastia, having arrived late in the fight once all dance partners were already committed. On the opposing side, the Chaos fleet was practically in tatters by last account, but frustratingly tatters that yet lived.

First, and most importantly, was the swift retreat of the heavily damaged Ruination of Purity and its attendant strike cruisers, who had fled using the rest of the fleet as a screen back towards the inner system with short-range warp jumps. Though the Blood Ravens had successfully boarded and destroyed the three Hades-class Heavy Cruisers, the sudden need to return to aid the Litany meant they could not repeat their feats against any other ships. The deployment of a single cruiser-tonnage experimental had seen to the immediate end of an entire enemy Avenger, with the twin to that traitor ship being blown apart by Admiral Graves and the numerous attack craft at his disposal. A good number of enemy destroyers had been destroyed, but more than one of the Chaos cruisers had executed emergency warp jumps to escape further in-system out of immediate pursuit range the moment they veered towards taking too much critical damage. Some had been destroyed in the attempt, but not all.

Crews were certainly somewhat depleted across most of the Imperial Fleet that remained as well due to numerous vigorous and violent boarding attempts. The Blood Ravens were not immune from that, though the nature of their ships that most of the damage was the to the immensely sophisticated systems that allowed them to run their vessels with comparatively reduced crews.

In the end, it could not be denied that victory had been won. But it could also not be denied that Lord Mortirex of the Black Legion had extracted quite a bloody toll for it.

Worse, there would be more bloodshed to come now that they were able to take a moment and actually test their long-range auspex systems and send out recon probes out within the contained system. Once again, the three of them had met by holographic communication.

“By the Emperor,” Graves sighed as the three of them collectively looked at the resulting data. “This is no mere pirate hideout on a hollowed out asteroid.”

“This is a festering boil of corruption and madness,” Adrastia hissed, her eyes wide in her outrage, “A pustule of heresy that has grown beneath the notice of the Imperium for far too long. The entire line of Vandis has been tainted by heresy for longer than any of us had known.”

That was one way to say it.

An impassive yellow sun sat at the center of System 384A, providing light and warmth to the five planets that orbited it. Each was occupied. Each was astonishingly developed. Initial examinations of the systems of the hulks of the Chaos-held ships by enginseers protected psychically by Blood Raven Librarians provided a small trove of clarifying information. At least once they’d stripped the information of soul-tainted scrapcode and infernal glyphs. Which, of course, also took time. Tarkus swore that, after this point at least, that he would request that at least a few techmarines be permanently stationed with the 5th Company or at least on the Litany of Fury. None had been brought along on this excursion, all instead sent towards the Mede Subsector with the majority of the Chapter.

“This is not the work of decades in secret and hiding,” Adrastia continued as her eyes flicked up and down the information the auspex was revealing. “This is the work of centuries!”

There was no other explanation for it.

“We know what they call this place for themselves, now,” Tarkus grunted as he looked over the psychically sanitized and ritually purified data slate. “Jubacael.”

“Named for the great, great grandfather of Marcus Vandis, no doubt,” Adrastia noted. “Perhaps even founded by him.”

“Always knew their House was off,” Graves grumbled as he slumped in his command throne. “Every Vandis I’ve ever met was slimy.”

“Then you should have reported it to the Inquisition, Admiral,” Adrastia’s voice was the chill of the void.

“If I reported every noble I’d ever met for being slimy, Inquisitor, you’d never have a spare moment to blink, let alone sleep,” Graves shot back.

Tarkus and Adrastia both blinked at this blatant response. Surely it was only the exhaustion from the fight and his lost ships and crews that let the man so boldly speak. For a moment, Tarkus wondered if she was going to teleport over to the man’s flagship and shoot him for doing so. Until, at least, Adrastia huffed and returned to her reading of the data in some purposefully chosen non-descript office or another in her ship. The flickering holographic imaging increased in static for a moment as she said leaned back in her chair.

“Fair enough, Admiral. But speak with such disrespect again, and I’ll burn you alive,” she said casually.

“Noted, Inquisitor,” Graves bowed his head.

“Now then…pfragh, ‘New Meridian’. Of course,” Adrastia rolled her eyes. “Of course they’d name their capital world that.”

New Meridian was unmistakably a Hive World, with numerous hives sprawling across its surface. A whole third of it was apocalyptic wasteland where, apparently, House Vandis sent its undesirables and disfavored. After the sanitization of what little information was recovered from the Chaos ship databanks, what had resulted was even further reduced. But auspex scans showed massive spires that radiated hellish energies, temples and settlements in tandem dedicated openly to the Chaos Gods. They also helped produce anti-orbital shields of both mundane and sorcerous design. It sat closest to the sun, baking in the heat while enormous solar energy arrays hung across its atmosphere connected to the planet below, simultaneously darkening what lay beneath heavily. Its defenses were considerable, as befitting its likely capital status in the system. Defensive emplacements, orbital stations, and its own fleet of ships that Tarkus rather suspected were loyal specifically to Vandis rather than to Mortirex.

“That will be a hell of a nut to crack with the forces we have,” Graves sucked some air through his teeth. “But I’m more worried about this ‘Opus Maxima’.”

It was a Forgeworld, or at least half-way on its way to one. Sprawling industry spread out across a cold planet furthest out from the sun, with whole forge-temple complexes the size of cities sitting in dried up ocean beds. Its own defenses were formidable, outright blocking auspex scans with scrap-code bursts and destroying recon probes with warp-incapable system monitor ships. More importantly, however, was the sight of the remaining Chaos ships hanging over Opus Maxima at its shipyard for repairs with far more sophisticated facilities and personnel than the Imperium possessed at the moment. While the facilities of the Dark Mechanicus had not fully claimed the whole of the planet, it would surely come with time if they were not stopped. A central complex the equal of a primary forge-temple on a true Forgeworld sat on the equator of the slowly rotating world, eight other lesser forge-temples connected to it with massive railways and passages. Stubby defensive emplacements were visible even at a distance, however with anti-orbital defensive lasers on the surface, which were joined in their efforts by the defensive orbital stations around not just Opus Maxima but all five of the planets in the system.

“It’s worse than that,” Adrastia shook her head. “He has clearly been consorting with xenos. Look what is orbiting over Aeterna and Croxnov.”

Despite the Blood Ravens deliberately not choosing to combat the Swells, it seemed that they were destined to fight against the Saharduin. For a small fleet of said species’ ships hung over the roiling ocean world of Aeterna connected to its space-elevator spires. Lengthy tracks of bone, flesh, and metal formed docking rings, while the elevators ascended and descended constantly carrying unknown materials back and forth. References were made by the scoured Chaos databanks for a xeno leader known as ‘Reaverlord Carnax’ who had allied with Vandis in exchange for an ocean world to breed his kind for further warfare. On the other hand, Croxnov was an arid nightmare above which hung nothing less than a Kroot Warsphere, though this one was most obviously corrupted by Chaos. Vast sigils painted in blood and viscera coated the outside of the enormous ship, and frankly how it had gotten through the gravity reef Tarkus could not understand. Below, swarms of kroot held gruesome court in savannahs full of ‘bladed-grass’ and ‘hungering trees’, whatever that meant. Tracks of swamps upon the planet were filled with loxoatl and galg, as well as creatures and species that even the vaunted databanks and Librarius of the Litany failed to identify. Entropic temporal distortions returned by the auspex scans suggested there was a notable Hrud presence as well. No orbital shielding existed on the planet, the corrupted xenos apparently feeling that their Warsphere was deterrent enough.

“Madness,” Graves said, almost in awe. “What, was he trying to go for every heresy simultaneously?”

Runao, the fifth and final world, sat in the perfect life-bearing band. As a result, it had been turned into nothing less than a fully formed Agri-World. Here, several ships hung protectively over it, as well as a rather significant number of orbital defense stations in multiple variants. Thankfully, if that word could even be fully applied, there were far less ground-based defense due to the need to use that land for other purposes. Whatever its specific crop-type was, it would have to be significant to produce for the remaining worlds sufficiently. If the orbitals could be cleared, the planet would be surely vulnerable, but due to its position within the system reaching it would be difficult without being attacked by the remaining Chaos and xenos fleets within the system.

Still, long range auspex scans could only do so much. The few attempts by the Librarians to pierce the veil within the system were rebuffed rather painfully by sorcerous wardings.

“There is nothing to do but keep moving forward,” Tarkus said quietly, making both look over at him through their projections. “If we retreat now, we leave with them fully aware that we know of their presence. They can increase their defenses, marshal their troops into defensive postures, fortify even further than they have. Call upon other allies, possibly outright build new ships,” he nodded towards the actuality sphere’s projection of the system.

“I don’t disagree,” Adrastia said with a deep sigh.

“We’re outnumbered,” Graves said pointedly. “If we get hit by all of those fleets at once, it won’t be pretty.”

“We can’t give them time to concentrate their forces, then,” Tarkus said as he rubbed at his chin. “We need to hit one of their fleets now before they can bring them all together to surround us.”

“The shipyards over Opus Maxima then?” Graves prompted.

“The defenses there are possibly the most potent in the entire system,” Adrastia pointed out.

“But it is also where a number of the ships are critically damaged,” Graves countered. “Every other fleet I see on the auspex is fresh. The moment we start moving towards one or the other, the others will surely respond.”

“Not necessarily,” Tarkus spoke up. “Upon our entrance into the system we heard the friction between Mortirex and Vandis. They’ve spent decades cooped up in close proximity. Who is to say whether or not they would aid him if he came under assault?”

“Mmm…possibly,” Adrastia pursed her lips. “Alternatively, we could try for Runao. Even as we speak, there are transport ships delivering rations and food supplies to the other worlds. If we burn that world to the ground, attrition might turn in our favor.”

It was a definite possibility, certainly. Even space marines required nutrition and sustenance to keep their superhuman bodies functioning. Only a short time needed to pass to before mass-starvation would set in and likely cause widespread damage. It was not as if any other major supplies were currently incoming through the gravity reef’s tunnels. On the other hand, the orbital defenses were significant to make up for the deficit on the ground. The ships that hung over Runao were untouched by the fighting thus far, and unlike Mortirex were possibly far more likely to be reinforced by other ships.

“Well, we need to decide quickly,” Graves mused. “Every minute we spend here deliberating is another minute they have to make the decision for us.”

Jubacael System Name Discovered!
Planets of Jubacael System Identified! Hidden Chaos Anchorage!
Litany of Fury bombardment cannon destroyed, cannot be repaired without Forgeworld assistance!
All Fire Ships Utilized, None Remain!
Apollo Diomedes In Hyper-Critical Condition! 70% Chance Of Requiring Dreadnought Internment To Survive!
Chapter Master In Critical Condition!
2 Chaos Avenger-class Grand Cruisers Destroyed! 3 Hades-class Heavy Cruisers Destroyed! 6 Carnage-class Cruisers Destroyed! 2 Hecate-class Cruisers Destroyed! 10 Iconoclast Destroyers Destroyed!

Captain Tarkus, What Is Your Decision? (Choose One)
GM NOTE: Refer to above for information on planets. Exact parameters, defenses, and numbers uncertain in most locations. Moratorium Of 12 Hours.
[] Opus Maxima, Proto-Dark Mechanicus Forgeworld. Significant defenses, Orbital Defense Stations, Planetary Monitor Ship Fleet, Remainder Of Initial Chaos Fleet. Small Dark Mechanicus Fleet.
[] Runao, Corrupt Agri-World. Significant but purely oribtal-based defenses. Defensive fleet present composed of cruisers and escorts
[] New Meridian, System Capital, Location of Ex-Governor Vandis himself. Thoroughly defended Hive World. Two thirds of planet Hive, one third toxic wasteland.
[] Aeterna, Ocean World, Held by Chaos-aligned Saharduin, ruled by Reaverlord Carnax, further information unknown. Ten Saharduin Torrent-class Cruisers present.
[] Croxnov, Arid Feral World, Held by Chaos-corrupted Kroot. Single Kroot Warsphere in orbit. No other notable anti-orbital defenses or vessels.
[] Retreat Like A Coward, Shaming The Chapter And Ensuring The Enemy Can Prepare Better In The Meantime, Dishonoring the Blood Ravens Forevermore And Blighting All Future Campaigns

Spoiler: Imperial Fleet

Blood Ravens
1st Company: SC Spiraling Fury + 2 Escorts (1 Gladius/1 Hunter Destroyer)
5th Company: BB Litany of Fury + SC Rage of Erudition + SC The Great Father’s Fist + 7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
20 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius (+All Unassigned Librarians)
75 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Chapter Master Gabriel Unavailable For Deployment
Apollo Diomedes Unavailable For Deployment

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage)
5 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor to Moderate Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor to Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class.

Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
3 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Initial Chaos Fleet, Currently In Orbit Around Opus Maxima

1 Battle Barge 'Ruination of Purity' (Significant Damage Sustained)
2 Strike Cruisers 'Joyous Lament' 'Rex Magnifica' (Minor Damage Sustained)
4 Carnage-class Cruisers (Critically Damaged)
2 Hecate-class Cruisers (Critically Damaged)
5 Iconoclast Destroyers (Critically Damaged)

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
81 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
8 Khornate Berserkers
100 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
Hundreds of Cultist Troopers
10 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Six)

[] Opus Maxima, Proto-Dark Mechanicus Forgeworld. Significant defenses, Orbital Defense Stations, Planetary Monitor Ship Fleet, Remainder Of Initial Chaos Fleet. Small Dark Mechanicus Fleet.
[] Write-In: Before moving towards our target (but after whatever emergency repairs we're making before movement, if any, are finished) send a message to Vandis saying "You were so eager to boast of the 'servants' you were given in exchange for your soul, but we see how readily the pacts of traitors are rewarded with further treachery. Does it burn you to know you sold your soul for nothing, heretic?" and attaching a vox recording of Mortirex saying "And to think, you were out there this entire time, waiting for me to whet Soulsplitter upon you. I think…yes, Vandis has served his purpose. Abbadon is consumed with Cadia. This anchorage…shall be mine. A Black Crusade of my own shall set this entire Segmentum aflame. Perhaps…heh, I might even go to Ultramar." And just ending the call at that, bonus points if we can hang up on Vandis mid-sentence when/if he's replying.

GM NOTE: Moratorium 6 Hours

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

“Vox is ready, Captain,” the serf at the communication console announced.

Tarkus grimaced as he looked at the projections of the actuality sphere, both of the enemy and of those of the Blood Ravens and their allies. It was, perhaps, an equal fight. Possibly. But an equal fight here, would mean even harder ones for the rest of the system. The Blood Ravens could be as strategic and skilled as possible, but fortune still carried the fatal possibility of bending against them. It was time, now, to see if they might bend it in the other direction.

“Go,” Tarkus nodded.

This time, it was the Blood Ravens who cast out across the entire system, broadcasting towards New Meridian. First was the recording, of Mortirex’s own words, his vile ambition and hellish disdain. A handful of seconds were allowed to pass, to process, before Tarkus cleared his throat and spoke.

“You were so eager to boast of the ‘servants’ you were given in exchange for your soul,” Tarkus ground out through gritted teeth, hands clenching on the lip of the actuality sphere’s projector table. “But we see how readily the pacts of traitors are rewarded with further treachery. Does it burn your soul to know you sold your soul for nothing, heretic?”

Fayhem Roll: 47

Only silence answered. Tarkus narrowed his eyes as the actuality sphere projections flickered outwards into showing the entire system. The xeno ships did not shift or move. The fleet over New Meridian did not suddenly begin swarming towards Opus Maxima. There was a flurry of increased comm traffic, that was detectable at least, towards the rest of the planets in the system. But more than that was hard to tell without dedicated techmarine support. And they had all gone to aid the Ebon Claws, none requested for this effort. The tech-priests seconded to the ships of the Imperial Navy and Imperial Guard were doing their best, however. Somewhat more disheartening, Graves had reported rather unhappily that some of his astropaths had just about burnt themselves out – literally – trying to force communications through the gravity reef. Intense enough gravity could strangle and cause terrible issues with the Warp, and where the Warp was twisted, psychic emanations and communications grew difficult as well. There was no bright bloom of weapons fire, or anything of the sort.

“Enough of this,” Tarkus shook his head. “Onward to Opus Maxima. We cannot simply wait for the enemy to maneuver.”

=============================================================

Frigandus Cordis was a massive terrestrial planet of ice, glaciers, and snow. The razorstorms here were capable of shredding through adamantine and ceramite due to the unique molecular and chemical composition of the frozen liquids of the planet, though the specifics evaded Cyrus’ understanding. Then again, he didn’t need to understand every single thing about them, only that it did what it did. He watched impassively as the swarm of tyranids squealed and screamed as they were turned into steaming piles of shredded meat, the rapid approach of the storm having caught the aliens off-guard. They were doing as they always did, adapting, growing more and more dangerous the longer they spent in an adverse environment. But they hadn’t yet evolved some form of defense other than psychic shielding emanating from bio-structures and zoanthroapes from the razorstorms. Apparently the planet had always been that way, a horrifically dangerous place where megafauna still lived in the deep tunnels and on the frozen plains, where the human tribes had learned that silence and careful movement was more valuable than almost anything else to survive.

Speaking of which, he sighted one such synapse creature and fired at it, once. The sheer velocity behind the sniper round managed to make it through the razorstorm, and the resulting feedback eruptions ensured the rest of the incoming swarm died a swift death.

“A good shot,” murmured the Ebon Claw next to him. “And with that, the last of their major synapse creatures is destroyed.”

Captain Manin was dressed as much of the rest of his company, in the whites and blues that camouflaged perfectly with the greater environment of the planet. Twin lightning claws did not crackle or spark, their power fields deliberately kept deactivated when not required to further reduce noise profile. The rest of his company was spread throughout the planet along with the rest of the Blood Ravens, each of them astonishingly capable when it came to stealth and recon despite the fact that over half of their number utilized jump packs. Cursory and non-invasive inspection on the part of the techmarines had informed Cyrus that the patterns of the jump packs was something clearly altered and divergent, likely supplied to them by the Raven Guard of whom the Ebon Claws were successors to. Despite being outnumbered, the tyranids invading this area of space outnumbering the splinter fleet which had come to Subsector Aurelia, they had fought a spirited, vigorous, and technically successful defense.

It was simply unfortunate that there were only two companies left of them, even before the tyranids arrived. Less, before the Blood Ravens had managed to get there. Captain Manin’s peer, Brother-Captain Kambine, had fallen to the tyranids, his body so torn apart that not even his gene-seed could be recovered. All told, of the 9th and 10th Companies of the Ebon Claws, there were only about a hundred left. Though Cyrus had not yet said it aloud, it had been otherwise confirmed by Captain Manin’s own gratitude that the Ebon Claws would have been extinct in but a few more years’ time.

“There will be more,” Cyrus grunted. “But for now, Frigandus is free of major threat.”

“It will be the work of decades to eradicate every tyranid spore and cell,” Manin sighed, even that noise quiet through his helmet’s systems. “But yes, the Hive Mind no longer has a hold here, only its dregs. I must pass on my compliments to your techmarines once more, Captain Cyrus. Without their work and their turrets, we could not have held the tunnels and caverns as we had.”

Cyrus grunted at his words.

“Martellus will be pleased to hear it.”

Once he got over the fact that some of those turrets had been destroyed in those same vital ambushes.

“In the meantime, we have much work left to do. While we destroyed the Shadow Towers on Frigandus, other planets reported that the tyranids were assembling biomass in similar fashion.”

The two began walking away from the scene as the razorstorm continued to pelt downwards.

“It will be a hard fight to get through their protective screens,” Manin muttered. “But doable.”

“It must be done regardless,” Cyrus said sourly, his usual grimace deepening. “These new structures must be eradicated, this entire splinter must be, lest the rest of the Hive Fleets in the galaxy gain access to them.”

Cyrus had not been pleased to learn about the Shadow Towers. An unwholesome flesh pylon of towering height and size the equal of Titans God-Machines, purposefully crafted to propagate the Shadow in the Warp, ruining astropathic communication and warp travel. It had nearly destroyed the entire Blood Ravens fleet, forcing them out of the Warp in the middle of a number of bio-ships just waiting for something to crush and devour. Each one looked like thousands of zoanthropes melted together, each one practically made the navigators, astropaths, and Librarians nearly pass out from the pressure on their minds and souls. Only one had been successfully spawned on Frigandus Cordis, but other planets would have more, each one linking with another and forcing them to drop out of the Warp further and further away, all while giving the Hive Mind more time to devour the planets it had landed on. It was the perfect addition to the tyranid arsenal, giving them the one resource more than biomass that was important to keep from their grasping talons: time. The greater distance, the more time it forced upon Imperial reinforcements, the more they were able to consume without interruption.

It was in wars like this that Cyrus felt that even the forces of Chaos were not as big a threat to the galaxy as the tyranids.

“Indeed. To battle, then. Some initiates will remain behind, to see to what tyranid biomass that they can, but the rest of what remains of the Ebon Claws shall accompany you outwards,” Manin said, offering his hand out.

Cyrus looked down at it, then back up to Manin, the Captain’s helmet scarred and pitted from tyranid claws and acids, before clasping wrists.

“To battle, then.”

============================================================

Opus Maxima was not a Forge World on the same scale as Mars, or even Aerus or Zerann. But it clearly held the possibility of reaching such levels of stature if given time to fester into full bloom. It was enough that it held multiple forge-temples, the equivalents of entire hives that no doubt manufactured all a manner of weaponry and goods for the purposes of the forces within the system. Those that would take them at least. Surely some of it was dedicated to arming the vile xenos who had been corrupted by Chaos, yet another blasphemy added onto the tally of their very existence. It was, on the one hand, the world that was furthest out from any other from the sun, which should have made it the chilliest of all of them, save for the fact that massive and merciless industry had well-clogged its skies enough that it was in fact a blasted and cracked heat-baked wasteland. It’s massive glaciers had melted into oceans and lakes, and those had been drained further by dreadful mechanized force. Nine complexes, the largest of them at the center of the tangled web with massive railways built between them as mechanical veins.

Above, the shipyard waited. Not only had the remaining – and critically damaged - ships of the Chaos fleet retreated here for repairs, with obvious priority being given over to the ships of the trio of ships directly under the command of Lord Mortirex, but there was a group of monitors as well. Without the need for speed, maneuverability, or warp-travel, their systems had been routed into powering lance arrays and weapon batteries capable of threatening even capital-class ships if given the chance. Enough of them could include battle barges within their reach. Amongst the rest of them were the small number of Dark Mechanicus vessels, their capabilities unknown due to the proclivities of their heretical kind in alteration and experimentation, and a brace of orbital defense stations. Below, on the planet itself, squatted anti-orbital defense lasers and massive void shield emplacements set around each of the forge-temples, things built to strike the ships of the space marines should they attempt to get close enough to land, and protect their charges from orbital bombardment.

Not that the Litany of Fury would be doing any such thing, the sheer damage dealt to its bombardment cannon ensuring that only a visit to a true Forge World could see to its repairs. Yet that did not mean that the other strike cruisers were incapable, only that overall bombardment would be reduced in efficacy by a considerable amount. The Litany remained fearsome, but her foes had worked quite hard to strip her outer carapace of weapons and defenses. Even now her void shields had just barely come back online, and only at half-strength. Most of her weapon batteries were slag. The superstructure remained viable, as did its engines and deployment methods, but the damage was undeniable. The ships of the Imperial Navy fared only a bit better, minor to moderate damage across all ships save for the Inquisitor’s and the transport vessels. The moment they began to approach, the system monitors reoriented towards them, though the Dark Mechanicus ships were not eager to get to grips while so thoroughly outnumbered.

"Well, here we are," Graves said as Tarkus opened communications with him and Inquisitor Adrastia. "Let's get to it, we don't have much time."

Tarkus knew he was right. Already, auspex scans were showing that some of the Chaos ships were rapidly attempting to unmoor themselves to return to fighting. Grotesque work crews swarmed about their bodies, servitors, machines, and near indescribable amalgamations of flesh and metal sprouting tools and cutters.

"We need to take out those ships, one way or another, preferably before too many of them can get a shot off on us," the Admiral rubbed at his chin.

"Approaching too close puts us at risk to the orbital stations and those Dark Mechanicus ships," Adrastia cut in.

"We may have to take that risk," Graves noted. "We can take on those orbitals and monitors, keep the hereteks back. Captain," he looked at Tarkus, "Can your space marines punch through and hit the docked ships?"

"Possibly," Tarkus nodded. "We must all be wary, however, they have defense lasers on the planet, and may strike up at us if they get a clean shot."

"Even if they don't, they still might shoot," Adrastia noted. "As an aside, Captain Tarkus, what of Gabriel and Apollo?"

Tarkus hung his head and inhaled deeply.

"Angelos will live. Repair of bionics and flesh is proceeding apace. Apollo...,"

Entombment Or Not: 71

"Will live as well, but it will take time to graft the bionics and mend his body."

It had been an incredibly near thing. Apollo Diomedes had been shot, almost quite literally, to pieces. To the point that his body was practically reminiscent of an ancient Terran curdled milk product. The Obliterators had utilized weapons that were known and unknown, of comparatively normal and utterly exotic extent. Bolters rounds had been joined by las-shots, struck with rounds disturbingly reminiscent to Vindicare rifles, as well as slivers of crystallized venom that dissolved into the blood while forcing immediate necrosis of the surrounding tissues, gouts of daemonic flame in excess of ceramite and adamantium-survivable temperatures, and more. Worse, obliterators were not restricted to mutating out purely ranged weaponry, as Apollo's wounds reflected. Chainswords, power weaponry, and pure brutal bludgeoning had been applied from head to toe. Then Apollo had attacked and been battered even further by Lord Mortirex.

His living at all was a miracle, the Brother-Apothecary Medici had flatly declared, that the apothecary had kept him from requiring internment in a dreadnought a second one.

"We must fight on without them both, for now," Tarkus said firmly.

"Very well," Adrastia nodded.

Spoiler: Fleet Over Opus Maxima

In Dock At Shipyard [Maintains Point Defenses, No Major Weaponry]
1 Battle Barge 'Ruination of Purity' (Significant Damage Sustained)
2 Strike Cruisers 'Joyous Lament' 'Rex Magnifica' (Minor Damage Sustained)
4 Carnage-class Cruisers (Critically Damaged)
2 Hecate-class Cruisers (Critically Damaged)
5 Iconoclast Destroyers (Critically Damaged)

Out Of Dock
1 Dark Mechanicus Heavy-Cruiser [Class/Weaponry Unknown]
3 Dark Mechanicus Cruisers [Class/Weaponry Unknown]
5 Defense Monitors [Anti-Capital Ship Weaponry]
10 Orbital Defense Stations [Torpedoes, Lances, Weapon Batteries]

Captain Tarkus, How Shall We Do Battle?
Moratorium 6 Hours
[] Ship By Ship: The damaged Chaos ships are quite fragile at this moment, especially with their inability to maneuver and fight back. The Blood Ravens can strike them, destroy them from within, and move on, all while sabotaging the Chaos-tainted shipyard as they go. Dangerous to the marines themselves, but less so to the ships that ferry them about if they move in, deploy, and retreat. [Write-In Target Priority List, i.e. Focus On Escorts, Focus On Battle Barge, Etc.]
[] At Lance's Length: There is no guarantee of what awaits on those ships, or on that shipyard. While the main bombardment cannnon is down on the Litany, that does not mean that the remaining Blood Raven ships cannot concentrate fire and tear apart the ships there, while hopefully remaining at enough range to prevent planetary defenses from striking them. [Write-In Target Priority List, i.e. Focus On Escorts, Focus On Battle Barge, Etc.]
[] Write-In

Spoiler: Imperial Fleet

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Void Shielding At 50%, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
20 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius (+All Unassigned Librarians)
75 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Remains Unconscious, Repairs Possible By Tech-Priests Accompanying Imperial Guard/Imperial Navy

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage)
5 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor to Moderate Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor to Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class.

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
3 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Seven)

Spoiler: Plan: Spin the Cylinder

-[X] Write-in: Move the fleet directly above the shipyard (to interpose it between our fleet and the planetary defenses) in a rotating cylinder formation. The space marines will board the shipyard and deal with the docked ships while the fleet fights the rest of the enemy forces engaging with them.
--[X] The cylinder formation will look like a cylinder of ships oriented "vertically" above the shipyard; like circling the wagons over the shipyard, except with wagons floating over other wagons. We will bring that formation there by bringing our ships "above" the shipyard while out of range of the planetary defenses before pushing directly "down" towards the shipyard with our toughest/least damaged ships at the front (which will be the "bottom" of the cylinder once it's in place). The cylinder will continuously rotate around the vertical axis of the cylinder, repairing, stabilizing shields, and preparing fresh broadsides while on the side of the cylinder facing away from the enemy fleet forces. Our ships will "roll ship", i.e. rotate on their horizontal axis, and swap which side is on the safe inside of the cylinder to protect/repair a side that was taking more damage and/or swap out which broadside they're using as advisable. The troop transports and the Litany of Fury are inside the cylinder, with the Litany of Fury in between the transports and the shipyard to soak fire.
---[X] Fleet targeting priorities: focus down the monitors first with most weapons. Once the monitors are down concentrate on focusing down the Dark Mechanicum ships if any are still engaging. Our SCs will use their bombardment cannons against the orbital defense stations however since those are most effective against stationary targets.
---[X] Throughout, whenever ships can free up a broadside to target docked ships (e.g., by rolling ship to use the inside-the-cylinder broadside while they are on a side of the cylinder facing away from enemy fleet elements to target before rolling back) they will use them to attack the docked CSM ships, targeting the Strike Cruisers as first preference and the Battle Barge as secondary preference. If the orbital defense stations on the "away-facing" side of the cylinder are proving too much trouble and the SC bombardment cannons aren't taking them out quickly enough, any such "freed up" broadsides will target them instead.
---[X] The Litany of Fury will focus fire from its remaining weapon arrays on knocking out the shipyard's point defenses, prioritizing any that might be in a position to shoot past the Litany and target the troop transports. The Litany of Fury and the point defense on the other ships at that end of the cylinder will shift all fire to targeting anything that launches from the docked CSM ships if/when they try to launch anything, however. Any fighters in the area will likewise prioritize shooting down anything launching from the CSM ships.
---[X] Ignore docked enemy ships unless they manage to undock; in that case finish them off before returning to the priorities above. If multiple ships manage to undock, any CSM ships undocking take immediate highest priority.
--[X] Boarding Priority list: Strike Cruisers -> Battle Barge 'Ruination of Purity' -> Hecate-class Cruisers -> Carnage-class Cruisers -> Iconoclast Destroyers.
---[X] When boarding, focus on destroying the controls/mechanisms that would be used to allow the docked ships to unmoor, ideally from inside the shipyard. Either way, try to also lockdown/jam the airlocks etc. that would be used to board the shipyard from the ships. Each independently-operating detachment of marines will have two tech-priests with them to assist with this; each tech-priest will have a marine assigned as a personal bodyguard, and each pair of tech-priests will be kept physically separated from each other (insofar as feasible) to make it harder to take them both out at once. The necessary tech-priests will be transferred from Graves' ships before the fleet approaches. Each tech-priest may bring one servitor with them for assistance.
---[X] As advisable/feasible, leave defensive detachments by the CSM ships to fortify and take advantage of the natural chokepoints of the airlocks/docking connections for if/when the CSM try to break through, withdrawing to rejoin the main detachments if it looks like a position could be in danger of being overrun.
---[X] Once the docked ships are stuck, divert the shipyard (and hence all its attached ships) into the most direct collision course possible with the largest complex at the center of the web. If this tactic becomes unfeasible due to taking too long or for any other reason, change priority to simply destroying the ships.
--[X] Assuming the shipyard is successfully diverted as planned, the cylinder formation will initially move with the shipyard as it is redirected to keep it between them and the planet; once it appears the enemy's planetary defenses realize they will need to target the shipyard to try to break it up before impact, the fleet will take advantage of this changed priority to disengage in relative safety.

Voting Moratorium: 12 Hours

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

The various captains of the fleet paused for approximately two seconds before responding to Tarkus’ orders. The moment they’d come into closer range, the monitors began to advance. Though they were not the size of battleships or even necessarily cruisers, their equipment could not be discounted. Without the bulk and energy draw of the engines and systems required for Warp travel and in certain cases even moving beyond a small area around their planet of responsibility, such vessels could wield weapons of devastating effectiveness. The thought had come to Tarkus like a bolt of lightning as he’d scrutinized the enemy defenses, the placement of their stations, and the shipyard where the quarry they’d come to chase had hastily ensconced themselves. Immediately, the ships of the Imperial Navy, battered but not yet broken, pushed forward in response not only to the monitors but the rapidly moving ships of the Dark Mechanicus. The vessels of the Blood Ravens, by contrast, rushed past as quickly as they could, for their course would take them directly to the shipyard before any other vessel. Below, at least a dozen massive anti-orbital defense lasers lit up on the auspex, charging themselves to fire at extreme range.

There was a very short estimated time before they fired.

“I sure hope you know what you’re doing, space marine,” Admiral Graves said through gritted teeth as the first long range weapon exchanges began. “And may the God-Emperor be with you.”

“May He be with us all,” Inquisitor Adrastia said coolly as her own ship joined the vessels of the Imperial Navy.

The most critical part, of course, was the troop transports. More vulnerable than any other ship present, they would have to rush above the shipyard and attempt to find some measure of safety, if such a thing could be possible at all.

Advancing Past 78 vs. 60

Weapon arrays fired and void shields flared. The initial salvoes chipped the plating on some of the cruisers of the Imperial Navy, but the doughty ships of the Blood Ravens soared forward on wings of fire without a single void shield breaking. They had, of all the ships of the Imperium present, sustained essentially no damage at all. Their skill and speed had served them in the previous fight, and served them well now. Though the point defenses of the shipyard were not inconsiderable, they were not, in truth, rated for taking down ships meant to sit over planets and lay siege to them. Tremendous lance blasts fired from the monitors, yet before they could focus fire on any of the strike cruisers or the troop transports behind them, the Imperial Navy had closed to optimum range. Orbital stations began to rotate, to turn, reactors glowing and ammo loading, each of them a piece of dread artifice crafted by the Dark Mechanicus many decades ago. But most direly important, thankfully, the defense lasers on the planet below remained lit, charged, and yet they could not fire, lest they strike the shipyard itself.

“Bombardment cannons loaded, Captain,” a servitor connected to the weapon’s systems calmly stated. “Boarding pods and assault rams prepared.”

“Fire and deploy, brothers!” Tarkus called across the command vox channel as he stomped onto the teleportarium platform.

Assembling Cylinder 34 vs. 50

Deploying Boarders 72 vs. 50

Though the Litany of Fury was undoubtably damaged, with its void shields reduced to 50% capacity and over two thirds of its weapons slagged, it remained a powerful implement of war. As a bulwark, if nothing else, its hull capable of withstanding even greater damage for far longer. As such, when the first few lance blasts struck it, the first torpedoes snaking their way forward, it joined the cylinder formation and utilized what weapons it had as well as its own bulk to serve before maneuvering horizontally while aligned vertically to protect the troop transports. Assault rams thumped out down towards the shipyard where so many ships yet waited, several of them straining to try and force themselves out of the docking clamps which had held them in place for repairs. The cylinder came into place, then, as all ships present managed to join the formation, but it was not without damage. Some of the ships of the Imperial Navy trailed, their engines stuttering at final moments, their techpriests screeching about a ‘corrupted Noosphere and scrap code assaults’ allowing torpedoes to strike them in the rear. The monitors and the Dark Mechanicus ships rushed forwards, desperate to force the enemy back out from the shield that the shipyard had inadvertently become. The strike cruisers of the Blood Ravens, by contrast, angled themselves so that their bombardment cannons could fire upon stationary targets while their other weapon arrays fired at other targets.

All the while, a storm of fury and adamantium was thrust down into the belly of the shipyard proper.

===============================================================

The Joyous Lament and Rex Magnifica’s previous affiliations were wholly unknown, by this point. Perhaps they had never been loyal ships to the Imperium at all. It was not beyond the Dark Mechanicus to create new vessels whole cloth, things filled with fell technosorceries and made with stolen STC plans. In the end, it didn’t matter. Though they had sustained very little damage, at least compared to the rest of the initial fleet that had confronted the interlopers, they had still entered the docks to patch what damage they had taken. After all, they deserved such things, their crews and complements being superior to the slavering creatures that Vandis favored out of jealousy. Thus, they had taken priority, and so were in the near absolute center of the shipyard, the ship crewed by the mortals spiraling outwards in order of entry and importance. Yet now that same insistence had turned against them. The destroyers were already halfway released from docking, still trailing atmosphere and their weapons sparking, but it would take far longer for them to be freed unless they outright forced themselves out of the shipyard – sustained damage and dealing damage to the center of the shipyard itself.

Secondary concerns, at best.

For the Blood Ravens had come for them.

The shock of discovering a massive Black Legion base had passed. The information, the realization, had been taken, examined, and accepted with all the grim fatality that space marines possessed. For they had been born, crafted, into war. There was no space marine that had died peacefully in the history of the Imperium. At peace, occasionally, if the death was worthy, was satisfactory. And, in truth, there were fewer more satisfactory deaths, more worthy deaths, than battling chaos space marines. Traitors, fallen creatures of foul character and weak wills. Betrayers of the Imperium, of the Emperor. Thus, shock turned to acceptance, turned to righteous fury and anger. Vengeance needed to be taken for the Honor Guard, for Captain Doukas Laskaris, for Apollo Diomedes and Chapter Master Angelos. For all the uncounted fallen slain by the Black Legion since the Horus Heresy. The 5th Company, led by their Captain, appeared on the Joyous Lament in flashes of lightning and thunder, and less than a heartbeat later began firing. There was no hesitation offered, for none was given by the chaos space marines and cultists present upon those ships. The situation was similar upon the Rex Magnifica the moment the terminators of the 1st Company arrived.

“BLOOOOOOOD RAAAAAAAAVEEEEEEENS!!!”

The bellowed voice of Mortirex boomed across the vox systems of the Chaos ships, followed shortly by a deep guffaw.

“BRAVE OF YOU TO COME HERE, STRAIGHT INTO OUR TEETH!” He laughed again, voice bending and bouncing around the corridors that were illuminated by dim red lighting and the muzzle flashes of many bolters. “Brave, but stupid! Perhaps if I peel your helmets off, I will find Butcher’s Nails! But then, such sodden collapsed brains as must reside in your glass boned bodies and covered by your paper thin skins is more likely the simple result of your suckling at the Emperor’s rotten desiccated toes for a salvation that will never come!”

Tarkus did not even bother responding.

He had traitors to kill.

Boarding Parties: 88 vs. 7

And kill traitors the Blood Ravens did.

Sergeant Stromahn crushed the head and upper torso of a charging Khornate berserkers with his power fist before shoving his storm bolter into the open mouth of a possessed marine and firing until the smallest tendrils stopped twitching. Around him, the rest of his terminators fired at their attackers while behind him Sergeant Minos liberally smashed apart consoles and mechanisms at the directives of the tech-priests that had accompanied them. To be frank, the tech-priests were terrified, screeching in frantic binary at one another as they worked, but then they’d never expected to be part of boarding parties in their lives. Especially not ones like this, where the goal was not even immediate destruction, but blocking.

Chief Librarian Justinius did not even turn his head as he struck out with his force staff, catching a surprisingly silent chaos space marine around the midsection. The power sword that had been about to plunge into his back dropped uselessly to the ground as the staff passed through the chaos space marine’s midsection. Though it was not a force sword, in truth the limitations of the physical world were more guidelines to psykers such as he. Instead it was a blade of pure psychic force that cut the marine in half, flash-boiling the organs within fatally. Nearby, other librarians fought the enemy, deployed despite their rank by virtue of the fact that they just needed that many more hands firing bolters and plasma guns. Docking clamps were slagged, airlocks were literally melted and blocked off by the hands of Epistolary Idmon. Codicier Aeneas, on the other hand, who had proven to have little psychic skills in all but a few sectors, was of no help for such matters. On the other hand, he was perfectly suited for killing the enemy while the rest of his brothers worked, dipping in and out of the Warp and leaving severed body parts and multi-parted corpses in his only occasionally present wake.

By pure serendipity alone, or perhaps not, the tech-priests spoke in the same span of seconds.

“Docking systems partitioned and disabled!”

“Then onwards, brothers!” Tarkus yelled immediately. “The shields of the shipyard have regenerated, we must move on foot! Speed is of the essence!”

“MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!”

Above, in the void, the battle was just as fierce.

=========================================================

Cylinder Over Opus Maxima: 41 vs. 19

The monitors were burning hulks, as were a number of orbital stations, but the damned ships of the Dark Mechanicus were as of yet practically untouched, despite the damage that had been sustained by the ships of the Imperial Navy in the fight thus far. They fired with their own long range weaponry, skating across and popping the void shields of his ships, but managed to skitter backwards the moment he tried to do the same to them. The tech-priests were already screeching about ‘breaching the holy specifications laid down by the Omnissiah’, but all that mattered was that the enemy kept backing off faster than he could get any damage on them. It couldn’t last, not in the long run. A death by a thousand cuts? Not on his watch.

“Could never stand a dance partner that won’t bloody commit,” Joshua Graves muttered as he scrutinized the actuality sphere. “Will someone please get a lance lock on those damned ships?!” He shouted to the rest of the bridge.

“Trying, Admiral, but…the auspex, the targeting cogitators keep fuzzing up!” His chief gunnery officer shouted back. “It’s not just the lances, it’s the macro cannons as well!”

Graves dragged his hand down his sweaty face and grimaced.

“All right. We do this the hard way then. Load up some interceptors with targeting lasers,” he said with a bowing of his head.

It was, effectively, a death sentence for several of the pilots. He knew it. They knew it. The point defenses of the Dark Mechanicus ships were as untouched as the rest of them. Whatever sensor baffling they possessed was effective only at long range, not close range, as he’d managed to figure out before the cylinder was fully assembled. Thus, the interceptors would have to fly up, and close, and maintain locks so that the weapons of the actual ships could find their targets. In the meantime, they would absolutely take casualties. At such distances, ejecting would only prolong death for a short time. Given how the battle was going, there was no chance that Graves would be able to retrieve them in time before their oxygen ran out – if the enemy didn’t kill them first.

At least they got most of the orbitals and monitors down.

Undocking: 20

“Admiral! Enemy ships undocking! Destroyers, Iconoclast-class!”

“God Emperor’s blood,” Graves snarled. “Redirect, redirect now!”

Trailing fire, critically damaged in almost every system, he could tell by the auspex readings of their strained engines – the destroyers had no intention of returning to dock. Any dock. Ever. The fire ships had been useful, those that had actually been utilized properly and not blown up fruitlessly. Just went to show that perhaps there was a reason the Imperial Navy was the main power in the void, and not the space marines who sometimes forgot not all ships were built like their own. Now, before his very eyes, the destroyers were accelerating for one final explosion, one last act of devotion and sacrifice before their blasted Dark Gods.

Killing Suicide: 46

Graves breathed a sigh of relief as all five went up in explosions that thankfully only buffeted his ships, but the relief died quickly as he watched the interceptors launch and head out.

“Let’s make their sacrifice count!” He called, “Be ready for targeting laser locks!”

===========================================================

Boarding Parties: 65 vs. 5

In a direct reversal of the immediate past, now it was the Blood Ravens charging into the depths of a traitor-held battle barge. Unlike the strike cruisers, however, where they had pushed through quickly, Tarkus was quick to note that the chaos space marines present were far cannier. Minute differences in heraldry was enough for him to denote the difference, especially after moving from one ship to the other. The Ruination of Purity had, based on his estimates of the enemy the Blood Ravens had met so far, barely delivered any of its own marines onto the Litany of Fury. Rather, it had been the space marines of its attendant strike cruisers that had so dedicated themselves to the fight, and thus had been depleted by the time the Blood Ravens boarded them.

“Pull back!” He called aloud, “This corridor is impassable!”

This was a lie.

Though the quad-linked heavy bolter turret and the chaos space marine havoc squad were dangerous, they were not undefeatable. Codicier Aeneas could literally walk up to them through the warp and cut apart their number. Or grenades could be phased forward with the aid of another Librarian. But that would not occur. Instead, the Blood Ravens followed his orders, to the laughter and raucous cries of the enemy. Similar actions occurred elsewhere, sergeants declaring that the enemy fire was ‘too much’, or that they had to perform tactical withdrawals to avoid being flanked and surrounded. It strained at the Blood Ravens to do so, and the mockery of Mortirex at their absolute failure to penetrate into the depths of the ship proper burned at their souls, but Tarkus weathered it all.

The point was not to destroy the ship, nor even to take Mortirex.

“Speak to me, tech-priest,” he ordered as he fired his bolt pistol down the corridor, laying down covering fire along with the two present squads to keep the enemy back.

“Nearly done…successful,” the toneless amalgam of cybernetics and flesh announced, standing up from the guts – also an amalgam of foul organs and rusty pulsating metal – and made the sign of the Omnissiah. “The machine spirits are insane, maddened, and are thus led to turn spite upon spite.”

Muted booms in the distance heralded a crackling as the vox opened.

“Melta charges detonated, Captain,” Sergeant Stromahn said calmly despite the thunder of a nearby assault cannon.

“Good work, sergeant.”

Like blood, they turned and flowed out of the ship at rapid speed. At first, the chaos space marines cheered and laughed as the Blood Ravens showed them their backsides. Then, however, they realized what had happened as chittering cherubs bound with umbilical cording chattered out regular progress reports of ongoing repairs – or the lack thereof.

“You…ahah…ahahah! Cowardly! Clever! You are too afraid to face us? Well, do not worry, Blood Ravens!” Mortirex boomed and laughed, a clear edge of anger now present. “We…will come…to you.”

From out of the Ruination of Purity, the Blood Ravens had flowed outwards, sweeping towards their next targets. Shortly afterwards, however, the battle barge spewed forth a new tide from its wounds into the surrounding environs of the shipyard. This time, however, where ceramite-coated adamantium boots walked, there were painted black and encrusted with filth and blood. What had become and orderly redeployment became an embattled conflict, Blood Ravens outright retreating towards their next targets. The Black Legion was not willing to give up the fight, not just yet. Not after the loyalists had so insulted them, offering battle and then fleeing.

========================================================

Void Combat: 30 vs. 86

“The Sword of Light is gone, Admiral.”

“I can see that,” Graves spat, glaring at the tumbling wreckage that had once been a proud Lunar-class cruiser.

It hadn’t worked. The moment the interceptors had gotten in range, the Dark Mechanicus ships had reconfigured…something…and suddenly the targeting lasers had been refracted and shifted. No targets had been locked, and so the painful dance continued. The enemy would move in, attack, deal damage, and then retreat the moment their shields took enough damage. This time, however, they had managed to guide slowed torpedoes through the debris of the monitors directly into the Sword of Light. Advanced guidance systems, auspex and target baffling, higher speed engines and multi-emitter void shield sectors. It was more than frustrating, it was turning deadly. The orbitals and monitors were gone, but at this point he was realizing just why they had four ships. They didn’t need any more than that, if they couldn’t be hit. It was like fighting Eldar, of all things.

“Eldar,” Graves muttered. “Like Eldar.”

The Dark Mechanicus had no principles. No honor. No restrictions. No ethics. Nothing that would prevent them from aping xenos, from meshing the pure mechanisms of the Omnissiah with that of the foul alien.

“Reload incendiary torpedoes,” he growled. “Rotate the cylinder, ships without torpedoes or launchers forward. Can anyone tell me what the Inquisitor is doing?”

“She’s had her ship focusing on the point defenses of the shipyard, Admiral.”

Undocking: 17

“Cruisers are withdrawing from docking!”

Immediately, Graves shifted the actuality sphere’s image with his fingers. Both Hecate-class and one Carnage-class. The remaining three Carnage-class ships hadn’t yet gotten through a quarter of the proceedings.

Inquisitorial Boot: 63 vs. 34

It appeared that was precisely what the Inquisitor had been waiting for. The guns of her Vengeance-class Grand Cruiser opened up entirely upon the oncoming ships. The point defenses had been struck solely by well-targeted macro cannons. Now those macro cannons joined with lance arrays and a series of plasma projectors and fusion beamers that were entirely absent from standard Vengeance pattern weapon allotments fired. The cruisers had been barely hanging on before they’d successfully retreated to Opus Maxima, their repairs direly needed. At the moment, they hadn’t even gotten their shields back online just yet, and thus their fate was sealed. They, too, appeared willing to sell their lives in service to Chaos, and yet it was the black ship of Inquisitor Adrastia of the Ordo Hereticus which ended them before they could.

===========================================================

Boarding While Surrounded: 89 vs. 26

Aggressive Stealth: 50 vs. 83

The Blood Ravens were now faced on all sides. Ahead, the defenders of the remaining docked cruisers were preemptively attacking them, for their plan had been discovered and relayed by that point. The defenders of the shipyard, legions of skitarii and mutated cybernetically enhanced abominations, began to swarm and attack like a bio-mechanical immune system attacking a virus. Behind them, howling for their blood, the Black Legion chaos space marines pursued them after the Blood Ravens had successfully ensured their ships would remain locked in place. All the while, the shipyard itself proved an uncooperative battlefield. Doors and bulkheads slid and locked, oxygen vented and lights blinked or grew so bright as to be blinding. Minor things, all told, but every obstacle aided the enemy and hindered the Blood Ravens that much more.

It wasn’t enough.

Assault cannons whirred, thunder hammers smashed, and bolters roared. Chainswords and combat knives dug through gene-hound throats and plunged into cultist eyes. Power fists smashed through blocked passages, and heavy flamers incinerated charges of near-mindless zealots. The Blood Ravens were surrounded, and yet they remained an inexorable boulder that rumbled forwards. Again, the Librarians showed just why a single psyker was often enough for an entire company in other chapters, and just why the Blood Ravens had relied on them for so long. In truth, it was not even Justinius as the Chief Librarian who distinguished himself most of the Librarium. Instead, it was two others. The first was Epistolary Idmon, who could literally warp and melt the bulkheads, the ceilings, the floors, and force new molten tunnels forward outside of pre-defined paths. Thus, the Blood Ravens avoided ambush, flank, and sure casualties. The second was Codicier Aeneas, who faced such flanking attacks when they were unavoidable, leaving only carnage in his wake.

In truth, however, every Blood Raven accounted well for themselves. Whether of the 1st Company or the 5th, they tore their way through the ranks of the enemy while trading fire with the chaos space marines rushing up from behind. There were sightings of Mortirex, but no outright confrontations just yet. His foul presence within the warp was a cloying and unmissable thing, thankfully, and as such Justinius could guide his brothers away from the increasingly gleeful fury of the Chaos Lord. This close, without the fog over his sight created by the sorcerer, Justinius could see the horrifying power within the traitor’s weapon, the multiple daemons bound within it, but also of the traitor himself. Well-acquainted with the lore within the records, he could see the signs. The energies, the way they swirled inwards, ever condensing, ever thickening and solidifying, melding with flesh and armor alike.

Mortirex was coming dangerously close to either exploding as the ‘favor’ of the Chaos Gods became too much for him to take, or ascending to something altogether worse.

Even from here, half the shipyard away, Justinius could see it all too clearly in horrifying detail. It was like watching a clogged wellspring be cleared. A volcano that had slumbered beginning to wake again. It was slow, at the moment, and in that moment it further crystallized for the Chief Librarian. All those decades spent inactive, relatively at least, had put a stopper to things. It had literally slowed development, slowed the transformation, until it had become practically frozen in the amber of boredom. But with the shedding of blood, of true conflict, the energies were beginning to swirl about again. The desire for extending the conflict took on yet another dark facet, in that moment. If, indeed, it had ended too quickly, it might not be enough. But the longer the fight took, the more conflict, the more bloodshed, heightened emotions and potential for so-called glorious deeds…

“Ships reached, Chief Librarian. We are entering the Hecate-class ships now!”

Justinus blinked and turned back to the fight, having been so focused on his scrying that he had barely noticed them arriving at their next destination. A fusillade of multi-las fire had turned the armor of numerous Blood Ravens white hot with heat even as they charged through the airlocks. The Chapter had already boarded the other ships, this was the last. They would have to be quick, over half the clamps were already unlatched. They might not have managed to get all of them, but they would get some. They had to. The longer this took, the worse things could become.

"Captain," he said quietly into the vox, "There's something you should know about Mortirex."

=============================================================

Void Combat: 80 vs. 50

“Burn, you mongrels!” Graves howled as the incendiary torpedoes erupted.

They had not struck the Dark Mechanicus ships directly. But then, they had not needed to do so. They had done their jobs. Fire clung to them, lighting up the darkness between the stars with flames enough to burn whole cities. Suddenly, all the light refraction and holographic field projectors in the system could not keep up with the conflagration that spread across their hulls. By that point, the cylinder had rotated and expanded to a near rectangular pane, if tightly pressed together. If the space marines wanted to complain about Graves changing the formation, they could do it after the battle was over. For now, their auspex scans did not need to find the illusive ships. They just needed to point at the gigantic heat signatures in space that were not there before and shoot the absolute living hell out of them. Literally, in the case of the Dark Mechanicus, whose ships often mixed daemons and machinery without a care in the world for the internals of their ships. Even as the flames spread, the ships turned at insane speeds to attempt to retreat.

“All ships! Fire at will! Target their engines! Don’t let the bastards get away again!”

Fire joined fire, as holes were punched into the hulls of the hereteks. Lances and hastily fired torpedoes joined with macro cannon blasts and more. Explosions rippled across the rear of all four ships, engines not dimming but outright torn apart, sending them rotating without the ability to check their own movement. Soon enough they would be out of range for many weapon types, but not out of range for Graves’ bombers and every lance array he could find. One servitor linked to the Spiraling Fury’s bombardment cannon noted a statistically likely chance of success and fired, sending a shell meant to crack open planetary void shields directly into the backside of the largest Dark Mechanicus ship, blowing the back third of the ship apart. The servitor noted the successful shot in its logs and turned back to its duties.

Undocking: 42

“Cruiser undocking! Just the one though, I think the space marines have bloody done it!”

Crusher of Heretics: 50

“They’re the bloody Blood Ravens, you twit,” Graves snapped at the crewman with a vicious smile on his face. “I think…yes. The Inquisitor has it.”

Again, the multitude of non-regulation weaponry of the Inquisitor’s vessel unleashed themselves. Though the Vengeance-class ships were regarded as old and mostly obsolete, apparently no one had told the Inquisition that. If every Vengeance had such weaponry and shielding, the things would have had pride of place in any fleet in any Segmentum. But then, its upgrades and altered systems surely cost far too much to make that a viable prospect. In any case, that didn’t matter as much as the fact that the cylinder needed to reform properly, a delicate yet vital maneuver to keep the shipyard between them and the planetary defense lasers. Which were still threateningly lit up. On the one hand, it was giving them good signs of where they were. On the other, he’d already run the calculations through the cogitators, and they would have to pull backwards far sooner than initial estimates, even if the mad plan of throwing their own shipyard at them worked. They’d been opened up to the perimeter defense lasers far sooner than estimated.

“Admiral!”

“What!?” He whirled at the tech-priests frantic scream. “What is it?!”

The devotee of the Omnissah stabbed a finger at the images displayed on their console.

“The shipyard, it moves unbidden to our directives! Out of schedule! Our tech-priests do not yet control its maneuvering jets or orbital drives!”

Graves gaped.

“What?!”

========================================================================

Tarkus frowned as the entire shipyard seemed to shudder at once. He could tell, even minutely, that there was far too much movement than there should have been. The docking clamps had been slagged, re-enabled and then shut off, and yet a terrible sense of foreboding came upon him. It only got worse as he was joined by Justinius, whose face had suddenly gone white, all the while the tech-priests that had come with them were all screeching in binary, frantically working multiple nearby consoles. All around them, there was fighting, as ever more slaves of the Dark Gods came after them. For the moment, the Black Legion seemed to have backed off, but only slightly. Briefly, he scanned the area and the makeshift barricades that had been put into place before Tarkus had boarded the last of the Carnage-class cruisers and helped force it to remain in place. The last that Justinius had informed him was that he had felt the suffocating presence of Mortirex half-way across the station, even as he drove his traitor brethren after them.

“Chief Librarian, report!” He said before both ducked slightly as a screaming gene-hound with heavy bolters for arms fired wildly at them.

“The shipyard is descending ahead of schedule,” Justinius said promptly.

Then the vox crackled.

“Do you think me a fool, Blood Ravens?” Mortirex’s usual booming roar had become a low, sibilant hiss that nevertheless retained enough volume to blow the eardums of a child into red mulch. “That I cannot see what you are doing, have done? Hah! Little children, hiding behind the skirts of the Dark God’s artifice like a child seeking a stranger’s help!”

A sound of metal creaking and tearing came through the vox.

“You think to use this shipyard as a shield? THEN I WILL TAKE IT FROM YOU!”

Tarkus’ eyes widened as he felt another shipyard-wide rumble as the gravity of Opus Maxima began to tug on it more heavily.

“Enemy commander Mortirex location identified!” A tech-priest called out, oil weeping from beneath the green of his mechanical eyes. “Shipyard command center, location avoided due to heavy defenses and demands of ordered directives!”

“Maneuvering thrusters engaged! Orbital drives no longer preventing gravity well from reacquiring station!” Another stated, mechadendrites wriggling nervously.

“Can we teleport?” Tarkus asked aloud, looking from Librarian to tech-priest and back again.

Neither assault rams nor boarding pods could provide return trips, they were meant to be recovered afterwards or replaced entirely. The goal had been to disable the void shield arrays of the shipyard and then teleport to safety, or to reach a hangar bay and retreat in thunderhawks.

“Shipyard void shields have just completed regeneration cycle and are at full power! Teleport impossible! Warning, shipyard’s descent is removing shielding position from allied vessels,” another tech-priest all but wailed. “Teleportation grows more unsafe with distance!”

That was putting it lightly. The greater the distance, the greater the chance that the subject might outright never return from the Warp. Or, if they did return, not whole or unchanged. It didn't help that the system was tainted with Chaos. Already, Justinius had described how the Warp writhed with daemons here. Teleporting at all would briefly expose all who utilized it to such things. On the other hand, the teleportariums of the Blood Ravens were highly sophisticated, and the aid of the Librarius could hopefully ward off the worst potential side effects of travel.

“Mortirex! What in the name of the Omnissiah do you think you are doing!?” A new voice screeched onto the shipyard’s broadcast systems, this one wholly mechanical and androgynous yet audibly shaking with fury. “That shipyard is-,”

“A liability, Fabricator-General,” Mortirex interrupted with a dark chuckle. “Or are you incapable of calculating the percentage that they would have done so themselves if they had the chance? The moment the shipyard is moved, begin firing on the Imperium's ships with the defense lasers. Salve the wound of the shipyard's loss with a pretty painting in the sky made of blood and metal.”

Mechanized sputtering was the only immediate answer.

“Captain, the command remains yours. What are your orders?” Justinius looked at Tarkus with a raised eyebrow.

The shipyard was hurtling down, and they were trapped on it. The further it moved, the more impossible retrieval could become. the further it moved, the more anti-orbital defense lasers would be able to fire upon the ships of the Imperium, which with every second they were beginning to leave behind. Around them, the skitarii, the gene-hounds, the cultists swarmed. With plasma guns, high powered las rifles, grenades and explosives, they were not equipped poorly at all, and in fact were proving as fanatically willing to die simply to injure a Blood Raven as was expected. More so, even. One way or another, the fleet would have to pull back as the shipyard dipped lower, opening them up to the defense lasers. The troop transports and the Litany especially.

A decision had to be made, and quickly.

Captain Tarkus, What Shall You Do?:
Voting Moratorium: 12 Hours
[] Run For A Hangar: Retreat, and quickly! Reach a hangar with all haste, and try to land as many thunderhawks as possible to withdraw all troops from the shipyard. This will mean combatting point defenses, and will force the ships of the Imperium to linger within the danger zone of becoming vulnerable to the defense lasers on the planet below, but it may be your only chance.
[] Shut The Shields Down: The only thing preventing retreat by teleport are the overlapping heavy void shields of the shipyard. Shut down the arrays from within, and you will be able to retreat. The station is vast, however, but collapsing a sector's shields should not be beyond the Blood Ravens. Hopefully before the distance reaches the danger zone for teleportation, and before the shipyard impacts below.
[] Rush Mortirex: He has taken the command center. He is not moving, according to Justinius. The command center could be used to shut down the shields, instantly, across the entire station. Or perhaps even move the shipyard back up slightly, enough to give the fleet time to pull back. Kill him, something that Justinus stresses would be good sooner rather than later, given how the Chaos Lord seems to be feeding upon the fighting.
[] Write-In:

Spoiler: Imperial Fleet

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Void Shielding At 50%, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
20 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius (+All Unassigned Librarians)
73 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Remains Unconscious, Repairs Possible By Tech-Priests Accompanying Imperial Guard/Imperial Navy

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor to Moderate Damage)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor to Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class (?)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
101 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
18 Khornate Berserkers
100 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
23 Heavy Combat Servitors
Dozens of skitarii
1000~ Cultist Troopers
10 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Eight)

[] Rush Mortirex: He has taken the command center. He is not moving, according to Justinius. The command center could be used to shut down the shields, instantly, across the entire station. Or perhaps even move the shipyard back up slightly, enough to give the fleet time to pull back. Kill him, something that Justinus stresses would be good sooner rather than later, given how the Chaos Lord seems to be feeding upon the fighting.

GM NOTE: 12 Hour Moratorium

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

Mind racing, Tarkus looked upon the Blood Ravens around him. Their armor was pitted and chipped in many places. The foes they fought were not to be discounted simply because they were not chaos space marines. The gene-hounds were the size and strength of ogryn, but with gruesomely implanted cybernetics enhancing their minds. The skitarii of the Dark Mechanicus wielded an assortment of powerful weaponry, things capable of punching through the adamantium of their armor, not just the ceramite coating. Yet, in this moment, the marines of the 1st and 5th Company – his Company – were holding them off. Some stood behind hastily made barricades, others stood out in the open as they fired their bolters. Nearby, the Librarians had gathered in a small group of considerable psychic power. It surrounded them, emanated from them, like the mists of a Calderis morning after a rare rain. Justinius Probalis, student of Jonah Orion, now Chief Librarian, looked upon him steadily. There was no need to be able to read minds, not in this moment.

They did not have the plans for the entire station, deep penetrating scans had been focused upon the docking clamps and subsystem consoles. The internal architecture was largely unknown for them, save for the paths they had carved or melted through to advance. But one place on the station was unmistakable. The tech-priests could track the bevy of scrap-code and directives commanding the machine spirits of the blighted shipyard to a nexus point of command-grade cogitators. Below, the planet approached. Above, the ships receded, save for the strike cruisers, for Admiral Graves was no fool. He had informed Tarkus tersely of what would be done, and Tarkus had agreed. Better to risk only them, than the rest of the ships. There were wholly unknown defenses in any direction, as well as force concentrations. Point defenses were guarding the hangars. Exact void shield generator locations were well-disguised through the ship’s systems, and the tech-priests simply did not have enough time.

Time, in the end, was what it all came down to.

“Blood Ravens!” Tarkus called out on the command vox, his grimace deep and his eyes narrowed. “We move on the command center as one! One way or another, this battle ends here, and now! May None Find Us Wanting!”

“MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!”

Advancing: 78 vs. 54

Pivoting near-seamlessly, more than a hundred loyal space marines turned and charged forward. Tunnels and corridors leading elsewhere, points of defense only seconds previous, were collapsed as melta bombs and grenades flew. In some cases, the tech-priests triggered total lockdown procedures, shutting bulkheads and security shields to block off outraged skitarii and screaming cultists. In a few others, the terminators utilized their power fists to wrench, tear, and pull blockades into place. At the forefront, Tarkus led the charge, firing his bolter one-handed and cutting and cleaving with his combat knife in the other. He was joined by the Chief Librarian, by all the Librarians in fact, who became a driving spear-tip that tore through the enemy defenses as they went. There was no time to carefully marshal, to do anything less than to rush forwards with steely determination and faith in themselves. Numbers designating different sections of the station flashed briefly in the mind as they thundered past, only glances being offered before eyes refocused upon the enemy pouring in from all directions.

“BLOOOOOOOOOD RAAAAAAAAAVEEEEEENSSSS!”

Their movements were unmistakable to any who had access to either the reports of the troops trying to slow them or the internal auspex sensors of the shipyard such as was possible in the shipyard’s command center.

“You surprise me, Blood Ravens! Perhaps there is a modicum, a mote of dust, a speck of something that might be considered courage in your worthless hearts! Then come! Come to me! Face the gauntlet, and those of you that survive shall have the honor of feeling my axe!”

The shipyard rattled again, a quake covering its entire superstructure as it continued its unexpected descent, sending more than a few less steadied cultists to the ground to be trampled by their brethren.

“I have told the Fabricator-General that I shall reverse the shipyard’s descent if you are all dead,” he continued, guttural growl turning almost whimsical before returning to the customary roaring shout. “So fight! FIGHT! KILL! MAIM! BURN! Or all shall be LOST, you mewling babes! Soar! Soar like the birds you style yourselves after! HAHahahahaHA!”

Advancing: 24 vs. 69

Tarkus did not respond. Nor did any of the other Blood Ravens. Even as gene-hounds began to appear in greater and greater number, with the first few chaos space marines interspersed amongst them. Even as some of the 5th Company were thrown from their feet by sonic mines, set aflame with incendiary grenades, or bled heavily as power weapons were utilized against them. Missile launchers began to fire, gene-hounds pushed past fatal wounds to strike blows against the Blood Ravens, and yet more skitarii and cultists began to appear from behind having found alternate routes. Plasma guns and emplaced weapons took their toll, even against the renowned armor of the Adeptus Astartes. A howling Khornate Berserker appeared, cutting their way through a handful of cultists and shoving aside a gene-hound, all so that they could slam a chainaxe into a Blood Raven of the 5th Company’s chest, tearing in deeply and riding them to the ground even as they were shot dead. The momentum of the column had two other Blood Ravens grabbing their gasping brother by the arms and dragging them upright once more, then helping carry them forward.

It was, in the end, Epistolary Lucan who helped keep any from outright dying. With the rest of the Librarians focused on blasting a path forward quickly enough for them all to hopefully somehow avert doom and destruction, they found their abilities strained to do even that much. It was they, who concentrated will and knowledge of esoteric lore, who helped preserve many from death. Flesh and bone warped and regrew, blood ceased to gush, and life sparked anew in those who had just fallen off the knife’s edge. In some instances, the Chief Librarian would summon forth psychic barriers so powerful they were opaque to all senses and sensors while Lucan healed barely conscious brothers to the point they could fight once more. In others, Lucan would clench his fist, and temporarily granting the terminator-clad marines of the 1st Company speeds more akin to assault marines with redlined jump packs so that Apothecary Medici could gather a severed limb so that Lucan could reknit the nerves, bone, and musculature without worry or distraction.

All so that the advance could remain at the highest possible pace without slowing down, fighting and killing their way through the shipyard. It was not an elegant advance, not something carefully planned and executed as was the usual desire for adherents to the Chapter’s tactics. It was a bloody and tightly clenched fist, grinding forward relentlessly no matter the damage it took itself. The enemy did not relent, even for a second. The few chaos space marines that appeared were more than their past brethren. These fired, shot, ambushed, and melted backwards the moment the concentration of fire levied at them was too great to survive, scoring numerous hits that sent many marines of the 5th Company to the ground only to be hefted upright again with the aid of the Librarians. One, Brother Marius, lost his left arm entirely, the plasma gun having successfully vaporized his flesh so completely there was nothing to reattach, and certainly not enough time to try and regrow entirely no matter the skills of the Epistolaries. Not when others, like Brother Baptiste had only a few seconds before his decapitated head could be reattached with frantic effort on Epistolary Lucan’s part or else die outright from sheer massive trauma.

“We should have studied biomancy more,” Lucan said through gritted teeth, “A lot more!”

“Lucan,” Idmon called out as he blocked a burst from a heavy flamer wielded by a combat servitor with a shield of metal and stone. “Hurry up!”

“If I don’t reconnect the nervous system correctly, he’ll be naught but a quadriplegic!” Lucan grunted as dragged the unmoving body of Baptiste in one arm, the other tightly wrapped around the throat.

The young Blood Raven’s eyes danced about wildly in his eye sockets, tongue lolling and jaw twitching madly. Veins had been mostly reconnected in the first seconds, ensuring a circulation of blood and oxygen to the brain, but forcing the Larraman’s Organ from trying to scab and block off the neck and throat was a constant issue. Lucan’s own psychic shielding had winked out entirely as he focused all his effort on preserving not just the marine’s life but combat capabilities. Standing next to him, Idmon was creating not just a barrier to keep the three of them safe, but several other more wounded brothers at the same time. The effort of doing so had already caused burst blood vessels in both eyes, giving him a particularly disturbing, red-eyed look.

Finally, the thin tendrils of nerves, the last veins, the spinal connections, all of it was slotted into place, the organic matter regenerated with extreme care to not cause major scarring or aberration. The effect was instant, as Brother Baptiste's legs suddenly moved, the marine’s body upright on his own power once more. Still, the Meridian-born marine’s eyes remained wide, his grip on the bolter that was shoved back into his hands loose, shoving and jostled on all sides. Instantly, Lucan’s hand on his throat left it and the Epistolary was gone to the next falling marine, grabbing them by the shoulder to keep them from collapsing entirely and picking their leg up from the ground from where it had been blown off. Idmon shoved Brother Baptiste on the shoulder, causing those too-wide eyes to finally refocus on him.

“Get it together, Blood Raven! Fight isn’t over!” The Librarian shouted over the din before moving on.

Still twitching, and quite slowly – for a marine – Brother Baptist raised his bolter and put a few rounds into a drooling gene-hound.

Advancing: 38 vs. 50

The command center itself sat deep within the shipyard, itself a large compound built in eerie mirror to such locations within regular Imperium shipyards. A tiered series of platforms forming a low sloped pyramid of cogitators and consoles meant to coordinate the entire station’s work, itself at the basin of a lowering series of tiers for secondary and tertiary work-related cogitators, data storage, and processing. It was a vast amphitheater which, when operating normally, had dozens of heretek techpriests, hundreds of lesser acolytes, and thousands of servitors stationed across is length and up its height. At the very top was a series of intensely powerful cogitators, each bearing command-permissions capable of overriding anything and anyone else in the entire station, as befitting the treacherous nature of the Dark Mechancius. The Magos not only desired, but required, the ability to retain control against any would-be rivals. Even if the rest of the pyramid was damaged or destroyed, deep-set subsystems and backup arrays buried within its peak would ensure control and dominance. A control point that remained, as best as could be told, yet untouched and functioning if not receiving any inputs at the moment.

All of this, the tech-priests were able to relay as they regularly but carefully dipped into the tainted Noosphere of the shipyard, hacking and scanning in bite sized excursions lest they taint their souls. What they had not been able to tell, however, was the current condition of the command center. They were deliberately blocked on such matters, only able to scan, to taste, the echoes of reports and pulses of energy long past hidden away in regulatory reports – for even maddened hereteks required some measure of statistical control and command if only to maintain their creations. Soon enough, Tarkus had to command them to stop, for there was little point. They were already discovering the defenses present – blocked off passages, hastily but dangerously well-placed minefields, even ambushes of chaos space marine squads that would let off devastating salvoes of bolters and plasma guns before disappearing again in retreat to better positions.

But then they reached the amphitheater, and though Tarkus did not falter, his steps did momentarily slow as he worked through the implications of what he saw.

Here, the Black Legion had entrenched itself, and with startling speed and thoroughness. Havoc squads, the twisted peers to devastator squads, let loose with heavy bolters and lascannons the moment the first Blood Ravens came into proper range from behind heavy fortifications made of scrap metal and blocks of materials meant for construction elsewhere. Black Legion marines at higher positions wielding combi-bolters and a large assortment of tactical weaponry fired as well, sending screaming missiles leaving multi-colored trails behind them forward behind superheated spheres of plasma. Some even wielded stalker bolters, nearly taking the head from a few Blood Ravens and instead simply heavily damaging helmets. Others sat behind autocannons that let loose measured destruction without being utterly wild and inaccurate. Tarkus could hear the distinct sound of vengeance and kraken rounds being fired. There were gene-hounds milling about below at the foot of the pyramid, all of them turning and sprinting upwards, howling with weapons held high, the moment the Blood Ravens arrived. They were joined, here and there, by screaming berserkers in blood red armor. Interspersed amongst them, and amongst the pyramid, were cultist troopers. These were dressed not as the wild-eyed and haphazardly equipped troopers of the past that Tarkus had previously fought here. These shifted as squads, as platoons, bringing heavy weapons forward or letting loose with a few volleys from their lasguns, and did not come charging out from behind cover. Others were still arriving, alongside skitarii and combat servitors controlled and commanded by seething hereteks, through other passages than the one that the Blood Ravens had taken for themselves.

Above them all, looming like a god from atop his mountain, Mortirex waited. Not within the bank of hardened cogitators and consoles, but rather several feet down from it. Because of course, a challenge had no worth if it could not be won. A trap could not be prepared without the right bait. Mortirex knew that, for all his supreme confidence. After all, assuming that he was victorious, being able to reverse the shipyard’s descent would be something to keep in mind. So, there he stood, displaying, guarding even, the prize that was so desperately required. Close enough that any stray shot might have ruined everything, that any explosive thrown or missile shot might spell doom rather than victory.

“I was wondering if you would ever arrive, Blood Ravens!” Mortirex guffawed, even as the first salvoes sent the Blood Ravens back with concussive force alone. “Look at yourselves! Ragged little motes of scorched flesh and broken bone!” He splayed his arms wide, for all that many of the Blood Ravens had to fall back into cover to avoid simply being torn apart by the weight and diversity of enemy fire. “Come, try to avenge that pathetic waste of metal that was your Chapter Master! Try to stop the sky from falling! HAHAHAHAHAH!”

Tarkus looked upon it all, heard the storm of fury and hatred levied upon him, and blinked – once.

Ahead, a minimum of three hundred marines of the Black Legion, behind entrenched defenses. The heraldry alone was similar but not wholly congruent with previous Black Legion marines that had been fought thus far, whorls and knots carved with unique sigils in their armor. Only some were of the previous two groups, bearing iconography that seemed most fitting for the compliments of the strike cruiser crews. These, then, must have been those upon the Ruination of Purity proper. They may have been veterans, elites, or at the very least more favored than those set forth in the initial boarding parties. There were also numerous cultist squads with an assortment of heavy weaponry. Gene-hounds charging, with berserker marines and frothing cultists amongst them. The command center was too large for them to have feasibly blocked off its various other passageways, and thus the enemy was receiving reinforcements constantly.

Behind, he had just over a hundred Blood Ravens. Many of the Librarians were already exhausted, pushing themselves to the limit and beyond to make up for the disparity in numbers between traitors, hereteks, and loyalists. Less than a tenth of them were without wounds or armor damage of some sort. More than half were at minimum moderately wounded. Greaves, gauntlets, pauldrons, breastplates, all of these and more were cracked, torn, ripped, or blown apart or open entirely. Reddened and blackened skin was visible on many, while others had fully exposed musculature from tears and explosions. A fourth were outright limping, and at least a dozen were being supported by their brothers to even stand, let alone walk. Others no longer had helmets, having been forced to tear them off or otherwise have them pried off after taking too much damage that they became more liability than protection. They were running low on grenades, on melta bombs, on explosives in general.

Then Tarkus opened his eyes again, less than a second having passed.

Advance: 61 vs. 40

“WITH ME BROTHERS, ADVANCE!” He shouted as he leapt from cover and did just that.

“MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!” Came the ragged call as others followed.

Tarkus shouted with them, slamming his knife into a charging gene-hound’s eye socket and ducking to help roll it up and over him to land with a sickening thud behind him. That was not, of course, enough to kill a gene-hound, as the Blood Ravens had rapidly discovered. As such, the terminators behind Tarkus saw to finishing the kill. Sergeant Minos slammed his thunder hammer down atop the gene-hound’s skull and then liberally stepped upon the corpse so that the sheer weight of his armor and equipment bore him down through its body as Minos followed with the rest of the assault terminators of the 1st Company. Behind them came the other ten terminators, firing with their storm bolters, assault cannons, and heavy flamers. Sergeant Strohmahn liberally utilized his few remaining cyclone missiles to land amongst the defensive emplacements of the enemy marines. The tide of Blood Ravens was such that the gene-hounds, for all their cybernetically improved and genetically enhanced frames, were torn apart by sheer weight of bolter fire. The berserkers fared slightly better, at least until the assault terminators reached them. In a single mass, squads only just beginning to split apart to reduce the ability of the enemy to simply levy explosives upon them with total ease, the loyalists carved a swift path to the bottom of the command center and looked up at their traitorous counterparts with weary determination.

The Black Legion gazed back down upon them with hate and dark joy in their baleful hearts.

There had not been a single second of paused fire, even when the Blood Ravens had been fighting their way past the gene-hounds, berserkers, and most insane cultists. There was not now. There would not be as Tarkus took the first step upwards, reloading his bolter despite a scattershot of kraken rounds slamming into a hastily ducked shoulder. Deathdealer racked easily despite the blood coating it. Around him, others reloaded their weaponry as best as they could under fire, some succeeding, some not before it was time for the charge to continue. The moment they lost momentum, Tarkus knew, they were well and truly doomed. They could not stop. They could not afford to cease for anyone, or anything. At this point, even those who were wounded and those who fell would have to be left behind.

“DRIVE FORWARD!”

Advance: 49 vs. 10

Bolters, heavy bolters, combi-bolters, storm bolters. Plasma pistols, plasma guns, plasma cannons. Autocannons. Lascannons. Hotshot lasguns. Multi-las cannons. Missile launchers firing frag and krak missiles. All of this and more fell upon the Blood Ravens, a hailstorm of death and destruction fit to tear whole armies asunder. It had done so before, on a hundred and more worlds elsewhere throughout the galaxy in both realspace and in the Immaterium. And to be sure, many Blood Ravens were thrown from their feet, and many were slow to rise. Yet to the surprise of more than a few of the chaos space marines upon the tiers, they rose all the same. But it was the one at the head that caught their attention most.

Tarkus did not fall.

Tarkus did not falter.

Tarkus Varianus, Captain of the 5th Company, weathered the storm and advanced, firing his bolter all the while. Behind him, the terminators of the 1st Company similarly marched forward resolutely, trusting in their wargear, firing all the while at all possible targets of highest priority. The Librarians came next, enormous half-sphere shields of energy or solid matter warping into existence to block salvoes from particularly dangerous weaponry, and though blood began to spurt out of Epistolary Idmon’s ears and nose, even the incandescent spheres of plasma cannons would erupt without harming his brothers. Columns of psychic flames so hot as to be pure white fell upon distant havoc squads, conjured forth by the Chief Librarian just as they prepared to let loose with missile and heavy bolter alike. It burned them to organic slag within the somewhat melted remains of their armor. Codicier Aeneas disappeared altogether, or at least to the eyes who could not perceive the disturbing clear and colorless wake he cut through the Warp, the only signs of his passage to most being the bodies of the slain falling to the ground.

It was in this way that the first three tiers, of the nine, were passed.

It was far enough.

Tarkus was emptying his current magazine into the head of a chaos space marine when he felt it. His head snapped up, his eyes tracking Mortirex as the Chaos Lord almost languidly descended from where he had previously stood immobile. The world seemed to slow, the battlefield growing almost curiously silent as Mortirex stomped his way down. The twin burning spheres of flame which had long ago replaced the traitor’s eyes burned brightly, leaving fiery trails of smoke and light as he passed downwards. The wounds that he had sustained on the Litany of Fury had completely healed, his armor itself showing no sign of damage whatsoever, even the broken horns on the side of his head regrowing fully and prominently. Mortirex stared at Tarkus, and though his helm concealed his face, or perhaps had long ago replaced it, it felt as if he was smirking.

“Glorious bloodshed, Blood Ravens! Truly, I had thought you to shake in your boots and flee like the cowardly dogs you are, barking and yipping for succor at the Corpse-Emperor’s feet after facing true space marines!” He boomed, waving his axe in the air and letting a trio of warp energy beams to go slicing across the ground in front of Tarkus, cutting through the deckplates and leaving a chain reaction of explosions behind. “Worthless wastes of flesh that you are, you may take heart in the fact that all souls might burn in the furnaces of war, even your pathetic match-lights, unfit as they are to even bring comfort to a child in the night!”

Tarkus grunted, sighted, and began firing. He was joined in this by a great many other Blood Ravens, for if they failed to do anything else, they could at least attempt to bring the Chaos Lord down.

Advance: 27 vs. 93

This time, however, was different. Mortirex had been caught by surprise beforehand, but this time he could not fail to have seen it coming. He thrust his axe forward in front of him, and his considerable nimbus of warp energies swirled about and coalesced into a semi-opalescent shield even as the traitor continued to descend the tiers. The fighting across the rest of the tiers was faring little better. More hereteks and skitarii had arrived from behind where the Blood Ravens had first appeared, others appearing from further side passages, and thus the loyalists were fully surrounded. As the Blood Ravens had advanced up the tiers, they were forced to spread out and try to defeat all on each tier at a time, lest they be attacked and flanked at close range. Some traitors, unfortunately, had been able to play dead amidst the carnage, only rising now and letting loose once more from amongst their fellow dead. It was too much, even for the Librarians and their barriers, their reknitting of flesh and bone.

Now, Blood Ravens fell that would not be rising again.

Throughout all of this, Tarkus had kept up his firing, switching targets to more vulnerable foes when it became apparent that the shield that Mortirex was producing was inviolate to mere bolter rounds. Others were slower on the uptake, but not by too much. As Mortirex continued forward, the chaos space marines around him that were not so protected were cut down, blown apart, or simply shot through with enough holes that they were forced off the mortal coil. But for all of that, the aura around Mortirex only seemed to grow in strength, regardless of whether it was marines of the Black Legion or of the Blood Ravens that were felled. Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis lifted his head, eyes filled with light and lightning, and pointed at him.

“Go!” Justinius roared, and the weight of the Librarius of the Blood Ravens turned as one and concentrated their might together, weaving their wills into a single joined weight, a single psychic spear.

Advance: 30 vs. 85
Assault: 62 vs. 31

All save one.

==========================================================================

The Warp was screaming. The death of so many, some of them veterans of thousands of years, all within a place of Dark Mechanicus artifice? How could it not draw in the hungry? Many souls, Aeneas saw, were being torn apart by amorphous beings who were as much teeth and hunger as they were anything else, feasting endlessly upon the slain cultists in their hundreds. The gene-hounds, curiously, left nothing at all behind, as hollow in death as they had been in life. Some of the living had greater attentions than others, coronas of energy surrounding them as they fought, as they killed, as they died. Champions, those rising in favor. None, however, were as bright, as searing to eye and soul alike, as Mortirex. Where some of the Black Legion, and surprisingly some of the cultists, were clouds of dark energy, of sibilant whispers that swathed their souls and darkened them further, the Chaos Lord was an outright hurricane in the Warp. It was so encompassing that it was like looking into an auspex reading’s representation of a black hole devouring a nebula.

But Aeneas wielded the crystallized light of a star in his hands.

He thrust forwards, and to his absolute shock, Mortirex turned. It was meant to be impossible. Nothing had ever reacted so quickly, not even other chaos space marines. Yet it was happening nonetheless. Mortirex spun so quickly that the deck plating which had already become semi-molten beneath his feet and the infernal heat that his body exuded was torn and shredded. His shield winked out as he brought his axe to bear, itself another terrifying amalgamation of metal and daemons fused and formed and outright forced into shape. The Blade of the Martyr’s thrust of blazing golden light was turned aside, transforming what should have been a sure strike to the heart into a deeply gouging blow that skated away along the torso and out into open air once more.

It was all Aeneas could do to dodge forwards with the force exerted upon him to avoid a killing blow, sinking through the floor himself before he could stop it, the laws of reality gone missing altogether before Mortirex’s warp presence. Shadows of physical matter that should have provided solid enough bases to temporarily walk upon became murky liquid that had no grip, no purchase, nothing.

He screamed as he was swallowed by rock and metal, to the gales of laughter of the daemons.

===============================================================

Tarkus watched as the shield winked out, aim twitching immediately back over to Mortirex as the Chaos Lord spun about and swung at nothing. In the faintest and quickest millisecond, Tarkus swore he saw a faint golden light briefly flash in and then out of existence. A cleaving blade of warp energies erupted out of Mortirex’s axe as he swung it, the blade cleaving and extending on for quite a distance, cutting apart several chaos space marines and several cultists as it went. The line of explosions that followed the temporarily splitting of reality followed after, causing even more damage. At that point, the psychic spear that had formed in the air thrust forward, striking Mortirex directly through the back and out of his chest before exploding like shattering ice, sending shards of psychic energies flying everywhere – including the Chaos Lord’s innards.

Mortirex let loose a howl of genuine pain, body stiffening momentarily from the pain, and as the remnants of the energies faded it revealed a gaping hole that had been torn through his chest the size of a terminator’s boot. That small handful of seconds after the shield had faded so he could strike at whatever it had been that he had perceived proved a boon to the Blood Ravens. Even as they were shot themselves, they let loose upon his back. Plasma guns and assault cannons pounded into his back, forcing him forward with a grunt of surprise from the kinetic force behind them, while a small number of marines threw their very last grenades to his feet, though they failed to knock him down outright. Such shots were taken with the full knowledge that it would cost them as other chaos space marines shot at them with their own bolters. A cultist trooper reached up and swung an autocannon about and fired upon the Blood Ravens contributing to that fusillade, blowing holes in armor and sending many bouncing along the ground bleeding heavily. Only some managed to rise.

The reward for such effort, for such blows struck, was a howl that turned into gales of laughter as Mortirex turned around, patting the hole in his chest absentmindedly, for there flesh and adamantium were already beginning to wriggle, to twist, and to regenerate together.

“Good…,” Mortirex growled, raising his axe high. “GOOD!”

He rushed forward and leapt, his nimbus of power making him appear as if a comet that spelled only death as he fell the last two tiers to reach the Blood Ravens properly.

Fighting: 19 vs. 37
Through The Warp: 84

Tarkus did not retreat.

Tarkus did not falter.

Tarkus was struck low. His bionic arm was sliced off as he raised it to defend himself, and the subsequent explosions that rippled in the wake of Mortirex’s axe sent him flying down to the bottom tier, bouncing and crashing through consoles and cogitator banks for more than forty feet while covered in daemonic flame that clung to him and continued to burn. Sergeant Minos, of the 1st Company, advanced with the rest of his terminator brethren. Thunder hammer swung out, and were rebuffed. Storm shields were shattered, and the bodies beneath them struck. Veterans of the 1st Company all, their venerable terminator plate proved to not be inviolable against the daemonic axe that was wielded by their foe. Others, the closet, attempted to intervene, screaming, shooting, and these Mortirex tossed aside with one hand while his axe flashed back and forth. Some were crushed underfoot, others were simply thrown with daemonic strength amongst chaos space marines who had followed in their masters wake, one dazed Blood Raven amongst mobs of enemies with only a combat knife and bolter to defend themselves with. These unfortunates did not last long, most not even able to get to their knees, let alone their feet, before they were shot or cut apart.

Throughout it all, Mortirex laughed as he killed.

Fighting: 66 vs. 6
Through The Warp: 76

“MORTIREX!”

Justinius stood firm, psychic energies pouring off of him, lighting and curls of white flame briefly appearing around him at random. The Talonstaff of Jonah was held in both hands before him.

“Mmm?”

The Chaos Lord turned and stepped over the twitching body of one of the terminators, igniting their body in hellish flames in the same motion. The hole in his chest, both flesh and armor, had nearly fully regenerated.

“Ah…the Librarians. Paltry conjurers of cheap tricks, lobotomized trifling babes pretending at being scholars of power,” Mortirex snorted as he nevertheless swept towards them as a blurring mountain of adamantine and muscle.

It was then that Justinius struck from behind, and the image before Mortirex faded away. The Chief Librarian thrust the bottom of his force staff directly into the closing hole bored through Mortirex’s torso, and summoned forth flames, lightning, tearing razor winds, and pure shredding spinning force. It was the effects of a vortex grenade concentrated and brought ever so briefly into existence by sheer will and esoteric knowledge. On the other end of the hole, a multicolored light bloomed briefly into existence, lit from within. Mortirex screamed in pain, his innards wracked by the forces being unleashed. White silvery fire belched out of the exit wound on his chest, scattering outwards before clinging tightly to his frame. Mortirex snarled before reversing the grip on his axe in a spin of his wrest and slammed the blade down through Justinius’ left leg, cutting off the continually channeled psychic blast as well as the limb. He lumbered forward before turning about and raised his axe high in both arms, all three bloodshot eyes glowing brightly before beams of warp energy shot downwards. A cry of defiance came from Epistolary Idmon, who thrust his arms out and summoned forth yet another barrier, only to find the wall of metal cracking and shattering as blood spurted from his eyes and mouth. It held long enough for Justinius to roll out of the way of the third beam, at the very least, yet Idmon’s effort cost others elsewhere, some of the Lexicani proving to be unable to bear the strain that he had shouldered alone and faltering long enough for the enemy to close with them.

Then a thunder hammer struck Mortirex in the side of the head, forcing his head so sharply to the side that bone creaked and flesh cratered, smashing aside the left half of his helmet entirely as well as the horns there. Against most, it would have been a near fatal blow, if not fully fatal outright. Mortirex merely turned, the fires that filled his eye sockets burning brighter in fury. Helmet half stripped away like this, some of his malformed flesh beneath was revealed, if only to show that it had long since become a solid mass bonded with the armor. Indeed, Mortirex bore no nose, no mouth, only a craggy and scarred expanse of steadily reddening skin and exposed flesh. He glared at Sergeant Minos, who had once again dragged himself to his feet despite his own grievous wounds. No other assault terminators stood with him, for none were left alive to fight.

“Bloooooooood Raaaaaaveeeeeeens…,” Mortirex growled, his voice emanating into the air from his mouthless face.

It was hard to tell, but there might have been a twitching of mutated skin, of inhuman bone, that might have been suggestive of a smile.

“You are worth killing!” He roared with glee, bowling over Sergeant Minos as he rushed him with a single kick to the midsection.

Just after he cut the last assault terminator in two, however, five krak missiles struck him in the side while three assault cannons fired squarely at him from another direction. Justinius let loose with another blast of pure flame and lightning as Epistolary Lucan tried to weave his seared shut wound back with his leg at his side. To see Mortirex in that moment was to view a goliath set alight from head to toe, one that laughed even as he fought on. To Justinius, to the Chief Librarian, however, it was something else all-together. He watched the Warp as it boiled over, funneling more and more into the only semi-mortal frame that was Mortirex. The Chaos Lord was growing in power for all that he was being hurt, being damaged, for the Blood Ravens were dying around him too.

Fighting: 97 vs. 44
Through The Warp: 70

Then the station shuddered, shook, and several of the red emergency lights flicked off. The distant yet growing tug of gravity beyond that of the shipyard’s own suddenly eased. In the far distance, tremendous machines began to chug, to burn, that had previously been turned off. More important than that, however, was something that none but the tech-priests and hereteks could discern had occurred. Several bulkheads and security gates also slammed down, blocking off the incoming reinforcements from all directions, isolating the command center outright using programs prepared decades ago for locking down against attempted rebellions.

The battle within did not cease entirely, but the tempo was heavily throttled as many craned their necks.

Silently, still aflame with fires psychic and mundane, Mortirex, and indeed a great many others, paused to look up at the top of the pyramid.

There, armor still white hot from some insane heat with portions partially melted into his body, missing half of his face to grievous skull-deep claw marks inflicted upon him by daemons whilst within the Warp, Codicier Aeneas stood, chapter relic sheathed and hands on the consoles. He glared angrily down at the battlefield that had become the command center, though it was difficult to tell at this distance. His psychic hood had been torn from him entirely, at some point within his desperate struggle through the Warp, but his one functioning eye was narrowed and clear, if considerably bloodshot.

“Codicier Aeneas to Spiraling Fury,” his breathless growl carried across the Blood Raven vox channels. “Shipyard void shields are no longer active. Several members of the chapter require immediate teleport to the Apothecarium.”

“No…,” Mortirex said slowly, shaking his head at the same time. “No!”

A series of krak grenades slammed into his back, forcing him to stumble forwards, before all of them detonated at once. A burst from Brother Jacobus’ flamer covered the newly revealed flesh within. Bolter rounds, assault cannon rounds, plasma cannons, plasma guns, and every last grenade that the 5th Company had carried with them flew in the same instant. Lightning and flame crafted of psychic power crashed into the Chaos Lord next. Tarkus had dragged himself back up the tiers, firing Deathdealer until it ran dry with his remaining hand and then dragging a heavy bolter upright onehanded to do the same with it as well. Others focused on the chaos space marines that continued to fight, of course, but the sheer weight of fire was considerable nonetheless.

“This is Captain Tarkus,” the Master of the Marches rasped as he patted the last of the flames on him out, “Initiate teleport on Blood Raven beacon spreads Secundus-2, 4, and 7.”

Instantly, several of the fallen Blood Ravens began to disappear in flashes of light and crackled slightly-soured ozone. Those whose biosigns had completely fallen silent, but whose armor and beacons remained intact enough for penetrating scans boosted by surrounding active armor systems to be recovered. Others who still yet lived but were reduced to suspended animation, or those who were grievously harmed and combat ineffective, were next to follow.

“And initiate teleport deployment Mortis Silentius,” he finished with a savage click of his teeth before tearing another heavy bolter off a fallen brother and firing with it. “Primus on my position, secundus and tertius on Codicier Aeneas.”

“NO!”

Mortirex’s bellow shook the ground as he turned on Tarkus, most of his body obscured by the firepower being unleashed upon him.

“You…I will not…you will not…,” his voice began to choke off as parts of his body began to bulge and shift unnaturally.

Then the atmosphere shifted, was forced to shift, as three large displacements of air and matter occurred. With simultaneous loud booms of adamantium on the deckplates, the whining burn of reactors and chugging of exhaust pipes, Mortirex paused as he found his path towards Tarkus barred by a bulk of heaving ceramite that loomed above even him.

“I will be your end, heretic,” Tomb-Captain Davian Thule promised with a throaty deep growl.

Up at the top of the pyramid, on the eighth highest tier just below the ninth where Codicier Aeneas slumped slightly against the consoles, breathing heavily in the air of realspace for all that it was being pumped through Dark Mechanicus-devised life support systems, Tomb-Brothers Nathan and Cordas appeared behind the totality of the Black Legion troops remaining. Both bore no close-combat weapons at all, in direct contrast to Captain Thule, and instead with multi-meltas directly linked with their power systems. There was no hesitation, and from the moment they appeared they began turning Black Legion veterans of the Long War into melted lumps of ceramite and meat from behind, stomping forward and mercilessly sweeping four beams of near-instant death back and forth with mechanical precision. In turn, the Black Legion and its auxiliaries were forced to split their attentions for the first time since the battle began as the tide of enemy reinforcements were abruptly cut off.

Fighting: 99 vs. 36

Mortirex’s arm and axe flashed out.

Captain Thule’s dreadnought power fist clamped around the arm at the elbow, and with a single smooth twist and tear literally disarmed the Chaos Lord.

Mortirex’s legs tensed as he attempted to leap backwards.

Captain Thule’s other power fist grabbed him by the bottom of his left leg, the rest of the Chaos Lord’s body escaping him out of sheer speed and dragged him right back into range and began slamming him back and forth across the ground in a painful and yet glorious mirror to the method by which Mortirex had dealt with Apollo Diomedes.

Mortirex’s axe flashed back into his other hand, leaving a trail in its wake, all three eyes glowing brightly in ominous preparation.

Captain Thule reached forward and grabbed the axe outright, clenching about the portion of the shaft where the eyes glowed. The explosion that occurred after crushing said fist closed threw the dreadnought backwards, legs leaving huge furrows in the deckplates and the fist itself a melted piece of white hot slag that dripped and splattered upon the ground. In its wake, however, the daemonic axe lay in two pieces, the head beginning to fizzle and fuzz as the properties that kept it as a functioning weapon in reality began to flicker and fade. Three enormous warp presences half-emerged into the Immaterium before a blast of psychic fire from the combined force of all conscious and present Librarians banished them once more. The remaining piece of the axe was stuck in the ground, a half-vaporized piece of scrap metal.

Then he pushed that melted ruin directly against Mortirex’s chest and triggered the still functional heavy flamer while also clamping his remaining power fist on the Chaos Lord’s shoulder to hold him in place – while also triggering the storm bolter there at point blank range into another portion of his chest. In a complicated and rarely utilized maneuver, he further managed to extend his left leg upwards to the absolute limit of its capacity, which just barely granted him the clearance to slam his right leg down directly upon the armored groin and down to the floor beneath with the almost all the weight of a dreadnought chassis focused upon a single point.

As the duel was fought, the Blood Ravens attacked the Black Legion with renewed fury. Two dreadnoughts wielding two multi-meltas from behind slew scores themselves, and outright demanded the Black Legion turn their remaining heavy weapons upon them lest they be slaughtered entirely. Turning such weapons about let the remaining Blood Ravens savagely attack them. Codicier Aeneas did not flicker into the Warp again, yet the chaos amongst the upper tiers let him make use of his force sword once more albeit without nearly as much strength and speed as he was accustomed to. Bloodied, battered, many of them with utterly ruined suits of power armor, the Blood Ravens fought and killed. Such was the carnage, the wounds they had suffered up until that point, that they were barely discernable from corpses in only that they were still fighting.

“RRAAAAAARRGGH!” Mortirex bellowed, somehow managing to blow Captain Thule away from him with nothing more than a blast of his own inherent warp energies, stumbling upright and shifting backwards faster than Captain Thule could immediately grab once more.

His body continued to twist and bulge, musculature warping and changing visibly and uncontrollably now that his fused ceramite armor shell had largely been stripped from him. Now that he was out of range of Captain Thule’s fists, however, he was once more attacked by the remaining Blood Ravens, eager to avenge the deaths of so many of their brethren at the Chaos Lord’s hands. There was no refuge, no place of retreat, that at least some of the Blood Ravens could not find sight lines upon him. The remaining cultists were being culled at rapid pace, a single second of targeted sweep from a single multi-melta vaporizing them in the dozens. The marines of the Black Legion were faring only slightly better against the two dreadnoughts. Which was the point when Epistolary Idmon staggered to his feet, staff on the ground and psychic hood cracked, reached up with both hands and clamped them down on some invisible ledge before violently pulling downward – which coincided with the seventh, sixth, fifth, and fourth tiers momentarily partially liquifying and creating a similar effect to an outright landslide on the ‘slopes of the pyramid. Though that final angry effort blew Epistolary Idmon’s face off and shorted out his armor’s power pack, leaving his perpetually grinning skull wrapped in burnt muscle fibers as he slumped to the ground unconscious and smoking, the effect was devastating upon the prepared defenses of the enemy.

More than two thirds of the remaining of Black Legion veterans tumbled downwards, unable to find purchase before the metal and plastics resolidified, but in that time the dreadnoughts had performed their terrible, gruesome, and eminently effective work. Undignified as they’d fallen head over heels, more than a few had died, cut apart or simply melted entirely as the multi-meltas continued to fire. Those that had managed to find handholds were stuck in place by that same act of self-preservation, and thus became stationary targets, an even more fatal prospect than those who had fallen downwards. Many of the remaining cultists suffered truly terrible deaths, having slipped and disappeared into the temporarily liquid slopes and remained there when they solidified once again. The sheer weight of the dreadnoughts allowed them to stay upright and moving even when the tiers shifted and twisted beneath them, simply tearing their feet upright after the deckplates had reformed around them.

Mortirex saw none of this, focused as he was on fighting Captain Thule. He had dragged a power axe out from amongst the Black Legion dead, and had left many smoking rents and tears in the dreadnought’s frame. By now, half of his body seemed obscenely swollen, granting the arm wielding the axe even more insane daemonic strength, a twisting and barbed tentacle having exploded out of the socket of his left arm that lashed out with surprising effectiveness against Captain Thule. Though many of the Blood Ravens had been forced to focus on the remainder of the Black Legion lest their interference caused harm or difficulty to Captain Thule, some warily approached, led by the Chief Librarian. Justinius could see how the swirling cauldron of energies that flowed through the Chaos Lord had ceased to do so smoothly and had instead become a spiked and inverted tide. Now, Mortirex was no longer steadily drawing more of it into himself, but rather had become subject to an overwhelming and seemingly uncontrollable deluge. As more and more poured into him at a magnitude beyond his previous ability to control and direct, his body suffered as a result, already sprouting new mutations and unrestrained growth of biomass without direction.

For all of that, though, he still fought on.

Fighting: 38 vs. 20

Captain Thule was as relentless in half-death as he had been in life, and for all that the minds of the entombed were often clouded and distant, on this day and in this rousing from that deathly slumber his mind was as clear as it had ever been since he had first fallen on the planet Calderis. His storm bolter and heavy flamer were essentially always firing, exhausting his ammo and fuel stores at a pace that was frankly unsustainable for long-term battlefield conditions. In exchange, a wash of ignited promethium was constantly coating Mortirex from top to bottom while the storm bolter dug deep holes and trenches into his increasingly inhuman flesh. He made no more proclamations, and instead focused his mind wholly on manipulating the systems of his tomb to fight as effectively as possible. The Chaos Lord did not bellow, did not laugh, and instead only snarled and frothed as he fought back against the dreadnought, the power axe beginning to dig deeper and deeper into the chassis. The new tentacle he had grown from the stump of his previously torn off arm whipped back and forth, and each strike carried with it enough force to his opponent back, and with a shriek that could not have come from anything human he utilized both to nearly knock Thule onto his back, a fatal prospect for those entombed.

Which, in turn, cleared enough space around him for Tomb-Brothers Nathan and Cordas to turn away from the smoking remains of the last of the Black Legion and turn their combined four multi-meltas upon him. A single multi-melta, when wielded by a heavy power pack, sent two beams of pure superheated plasma that could burn through a variety of targets from regular infantry to superheavy tanks. A multi-melta hooked up to the far greater power supply capabilities of vehicles or dreadnoughts had its range and power extended all the more. Four multi-meltas, two for each dreadnought, fired eight total beams of searing destruction – all of which directly centered upon Mortirex. Two of the multi-meltas being utilized in that moment had once been used to help burn through armor of the Baneblade granted to the 1st Kronus Liberators in the Dark Crusade. Mortirex screamed, though he had no mouth. What little remained of his armor was vaporized and melted into dripping liquid ceramite and adamantium that splashed upon the ground. His newly grown tentacle was severed, and his overgrown mutated bulk gained several new holes in in less than a second. Mortirex recoiled, fell back from Captain Thule, and flailed as his scream reached a new fever pitch, seemingly emanated from many more throats.

Mortirex: 1

Justinius’ triumphant cry was cut off as he saw what no one else could, the rest of the Epistolaries having been forced unconscious or were utterly focused on saving what lives they could amongst their brothers. The maelstrom of energies, so uncontrolled, had shifted. Slowly, very slowly, but surely all the same. A grasping, evil will took hold of it. It was not enough, thankfully, to stem the tide. It could not steer an ocean. But what it did do, to Justinius’ horror, was steer the vessel upon it. Just enough. Enough that the energies did not collide and erupt and break apart the whole of the body. Instead, even as the Chief Librarian marshalled his will and lifted his hands, desperate to stop what he saw coming, it was too late.

“Brace yourselves!” He managed to shout.

What followed was an explosion of titanic proportions. Captain Thule managed to brace and was still driven off the tier and another fifteen feet back, powerful legs having dug enormous trenches into the deckplate and cogitators. For more than thirty feet all around Mortirex was an eruption of curdled Warp energies that blackened and altered the surroundings fully. Metal became flesh, became multi-colored vegetation. Foul life bloomed into existence before dying immediately, leaving confusing and revolting corpses of things that should not have been. Daemons emerged before collapsing back into themselves. The data within the nearby cogitators took on new abominable life that emerged upright as monstrosities of living physical code before the unnatural life and animus abruptly left them has stillborns. All of the smoke produced began to fade away, far faster than it should have naturally, sucking inwards into a suddenly revealed multitude of mouths.

It was an amorphous mass of tooth-covered flesh, flailing tentacles bearing black fire and barbs. Taller and wider than all three dreadnoughts combined, it had no discernable face whatsoever. In fact as it unbent its heavily segmented back, it was revealed to be some horrific looking exertion of biology that was an extant of what should have been a human arm. Five grasping fingers with a hundred bloodshot eyes, each joint length the size of landspeeders, clawed endlessly at the air. A single mouth fit to swallow a predator tank whole gnashed its massive teeth that filled said orifice to the brim and even on the flesh of the ‘palm’ where it was placed. Lesser limbs hefted it upright, things that were almost arms and almost legs, enough of them in multitude to manage its heavy bulk. Insectoid arms sprouted from newly forming pimples more than three feet in diameter, covered in pus and bearing blades which hummed and crackled with daemonic energies.

Far below, having crashed down multiple tiers and landed in a crumpled heap, was Mortirex.

Mortirex, who stood completely naked and scarred, slowly and shakily, his right arm gone from the shoulder down and the nimbus of dread power which had surrounded him missing completely. No, that wasn’t quite true, Justinius realized as he reflexively cast out his otherworldly senses. It hadn’t gone missing at all. It had simply moved. Forcibly. Desperately.

Successfully.

Into the chaos spawn made of the Chaos Lord’s former limb.

Justinius gaped, his mind trying to refuse the possibility outright, only to fail as he cast his eyes upon the chaos spawn once more. Indeed, that same infernal cauldron of Warp energies hung clearly about its frame now. It was directionless, without command or control. What it drew in on itself was not the favor of the Dark Gods or any other daemonic entities but was simply a natural consequence of its monstrous nature tugging upon the Warp, for it was born of such. A bounty, then, a glorious and hard-won thing that had been excised by nothing more than pure will and control. Given up, simply to survive that much longer rather than suffer what should have been the unavoidable consequences.

“There!” The Chief Librarian pointed, “He still lives! Kill him!”

Many turned swiftly, including the dreadnoughts, but by then the giant chaos spawn born of all that power that Mortirex had once possessed shrieked, screamed, and babbled before attacking in all directions. Some were picked up and flung away. Others were struck by acid covered teeth that were spat out at gunshot speeds at them. Its bulk shifted and bulged, twisting about and slamming its way through more cogitators and consoles, spreading out across two tiers with nothing more than sheer biomass. Beams of warp energies, wider and less compact than those once wielded by Mortirex through his axe began shooting out in all directions, even carving into the chaos spawn’s own flesh and forcing out new cries of insane pain. By necessity, if nothing else, many of the remaining Blood Ravens could not do anything less than try to fight this new foe before it slaughtered them.

Fighting: 96 vs. 33
Mortirex: 11 vs. 73

Unluckily for the chaos spawn, no matter its size, Tomb-Brothers Nathan and Cordos retained the high ground and had not even come close to overdrawing their reactors. Now they had reason to do so, and drew deeply upon their engine hearts, sinking their feet deep and letting loose at even greater intensity than before. Justinius let loose an inarticulate noise of frustration before he let loose with sheets of white flame upon the chaos spawn to burn away it its bubbling and already regrowing flesh. He watched, helplessly as he cast out another hand to shield a fallen Blood Raven, as Mortirex – now no longer the goliath size of before but rather something closer to more ‘average’ size for a space marine – slam the hilt of his stolen power axe into his jaw, locking it into place with torsion and leverage and fleeing, hacking at the doors of one of the blocked passages and disappearing through it.

By the time the spawn was felled, thankfully without any further casualties, it was too late.

When the tech-priests reached the master control tier, their first report was not that they had found the fallen Chaos Lord wherever he’d run to, but rather that a fleet of strike craft was rising up from the nine forge-hives of Opus Maxima. The shipyard had stabilized itself before reaching the tipping point of no coming back, but it was also close enough that there were more than a few kinds of transports capable of reaching it. At least two full skitarii legions were coming to reclaim the shipyard once and for all. The point defenses could be reactivated, possibly, but it wouldn't be enough to stop them all. More to the point, the descent of the shipyard had always been planned, it was just that Mortirex had pre-empted them.

"We have bled enough for this station," Tarkus said as he glanced about the shattered arena that had nearly been the end of them all.

"But what of Mortirex," Justinius argued. "He yet lives!"

"For now," Captain Thule intoned. "But the forces of Chaos do not kindly look upon failure."

The Chief Librarian shook his head.

"I will not hope that he shall be dealt with so easily. He is wounded, without followers, and managed to sacrifice the bulk of his power in order to live. But so long as he is alive, I do not think he will stop."

Tarkus clapped his remaining hand on the psyker's pauldron.

"Perhaps, brother, but for now...I would be done with this place."

The tech-priests as of yet maintained some control over the master control, and as such there was a choice to be made: where to drop the shipyard. Mortirex had intended to do it in the wastelands of the planet, where it would not harm the forge-hives. The Blood Ravens had no such compunctions. For ease of designation, Forge-Hive Primaris was that which sat at the center of the wheel, the rail lines spokes that extended out to the eight lesser peers. Being the primary, and likely initial landing sight of the Dark Mechanicus on the world, it was the best defended. Overlapping and vast void shields covered it well, and multiple defense lasers defended it. The other forge-hives had their own defenses, but none so complete as the main. Unfortunately, discerning more in depth data, such as specializations if any, was unavailable on the master control, such files required permissions that the tech-priests simply did not have the time to falsify or force their way past.

The vox crackled open.

"Captain Tarkus, I hear you still live," Admiral Graves said sardonically. "Do you still aim to drop the shipyard on the planet?"

"I do indeed, Admiral," Tarkus nodded, though the Admiral could not see it. "This place is too tainted, I suspect even the fuel lines might introduce corruption into any that partake of it, let alone their maintenance servitors."

"I agree," Graves sneered at the thought before brightening somewhat. "We've managed to destroy the remaining Dark Mechanicus ships, dead in the water means dead soon after, after all. What about you? You're not planning on riding that damned thing all the way down, are you?"

"No, merely attempting to choose the best target. The Dark Mechanicus is already attempting to try and reclaim the station."

Indeed, the remaining thousands of skitarii on the shipyard were already trying to break through their own defenses to reclaim the command center or kill the remaining Blood Ravens. Or both.

"I can tell, those strike craft are making clouds on the auspex. Better make it a quick decision, Captain," Graves said tersely. "Don't forget, the moment you start the shipyard on directed descent, it removes the shield for your strike cruisers."

"I know, Admiral. We must all move swiftly once the decision is made, one way or the other," Tarkus replied calmly.

What Does Tarkus Choose To Do?:
Moratorium 12 Hours
[] Main Drop: Drop it on top of the main forge-hive, and attempt to do some real damage to it. If it really works, it could decapitate the entire Dark Mechanicus in one swift blow. At the least, it shall cause chaos and distraction at the main hub. Enough to perhaps allow the fleet to pull back further if desired.
[] Side Drop: Crash the shipyard atop one of the lesser forge-hives, and by doing so aim for the defense lasers. Perhaps, if successful, it could create an opening in the anti-orbital grid that would allow for proper landings, and thus ensuring the Imperial Guard can join in on the fight, if that is the path chosen.

ALSO

[] Land On Opus Maxima: If the Dark Mechanicus is able to maintain supply lines through esoteric means or the like, they could continue to supply the rest of the Chaos forces in the system. Or they may reveal some abominations of technology that could prove too great of a threat to ignore. The die is cast, Opus Maxima must burn.
[] Retreat: The defenses of the Dark Mechanicus are considerable. It may be prudent to temporarily pull back and attempt to head to another of the planets instead. You've taken their ships, and are about to destroy their shipyard, hopefully completely stranding them.

Spoiler: Imperial Fleet

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Void Shielding At 50%, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius (+All Unassigned Librarians)
15(39) 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Remains Unconscious, Repairs Possible By Tech-Priests Accompanying Imperial Guard/Imperial Navy

24 5th Company Marines Require Bionic Replacements Or Dedicated Work By Chief Librarian And Epistolary Lucan Or Will Be Combat Crippled (Able to fire weapons, but not heavy weapons/able to fire heavy weapons, but not be standing or walk/ etc.) Total conscious 5th Company marines = 39. 15 are fully combat effective.

Epistolary Idmon is in an unshakable suspended animation coma.

Codicier Aeneas has fallen into a suspended animation coma, and will require intensive healing.

Epistolary Lucan has displayed additional mastery: [+Master Biomancer]

NOTE: Dedicating the psykers to healing purposes means not being able to contribute to immediate upcoming combat.

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor to Moderate Damage)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor to Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class (?)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
341 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
100 Heavy Combat Servitors
600~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
100 Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
2000~ Cultist Troopers
300 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
10 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Nine)

[] Side Drop: Crash the shipyard atop one of the lesser forge-hives, and by doing so aim for the defense lasers. Perhaps, if successful, it could create an opening in the anti-orbital grid that would allow for proper landings, and thus ensuring the Imperial Guard can join in on the fight, if that is the path chosen.
[] Land On Opus Maxima: If the Dark Mechanicus is able to maintain supply lines through esoteric means or the like, they could continue to supply the rest of the Chaos forces in the system. Or they may reveal some abominations of technology that could prove too great of a threat to ignore. The die is cast, Opus Maxima must burn.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

The difficulty was that none of the Dark Mechanicus holdings appeared wholly congruent to true Mechanicus counterparts. Perhaps that was the point of it, or perhaps they retained the same auspex baffling scrap code technologies that the ships had possessed. Tarkus personally felt that it was likely both, as well as some third and possibly even fourth attribute that was the reason for their inability to choose a most tactically prudent target. It was the way of Chaos, to mislead and obscure to protect itself. But he did not care, in the end, and instead elected to pick the swiftest target that the shipyard was closest to, as to ensure that as much of the enormous edifice of accursed artifice could strike the ground as possible. No doubt the moment it began moving again, the shipyards dark masters would eventually begin firing on it to reduce the effective damage it could deal. But perhaps not too early. Corrupted or not, they claimed to be tech-priests, after all.

“Target locked. Everyone, prepare for teleport back onto our vessels,” Tarkus announced before looking at the tech-priests. “Can you do anything to accelerate the descent? Make it hit even harder upon this target?”

The assembled tech-priests did not look well. Many of them had not necessarily been prepared for the sheer tempo of war that space marines lived within, and it showed upon their haggard frames. Some of them had been terribly affected by connecting into the tainted noosphere of the area, and wept oil and blood from various ports on their bodies. Still, some of them raised their heads, and of them all the one that still retained a biological eye looked to have gained a bit of fire back in it. They barked out something in lingua-technis to its companions. Some of the tech-priests shuffled slightly over to the consoles.

“We may try, Captain,” one declared.

Omnissiah Willing: 43 vs. 20

All who still walked upon the station felt it as its descent rapidly accelerated, a thunderous whine coming from its suddenly redirected gravimetric drives and maneuvering thrusters. Tarkus focused more on the triumphant blat of noise that erupted from many vocoders.

“We must evacuate immediately,” the tech-priest with the one organic eye proclaimed frantically. “Void shields will re-activate in thirty seconds!”

“Very well,” Tarkus nodded. “Attention all ships, prepare for shipyard descent on the designated forge-hive! Prepare for immediate hostile landing procedures!”

A new buzz filled the air as the teleportariums on the strike cruisers activated once again.

“Emperor, protect us as we travel through the blasted realm,” the Captain muttered to himself.

Teleport In Hostile Warp Environment: 65 vs. 50

It was only ever a brief thing, teleporting. But daemons needed only a second, in truth. Tarkus felt reality split open and shift, the laws of physics briefly ceasing to touch his body. He heard the howling beyond keenly as they shifted through the Warp, before suddenly gravity was real again and the screams dissipated. With a grunt and thump, he landed on one knee as he came crashing back upon the teleportarium platform. Around him, the few remaining combat capable Blood Ravens did the same in various states of stability. Nearby, on another platform, the three dreadnoughts of the 5th Company emerged from the Warp with a great many new scars still steaming and hissing on their frames, wounds garnered during that brief not-second between reality.

“Captain Thule, are you well?” Tarkus called out in concern.

“The rage of daemons are nothing before us,” the entombed Captain declared, swiveling slightly on his hip joints to look over at him. “But our hulls do require repair, and I..,” the dreadnought lifted the still sparking connector where his fist had been obliterated, “Require a replacement fist. We shall be repaired in time for battle on the surface if the servitors are fast enough. What of you?”

Tarkus glanced around. Not a single marine bore wargear unmarred by the fighting. Some were worse off than others. His company had been grievously depleted. They had slain a great many more of their number in chaos space marines, in traitors, in hereteks, and abominations. But there was yet much more fighting to be done. Many of his marines were too injured to return to the fighting just yet.

“Apothecary Medici?” He said instead on the command vox. “What is the status of our brothers?”

“Those that live might continue to do so,” the apothecary replied through gritted teeth. “Chapter Master Angelos’ repairs are proceeding apace, his organic components are mostly healed. Next time, bring a tech-marine along,” he added waspishly.

“Medici!” Tarkus barked, his tone stern. “Contain yourself.”

Instead, the apothecary outright snarled over the vox, each word of his reply bitten on the way out of his mouth.

“I am up to my arms, alone, in dead and dying brothers because we were so arrogant as to not request a single tech-marine or additional apothecary, let alone any other additional brothers. Falkor is dead!” Medici outright shouted over the vox. “I will make penance later, but for now do not bother calling upon me until I have preserved who and what I can!”

With that, the vox was shut off, Tarkus briefly squeezing his eyes shut in consternation as he sighed.

“Prepare for landfall on the surface,” he grunted as he got moving, “Resupply and see to your wargear as best you are able beforehand, meet in Hangar Primus-4.”

There was no time for self-recrimination.

==================================================

The shipyard over Opus Maxima had been given a name by its masters.

That sort of designation no longer mattered, now.

What mattered was that an utterly massive construct of adamantium, steel, oils, and reactor cores was racing beyond terminal velocity at one of the eight secondary forge-hives of the planet. It had been built to service an entire fleet at a time, ranging from escort ships to the behemothic vessels of battleships and battle barges, all at once. It was even able to service the ships of xenos, and was indeed the largest of its kind in the entire system as befitting its masters. Now it was crashing to earth, surrounded in a vast and blinding sheet of red and white fires as it shot down through the atmosphere. The strike cruisers shoot upwards at full speed with power directed to their aft shields, wobbling only slightly as the first few cursory strikes from the defense lasers struck them the moment they left the edges of the shipyard itself.

At first, the Dark Mechanicus rejoiced at the chance to reclaim what was theirs. The Chaos Lord had severed their ability to command it from below, and so they had marshalled a significant portion of their legions to reclaim it. But now it was falling again, and far faster than before.

Crashdown: 100 vs. 33
Mortirex: 9

One third of the assembled skitarii legions of the forge-hives, hastily and frantically assembling with mad mechanical precision into waiting shuttles and strike craft, ceased to be as the shipyard flew through the cloud of ships that had previously been straining to reach it. Others were just barely able to swerve out of the way, to accelerate horizontally rather than be swatted, crushed, or burnt to cinders by the intense heat surrounding the station as it descended. What had once been a distant but proud symbol of their mastery of technology was now falling upon the planet as if it were the fist of the Omnissiah Itself, coming to punish the hereteks. Immediately after passing through the fleet of ships that had been sent to reclaim it, the defense lasers opened up, hesitation only lasting so long as it descended further and further. Void shields sparked and bloomed into visible life, the artifice of the Dark Mechanicus proving proof…against the artifice of the Dark Mechanicus. Missiles flew, ballistic cannons that would not have been out of place on a titan’s frame boomed.

It was not enough.

Coming in from the far east at low angles, the troop ships of the Imperial Guard had descended almost as rapidly as the station, but just expertly so that the defenses of the enemy were wholly consumed with what was coming. They had come together, concentrating power on shields and engines, temporarily pulling from what few weapons they possessed and even life support to ensure as total a protection as they could temporarily maintain. Even so, these venerable ships that had served as arks of war for so long were buffeted insanely as the shipyard finally impacted. It had not broken up into pieces, an avalanche from the heavens, but rather struck as a single concentrated object with only a modicum of lost debris.

The forge-hive’s void shields did not even properly pop, but rather bent, snapped, and erupted as the generators which created them blew up as their capacity was violently overloaded beyond their limits. Hive spirals and smoke stacks shattered into fragments, metals were superheated into melting and in some cases into metallic vapor as the heat splashed upon it all. Flesh was not so much burnt to ash as simply reduced unto nothing at all. The concussive shockwave that followed afterwards lifted up entire buildings off of their foundations, shredded thousands of miles of pipes and plumbing for fuel and waste products, creating a hundred simultaneous eruptions of their own. Electrical cables several feet wide sparked into slag, causing major shutdowns in other locations before other shockwaves reached them. Stored explosives throughout the city, from grenades held in grenade launchers or held on the waists of certain skitarii and hereteks to the explosive shells meant for tanks and artillery vehicles to the bombs left in the bays of certain flying vehicles exploded from the sheer magnitude of the forces pushed upon them. Something of infernal artifice was surely destroyed, based on initial observations, as a warp rift tore open within the center of that ongoing inferno just before the latter half of the station finished hitting the ground, a few split seconds of difference.

Then the shipyard’s reactors exploded as they were crushed and battered by their own destruction, followed shortly by the forge-hive reactors built deep below, reached by the sheer violent force of what was unleashed. So much had been hollowed out, earth replaced with tunnels and supports, that an underground airburst explosion erupted, causing an upwards geyser of destroyed materials that had beforehand been buried beneath. The Dark Mechanicus had dug their roots deep, but now found that manipulation of the earth and rock turned against them. Gravity shuddered and ripped apart, earthquakes spewing outwards in all directions at magnitudes averaging 10.5, causing the entire massive edifice to begin crumpling inwards and down into a growing crater.

What resulted from all of this were massive shockwaves that practically threw the Imperial Guard ships together, or even possibly out of the skies. At least, that was what would have occurred if these were not veteran pilots and captains themselves, who had landed amidst ongoing wars and atmospheric hurricanes that could tear the skin off the bone. The waves of wind and force ended up crashing several more of the enemy transports and strike craft that had been so determined to reclaim the shipyard. Instead, ancient engines strained as they maneuvered back into place, coming down for a reasonably comfortable landing only a dozen miles away from the lip of the massive burning crater of shattered earth and obliterated metal which remained from the forge-hive. Ten miles of railway from outside the perimeter of the crater leading back towards the central and ninth forge-hive were destroyed as well.

“Well,” Colonel Gabriel Derosa declared as he listened to the ongoing reports of the destruction from within the safety of the ship. “If only we had eight more of those, eh?”

“And more for every other planet besides?” Said the woman standing next to him, her jet black hair cropped close to her head, gleaming medals for valorous service covering her front. “Hardly a chance for glory, that.”

“And yet,” Gabriel shook his head, “I almost find it poetic.”

“To use the weapons of the enemy is to be them,” the woman said stiffly, eyes narrowed.

“This isn’t using the weapons of the enemy like picking up a tainted bolter with a face growing out of the barrel, this is shoving their own evil works onto them, and letting the universe correct for it,” he shook his head. “Are we all prepared to deploy?”

“Initial platoons have already been deployed, schedule shows that within the hour over half of our strength shall be fully disembarked.”

“Excellent,” Gabriel nodded, squinting as he saw a new signal being transmitted from the auspex. “Ah, and there are the Blood Ravens.”

The woman narrowed her eyes.

“They only send a pair of thunderhawks to aid us?”

“They did take the station and ensured the aftermath most are celebrating,” Gabriel pointed out politely, “And all things told, they took casualties.”

He shook his head, many more ignorant citizens of the Imperium would have thought space marines utterly invincible. Indomitable. But if there was anything he knew after the three Aurelian Crusades, it was that they were far more fallible than most would like to contemplate.

“Hmph. I shall take their measure for myself,” she sniffed as she stepped away from the bank of consoles within the ship’s bridge.

“As I have told you, wife,” he said, catching her hand and making her look back at him with a raised eyebrow, “These are not the Blood Ravens that your father knew.”

She glared at him and tugged her hand free, sniffing again as she fiddled with her commander’s hat.

“So you and your mother have said. And yet, I will accept only the truth before my very eyes, not just my ears. That is practically a third of the reasoning behind our joining at all, your mother’s desperate work to work diplomacy on the part of these…Blood Ravens,” she sneered the words.

Less than twenty minutes later, Gabriel was marveling at the Blood Ravens in person, along with the rest of his command squad. Just as he’d known, they showed little to no reaction to his sanctioned psyker Brellis, the older man mumbling to himself as a cloudy liquid dripped from his hollow eye sockets. They were not, he saw, without wounds. Many of them showed clearly hastily applied repairs to their wargear, their power armor, and yet their weapons had clearly been made relatively pristine for their descent onto the planet. To attempt to simply fly into a heavily defended forge-hive was impossible, of course.

“Captain Tarkus, we are already setting up a perimeter for defenses, and our basilisks are zeroed in for the moment the enemy tries to bring out their own artillery,” he said as around them the Imperial Guard rushed to emerge from their transports. “And we-,”

A mechanical roar deafened his next words, and many others besides. The Meridian noble winced and crouched slightly as the noise continued to emerge from the massive Galaxy-class that he had ridden on.

“I apologize,” he said after the noise had barely begun to fade. “That is…,”

“A Baneblade,” Captain Tarkus finished for him, eyes narrowed towards the utterly cavernous mouth of the landed Galaxy.

“Well, rather-,” Colonel Derosa’s next words were drowned out as the noise came again, closer.

Along with answering roars as well.

The Blood Ravens watched, unmoving, as ten Baneblades emerged from the ramp of the Galaxy-class transport. A hundred and ten barrels of hell swept across the surrounding area as they drove out in wedges of five, the first of the wedges driving forth at dangerously rapid pace to approach where Gabriel and the Blood Ravens stood. It yet bore the flags of the Imperium, however, and so they did not shy away. Several guardsmen had to leap out of the way, however, to avoid getting run over. Many of these did not escape getting absolutely covered in dust and ash cast out by the passage of the superheavy tanks. The lead of them, clearly customized as a command vehicle, came the closest, leaving the remaining four of its wedge behind.

And immediately, Tarkus closed his eyes in silent pain before opening them again as he recognized the flags that hung proudly upon the Baneblade’s sides. But he said nothing before the cupola was opened and a scarred woman with black hair, medals upon her uniform, and a large bolt pistol on her waist emerged. A pair of slim power claws, currently sheathed within themselves, were attached carefully onto her heavily muscled forearms. If anything, the woman looked like an escaped Sister of Battle who had taken on the form of an Imperial Guard tank commander. More importantly, her face was intimately familiar to those who had studied the pict-captured faces of those who had been important in the War for Kaurava.

“Captain Tarkus. I am Colonel Amelia Stubbs, wife of Colonel Derosa,” she declared as she hefted herself, one-handed, out of the tank and strode along its top to look down upon the Blood Ravens, hands on her hips. “I believe you may know my father, the Lord Subsector?”

“Not personally, no, but yes I know of him,” Tarkus responded politely. “The actions of Captain Boreale are regretted thoroughly, Colonel.”

“Hmm. That is one word for it,” she sniffed. “For now, I command the 7th Meridian Consolidated Armored Regiment. But know this!” She stomped her foot on the top of her Baneblade. “I command my tanks, and no other. Is that understood, Blood Raven?”

Tarkus just nodded.

“Aye, Colonel.”

“…my husband says that you Blood Ravens have changed,” she continued. “I am here to see if that is truly the case. I suppose we shall see. What is our plan of attack upon these forge-hives?”

A clearing throat made all present look to the side.

“If I may,” Inquisitor Adrastia said, having somehow made her approach unannounced to the shock of many present. “I may have a solution beyond simply grinding our steel against theirs until we are all dead. Magos?” She turned to a twitchy looking tech-priest that had accompanied her.

In fact, the Inquisitor’s retinue had extended quite a bit. Colonel Merrick, declared KIA long ago, glanced at the Blood Ravens and shared a terse nod with pursed lips. On this day, he bore a hotshot lasgun and a rather enormous and heavily armored case on his back. He was joined not only by the Magos that the Inquisitor had referred to, but a steely eyed chiurgeon of the Sister Hospitaller as well. The Magos was almost wholly mechanical, and their upper torso was mostly seemingly made of mechadendrites which twitched and poked about, revealing an incredibly thin cylinder at the center which was the actual torso proper. A face covered almost entirely in varying lenses ducked this way and that, staring at certain points in the middle distance before moving on seemingly without any rhyme or reason whatsoever. The Inquisitor herself was dressed fully in power armor, the entire system closed with a black-painted and red lensed helm bearing the Inquisitorial Rosette stamped in the forehead.

“C-c-careful study of manifold transfers a-a-and electrical current wattage b-b-based on scans,” the tech-priest spoke oddly, twitching and bending with every word, stuttering like a lagging recording repeatedly. “H-h-have revealed g-g-general a-a-assumed junctions p-p-powering enemy subsystems r-r-relating-,”

“To summarize,” Inquisitor Adrastia interrupted with a sigh, a hand going up to silence the odd Magos, “Whilst the shipyard’s void shields were down, and during the duration within which the so-called Fabricator-General of Opus Maxima enacted a dialogue with Mortirex, the Magos was able to locate and designate the main geothermic reactor core which powers the majority of the main forge-hive,” she said rapidly, looking between the various personnel before her. “Based on even initial estimates, a properly engaged cascade shutdown could cause catastrophic damage to the entire forge-hive, possibly the entire planet given how widespread their geothermic grid is.”

She grimaced, then.

“I suspect that the only reason the grid is in such a state is with the assumed plan of fully transforming the world into a functioning Forge World, with the power requirements planned out in advance.”

“So there’s a chance,” the daughter of Vance Stubbs said with a tight grin. “Brilliant. I’d rather wondered if we’d all die here plinking against their bloody void shields or if we’d get hunted down and surrounded by their legions.”

“What, precisely, are you proposing, Inquisitor?” Tarkus asked, raising an eyebrow at her.

Inquisitor Adrastia smiled nastily.

“When I first realized we were preparing to go after Vandis, I envisioned some monolithic fortress, possibly built into an asteroid or a lone keep protected by sorcery and foul technologies,” she admitted, though a bit ruefully considering what they had encountered instead. “As such, I prepared several gate cracking explosives accordingly. Not necessarily on the scale of a full blown cyclonic torpedo, but specialized with built-in delivery system,” she then glanced at the case on Merrick’s back. “A specialized, high-powered beacon for teleport purposes.”

The veteran guardsman looked a bit put out about just what he was carrying, but shrugged at the stares sent his way.

“Better than landing the thing and trying to lug it who knows how many miles,” the Inquisitor continued. “But based on the Magos’ calculations, proper placement of the beacon – and successful delivery – could ensure victory here. There is only one issue.”

“Distracting the Dark Mechanicus while the infiltration team gets down there,” Colonel Derosa said, a grim look on his face.

“Exactly,” Adrastia nodded. “I shall personally escort the beacon, along with the rest of my retinue and some of my stormtroopers. We shall proceed along the rail line, underground, as with much of it destroyed by the explosion they are not likely to be sending troops there. But in the meantime, the ferocity of the distraction must be so great as to fully grab the attentions of the Dark Mechanicus.”

“I think they are mightily pissed enough with…that,” Colonel Derosa gestured towards the massive scene of wreckage a short way away.

The mushroom clouds were still raising high into the air, secondary and tertiary explosions cooking off every few minutes. Toxic smog clung tightly over the entire ruined forge-hive, creating a disturbing capped layer above the crater.

“They speak truly,” Justinius spoke for the first time, his eyes shut. “I sense…a vast ocean of metal and wrath assembling to crush the interlopers to their world.” He opened his eyes. “Interlopers being us.”

“Well let them come,” Colonel Stubbs declared, stomping back to the cupola of her Baneblade. “We’ll give you more than a distraction, Inquisitor,” she snarled. “We’ll give them death!”

All around them, the Imperial Guard quickly began assembling defenses. Heavy weapons teams, sandbags, and more began being rushed to the fore, lesser commanders taking admirable initiative to go about their work, barking commissars speeding things up further. Without another word to anyone else, Colonel Stubbs drove her entire force of Baneblades towards one of the flanks, essentially planting them on the front lines as mobile hard points. Basilisk groups began rumbling about and gathering together to be able to concentrate their fire.

“The main benefit of this landing zone is that they will most likely not try to drive through the crater of the former forge-hive,” Adrastia said, tapping a finger to her lips. “They shall have to split around it, come from the northwest and southwest, rather than directly from the west as I’m sure they would have preferred.”

“It seems you’ve thought this out well, Inquisitor,” Tarkus said with a gruff note of approval in his voice.

“This is not looking to be the easiest conflict,” she replied calmly, “I do not intent to spend the lives of those we have brought with us foolishly. Which brings me to my next question. Shall the Blood Ravens be joining me in plunging a dagger into the heart of this wretched planet, or shall you remain on the main battle line, supporting the Imperial Guard? And what of Gabriel?”

“Chapter Master Angelos is recovering swiftly,” Tarkus said honestly, “But his specialized bionics are not so swiftly repaired. The apothecary reports that he shall be conscious soon.”

If the shipyard had not done its work so surprisingly thoroughly, Tarkus knew that Gabriel would likely have been at least conscious before this conversation came up again.

“Unfortunate,” she pursed her lips and shook her head. “Yet the question remains. I am aware that your forces are depleted, Captain. But should we manage our work, we may be able to successfully cut any conflict on this world short.”

“What of the forge-hive’s void shields, how can you ensure the beacon’s function?”

Adrastia tilted her head at her Magos.

“Damage the genatorium grid enough to cause the void shields to fail, even for a few seconds, and it will be enough – both to deliver the bomb and to return ourselves to my ship in orbit in a single go.” Adrastia clicked her tongue. “This is about speed, Captain, if you do not think that your battle brothers can keep up, remain here.”

A dangerous, dangerous move. Bold in the extreme. But Tarkus could not see any other possibilities that did not involve tremendous loss of life on the part of their forces.

“Justinius-,”

“This place is madness for my kind,” the Chief Librarian grimaced. “There, there, and there,” he pointed into the distance, at the small dots on the horizon that were other forge-hives. “There are…pylons, it seems. Scouring pillars of warp energy that block my foresight. I’ll bet that each of the forge-hives has at least one. They are built of pain, solidified into cables that contain the warp energies which then pulse through obscene icons of their version of the Omnissiah regularly. Trying to even look at one of the cities with my second sight is akin to staring into a continually ongoing flashbang.”

But Adrastia clearly wasn’t listening, given how her focus had gone elsewhere. The space marines could, much to their misfortune, hear the words being spoken to her through the comm-bead.

“What do you mean you aren’t detecting the wreckage of the battle barge or its strike cruisers in the ruins,” Adrastia hissed to the man helming the auspex console on her ship. “They were locked into the docking clamps! The only way to escape would have been a warp jump while within the atmosphere, only a madman would-,” her jaw clamped shut, her expression twisting into something almost inhuman in its hatred. “Fine. Keep a watch upon the warp currents, then. The gravity reef means he can't leave the system.”

Tarkus, very slowly, closed his eyes and held them shut as he breathed in. And out. His fists clenched and unclenched, but not so much that it damaged the bolter they held.

“Whatever your decision, Captain, I shall support it – Angelos gave you command, and I shall follow his orders,” Justinius spoke up. “But we must make our decision now. I can feel that seething ocean of death closing in.”

“Hmm, indeed,” Adrastia nodded. We shall proceed through the ruins, toxic as they may be, to avoid the enemy forces. There we shall make our entry into the destroyed rail systems and onward onto the main forge-hive. Unless, perhaps, you have some brilliant plan of your own, Captain?” She turned to look at Tarkus.

What Does Tarkus Choose To Do?
Voting Moratorium For 12 Hours

[] Follow Adrastia’s Plan: If it works, it works. It may be the only chance there is to actually win this fight rather than get bogged down beneath the unfeeling legions of Dark Mechanicus skitarii and hereteks.
[] Another Plan: Write-In

REGARDLESS

[] Assign Forces Accordingly: Determine where Librarians, Battle Brothers, and Dreadnoughts will be deployed, whether in aiding Imperial Guard or joining Inquisitor Adrastia or whatever else. (Write-In) [EX: Terminators And Dreadnoughts Remain With Imperial Guard, Healing Specialized Epistolary Lucan Focuses On Healing Battle Brothers, Others Join Adrastia, etc.]

Spoiler: Imperial Fleet

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Void Shielding At 50%, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius (+All Unassigned Librarians)
15(39) 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Remains Unconscious, Biological Components Mostly Restored, Bionic Restoration Ongoing

24 5th Company Marines Require Bionic Replacements Or Dedicated Work By Chief Librarian And Epistolary Lucan Or Will Be Combat Crippled (Able to fire weapons, but not heavy weapons/able to fire heavy weapons, but not be standing or walk/ etc.) Total conscious 5th Company marines = 39. 15 are fully combat effective.

Epistolary Idmon is in an unshakable suspended animation coma.

Codicier Aeneas has fallen into a suspended animation coma, and will require intensive healing.

Epistolary Lucan has displayed additional mastery: [+Master Biomancer]

NOTE: Dedicating the psykers to healing purposes means not being able to contribute to immediate upcoming combat.

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor to Moderate Damage)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor to Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class (?)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Ten)

[] Follow Adrastia’s Plan: If it works, it works. It may be the only chance there is to actually win this fight rather than get bogged down beneath the unfeeling legions of Dark Mechanicus skitarii and hereteks.
-[] Epistolary Lucan concentrates on healing the wounded, a squad of regular Blood Ravens, Damion Tyrin, and Justinius Probalis join Adrastia under command of Kaius Jacobus, while the Terminators, the Dreadnoughts, the remainder of the Librarius, and the command squad including Captain Tarkus remain with the Guard.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

“We shall hold the line here,” Tarkus said grimly, getting a solemn nod from Adrastia in return. “However, some of the Blood Ravens shall accompany you, if you would have them Inquisitor.”

“I would welcome the aid,” the Inquisitor nodded, eyebrow raised. “Who did you have in mind?”

Tarkus turned away and glanced at the pittance of the remaining Blood Ravens before him. Most were looking at him, having been listening in even though they were surrounded by the hastily deploying forces of the Imperial Guard in all their cacophony. Sergeant Stromahn and his tactical terminator brethren were not. They would not be fast enough, and they knew it. Instead, the heavily armored veterans of the 1st Company were gathering their weapons and ammo amongst themselves and waiting for further orders of deployment. Instead, Tarkus glanced amongst the marines remaining. Two squads, one at half strength. Others of his command squad were present as well, and they too looked to him.

“Kaius,” Tarkus said, causing the quiet champion of the 5th Company to blink. “You’ll have command of the detachment I’m sending with the Inquisitor. Sergeant Graham, you and your squad will be accompanying him.”

Sergeant Graham had been recruited from Meridian, but as proven by Thaddeus and the many recruits they’d gathered from that planet since, the crucible of the Aurelian Crusades had hardened its populace considerably form the indolence that they had fallen into under the accursed House Vandis. More importantly, he had managed to keep his entire squad combat functional with minimal to no injuries during the carnage in orbit. The sergeant did not hesitate, did not question, merely marched over to Adrastia’s side, falling into formation behind Kaius who had managed to get there first without anyone noticing.

“Damion. You and the Chief Librarian shall go as well.”

Another pair of nods, but this time Adrastia looked mildly shocked.

“Are you sure, Captain? Without them-,”

“I choose to have faith in the strength of Meridian,” Tarkus nodded gravely. “And should your mission fail, this will all be for naught regardless, correct?”

Adrastia’s head drew back before she nodded.

“Very well. I assume all of you can environmentally seal your suits,” she directed this towards the Blood Ravens. “The readings we’re getting from the ruins of the forge-hive are…quite toxic.”

“We shall endure,” Justinius promised.

“Let us move out, then. Time is of the essence.”

Indeed it was. With those simple words, the entire group began moving at what was a loping run for the humans and a slow jog for the space marines, directly towards the waiting crater. In the meantime, there were preparations to be made, heavy weapons teams to be built up, and so on. As for the Blood Ravens, they prepared for the tide as best they could. There would be no point in tightly concentrating their forces, they were far too few for even that to matter much. The mass of the enemy would not be distracted by a single tantalizing point of Astartes. Instead, all Blood Ravens present took up the heavy weapons that they could, more than enough to go around after the casualties they’d taken and became semi-mobile hardpoints.

“HERE THEY COME!” a Guardsman yelled a startlingly short time later.

Guns began pounding immediately. Basilisks not even finished rolling down the ramps paused, turned, and began firing. The longest ranged weapons on the Baneblades boomed, and the crack of longlas rifles began snapping out. Tarkus glanced to the direct west, in the dusty trails left behind by the Inquisitor’s rapidly moving party and quietly murmured a litany of faith and zeal in their name. The horde approaching from either side of the crater towards them was voluminous indeed, and the anti-air vehicles that the Guard had brought with them were already busy. This distant from the rest of the void shields, however, the envelope of the anti-orbitals was not so thick as to utterly prevent any firing whatsoever from the ships high above. Tarkus felt the slightest of smiles make its way across his face, though none saw it because of the helmet, as he heard the familiar whine followed by titanic boom as a bombardment shell landed amongst the enemy cybernetic daemon-machine hordes, one fired with a clever shot from one of the strike cruisers.

As for himself, the Captain of the 5th Company hefted the two plasma cannons he’d requisitioned, their power and cooling packs left behind him while remaining connected with their cabling, testing the weight of them on his shoulders.

“May none find us wanting,” he growled as the first four legged monstrosities belched out of the madness of the Dark Mechanicus came into range.

==========================================================

The planet Cordelia was half-eaten already, but that did not stop the Ebon Claws, nor the Blood Ravens. Warp bombs and heavy munitions had helped prune back the feeding tendrils from their sites on the planet, engulfing whole swathes of the former civilized world in magmatic destruction. Less than a third of the planet’s former population still lived, holed up on the heavily fortified cities on the plateaus atop the savannahs, where the PDF cowered with them. And so it was left to the space marines to strike down the Shadow Towers, which would allow the Imperial Guard and Imperial Navy local to the subsector to actually make it into the planetary system. Some had been destroyed already, but others were too thickly defended from orbit to make such an attack upon. From orbit. From the ground was another matter.

“Go, go, go!” Cyrus yelled at the top of his lungs; his growling rasp escalated into a tumultuous roar as he began sprinting away from the alerted swarms behind him.

The Captain of the 10th Company was quickly grabbed, and in a somewhat undignified manner nearly had his arms torn out of their sockets as Captain Manin of the Ebon Claws dragged him forwards. It was occurring all across the base of the Shadow Tower, hundreds of thousands of tyranids swarming and fired bio-plasma into the air at the interlopers who had managed to get so deep within their territory. Some of the Blood Ravens and Ebon Claws fired what weapons they could, right before the first bombardment shell descended from the heavens. Over a hundred tons of organic matter were vaporized and turned to blasted charcoal in a single blow, the blanketing power of the Shadow of the Warp finally penetrated by the signal boosted beacons devised by Martellus. For too long, had the auspex scans and probes been unable to get sufficient locks, the clouds of tyranid ships preventing the ships of the Imperium from getting close enough for other methods.

Until now.

“Trigger the teleports!” Cyrus yelled through the whipping winds as the space marines flew at the speeds of customized jump packs being pushed to their limit.

“The Shadow in the Warp might yet be too strong!” Captain Manin replied, voice tight.

Cyrus could fell the shockwave of the bombardment about to reach them.

“We either risk the teleport, or we will be crushed by the shockwave!”

“…very well! Initiating!”

In the far view, one could easily miss the blink of less than fifty lights flashing amongst the absolute geological destruction being enacted upon the former luscious jungle that the feeding tendril had anchored itself upon. Many would, instead, be far more focused upon the frantic messaging of the astropaths high above on the edges of the planetary system. Though Cordelia was only one of the five planets in the system, the non-standard orbits of the planets happened to result in it being the absolute furthest to the edge in that very moment. And in that crucial moment, the Shadow in the Warp was weakened, its blanket of choking strength frayed.

Cyrus reappeared in the Ebon Claws strike cruiser with a gasp and grunt as both he and Captain Manin were flung forwards off the platform due to their original momentum partially carrying over. Both of them were on their feet in an instant, watching as others arrived in similar manner. Few were as lucky as they in terms of wounds, many still gritting their teeth or groaning as bio-plasma burned through the ceramite coating and adamantine plate into the flesh beneath. A handful did not reappear at all, and one pair emerged as a disgusting melded abomination that required immediate destruction.

“Was it enough,” Cyrus grunted, looking at Manin as the Ebon Claw listened to the vox channels.

“…yes,” the Ebon Claw grinned fiercely. “We are receiving reports that the fleet was able to enter the edges of the system, enough to tip the balance. If they are swift, we will be able to advance swiftly throughout the rest of the planets. If the Navy’s leadership is capable enough…this may be enough to save the system.”

“Hrrngh,” was Cyrus’ grunted response. “We’ll see.”

Every moment was precious. The presence of the Shadow Towers vastly extended deployment times, meaning that every moment spent was another moment of them devouring the planets they’d taken further. Based on the reports, and the follow-up calculations, Cyrus knew that at least three worlds were likely to be completely lost by the time that the forces of the Imperium reached them. Ten billion citizens of the Imperium turned into biomass for the tyranids, to be shaped and remolded into new xenos forms thrust out of the spawning pools covered in toxic amniotic fluids. Ten billion at minimum. One civilized world lost. One mining world with its resources stolen out from the coffers of the Imperium. One death world, a major training base for the Imperial Guard. The latter bothered Cyrus the most – that was the most likely location for the tyranids to gain new and dangerous adaptations aside from the baseline.

=======================================================

Through The Crater: 98
Defense: 59 vs. 56

The ruins of the forge-hive were a shattered wasteland of metal and daemonic flesh. Toxic waste and acidic fluids spewed from shattered piping, sewer systems where failed experiments and warp-tainted materials were flushed had been thrust upwards as the foundation had cracked and splintered. The forces enacted upon it, first from the falling station, then from its reactor hearts erupting, had wiped out all living beings that had inhabited it – slaves and masters alike. Yet for all of that, things still moved. Fires miles in length and height, powered by hundreds of gallons of promethium and other fuel sources still burned. Portions of the upper buildings continued to fall to earth, and the ground itself was constantly wracked with quakes as the crater continued to settle. The heat itself was blistering and would have been fatal to those without closed environmental suits of the sophistication available to the Inquisition and the Adeptus Astartes. Certain areas were so irradiated that even then the force had to shift to avoid them, lest they rot into slurry within their armor. As it was, auspex scanners were all but useless, the heat signatures, radiation, and other hazards forcing all to fall back onto the psychic senses of the Blood Raven librarians. Were it not for them, it was likely that even the Inquisitor would have been lost within that burning labyrinth, even with her own psychic abilities.

Behind them, the legions of Opus Maxima finally reached the forces of the Imperial Guard, those that made it past the carefully fired bombardment shells of the Blood Raven strike cruisers. There were daemon machines, loping things that aped the appearance of ancient terran wolves and lions, flesh grown in tubes and enhanced with hypersteroidal injections melded with metal madness incarnate. There were skitarii and war servitors whose lower bodies were treads, were wheels, were hover sleds, all to push them forwards at fast paces. There were flying craft that lifted just above the heads of those they fought alongside. Weapons as simple as slug throwers were joined by plasma and bolter and even more hideously advanced things.

The Imperial Guard beheld the insane creations of the Dark Mechanicus, who had followed the traitor Horus into darkness, who willingly joined their creations with the Warp, and stood firm.

===========================================================

“Blessed be the machine spirit within you, who grants you animus. Blessed be the servitors who loaded thy ammo, blessed be the Omnissiah who cast your design into the minds of His Holy Servants,” Martellus muttered.

With a final, heavy wrench, the tarantula whirred to life. Its activation lights turned green, and it began to shift back and forth, going through initial diagnostics at high speed. Martellus let a sigh of relief escape him as he stood back from it, glancing around at the rest of the holy machines surrounding him. His expression turned sour, however, when he glanced upon the broken thunderhawk. Half of it was still melting away into slag, the bio-plasma of the tyranids eating through its hull and the internals easily. It would be utterly unrecoverable, at least in terms of making it fly again. It held many valuable parts still, things worth salvaging, but he didn’t have time for that.

“So,” he grunted, racking the slide of his storm bolter and placing it into the waiting manipulators of his servo-harness mechadendrite. “You think that’s going to be enough?” He muttered to himself. “Do you?”

All around him, the screams of the tyranids could be heard. They were eager, waiting, ready just to feast upon the target that they had shot down. The rest of the formation were turning about, even now, but they would not be able to land in such a hot zone. It would have to be elsewhere, and they would have to forge their way to his position. Or they would proceed with their mission to destroy the hives of the tyranids to keep them from spawning even more combat creatures. It would not matter, in the long run, if he did not survive the coming moments. He turned, sneering, as the first of the tyranids crested the hills nearby, shrieking and chittering, some of them even firing small bio-plasma bolts in his direction haphazardly.

“YOU THINK THIS IS THE FIRST TIME THE HIVE MIND HAS SHOT ME DOWN?!” He roared, and with a wave of his hand, activated the rest of his cargo which he’d placed after making sure they were all functional.

There was a reason the thunderhawk transporter had only registered a single organic occupant.

“TASTE THE FURY OF THE OMNISIAH, XENO SCUM!”

And all fifteen Tarantulas opened fire, Martellus doing the same with the belt-fed bolters he held in each hand and the storm bolter in his mechadendrites. Such was the volume that one could not even hear the sounds of grenades and heavy weapons fire coming from where the other thunderhawks had hastily landed. Hormagaunts and termagaunts in their hundreds charged at him, and hundreds of hormagaunts and termagaunts died. Martellus palmed, armed, and threw a frag grenade in a low bouncing skip that took it just beneath the zoanthrope that crested the hill, blowing the synapse creature to pieces. When the warriors showed up, a twist of his wrist and the networked turrets turned as one and spent a single second’s worth of heavy bolter and multi-melta fire to kill them. With each eruption of the nearest synapse creatures, the momentum of the enemy slowed, became confused. Each such kill bought him more of that precious, precious thing called time. Through the toxic clouds of the xeno-formed landscape, Martellus could see the lights of jump packs on the horizon.

“NONE SHALL FIND ME WANTING!”

“FROM DARKNESS, SALVATION!”

The Ebon Claws 9th Company had arrived, Captain Manin at their head.

=================================================================

Railway Tunnels: 92
Defensive Distraction: 86 vs. 75

“Status,” Tarkus grunted as he triggered one of the plasma cannons.

Another superheated sphere impacted directly into the face of an approaching combat walker, sending it crashing to the ground with a scream of metal and multiple cybernetic exhaust throats. The cooling cycle meant that he could not fire both with impunity, but he had found that in this position, the power packs protected, he could fire one after the other. One usually finished cooling by the time the other had charged up, fired, and begun its own cooling cycle. Around him, the rest of the Imperial Guard fought extremely fiercely, and here Tarkus could find the hidden grit of Meridian revealed to the galaxy once more. Some were outright crying at the visions being shown to them, the insanity-inducing sight of the Dark Mechanicus unleashed sure to cause nightmares in the future. But the most important thing was that they were shooting back. Being able to fire a lasgun, a bolter, an autocannon, a lascannon, or a grenade launcher into the face of an abominable enemy, Tarkus understood, helped reduce the amount of fear that one held. Or so he’d heard from the ranks of the Guardsmen in times past.

“Kill them, in the name of the Emperor!”

“Ugly bastards, aren’t you! Well don’t worry, I brought enough lasbolts for all of you!”

“BRING! THEM! HELL!”

The last was broadcast from the nearest Baneblade, each of them now unleashing all eleven barrels of hell upon the enemy. They had formed an impressive wedge, around which the Dark Mechanicus was pushed back, was cut or blown apart, far in excess of almost any other part of the battle line. It did not mean that the servants of the Dark Mechanicus were not still trying, merely that weight and potency of fire was killing them faster and further than elsewhere along the line. Other hardpoints of major resistance existed, heavy weapons teams, the dreadnoughts, Tarkus himself, and other locations with the Blood Ravens. In other portions, however, the Imperial Guard were forced to deal with monstrosities of abused flesh and twisted metal getting right up in their faces before they could be brought down. Anywhere that was in too much danger, where the line was in danger of breaking, would receive danger close bombardment from the basilisks.

“Epistolary Lucan is still working upon the wounded left in orbit,” a serf responded after a moment from the bridge of the Litany of Fury. “Chapter Master Angelos is nearing wakefulness once more, his bionics are mostly repaired.”

“Very well. If anything changes, let me know,” Tarkus said tersely.

A single winking thrum in Tarkus’ mind appeared and then disappeared. The sensation of a hand clapping upon his pauldron in comradeship, a grim nod suggested through the mind and whirling of the wind. It was the assigned signal, a complex but recognizable series of sensations delivered by a powerful psychic mind. Tarkus did not let himself feel any satisfaction that Justinius and the others were in the tunnels, not when so much else could still go wrong. There was still a major battle to be fought here, if nothing else. They were out of time, outnumbered, and given the sophistication of the enemy, possibly outgunned.

But then, Tarkus knew, in the end the man who had nothing could still have faith.

It would have to be enough.

==================================================================

Through The Tunnels: 68 vs. 26
Defensive Distraction: 48 vs. 70

“…impressive,” Inquisitor Adrastia murmured as the patrol of skitarii passed by, eyes and scanners passing over their entire party without pausing.

“Difficult,” Justinius corrected through grit teeth as faint energies bloomed from his hands. “Their technology is aided by the Warp, by daemons, in the process of the forging.”

“I see,” she nodded curtly. “The deeper we get, the more patrols we run into. They are beginning to suspect something, no doubt.”

The skitarii began to poke and prod at their stolen transport train, barking at one another in scrap code through corrupted vocoders. It had been a stroke of luck that it had survived the explosions that had filled the tunnels when the forge-hive died, its bay protected by thick blast shields that had closed just in time. Shields that had not, however, been enough to stop Justinius from manipulating the locks within the structure and letting them inside. They were still going to be setting off radiological alarms in the meantime, but thankfully the reckless industry of the Dark Mechanicus worked against them. In a realm where illicit compounds could take on lives of their own, aided or possessed by daemons or random bursts of Warp energies, where containment breaches of experiments could occur whenever a Magos was looking to sabotage his rivals, where weapons deemed illegal even by the standards of the Imperium were wholly unregulated. Even now, some of the skitarii walking past were clearly on their last legs, their organic components withering away from the toxic fumes of the area, requiring either replacement or recycling. Knowing the Mechanicus, Dark or otherwise, it was likely that the metal components would be deemed more valuable when more organic matter could be grown in tubes to.

“We should move on,” Kaius spoke up, the Champion of the 5th Company having holstered his flamer for now. “There will likely be entrances and areas that even Justinius cannot shield us within.”

“I agree,” Adrastia nodded before gesturing, her stormtroopers and retinue following with her as the Blood Ravens moved. “Magos?”

“T-t-t-tapping n-n-noosphere,” the twitching tech-priest stuttered. “R-reports indicate interlopers giving h-h-heavy resistance, but kills have been made. L-line-lines broken in certain location-n-n-ns?”

Kaius pursed his lips inside his sealed helmet and glanced over at Justinius, who shook his head in turn.

I do not trust this stuttering thing. It is broken, and I do not have to be a psyker to see that much, the normally quiet Champion said in his mind.

It bears a taint in it, yes, Justinius replied mentally, his expression equally invisible in his helmet. But it is bound, chained. Inquisitor Adrastia risks much utilizing it rather than putting it down, but for now its worth outweighs the risk.

The moment it begins to break those chains…Kaius let the thought trail off.

He did not need to say anymore.

Understood.

“Do you, or do you not have a map yet,” Adrastia said, impatiently.

This time, Justinius watched as the Inquisitor flexed her own psychic talents. She had been, when she had arrived in the Third Aurelian Crusade, a staunch Puritan. That much, Justinius knew. This woman, however, had seen more than half a century pass since that day. By the reckoning of some calendars, at least. More than half a century of the Empire fracturing further and further, systems burning and dying, the 13th Black Crusade grinding ever on. Now, she arrived with a heretek, and as Justinius watched, crushed and strangled the mind within that wracked frame with her psychic abilities. A prisoner. A tool. It was not a bound daemon, or anything so foul, but that did not mean that it did not bear watching.

“A-a-a-access g-g-granted. Welcome, Fabricator-General,” the Magos twitched and bent nearly double before twisting upright again, its voice abruptly pleasant and unbroken before it went back to mumbling beneath its breath.

“There,” Adrastia hissed, stabbing a finger at the map being projected out of the Magos’ eye. “That is where we shall make our entrance into the genatorium grid.”

“After that, I think we’ll have to fight our way forward,” Kaius murmured. “Look at the checkpoints and guard posts nearby.”

“We must risk it,” Adrastia said firmly.

“Agreed,” Kaius nodded.

====================================================================

Going Down: 22 vs. 43
Defensive Distraction: 62 vs. 12

“Pull back! Pull back! PULL BA-AAAAGGHH!” The sergeant screamed as he was lifted upright in the servitor’s crab claws, the power fields crackling, and then cut off entirely as he was torn in half.

All around them, the lines were stretching, bending. Hard points of defiance still existed, but the Dark Mechanicus were penetrating deep. Too deep. Any further, and they would snap outright. Then there would be nothing that could be done, only a frantic retreat back to the ships and a hope that they could lift off. It was a short distance, that, purposefully so, but they could not afford the sure slaughter that could occur if forced into a full retreat. The Blood Ravens fought on, the terminators stomping and firing with their storm bolters and assault cannons, the dreadnoughts with their own weaponry, once again using their multi-meltas at deadly close range.

“STAND YOUR GROUND!” Came a boomed broadcast on loudspeaker.

Tarkus glanced to the side and saw the cupola of a Baneblade open despite the enemies that had clambered atop it. Emerging, firing with bolt pistol in one hand and slashing with lightning claw in the other, came the daughter of Lord Subsector Vance Stubbs.

“GET! OFF! OF! MY! TANK!” Colonel Stubbs shrieked as she kept killing the boarders atop her Baneblade. “Miserable SCUM! Pavins! DRIVE US FORWARD!” She yelled down into the cupola before straightening and continuing to shoot bodies off of the Baneblade.

Simultaneous to that moment was the wedge of superheavy tanks that she had brought to the battlefield doing something completely incongruous to the rest of their brethren. Rather than turn back, falter, or anything of the sort, the Baneblades born of the industry of Kaurava advanced. They drove forward, grinding the enemy beneath their treads while continuing to fire. They twisted and spun, maneuvering hundreds of tons of metal at high speed, simultaneously opening up whole swathes of ground for the Guardsmen to regroup in. All the while, Colonel Stubbs remained standing atop her tank, firing down into the crowds of the enemy with her bolt pistol.

“Soldiers of the Imperium! You shall not falter! We fight in the Emperor’s name!” Colonel Derosa, husband to Stubbs, yelled as he strode forward as well.

His power sword clove through a combat servitor, his plasma pistol taking the head off of another skitarii. Around him, buoyed by the heroism of their leadership, the rest of the Guard turned about once more. Fear drained away, was replaced by desperate anger, by shame. What had stretched near to breaking once more solidified, strengthening into walls of guns and fury. Tarkus noted as he continued to fire that many of the Guardsmen took heart in the presence of the Blood Ravens as well, especially around himself and Sergeant Stromahn. Captain Thule had not even shifted his feet, merely rotated back and forth while firing his multi-meltas, even as some of the enemy had begun targeting him specifically. His chassis glowed where lascannons had struck, but the dreadnought refused to yield.

Just as the rest of the Blood Ravens refused to yield.

=================================================================

In The Grid: 32 vs. 40
Defensive Distraction: 90 vs. 50

“Go Inquisitor! We’ll hold them off!”

Adrastia did not stop, did not pause to offer anything other than a nod as she pressed the activation rune to shut the door. The stormtroopers had not expecting anything more. That was their lot in life, and that was the nature of the missions that they undertook. The blast doors continued to shut, extra layers of metal and sheathing emerging from their sockets and fusing shut. Within a handful of seconds, it was too thick to hear the sounds of the doomed last stand of the stormtroopers on the other side. A handful of explosions managed to make themselves heard, but soon not even that much was possible. Besides which, there were plenty of other foes on this side of the door to deal with instead. Rapid lasfire was flung down the corridors leading to their position, but still the skitarii came on. She paused, in fact many did, as their armors suddenly screeched and locked up. Guns failed as a wave of some sort of energy field washed over them.

“HERETEK! Take him down, now!” Kaius Jacobus bellowed, seconds before a bolt of psychic lighting did just that – allowing their weapons to function normally once again.

“That’s half of who I brought,” she said tersely as they continued running through the corridors, her captured heretek bobbling along as its internal gyroscope kept it upright. “Gone.”

It wasn’t as if she’d been able to bring the entire regiment with her, but that only meant that she’d purposefully picked some of the elite formations that had existed within the elite force. Half whom had now died, or were soon to die. Their deaths irked her, but there was nothing for it but to keep moving forward. She glanced about at what forces remained. The psykers of Gabriel’s Chapter were proving their worth several times over, projecting force far in excess of their numbers, but the more ‘mundane’ – if that word could ever be applied to space marines – battle brothers were not untouched by the fierce fighting it had taken to get to this point. Unlike some of her kind, she was not unaware that space marines could be far more mortal than the tales suggested.

The nature of her Ordos ensured that, even if experience had not.

“I regret their deaths, Inquisitor,” the Chief Librarian said as they moved. “I had not anticipated that…monstrosity.”

Monstrosity barely covered it. It had been a horrid amalgam of broadcast Null-souled creatures and mechanical systems used to enhance and boost its nature. Something to deaden, to block, perhaps even to reduce overall metaphysical contamination of vital areas of the forge-hive’s depths. It had, unfortunately, also worked in stripping away the psychic shielding that Justinius Probalis had produced to block them from sensors and eyes alike.

“They knew the risks, Blood Raven,” she shook her head, pausing to fire her inferno pistol at a skitarii with three power mauls in its many hands, killing it instantly. “But lacking their numbers will make our job harder.”

An explosion from up ahead made them both look up, finding Kaius Jacobus standing atop the burning ruins of what almost looked like a Kastelan robot, only twisted by the touch of Chaos. The hordes of the Dark Mechanicus were coming for them, from all directions, but they couldn’t turn back. Explosives flew to block off tunnels, concentrated fire opening holes for them to move through the bodies flowing towards them. Reaching out, Justinius swept his hand sideways and unleashed a wave of white hot flame which melted metal and flesh alike, vaporizing them and ensuring that they could move forwards at a rapid pace. Some of the Blood Ravens took wounds, their gifts ensuring that the blood clotted swiftly, and some of the stormtroopers fell to the ground dead, and yet for all that they kept moving forward.

They had to.

To stop was certain death.

=============================================================

To The Heart: 41 vs. 19
Defensive Distraction: 77 vs. 75

Step. Fire. Step.

They were almost surrounded. Almost. In truth, the absolute heaviest forces, save for the Baneblades, were set along the flanks. The one thing that could not be allowed was damage to the troop transports. And so the Guard had spread out to defend them. The oncoming forces of the Dark Mechanicus were reactionary, hastily assembled and sent out, and even now in the distant horizon Tarkus could see where their ranks finally came to an end. But more would be on the way now that this initial thrust was finally depleting themselves. Initial auspex readings of the armies being assembled had spied things that were at least the size of knights coming out of vehicle bays, clawing their way up out of the smog and filth of the forge-hives, and whole swathes of armored vehicles. The Baneblades were mighty, holy machines of war, but they could be destroyed. Overwhelmed. Especially when the enemy had more tanks on their side than they did, the industrial capacity of a nascent Forge World far greater than what they had on hand.

By now, one way or another, they had to pull back to the ships. Even if the Inquisitor’s plan succeeded, it would all be for naught if they could not retreat onto the ships and lift off in good order. And so the slow, planned tactical shift had begun. Not a retreat, certainly not, but Tarkus had been forced to hand off his plasma cannons to others, to be carried by servitor back to the thunderhawk. Now he fired with his bolter instead, the venerable weapon proving itself time and again. The terminators, at his order, remained at the absolute forefront, enduring what the lesser equipped Guardsmen quite simply could not. The dreadnoughts had assembled into a trio, killing as they went, focus firing down any overly armored foe that tried to overrun the line. The Baneblades were reaping the greatest toll of all, however, swiftly driving their way back and forth as a mobile tidal wave of metal and death. It was, quite possibly, the most aggressive utilization of tanks that Tarkus had ever witnessed outside of formations commanded by the Captain of the 4th Company.

==================================================================

Heartburn: 34 vs. 71
Defensive Distraction: 95 vs. 78

The absolute depths of the grid were as heavily defended as anywhere else. But even then, they had not yet accounted for the presence of the guardian. It made sense, in the end, that it would be there. But they had still somehow not anticipated it. The Warp was so thoroughly clouded and clogged here, squeezed and stretched, manipulated and transformed, the artifice of the Dark Mechanicus abusing it as much as the greatest of sorcerers might, that Justinius had not sensed the thing’s presence. It reminded him of some of the vehicles of the Dark Eldar, known to some as the Drukhari, mixed with an Imperial Knight. Spindly tendrils of not-quite-bone sprouting from atop a tri-legged amalgam of metal, poisonous fluids, and cackling daemonic mouths with infinite depth that had been stamped across its frame. It did not speak, it only screamed. Its hide was thick, and though it bled from many wounds caused by krak grenades and concentrated blasts of psychic power, it would not fall. The bodies of the elite stormtroopers lay strewn about the ground, many in pieces. Some had been vaporized entirely. The hulking beast stomped this way and that, firing with such a multitude of weapons that even the vaunted armor of the space marines was not inviolable, nor were their superhuman constitutions.

“Colonel Merrick! Get back into cover!” Adrastia cried aloud as she watched the crippled man force himself to his feet. Or rather, foot, using his own lasgun as a crutch as he crawled out from a pile of his dead brethren.

“Not…today, Inquisitor,” he grunted.

“Librarian!” Adrastia howled.

But Justinius Probalis could not do anything, for he was casting forth a shield to withstand the abominable guardian’s weaponry and protect the heavily wounded marines and handful of stormtroopers behind him. He wound lightning and flame and sheer kinetic force to keep the creature from advancing further, but for all of that, he could not move. Damion Tyrin, the Epistolary of the 5th Company, was near death, having been grasped and chewed upon by the creature’s main maw. Multiple tons of force delivered by sharpened metal ‘teeth’ had nearly rent him apart before he’d escaped with a detonation of psychic force, his body a broken ruin that had immediately fallen into suspended animation. Adrastia was concussed, she knew that much, and thus she could not muster up enough mental force either. Kaius Jacobus had been thrown into a nearby pylon, and though he had survived what should have been a fatal amount of electricity, he had fallen into suspended animation while retaining the appearance of charcoal.

They were losing.

They were dying.

And so Colonel Merrick hobbled forwards to the very lip which descended into the depths below the pulsating main reactor heart complex, the very center of the genatorium grid for the entire forge-hive. He had less than a minute to live, given how violently his leg had been torn off, and yet he retained enough dexterity in his fingers to input the command code into the device he slid off of his back. In an instant, the guardian had turned about with titanic steps that were impossible fast. It screeched even louder, enough to cause blood to squirt from many an eardrum as they erupted. It certainly deafened Merrick. Yet the man only smiled back with bloody teeth as the creation of the true servants of the Omnissiah unfurled itself. But that wouldn’t be enough, and Merrick knew it, just as Adrastia did.

It needed closer contact, it only had a certain reach.

“MERRICK!” Adrastia’s voice carried earnest anguish, so sharp that it nearly shocked the still conscious space marines.

Merrick could only shrug at her.

“Hell, I’ve already died once in His name. Most men never get to do it a second time. ‘M sorry, Addy.” Merrick whispered before he threw himself backwards over the edge with the device, just before a stabbing tendril the width of a terminator slammed down where he’d lain.

The last words that Colonel Merrick of the 85th Vendoland, Hero of Typhon, would ever yell echoed upwards through the cavernous depths beneath the primary forge-hive of Opus Maxima just before the device triggered.

“FOR VENDOLAND AND THE EMPEROR!”

And a coruscating blast of dampening energies exploded outwards. Machinery halted, pumps ceased, and the glow of the reactor disappeared utterly. Injectors halted, power packs became nothing more than dead weight, and cybernetics became little more than cold metal. The guardian of the genatorium grid’s heart screamed even louder as massive swathes of its body became inert, sloughing off of its body in the hundreds of tons at a time. Inquisitor Adrastia’s scream of pain turned into one of fury, even as she faced the guardian. Justinius’ head whipped around as he saw the daemons swirling inwards, even as she summoned forth a level of strength that she had not been capable of only moments before. Instantly, he had to turn his efforts to preventing her possession, even as she continued to build up as the guardian stumbled back and forth before unleashing a simple wave of force of incredible magnitude, forcing it tipping backwards into the pit.

The effort blew her eyes out of her sockets and sent blood spewing out of her ears, nose, and mouth while also knocking her unconscious.

“Damn it,” Justinius growled.

With the guardian down, he could spare the effort to drag her body – and those of the minimal number of living members of their party closer to him.

“Where…ah,” he said as he plucked the protected and hardened case off of the small of her back.

He did not need to understand how it had managed to be made immune from what had just happened, only that it had remained functional. In but a moment, he opened it up and activated it, feeling mentally just how many things were slowly picking themselves up off the ground and shambling in their direction. What mattered was that the beacon functioned, and just as they’d planned, he gathered everyone together. He did not need his armor to have its power pack functioning to do it, it was a simple matter of mental strength to pull all together. It was just unfortunate that there was just one of their number who he could recover nothing at all of.

The beacon blinked once. Twice.

On the third blink, a flash enveloped them all as they were pulled out of the depths. Just before they faded from the materium entirely, Justinius spied the absolutely massive warhead that crashed to the ground. And then he was gone, busy trying to keep the ruinous Warp environment from stealing away amongst the living or the dead. The Inquisitor in particular was a gaping wound, one he had to work hard on closing as quickly as he could. Psychic breakthroughs like that were almost always fatal, if only because of the otherworldly attention they attracted to those who were universally knocked comatose by the backlash of going beyond one’s limits. In the next instant, he clattered onto his hands and knees as they landed in the teleportarium of the Inquisitor’s vessel.

Frantically, he cast his mind out, only to sigh in relief as he read the battlefield far below. The shift, the change. He saw the flickers of fate and life as they lifted upwards, upwards and away. He saw the crackling burning of the planet’s heart, suddenly set aflame by its own power. The stolen and channeled heat and power turned in on itself, an explosion so big that he could almost have felt it from orbit. More than that, he felt the echoes as the forge-hive began to explode from below, as the deep, deep holes that the Dark Mechanicus had dug into the world became trammels with which to break it. He had felt the death of Typhon. He had felt the echoes of what had been done to Cyrene. He knew the tainted shattered sphere that was the planet Aurelia. All of these and none of them flooded his mind at once.

For the death of a world was ever unique.

==========================================================

“He stirs,” a distant voice said through their helm, voice echoing strangely.

“Bionic repairs complete. Warning, certain repairs unable to be completed due to specialists required. Functionality of subject: Angelos, Gabriel is below optimal state.”

A sigh.

“Understood, servitor. Return to your charging station and await further orders.”

Slowly, Gabriel Angelos opened his eyes.

His body was strung up within a bay more appropriate for power armor maintenance. He felt the click and whir of his damaged bionics, felt the cold phantom sensations that they were transmitting to his mind settle. It was a far cry from the more responsive standards that he had grown used to. In front of him was an apothecary – it could only be one, however. His mind was not so sluggish as to forget the sight of the dead Honor Guard strewn about the ground. A cold anger simmered in his gut at the thought of it, and without prompting he slowly shifted about until his legs were underneath him once more. He had, at some point, been extracted from his armor, the better to work on his body no doubt.

“Apothecary Medici,” he rasped.

“Chapter Master. It is good to see you awake,” the apothecary said, but his voice was exhausted and cold. “I have restored your organic components as best I can, but without a senior tech-marine on hand we cannot effect full repairs on your bionics.”

“I understand,” Gabriel nodded as he slowly shifted his weight back and forth, testing the repairs. “What has occurred in the meantime?”

“…much,” Medici said slowly.

Gabriel followed him out of the secure chamber he had been placed in, only to stop and stare at the bodies strewn about the apothecarium. Epistolary Lucan was standing over many of them, slowly and painstakingly regenerating lost organic matter. A bevy of apothecarial servitors busily worked cutting, sewing, sealing, and more. Some were conscious. Many others were in the throes of suspended animation, and even as he watched, more were being brought in, puncture wounds the size of his fist slammed through their armor in portions. Heavy munitions fire had struck most of them low, but some had clearly suffered their wounds from melee weaponry.

“I…see.”

Medici had not even paused, immediately going over to the new arrivals and ordering the servitors to place them on already crowded beds and slabs.

“I suggest going to the strategium, Chapter Master,” the apothecary said without looking up from one of the fallen Blood Ravens. “I’ll message them that you’re on your way.”

“What of Apollo, Medici?”

The white armor of the apothecary had been well coated with the red of his battle brothers, bits of space marine flesh and drying blood giving the healer a particularly ghoulish appearance. When he turned his head, Gabriel could not help but be struck by the bloody palm print that had been pressed against the apothecary’s helm by some pained battle brother or another. Only his holy tools remained pristine, but given the multiple jars of bloodied antiseptic and cleansing unguents around, it was an feat constantly in progress to manage.

“He remains in suspended animation. I do not possess the expertise to revive him, Chapter Master,” Medici said quietly. “The bionics required, or psionic power to mend his battered flesh and bones, are not available.”

Gabriel’s eyes flicked towards Epistolary Lucan, who was currently helping a marine who had suffered a plasma blast which had scorched them down to the bone in the pelvis.

“I am good, Chapter Master, but even I do not possess the breadth of power and knowledge required for Brother Diomedes. Only the Chief Librarian might have a chance. Once the wounds are truly set, flash-repairs become untenable,” the Epistolary spoke up without stopping in his work. “It taxes not just my mind, but the body of the subject as well.”

Bone was unblackened, small amounts of tissue regrown around it to sheathe it from the open air once more. More importantly, the marine finally relaxed in their rictus tension, collapsing backwards onto the bed. There were many more wounds, but these had had time to set, to clot over, and were not in danger of swiftly becoming fatal like the one that Lucan had just healed.

“If all psykers could heal wounds such as Apollo suffered, there would be no need for bionics, or for dreadnoughts,” Lucan went on before standing up and then stumbling, the psychic light around him winking out as he caught himself on a nearby wall with one hand.

The psyker coughed and wiped some of the blood dribbling from his lips, but before he could say anything more Medici was by his side, helping him upright.

“That’s enough for now, Epistolary. You are draining yourself too swiftly. You will be of no help if you extinguish your very soul,” the apothecary’s voice was starkly gentle compared to the brusqueness of before.

“A fair price,” Lucan grunted before he shrugged off the apothecary. “For the Chapter.”

There was nothing that Gabriel could do there but get in the way, and so he turned and left the healers to their grim work. The atmosphere of the ship contrasted strangely with that of the apothecarium. The serfs that Gabriel passed chattered excitedly amongst themselves, at least before they heard and saw him coming. There were gasps, cheers, bows, and some even prostrated themselves as he passed. When he finally reached the strategium, the bridge of the ship had an air of grim satisfaction to it. Standing with shoulders set and back straight before the actuality sphere which displayed the system was Captain Tarkus. Nearby, eyes closed but leaking witchlight, the Chief Librarian mumbled to himself as he slowly waved his hands back and forth. Each movement carried ghostly afterimages.

“Chapter Master,” Tarkus said before falling to a knee with bowed head. “You have returned.”

“So it seems,” Gabriel nodded back. “Rise, brother. I have only just awakened. What has happened in my absence?”

Tarkus grimaced as he stood, his head still slightly bowed.

“I have failed the Chapter,” the Captain of the 5th Company spoke plainly.

“This is untrue,” Justinius spoke up, blinking slowly as he ceased his otherworldly work. “We found victory, Gabriel, but it came at a cost.”

“I saw within the apothecarium,” Gabriel was now the one bowing his head, the sight of so many wounded, some unmoving entirely, a painful one for any true space marine. “And yet…,” he reached up and pointed a finger at a rather significant absence on the actuality sphere, replaced instead with a series of red warning notifications, “I am inclined to believe you Justinius. Tell me,” he turned, pinning both where they stood with his eyes, “What. Happened?”

They did. A painful, grueling tale, it was, but Justinius was carefully dispassionate throughout it all. The station. Mortirex. The landing, the battles that took place, the startling reveal of the presence of Colonel Stubbs and her Kauravan Baneblade. The dangerous mission that was undertaken afterwards.

“Considering that Opus Maxima is no longer present…,” Gabriel interrupted, glancing once more at the actuality sphere. “I presume the mission was a success.”

“In a sense,” Justinius nodded. “The planet did not explode outward, continental plates could have struck our ships even at the distances we were at if that were the case, but total apocalyptic destruction was achieved. In the coming years, its shattered remains shall likely scatter further, but we will be gone by then.”

An entire nascent Forge World, destroyed. Wiped from the board. All in the time since the Chaos Lord had struck him down.

“Tarkus,” Gabriel placed a hand on the Captain’s pauldron, making him look up at him. “You helped win a great victory for the Imperium. It cost us dearly,” he said loudly, interrupting the words that had just begun to form on Tarkus’ lips, “But we are space marines. Our cause for being is to die in His name.. I would not have made you a Captain if you were not worthy of it. In my years as Captain of the 3rd Company, I watched more battle brothers die in a single battle than you have just witnessed, for less worthy victories.”

“It was my choice to drive into Mortirex’s trap,” Tarkus shook his head.

“And you will not always have that privilege,” Gabriel said firmly, making Tarkus draw back slightly.

“Chapter Master?”

“I meant what I said, Tarkus,” Gabriel sighed. “You, and our battle brothers, knew what they were doing and who they were fighting. You will not have that same privilege in every battle, every war. There will be ambushes, there will be betrayals, there will be unexpected arrivals and unforeseen consequences, and Blood Ravens will die to them, for that is the nature of the galaxy and it is not our nature to be invincible.”

Tarkus’ fists tightened. There was a rather obvious patch job for his bionic arm to reconnect it to his body after being severed, the armor not yet even repainted.

“…when I was a sergeant, my decisions could never have affected so many of our battle brothers at once.”

Or gotten so many of them killed, it could be said as well. Though the company had taken casualties before, fatalities before, whilst under Tarkus, this moment outweighed all of those in its single-instance nature.

“And when I was Captain of the 3rd,” Gabriel replied, eyebrow raised, “I could not have commanded the entire Chapter as a whole. And yet,” he swept out with both hands, encompassing the bridge, the ship.

The Chapter.

“Here we stand. By dark circumstance, yes, but we must not falter in the duties that have fallen onto our shoulders regardless of the how, or why, or even the when.”

Gabriel watched as the fire burned back into life in the eyes of Tarkus.

“…yes, Chapter Master. I understand.”

“Incoming communication from the Inquisitor’s ship!” A serf called. “Shall I put it through?”

The naked surprise on both Tarkus and Justinius’ face was not shocking to Gabriel. To be fair, by the recounting, Adrastia was still unconscious when they had transferred back to the Litany of Fury. After such a psychic exertion, far in excess of what her Assignment should have allowed, Justinius had described her soul and mind as ‘tattered’, stretched literally to tearing slightly. Or more than slightly, as the worry went. Not to mention the destruction of her eyes and internal hemorrhaging throughout the body. Unlike them, however, Gabriel had known Adrastia for far longer, and he knew the inner well of strength that the woman possessed.

“…yes,” Gabriel called out.

Just as he’d thought, the hololith projected the image of Adrastia from the waist up, her arms crossed. She no longer wore her hat, and instead wore bandages wrapped around the upper half of her head from which only a few strands of hair peeked out. Which was not, unfortunately, enough to keep from visible tracks of blood from having dripped down her cheeks from her emptied eye sockets. They were not freely bleeding, however, and had mostly dried by that point. Her suit of customized power armor had been stripped from her body, and several electrodes and other monitoring devices had been placed on her instead.

“Gabriel. I heard you were awake again,” she started the moment her image finished stabilizing. “Have you been brought up to speed?”

Gabriel huffed in bemusement.

“I have, for the most part. Should you not be resting?”

“There is no rest for the righteous,” she snapped back, her tone outright acidic.

“Inquisitor…,” Tarkus spoke up. “Colonel Merrick…,”

Adrastia’s nose flared, her grip tightening on herself for a moment before she forced herself to relax.

“…what, Captain Tarkus?” She barely kept herself from snarling.

“He was a good man. A hero. He stood with us at Typhon, and that will always be remembered by the Blood Ravens.”

“You-,” Adrastia cut herself off and sighed. “Yes. He was. Now he’s dead. And the job is not yet finished.”

The words were meant to be dispassionate, but in her current state she did not possess the same levels of sheer self-control over the body and voice that she could normally maintain.

“Very well,” Gabriel offered, “Then let us speak on what we shall do next.”

“I’ll bring in Graves and the Colonels Derosa again.” Adrastia nodded before waving at something off screen.

Seconds later, three more faces appeared on the hololith, Adrastia’s image shrinking and shifting to the side to make way. Graves seemed moderately recovered from the stress of the initial battles, whereas the two children of Governor Derosa were still in the process of decompressing from the brutal land battle around the transport ships. Tracks of sweat through the grim and blood on their faces had yet to be fully cleaned away. Gabriel Derosa had taken a black eye of immense severity, while his sister Arama had nearly lost half of her face to bloody swaddled bandages. For all that, however, their eyes remained bright and alert – those that could be seen at any rate.

“Will your wife not be joining us, Colonel Derosa?” Gabriel asked calmly.

“She’s overseeing repairs on her tanks at the moment, Chapter Master, my apologies,” the younger Gabriel shook his head.

“Very well then. I have been made aware of the events in my absence. What must be discussed now is our next move,” Gabriel moved on, glancing back at the actuality sphere. “What else have we learned about the enemy in the meantime?”

In the hours since the destruction of Opus Maxima, the ships had moved off to a safe distance, still gathered tightly together, whilst sending out probes and maintaining continual auspex scans throughout the system. Justinius added his talents to that as well, as it turned out, having immediately begun utilizing Battle Sight to look throughout the system as best he could through its churning local Warp environment. The probes utilized by the Inquisition were, unsurprisingly, particularly advanced and potent in their capabilities, having gone unused until that point due to the chaos and uncertainty of the fighting in the void.

“It’s not a surprise that Vandis has a shipyard for New Meridian,” Adrastia shook her head. “His pride and indolence would have demanded one for himself.”

“It does not possess the capabilities of that of Opus Maxima, but it is more than enough to maintain the ships he holds over his world in defense,” Graves sighed in frustration.

“He was aware that his position was tenuous,” Justinius mused. “Mortirex. The Fabricator-General. We’ve removed two of his potential rivals off the board for him, and all that he needed to do was contribute none of his forces. Now he possesses the single strongest concentration of forces in the system, and the best manufacturing capabilities.”

It had not been a pleasant thing to learn that Lord Mortirex was still at large. The churning Warp of the contained system meant that he could not have left, not just yet, but his loss of favor and his wounding was at least something of a balm to that bad news.

“We cannot simply sit and wait around. The Saharduin can maintain their ships with their own shipyard. The remaining Chaos vessels in the system can make use of New Meridian, though it will be a good deal slower,” Graves held his chin in his palm.

“I have never fought Kroot before, let alone those corrupted by darkness,” Gabriel Derosa pursed his lips. “I do not know the abilities of their Warspheres either.”

“Fleet killers, if confronted foolishly. Incredibly slow, however,” Graves said. “A swift strike could obliterate that planet from orbit, potentially.”

“Unfortunately,” Gabriel said quickly, “Our main bombardment cannon was damaged in the fighting. It is inoperable. Our strike cruisers, on the other hand, could possibly manage that.”

“Do you have the armaments for…for Exterminatus?” Amara Derosa gulped at the thought of it.

“We do, yes...but the armaments are meant for the Litany's damaged cannon, and thus cannot fire.”

It was difficult to requisition such things when the Inquisition was watching you most carefully, after all. Gabriel could have made an issue of it, of demanding it, but contrary to the belief of some Exterminatus was a matter of last resort, and not one that they had required restocking of in some time. It might become an issue after the campaign was done, however, given just how corrupted these worlds were. Hopefully Adrastia would be willing to make the case for the Blood Ravens that they be able to restock those precious and utterly horrific weapons should it come to that.

“Barring the Warsphere possessing some horrific modifications, I imagine that the strike cruisers could maneuver around it,” Graves posited thoughtfully, “But they’d be exposed to enemy ship movement from elsewhere in the system. It’s not like the enemy are going to just…sit around, waiting for us to come to them.”

"Orbital bombardment could be performed, but it would be far slower than Exterminatus," Gabriel added. "Possible, given the speed of a Warsphere...but dangerous regardless."

“Do we know any more about the capabilities of the Saharduin?” Adrastia spoke up.

“Only that they possess their same ten Torrent-class cruisers. Equivalents, roughly, to Lunar-class cruisers,” Graves grunted. “We’re reasonably sure that that is the extent of their naval capacity, and their shipyard is a minor thing, only capable of servicing a pair at a time. They’re clearly auxiliaries, not main contributors.”

And yet, ten such ships at their backs if they were attempting to assault any of the other worlds in the system could be devastating in the extreme.

“No orbital stations? Anti-orbital defenses?” Gabriel questioned.

“None on the former, uncertain on the latter,” Adrastia said, her head twitching ever so slightly in the manner that one would if they were rolling her eyes, only to wince instead from the pain. “The Saharduin had their industrial base eradicated long ago, and I did not go gathering any records beforehand – I did not think that House Vandis would stoop to working with xenos, even then.”

Gabriel frowned as he continued to look at the actuality sphere, watching the other planets float silently in the projected image, as well as the marked locations of the ships above them.

“And New Meridians defenses, do we have any more information on it?”

This time, it was Graves who grimaced.

“It’s not good. Bastard has a defensive fleet, his shipyard has its own defenses, and some orbital stations besides. If we had any of those fire ships left…,” he sighed. “But we don’t. It’ll be a hell of a thing getting past that screen in the first place, let alone trying to land.”

“…but what if we did?” Gabriel Derosa spoke up, unshrinking beneath the scrutiny that turned onto him.

“Explain, Colonel,” Gabriel said calmly to the man named after him.

“There are other ships in the system not directly over New Meridian. The Mechanicus ships are wrecks, aren’t they? But the superstructures are somewhat intact.”

There was only silence in return.

“And…there are Saharduin vessels as well. And the Kroot Warsphere. The latter might be corrupted by Chaos, and a xenos vessel besides…,” he trailed off as the stares intensified.

“Bold, Colonel,” Gabriel eventually said. “Very, very bold.”

“We don’t have the explosive material or fuel to flood those ships to bursting,” Adrastia was quick to point out.”

“They don’t have to be. They only have to accelerate well enough on a one-way trip,” Graves said slowly, having sat up in his command throne, eyes narrowing in thought.

“There’s no chance we’d be able to get all of them,” the Inquisitor insisted. “We would have to kill off the crews in totality, or somehow maintain control over their systems throughout the journey.”

“What matters is getting enough,” Graves shot back. “Otherwise, we’ll be looking to throw ourselves upon the guns of Vandis’ defenses and hope that he’ll be so surprised that we’re waggling our asses in front of his nose not to shoot us immediately. Personally, if nothing else if we could take the Warsphere…,”

Gabriel Angelos had fought the Tau before. He had, in fact, torn them out of the Vorga System just as the desperate calls for aid had come in from Aurelia, warning of the tyranids. Several cadres had been slaughtered. The void combat had been more difficult than the ground fighting if anything. The range and power behind Tau ships were dangerous in the extreme, their tactics diametrically opposite to the close range and boarding methods of the space marines. But there he had been aided by the Imperial Navy, and here, again, the Navy was present. It was possible. Dangerous. But possible. Then again, dangerous but possible was something that could be said about almost any potential way forward. The issue at hand was picking the one that would actually work.

“Are your pilots refreshed, Graves? Enough to target the point defenses of the xeno cruisers?”

“Likely, yes. The thunderhawks and some concentrated fire could help as well.”

“Historically,” Justinius said, a data pad linked with the Librarium in his hands, “Records show that the Saharduin vessels are half-full of water, with multiple decks and corridors completely submerged. They also favor close range fighting and boarding. The Warsphere, on the other hand, will be completely filled with, potentially, hundreds of thousands of Kroot. They are colony ships, after all.”

“And…what of Runao?”

“I touched their minds,” Justinius answered, his lips pursed as a look of disgust passed by his face. “Their minds are fogged by chains of drugs and bindings of the soul. Their only purpose is to defend that world, to try and leave its orbit, to leave their stations, would cripple them with pain. They cannot leave, they are trapped there without actually needing to physically restrain them. It is foul sorcery, Gabriel.”

“I assume they would act to defend Runao with insane ferocity, though.”

“Correct, Gabriel. The ships would possibly be easier to command if taken,” the Chief Librarian did not seem to relish the idea of exposing themselves to the innards of such ships, and the corruption therein.

“Hmm.”

“And them?” Gabriel gestured towards where the Saharduin still waited. “What of the xenos?”

Of all the Librarians in the Chapter, only Justinius could strengthen the will and power to use Battle Sight over an entire star system, even the next strongest Epistolaries restricted to hemispheres of single planets.

“They are base creatures,” Justinius sneered. “Eager, very eager for blood. They were intending to snap at our heels, to strike from behind and savage us, while we were occupied at Opus Maxima. Only fear stopped them, fear of Vandis. The Kroot are similar, but they are aware of the slowness of their ship.”

“I don’t understand how that sniveling wretch has such command over them,” Adrastia growled.

“Chains on their souls,” Justinius answered unhappily. “Bindings. Deals made, deals kept. Either Vandis has a powerful sorcerer on his side…or he is one.”

Neither possibilities were particularly welcome at the moment, and yet there they remained. Those with the power to bargain, to follow through on them, were capable of gaining such powers even if they were not natural psykers. The records of the Librarius held note of such things. It was not especially common, but on the occasions that it did occur were most troubling indeed.

“But if we attack one, or the other, they’ll likely attack from behind if at all possible.”

There, then, lay the risk. Either face the xenos head on, or risk trying for another target, and suffer the almost sure attacks from behind. Either carried terrible risk. There lay the option of trying to swiftly lay waste to Runao, or to try and skirt the Warsphere and strike down Croxnov, or even trying to go directly after New Meridian – but that would likely be sure suicide given the defenses there and the ships that could arrive from behind. Gabriel knew that he could try and suggest it, but he also knew that even Adrastia would not agree to such a thing, let alone Graves or the commanders of the Imperial Guard. There lay opportunities and danger in all of them.

“What of the Blood Ravens, then,” Graves turned slightly where he sat to look at where Gabriel’s face was being projected on his bridge. “What do you think, Chapter Master?”

“The defenders of Runao are bound to their positions, though I don’t doubt that Vandis would force their movement if he truly desired. The Kroot Warsphere is a lumbering beast that can be outmaneuvered. Vandis’ defenses might have been manageable before, but now…,” Gabriel grimaced. “We may well need to attempt to take the ships of the Saharduin, or even the Warsphere itself.”

“My stormtroopers are ready and able,” Adrastia noted, “As, I am sure, are your armsmen, Graves?”

“If required, the Guard can contribute as well to such things,” Gabriel Derosa said quickly, a sentiment echoed by his sister. “If the ship-to-ship transports can be spared, that is.”

It could work.

The operative word being ‘could’.

Gabriel mused to himself as he watched the others discuss amongst themselves. Was there another way? Possibly. But success was not guaranteed in any such things, let alone what they might well be attempting soon. Not just the Chapter, but every resource would have to be carefully utilized. Any waste would be disastrous to their cause. Thankfully, during the travel to the new target, more healing work could be performed upon the wounded. How many more might be combat capable when they got there would be up to Medici, Lucan, and possibly Justinius.

Chapter Master Angelos, What Is Your Decision?:
Voting Moratorium 12 Hours.
Note: Remember, this is just choosing the planet to approach. When you actually get there, you'll presumably make more in-depth planning.

[] Advance On Aeterna: Ten ships. Ten...opportunities, perhaps. To not face the Saharduin now means they can, and likely will, assault your ships from behind if they were to travel anywhere else.
[] Advance On Croxnov: Single Warsphere, no planetary defenses.
[] Advance On Runao: Defended by 10 Planet Monitors, 12 Orbital Defense Stations
[] Advance On New Meridian: Heavy defenses, orbital defense stations, defense fleet, shipyard, anti-orbitals on the ground likely.
[] Something Else: Write-In
[] Retreat Like A Coward, Shaming The Chapter And Ensuring The Enemy Can Prepare Better In The Meantime, Dishonoring the Blood Ravens Forevermore And Blighting All Future Campaigns

Ground Losses
2 5th Company Marines (Gene-Seed Recovered)
1 Regiment's Worth of Losses Spread Amongst 5 Guard Regiments
1 Hero of Typhon, Colonel Merrick of the 85th Vendoland

Spoiler: Imperial Fleet

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Void Shielding At 50%, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius (+All Unassigned Librarians)
25 (37) 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

14 5th Company Marines Require Bionic Replacements Or Dedicated Work By Chief Librarian And Epistolary Lucan Or Will Be Combat Crippled (Able to fire weapons, but not heavy weapons/able to fire heavy weapons, but not be standing or walk/ etc.)
Total Living 5th Company marines = 37. 25 are fully combat effective.

Epistolary Idmon is in an unshakable suspended animation coma.
Codicier Aeneas has fallen into a suspended animation coma, and will require intensive healing.

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor to Moderate Damage)
2 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor to Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class (Modified, Non-Standard Capabilities)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Eleven)

[] Advance On Aeterna: Ten ships. Ten...opportunities, perhaps. To not face the Saharduin now means they can, and likely will, assault your ships from behind if they were to travel anywhere else.

GM NOTE: 12 Hour Moratorium

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

The approach to Aeterna was a slow one, in comparison to the absolutely brutal pace leading up to this point through the system. One that was desperately required, however, despite the fact that it was obvious that long range auspex scans were granting them the discomforting sight of significant activity over New Meridian. There was nothing to be done about it, however. For all that it was a hive world with its own manufactorums, it was not a true Forge World. Not even close to the manufacturing capacities of even Opus Maxima, which had been only nascent. It did not mean that they were not preparing for the time when the Imperials inevitably turned for them. At the same time, however, it was mutually agreed upon by the existing commanders that anything which might trigger the aggressive tendencies of the Saharduin - such as presenting their rears to them while throwing themselves at the already prepared defenses of New Meridian.

No.

The xenos had to go.

Patching Metal: 72
Patching Flesh: 90

In the meantime, however, the tech-priests of the various Imperial Navy ships frantically went to work, while the Inquisitor herself assented to delivering some of the cadre which worked upon her own ship over to the Blood Ravens to assist in repairs of the Litany of Fury. Unfortunately, as initially suspected the main bombardment cannon of the battle barge was simply irreparable without more advanced shipyard facilities and several weapons batteries had been turned to slag, but there was much yet that could be patched up. Such as the battered void shield generators which had been so badly overloaded during the battle which occurred simply entering the system. Truly, the Black Legion had been supremely confident that they could take the ship, having focused exclusively on harming the ship's ability to defend itself and prioritized keeping its superstructure and engines as pristine as possible. Their arrogance would now aid in their continued undoing. The Litany did not have the teeth she was normally accustomed to, but her two skins would be as doughty as ever.

Within the ship, efforts were made extensively by the remaining Librarium. Rituals of mending the mind and body were enacted by the Chief Librarian after forcing Epistolary Lucan to rest, the gathered strength of the Codiciers and Lexicani was channeled forth. As had been noted by the now unconscious psyker, if all wounds could be swiftly, completely, and easily healed by their kind, bionics would never be necessary. And yet they were, of course, because in truth the psykers powerful enough to perform such things were rarities amongst their kind. Even then, trusting a psyker to fully patch the total intricacies of the biological form was also rare, the danger undeniable and constant. The slightest lapse could cause horrific damage, could cause death, could cause even worse, not just for the psyker but for the one they were altering the flesh of.

Many would not ever, ever risk it.

Many did not have the power of the Blood Raven non-typical psychic averages.

Many did not have the sheer breadth of knowledge that the Blood Ravens. How and when it was acquired, from what sources, for what initial purposes before study, was not particularly relevant at the moment - though it surely would for many within the Inquisition and Ecclesiarchy. But such things were not for them to know, neither when, nor where, nor even that they were the sources being used at all. Some knowledge was not worth using, even if it was worth knowing. Times and circumstances were desperate, but not yet that desperate. Not yet. What had been studied, tested, sanitized, improved. These were what were called upon now.

Justinius Probalis may not have faced the true shattering strength of the Hive Mind so directly as his mentor Jonah Orion, but he had spent his time since being placed into his position extensively studying the lore within the Librarium. He had to, if only to catalogue what might have been taken, or worse - altered - by the touch of those corrupted by Azariah Kyras. His strength had grown with his knowledge. Here, now, within a system constricted by unnatural gravimetric forces, with a churning cauldron of uniquely contained and stretched Warp, buoyed by the joined chorus of minds of the Librarium. Those that were conscious, anyway. Luckily, the Blood Ravens had scoured and taken what body parts they could, those that remained, if only to try and reattach later with the aid of an apothecary. And, to be sure, Apothecary Medici was present, but only to watch, and to check over those so risen.

And they did rise.

Bones twisted back into place within the shattered sheathes. Bruised organs rippled and undulated within membranes. Extraneous things, unnecessary additional fingers that were not necessarily required to grip and fire a bolter, to trigger and throw a grenade, were not focused upon. Instead, the whole of that localized storm of psychic energies which would have horrified more orthodox Chapters of the Adeptus Astartes focused instead on pure revivification. Awakening. Walking. Moving. Fighting. Reaching a point where the enhanced physiology granted to them over the years of work by the apothecaries since their Blood Trials could truly go to work. Spare pieces of power armor would be used to repair, to patch, to replace what needed to be done.

And they did rise.

Souls rent and tattered by exertion were filled, mended, soothed. Bodies reflecting that same damage, things inflicted upon the metaphysical level, undetectable by most technologies, were healed. It was under such circumstances that Epistolary Idmon, who had crafted maelstroms of metal and stone and lightning awoke once more, eyes burning with blinding psychic light, shocked into awareness so completely and thoroughly that he joined in the communion immediately. It was because of such joined mental strength, a deathly choir of psykers, beings reviled and kept distant by the majority of all the Imperium, that Codicier Aeneas awoke once more, saved from the nightmares both real and unreal which had plagued him since he had fallen through the Warp over Opus Maxima and barely escaped.

Thus did the remaining Blood Ravens of the 5th Company, battered, wounded, and far fewer in number since they had begun this fight, rise.

Only one did not, as the apothecarium emptied out leaving him as the sole unconscious remainder. For the wounds of Apollo Diomedes were too great, even then, to be healed in such a manner. His body had been so wracked, so ruined, that it was considered by Apothecary Medici a medical marvel that he had not simply died, or at least had been required to be placed within a dreadnought to survive. Perhaps, in time, given longer, willingly exhausting the Librarium in joined strength once more, it could be done. But such was not possible, certainly not with so much battle left on the horizon, and in the near future.

As Gabriel Angelos, at that point on the strategium in conference with his fellow commanders, well knew.

"The xeno ships are starting to move, they can see we're on the cusp of entering the local gravity well of Aeterna," Admiral Graves said unhappily. "Squinty bastards, based on the old records in the cogitators, but their auspex systems are extremely adept at finding biological signatures of enemy crews. Let's them know right where to go to empty ships out."

"Now is the time to finalize what forces we're going to be trying to deploy for this," Colonel Gabriel Derosa mused. "We are ready and willing to aid the boarding in any way we can."

"We may well need the Guard to be as fresh as possible once we hit New Meridian, Colonel," Graves pursed his lips. "We managed to transfer a goodly portion of the crews off our own destroyed ships before they were completely destroyed, and that includes the void armsmen. We can sustain more casualties than usual, based around that."

"What of you, Gabriel," Adrastia asked tersely, now having been forced to a medicae bed and be pumped with a significant quantity of high quality medicine to remain conscious. "How successful were your efforts at healing?"

"I can now safely say that, aside from Brother Diomedes, we stand fully ready to assault the enemy vessels," Gabriel said calmly. "Codicier Aeneas and Epistolary Idmon have been revived as well."

There was a noticeable lowering of tension in the shoulders of many of those present. While many of the Blood Ravens had fallen, their presence, their skill, was still incredibly valuable.

"Do we know which ship actually holds the leader of these xenos?" Graves now asked.

Piercing the Veil: 21

"Unfortunately, the Warp in this system is growing increasingly chaotic, and our Chief Librarian cannot seem to pierce it at the moment," Gabriel shook his head. "There will be few outward physical signs on the ships, as well. Saharduin follow the philosophy of all ships appearing the same to reduce the effectiveness of decapitation strikes," then he grimaced as he recalled something else he'd learned from the records. "Furthermore, records show that once they achieve a certain heightened frenzy state they continue attacking until they are dead or the enemy is."

"That about tracks with our own records in the cogitators," Graves sighed. "I can't believe Segmentum command thought it was better to simply corral their worlds rather than actually exterminate them."

"The Space Wolves were called away before they could complete their work during the Great Crusade...and then were never able to return. It took many centuries for the xenos to regain their strength, and the Imperium struck them down once again...before being forced to stop before total annihilation could be achieved. Four ork WAAAGH!s, two Eldar incursions, and a spat of over a dozen minor xeno aggression incidents were the cause," Justinian added in as he slowly entered the strategium, clearly still a little exhausted after his work in the apothecarium. "The resources could not be spared to ensure extermination. The Administratum decided that it would be more cost effective to station guards and focus on ending more direct and ongoing threats."

"Are you well, Justinian?" Gabriel asked, gaining a raised hand from Justinian in turn as he leaned against the actuality sphere projector.

"Well enough to fight," was the tired response.

"Let us correct, then, the mistakes of the past in some small measure here and now," Adrastia grunted.

"The question remains, then, how we try to do this."

"If our ships were better repaired, I'd be more willing to get in close, but I'd rather try for lighting strikes after taking down their shields, possibly some troop transports if we can disable some of their point defenses," Graves said unhappily.

"If I could make a suggestion?" Gabriel Derosa spoke, waiting until eyes had turned to him. "Chapter Master, you said that the Litany's void shields were once more at full capacity?"

"That is correct, Colonel."

"It might...distress, the tech-priests, but if certain parameters on speed and entry on the battle barge's boarding pods and assault rams were altered, would not that allow non-Astartes to utilize them?"

A dead silence was the most immediate response.

"It could certainly ensure that our own ships would be at less risk," Graves mumbled.

"We do not, admittedly, possess the full theoretical compliment of battle brothers with us to make use of them otherwise," Gabriel admitted. "There would be dangers, however, due to lack of training and acclimatization, even altering certain speeds in the launch procedure. It would be highly unorthodox."

"But it could be done," the Meridian native insisted. "Theoretically."

"Theoretically," Gabriel echoed.

"We need to decide, and quickly," Adrastia cut in, gritting her teeth as another wave of pain clearly washed through her. "We cannot simply hang back and let them prepare further for us, or do who knows what else. Graves can hang his ships back with the troop transports and utilize their lance arrays at long range, the Blood Ravens can use their own boarding methods, supplemented by the void armsmen that would have been used in the first place, and we'll get this done quickly."

Graves very carefully did not look towards the irate wounded Inquisitor's projected image on the hololith.

"And of you, Inquisitor?" Gabriel elected to take the plunge as the other commanders remained silent.

"The Sword of Reckoning will join in the fighting, we shall attempt to keep their shields down for boarding procedures," she responded drolly. "Worry not, Gabriel. I might not be conscious for it, but Captain Carlyle is extremely good at his job."

Ten ships of the xenos, already now shifting into something somewhat familiar as 'swarm formation secundus' by the reckoning of the cogitators accessing old files. They were running very, very short on time. A single squad of tactical marines could, perhaps, try to take a ship, each. As could a single squad of terminators, at least to take down the engines and shut them down impermanently. Then there were the numerous void armsmen of the Imperial Navy. There were sections of the ships that would be underwater, yes, but void armsmen were equipped for situations where there was no oxygen or artifical gravity by simple virtue of the fact of that being a major and regular risk for their combat theatres. The same went for those equipped in power armor. Gabriel himself would be able to join in, though his weakened and damaged bionics would hinder him significantly. The Librarius could aid as well...especially with Idmon and Aeneas once more back on their feet, Lucan having rested significantly and was no longer at risk of burning himself out. Gabriel considered all of this, as well as the presence of the dreadnoughts, and thought furiously as the actuality sphere projected the ever shortening distance to the enemy. To battle.

What Are Your Choices, Chapter Master Angelos?:
Moratorium = 12 Hours

[] Go Along With Colonel Derosa's Suggestion: Allow the damaged Imperial Navy ships to remain back, load up the ships of the Blood Ravens with Imperial Navy void armsmen, and utilize the superior durability and boarding capabilities of the astartes vessels.
OR
[] Refuse: To simply allow so many non-Blood Ravens upon your sacred ships would be extremely inappropriate. Admiral Graves can still contribute by sending forth his troop transports after the point defenses of the enemy ships have been either destroyed or shut down.

AND

[] Leapfrog Approach: Board and crush the crews of the xenos ships, one at a time. This will ensure that you manage to gain at least some ships under your control, should the battles go well, but some of the Saharduin ships will need to be destroyed as they continue pushing, most certainly. Especially if they attempt to head for the troop transports.
[] All Out Assault: It will spread you thin, but you could potentially try to board as many Saharduin ships as possible at once. It will be dangerous, but if successful, will surely win more of the ships captured for your purposes.
-[] If Chosen, How Should The Blood Ravens Deploy Per Each of the 10 Ships. EX: 10 Terminators To 1 Ship/1 Squad of Blood Ravens to 1 Ship/Epistolary Idmon and X Codiciers/Lexicani To 1 Ship/Etc.
[] Something Else: Write-In

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+12 Codiciers, 10 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
37 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Minor Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
4 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [Extremely Minor Casualties]

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Twelve)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[] All Out Assault: It will spread you thin, but you could potentially try to board as many Saharduin ships as possible at once. It will be dangerous, but if successful, will surely win more of the ships captured for your purposes.
-[] Ships 1-7: 1 squad of Blood Ravens per ship, assembled out of a combination of regular marines and the non-named members of the Librarius (even division of Librarius at each rank as far as possible; whichever squad gets the lesser number of Codiciers will be guaranteed to get one of the Epistolaries). Squads 1-7 will each receive one out of: Epistolary Tyrin, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas, and the 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Thule. The Terminator squad will also be split up. Squads 1-7 will each get 1 Terminator.
-[] Ships 8-10 will be initially targeted by void armsmen alone, with the sole goal of establishing a defended beachhead for additional deployments when available.
-[] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Captain Tarkus, Company Champion Kaius Jacobus, 3 Terminators, Apothecary Medici, and Chief Librarian Justinius will remain aboard ship in the teleportarium as elite reserves. Justinius will conserve his strength for battle and for safely guiding the reserves through the warp when deployed or retrieved. When enemy hardpoints are stalling progress or extraordinary or excessively dangerous levels of resistance are causing or threatening to cause excessive casualties, the elite reserves will be deployed to deal with it by teleportarium, targeting the Teleport Homer carried by the Terminator deployed with the squad already boarding. The elites will focus on breaking resistance and having Apothecary Medici conduct emergency field treatment on any Blood Raven casualties taken before the elites are deployed. The elite reserves and any casualties requiring immediate treatment in the Litany's facilities will then be retrieved by teleportarium for further deployment as needed (or for treatment in the case of casualties of course).
-[] If Reaverlord Carnax is found or shows himself, this will take immediate priority for the deployment of these reserves. This includes if he is found on a ship not currently being boarded by the Blood Ravens.
-[] As ships are captured, the 3 Saharduin ships not initially targeted by the Blood Ravens will be targeted for leapfrog assault by the squads freed up from captured ships if that is still viable.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

The Saharduin were a monstrous alien race who had languished under the yoke of the Imperium for thousands of years. First, it had been the Space Wolves, who had faced their Piscean Warriors onboard their ships, on the land, and in the waters of their preferred worlds. But before the watery domain of the aliens could be fully scoured, the demands of the Great Crusade had called the Space Wolves away. The fires of the Horus Heresy had ensured the Saharduin were transformed into little more than a splintered, bloody footnote in the annals of one of the first Legions and the Imperium. It had taken over a millennium for the Saharduin to claw their way back, and yet the Imperium had broken them again, and again, and again. Fate had intervened every time, either in the form of bureaucratic competition, alien incursions, traitors, heretics, and various other stella phenomena. In the end, the Saharduin Swells, as the xenos termed their domain, survived. They were, as such, well documented. The ‘crash rifles’ they bore were somewhat lesser peers to the esteemed bolter, while in melee they preferred their teeth, their claws, their knives, with leaders bearing power weaponry. They preferred to raid their enemies at the flanks, but were not afraid of full-frontal combat, boarding and emptying out ships and utilizing their captured prizes as scrap and salvage. Their religion was a primitive animistic thing, and psykers amongst their kind were vanishingly rare. Such were the notations in the records of the Librarium. They had not previously been known to be corrupted by the powers of Chaos, but it ever seemed in these dark days that the Ruinous Powers were waxing in strength and reach.

“Boarding pods loaded and ready, Chapter Master,” the serf’s voice crackled across the vox.

It had been a frantic, swift thing, the Imperial Navy troop transports practically redlining their engines to fill the ships of the Blood Ravens with void armsmen, hard bitten men and women used to a life of either boarding other ships or receiving boarders, and little else. They had been both awed and struck dumb by the haunting emptiness of the Litany of Fury and the other strike cruisers. Filled and made pristine by servitors and serfs, records, annals, trophies, symbols of triumph and loyalty filled the well-kept halls. A Battle Barge was meant not just for the carrying of up to three companies, their specialists, and their vehicles pools, but a veritable army of serfs and servitors as well. Here, now, the armsmen of the Imperial Navy far outweighed all of these things. A more prideful Chapter might have refused, the indignity of their weakness being shown to all and sundry too much to bear. But the Blood Ravens had been flayed open before the eyes of the entire Imperium, their weakness and the treachery of Kyras known to allies and enemies alike.

It did not mean that Gabriel did not bow his head in shame as the last of the void armsmen who could be transferred before contact was shuffled into the many, many boarding torpedoes which up until this moment had only ever been used by Blood Ravens. That they had been brought to this point by Chaos. By the tyranids. By the Eldar. By Boreale. His own weakness which had left him reduced in such a state, Apollo in suspended animation, only added to it all. A cloying, choking tide of shame washed over him, his gorge rising, but he forced it back down as his head rose. Klaxons began to ring out across the ship. The Blood Ravens would be the tip of the spear, the ships of the Imperial Navy remaining behind to use their lances at long range. For the first time too, Sword of Reckoning, the personal ship of Inquisitor Adrastia, would be able to fully commit itself to a battle in the void, rather than the stoppered progress of entry into the system and the mad dash over Opus Maxima.

“Inquisitor?” Admiral Graves’ voice was almost drawling as the shared battlefield command channel of the vox crackled open.

“What is it, Admiral?” Adrastia snapped back, astonishingly still conscious despite her own estimation of her wounds.

“I couldn’t help but notice the unfurling of your gun ports for the first time,” the Admiral said, clearly bemused. “Very sleek, very nice.”

“Do you have a point, Admiral Graves?” Adrastia sighed. “We are already closing with the xenos.”

“Nothing untoward. I was simply going to remark that the last time I had seen such a set of plasma macro-batteries, it was on an absolutely ancient Retribution-class Battleship,” Graves said blandly. “And that I am glad to see such things again turned towards the enemy.”

“Mmm,” Adrastia replied noncommittally.

“This is not the time,” Gabriel cut in.

“Fair enough,” Graves said.

Engines flared, shields emitters aligned, and generators thrummed.

“Onwards, then,” Gabriel said to himself as the lance weapons began to fire on both side at extreme range. “Into the maelstrom of battle!”

===================================================================

Violent Approach: 70 vs. 72

The concentration of enemy fire would have been crippling to the already damaged vessels of the Imperial Navy. But the Saharduin were not firing on those ships. Instead, they concentrated their fire upon the Blood Ravens. For it was they, in their strike cruisers and battle barge, which were cast shadows from millennia ago. They were not the Space Wolves, but they did not need to be. All such beings known as the Adeptus Astartes were reviled by the whole of the Saharduin race, for it was the boom of bolters and battle cries of power armored space marines which had heralded the destruction of their civilization when it had been at its utter pinnacle. Yet for all of that, despite managing to strip the shields from the Litany of Fury with their utter hatred, these Saharduin, corrupted by Chaos as they’d ranged far from home in search of the whispers that haunted their dreams, had never actually faced space marines in battle.

Suffering only minor hull damage, the venerable superstructure held strong.

And then it was time.

Boardings: 75 vs. 54

Shuddering spread throughout the battle barge as it launched its boarding pods. Aside from orbital bombardment, it was this that the ship had been made for. The Litany of Fury lumbered forward through the incoming swarm of Saharduin ships, which in turn were forced to break off, to twist about, to avoid being struck head-on. Such desperate maneuvers were expected, and boarding torpedo calculations realigned within seconds with the aid of the advanced cogitators of the battle barge. At extreme range, they fired out, slamming into the revealed bellies of a great many of the ships. As the battle barge roared through, its few remaining weapon arrays firing, it was followed behind by the strike cruisers, who themselves formed a spread out trident, tipping and rolling from side to side so that both sides of the launch bays could be utilized, ensuring that just that many more boarding torpedoes could impact deep into the Saharduin ships. The xeno ships had their own point defenses, but due to having to alter their flight paths so significantly, only a small handful of torpedoes were knocked off course, and none were actually destroyed. The armsmen had packed the assault rams and boarding torpedoes far in excess of how many space marines could have fit in them.

Within less than sixty seconds, literal thousands of veteran armsmen of Battlefleet Korianis had entered the ships of the Saharduin and begun killing the enemy. They had faced ork pirates in close quarters, had stormed the mirror maze passages of Eldar ships, set flames to the disgusting innards of tyranid bio-ships, and had fought meter by meter through ships taken by heretical forces. The damp ships of the Saharduin were new to them all, though. At the same time, those dark watery passages were, in fact, incredibly similar to fighting in zero-g combat, as many had done so many times before. Spread amongst many of them, spots of red or blue amidst the green and grey uniforms and flak armor, were the Blood Ravens. The scions of the Librarium were met with universal uneasiness and distrust, as they were all that most terrible of things, psykers, yet whether Epistolary or Lexicani they weathered that enmity as they ever had. More fearsome than that, however, were the legendary terminators, power fists crackling and assault cannons or storm bolters fully loaded.

The Saharduin answered immediately. Many of the boarding torpedoes had landed directly in crew compartments. Others had landed precisely where the xeno design philosophy would place passages which led directly to vital systems. The aliens had remained as static in such things as the Adeptus Mechanicus themselves when it came to their own hallowed designs. This would aid in their undoing. Bayonets and combat knives flashed in the darkness, bellowed cries to the God-Emperor being met with the hissing shrieks and gleaming fangs and blades of the Saharduin. The hiss-crack and steady staccato of lasguns and autoguns found themselves matched by the whizzing booms of crash rifles. Amongst all of which was the thunder of bolter shells and rapid-pace hurricanes of assault cannons. Occasionally, too, did reality twist and rip before the powers of the Librarians.

But neither did the Saharduin ships cease their movement, though they were certainly now heavily focused on ending their foes at close range, turning what had been a swarming charge into a chaotic cloud.

===============================================================

Ship 1: 68 vs. 38

“Progress is steady, Chapter Master. We have captured the reactor, the tech-priests are working to shut it down now.”

Left unsaid was the absolute tide of blue tinged flesh which was making its way down just about every corridor around them. It was, perhaps, a masterwork of hyper-advanced water-cooling which helped the reactor from overheating, but science could only be pushed so far so quickly. Certain electronic components required dryness, and even the Saharduin could not withstand the electrical charge that could be unleashed otherwise. For that matter, space marines would not be able to either. The venerable machine spirits might do their best, but even they could not easily withstand such voltage without leaving their occupants as charred remains.

Ship 2: 41 vs. 43

“Facing heavy resistance! We’re pushing through, but we are taking casualties!”

“Come on you fishy bastards! You like meat? How about grenades!?”

“It’s eating him! Kill it, kill it now!”

“Step aside.”

The booming voice of the terminator cut through the noise of battle, gently shoving armsmen aside. The rest of the Blood Ravens had arrived at the hard point as well, but they gave the terminator a wide berth. It was only good sense, as the resulting noise of an assault cannon firing at full power permanently deafened many of the armsmen who were nearby thanks to the close confines of the corridor.

Ship 3: 81 vs. 87

“Wolves! WOLVES! WOLVES!” The lead Saharduin screeched in badly accented Low Gothic as it stabbed down and snapped at the Lexicani. “KILL WOLVES!”

The young psyker struggled mightily with the xeno before a hail of bolter fire killed it, the Lexicani letting it slump to the ground as they picked their own bolter back up and began firing into the ranks of the enemy.

“We are Blood Ravens,” he snarled back at the aliens, “Learn the difference, xenos, so that your souls will know their killers!”

“Their first encounter in the Imperium was the Space Wolves, and it was almost their last. It is no surprise that the first thing they think of when they see space marines are the scions of Russ,” a Codicier noted gently before he flung a burst of lightning down the hall.

Ship 4: 32 vs. 30

“Fall back and regroup! Fall ba-AAAAAGGH!” The sergeant-at-arms’ scream cut off as the Saharduin dragged him back, stabbing into him with their knives and swords while others slithered past firing their crash rifles.

The survivors of the platoon sprinted as fast as they could, but they could not reach the doors in time before they slammed shut. The tech-priests on the other side immediately began welding it shut at rapid speed while those who had managed to escape the ambush attempted to catch their breath.

“Well, that didn’t work,” one of the armsmen quipped with a dark chuckle. “Anyone know another corridor we can try?”

“Well…,” another pointed at the dark ripples of a completely submerged passage.

Something on the other side of the doors slammed against them.

“I’ll take it! Tech-priest, you going to be all right?”

“Fear not, armsman,” the tech-priest shook their head. “I have applied the thrice-blessed unguents upon my person. The accursed rusting shall not harm my hallowed-,”

Another slam came against the welded door, at which point the armsmen ran for the submerged corridor, affixing their helmets and oxygen tanks on the way. Some picked up the tech-priest and dragged them along with them.

Ship 5: 70 vs. 60

“Will you be all right here, Captain Thule?”

The dreadnought twitched only slightly, rotating upon its base before the assault cannon let loose, shredding an incoming band of Saharduin.

“I will be fine, Sergeant. They shall not take the bridge from me. Go. Head to the reactor.”

Ship 6: 53 vs. 99

“This is Epistolary Idmon! We require immediate support!” Idmon bellowed into the vox before a clench of his fist closed off the corridor by crushing it closed. “Someone pick up Brother Michael. I shall not lose another brother, not on this damned ship!”

Reports had come from across the various ships of the iconography found there, the clearly ritual scarification. All of it pointed to clear corruption by the Blood God, though other more general symbols had been found here and there. Nothing to the extent of the ships of the Dark Mechanicus or those that the Black Legion had wielded, which was somewhat of a balm to the worries over the soul for even considering using the ships as weapons. But here, now, Idmon had rather unfortunately been deployed to a ship where some of the Saharduin had begun to earn ‘blessings’ of Khorne, mutating and strengthening into creatures even more monstrous than usual. Some of the slick-skinned snarling xenos looked outright possessed. The Blood Ravens were in full tactical retreat, firing as they went. The panicked void armsmen were less organized about it, but were falling back as well to the initial beachheads that had been established.

“You will have it, Epistolary. Hold fast!” The Chapter Master’s voice said over the vox.

Emergency Aid: 79 vs. 40

First to arrive in a flash of light was irritable Medici, who plunged his chainsword into an approaching Saharduin before they could harm his patient in Brother Michael, the apothecary pivoting from killing to healing in a single beat of two hearts. But then the others came. The Chapter Master, his form battered and hastily repaired, nonetheless wielding Godsplitter with aplomb. Captain Tarkus, who wielded his bolter with all a veteran’s skill and grace, rolling a pair of grenades to bounce just right to erupt behind the Saharduin charge. Kaius Jacobus, the unconventional champion of the 5th Company, arrived in the bright light of a teleport before blinding those around him further with several dropped flashbangs and smoke grenades. Afterwards, only the squelch of cut apart flesh could give one a hint as to where he was amongst the enemy. Three terminators, arriving at spread out points, quickly joined with their similarly clad brother and simply planted themselves at a main thoroughfare, one for each corridor not held by the armsmen and the fourth joining his fire to each of the three’s chosen front as needed.

And then the Chief Librarian arrived. His face was a mask of pure psychic light, his wrathful visage cast as a shadow upon itself from the burning fires of his will made manifest in reality. It was the heat of suns, which vaporized water and melted steel, that then twisted into thick lengths of solidified, crystallized lightning. The Chaos-corrupted Saharduin screeched for the favor of Khorne, promised the Blood God the blood of their enemies, the skulls of space marines much greater prizes than those of the panicked and running armsmen. The Blood Ravens responded with their own personalized litanies of hatred, of contempt, writ not just in word but in the movement of the blade and the thunderous call of the bolter and assault cannon.

Ship 7: 91 vs. 11

“This is Codicier Aeneas, to all. The Reaverlord is dead.”

Aeneas’ breath was heavy, his armor slick from head to toe with the blood of the alien. Saharduin blood was just a bit darker than human blood, for some medical reason that he could not bother to remember at the moment. It had cast him, at this point, in far darker crimson than normal. The Reaverlord lay in five separate pieces, strewn across the bridge of the ship, each of them squirting and spilling less and less blood. The monstrously mutated creature had been unnaturally fast, especially for its size, the blessings of Chaos strong with it. Strong, at least, compared to the rest of the Saharduin that they had faced as they’d run through the ship. As well as the rest of his guard. Piscean Warriors that had long given up their souls to Khorne, many of them outright forgoing crash rifles entirely in favor of their blades and mutated fangs and claws. The bridge was a wrecked ruin after the fight, and he paused for a moment before flicking The Blade of the Martyr to clean it somewhat.

“Holy God-Emperor…,” one of the armsmen whispered.

Aeneas glanced over and thus watched as the handful of surviving armsmen cringed away from the sight of him, faint witch-light still flickering over his frame as it did when he slipped in and out of the warp at high speed. Reality, reasserting itself. He was not fully recovered from his failure over Opus Maxima, his soul, and its defenses, were still fragile. The rents and tears the daemons had inflicted on him were still raw, despite his flesh being mended. As it was, none of the Saharduin present appeared to possess any psykers, let alone sorcerers, and with none of them – even the Reaverlord – possessing the sheer power of Lord Mortirex, they had not been able to stop him as he’d moved through the ship alone. Even so, the Reaverlord had scored his breastplate deeply with his power weaponry, the crudely engineered weapon chain having only increased its deadliness.

“Sergeant Amos, report,” Aeneas eventually called on the vox, forcing the exhaustion and stinging pains down. “Did you take the reactor?”

“Affirmative, Codicier. Life support is shutting down already in enemy-held sectors, and we’ve vented multiple compartments already. You challenging the Reaverlord managed to get a lot of them in the same passages. The tech-priests estimate we’ve cleansed the ship of almost seven tenths of the crew because of it.”

“Understood. Continue holding until it is time to move on to the next ships.”

The Codicier flipped the sword about to rest it point facing down and closed his eyes in meditative concentration as he tried to soothe the aches and pains in his soul and body. Though his gifts in such matters were feeble and threadbare, something was better than nothing, in the end.

Ship 8: 96 vs. 20

“Filthy creatures,” Colonel Hun’kai muttered as his fellow storm troopers cleared the barrack-creche.

Underwater combat was not something they’d often fought in, but the Inquisition faced battlefields and situations that would scour the mind and soul of the uninitiated. It did not matter that the Saharduin were born in the water, that their skeletal structure let them flex and twist about the pipes, pouring in from all directions. It did not matter that the lighting in the submerged portions of the ship was bad, their helmets and the systems within them were more than enough to compensate. Their guns worked in the waters, and their combat knives cut through alien flesh. They were servants of the Ordo Hereticus. The inhuman mentality and weapons of the aliens were twisted things, but then so were heretics. So were daemons. Traitors. Aliens. All of them were to be crushed, ground into dust by the Inquisitorial boot.

Today, they were the boot.

“All points, report in,” he said calmly into the vox as he dodged backwards from a snapping Saharduin jaw, jamming the barrel of his hellgun into the alien’s eye socket and pulling the trigger.

He swam forwards as other battle group leaders began reporting in, examining his hands to make sure that the sudden flash boiling of the water had not adversely affected the armor on them.

“The bridge has been taken. Objective achieved. Minimal casualties.”

“Primary reactor taken. Minimal casualties.”

“Secondary reactors taken. Medium casualties, Saharduin defenders achieved frenzy state.”

The list went on, and on. He would have smiled if his entire face had not long ago been replaced with superior bionics after being exposed to open vacuum for too long.

“Continue cleansing protocols. The Inquisitor wants this ship empty of all alien life.”

Ship 9: 40 vs. 90

The vox unit released sparks in all directions, the signal tinny and scratched heavily with static.

“Captain Vesner? Captain Vesner, sir!! We’re getting torn apart here, we’re pulling back to the pods, it’s the only secure territory we have left! Captain?!”

The Saharduin drooled greedily as they devoured the dead and dying armsmen, viciously tearing apart the bodies. They did not care that they had killed a burgeoning hero of the Imperial Navy. They had repelled the invaders, and all that was broken would be salvage or be food. Such was life amongst their kind. One, however, heard the squealing of the box, attached as it was to the headless armsman, and walked over to it, head tilting this way and that before sniffing at the screeching box. Then they stomped down on it, silencing it so that the feast could be done in peace. Soon enough, Piscean Warriors had reloaded their weapons, taken their trophies, and begun swarming out through the ship to the last crumbling islands of resistance left on the ship. The invaders had thought them prey. Oh, how wrong they were.

Ship 10: 46 vs. 24

“Back off!”

Those were the last words the Saharduin ever heard before the heavy bolter tore them apart. Some had questioned the usefulness of bringing heavy weapons teams on a boarding mission. Some of those people had not met Admiral Graves, who preferred that his boarding teams were more than just fodder to slow and distract the crews of the ships that he came into conflict with. The beachhead had been taken, and though the Saharduin were attempting to flood their taken areas, the tech-priests had managed to gain access to the plumbing systems of their taken sectors are record speed, ensuring that the water never actually managed to get past their knees.

“Well sarge, we took the beachheads. Now what?” A thickly muscled man covered in tattoos asked of a comparatively waifish woman.

“We wait for reinforcements, Pavus,” she said with a shrug. “Those were our orders.”

“M’kay.”

===========================================================

Ship 2: 60 vs. 34

“The xenos are retreating to the lower decks, but we’ve cut them off from all the vital systems,” the tech-priest straightened, flicking his mechadendrites as if to cleanse them of the disgusting alien coding. “Their engineer caste being chained to their stations was a foolish endeavor.”

Ordinarily, of course, they wouldn’t have been. However, after being under the influence of Khorne for so long, even the lowest and most docile of the predator carnivorous race had grown uncontrollable. Only by chaining them to their duty stations had the Saharduin been able to keep their ships functioning in the first place, to the screaming distress of their fellows. It was either that, or they were genuinely slaves made of their own race, who had been forced to remain as those who commanded the ships followed the whispers of Chaos. The Imperials killing them didn’t really much care for the reasons behind it, only that it had made taking the ship that much easier once they’d finally broken the stalemate in the on-board fighting.

Ship 3: 58 vs. 89

“Fall back to the rally point! I shall hold them off!” Lucan intensified his shield of will, reduced to maintaining it with every scrap of his psychic might.

He could not even manage to throw forth bolts of psychic power, such was his concentration. All around him, the armsmen were falling back, their gains in the ship torn to tatters by the especially fierce aliens here. Lasguns and autoguns fired rapidly all around him, intermittendly joined by the bolters of the Blood Ravens present. Similar and worse tactical retreats were being performed all across the ship. They had overextended, and badly. The reactor had been recovered, and most gunnery stations had been returned to the enemy. It was not necessarily a blessing that the aliens had fallen into frenzy, focusing on killing the invaders to their ship than actually sitting at the consoles to return fire to the Imperial ships outside.

“Damned xenos,” he snarled beneath his breath as a hailstorm of fire shredded several void armsmen just as they’d rounded the corner.

They had just been too far away to save.

Ship 4: 24 vs. 11

“Hah HAH!” The armsman cried aloud as he plunged his appropriated alien sword into the Saharduin’s back, causing it to squeal and thrash in its death throes.

“Get ‘em, get ‘em!” Another cried as they emerged from the waters, firing their guns on full auto, filling sinuous alien bodies with solid slugs.

In a total reversal of normal expectations, it was not the Saharduin who were emerging from hatches and submerged passages to ambush, but rather the void armsmen of Battlefleet Korianis who were doing the amphibious ambushing. Lasguns, no longer a danger to their wielders in the water, were unholstered and fired on full auto, others stabbing and slashing with their bayonets. Even so, it might have been a near thing, were it not for that which breached the water next. They had met up in the waters of the ship, unexpectedly, and had nearly shot each other apart before sense had reasserted itself. It was if a boulder of red and black was being thrust out of the water, something rejected by the waters themselves or thrust up by an irritated god.

“I am your death, alien,” Tomb-Brother Nathan boomed before he picked up a Saharduin and crushed them into pulp within his power fist, his momentum carrying him up the overstressed steps and out of the water, dripping with it even as his great bulk prevented the Saharduin from initially seeing the space marines that rushed out from behind him.

But they certainly felt their bolter fire, as well as their grenades.

Ship 5: 27 vs. 29

“We’ve taken the reactor, but some enterprising commander pried the engineers out of their stations. They’re somewhere in the lower decks, sabotaging our efforts,” the tech-priest said tersely as he removed himself from the console. “We must hunt them down!”

“Very well, tech-priest. They have stopped us for now. But they will not stop us forever,” Captain Thule said calmly. “I shall continue to hold the reactor.”

Ship 9: 47 vs. 15

“Those storm troopers give me the creeps, sarge.”

“Yeah, well, those storm troopers just took the ship where you,” Sergeant-At-Arms Acchus slapped his subordinate’s shoulder, “And me, couldn’t do it. Using the xenos own boarding pods was dangerous, sure, but you can’t really argue with the results.”

All over the ship, the armsmen were slumping against the walls in exhaustion after such a hard-fought battle, some outright sliding down to crumple in heaps and simply lay there. Others were eager enough to keep fighting, but had in fact been told by their various commanders to absolutely refrain from doing so. The Inquisitorial Storm Troopers did not brook interference, and unwanted aid most definitely counted as interference. Clad in black and silver, their hellguns and advanced autoguns had torn the Saharduin apart, especially since the aliens had been so committed to killing off all of the armsmen. An attack from the rear on all points, boarding the ship with another alien ship’s methods, just to get to grips with the aliens sooner.

Both men stiffened as a squad of the storm troopers passed by them, but relaxed after they weren’t given a second glance.

“…aye, though. They’re a cold bunch.”

Ship 10: 63 vs. 34

“Uh, sarge?”

“Yeah?”

“I thought you said we were supposed to wait for orders.”

“Eh…,” Sergeant Mckinna shrugged as she squirmed on the incredibly uncomfortable captain’s chair. “God-Emperor, this thing was not meant for human spines. Or bones. Engh.”

All around them, the rest of their squad shoved the floppy bodies of the dead Saharduin into the corner. Similar acts were ongoing across the rest of the ship, the Saharduin having been overwhelmed. Or surprised. Or both. Sergeant Mckinna’s chainsword had been turned off, and lay against the captain’s chair, the sheer amount of alien gore on it having made it come far too close to guttering off for her liking. The tech-priests would probably need to take a look at it.

“Uh this is…uh, Sergeant McKinna,” she said as she tabbed the vox. “We’ve taken the bridge. Any, uh, anyone else out there?”

Immediately, an answer emerged from the broadcaster.

“Oh, yeah! Hey McKinna! Yeah this is Godfrey, we met-,”

“Yes, we have,” she interrupted. “Where are you?”

“Oh, we uh…according to the tech-priest this is the main reactor complex of the ship. So me and a couple hundred others are holding that down right now.”

“Great,” McKinna nodded.

“So, hey, I was wondering, if you ever wanted to grab a cup of caff, maybe-,”

“Well!” Mckinna coughed loudly as she closed the channel. “Good job everyone. Good….good beachheads. Keep on holdin’!”

“Sarge?”

“Yes, Pavus?” She blinked owlishly at the lumbering armsman.

“What do we do now?”

She stared at him and then looked around the bridge.

“We hold the beachheads we made, and wait for further orders," she then brightened. "I hear that space marines might come to help us!"

“But we-,”

"We hold the beachheads," she said, staring unblinkingly at the armsman. "Understood?"

"Uh....yes boss!"

========================================================

Ship 3: 66 vs. 42

Lucan breathed deeply as he glared at the charred remains of the Saharduin. Though he had long preferred to turn his biomancy skills towards aiding his brethren and his allies, that did not mean he was a failure in other applications. He was an Epistolary of the Blood Ravens. Basic competence in multiple castings of psychic might were requirements to achieve that position. Such as taking total command of natural bioelectricity and expanding it in scope, to the great and painful detriment of his enemies. Even then, he was not the reason that they had pushed back so heavily. The ships had passed by again, delivering another shuddering barrage of boarding torpedoes and assault rams, flooding the ships with fresh combatants and bodies. Even the Blood Ravens had come from other ships that were determined to mostly be under control to aid them.

“The reactor is ours. The bridge has been retaken for the third and final time. System command is ours,” the tech-priest announced distractedly. “Beginning cleansing operations of living xenos in the ship.”

“Good,” Lucan nodded. “Let’s go to work, then.”

Ship 5: 69 vs. 21

The underwater sections of the cruiser thick as stew by now. Chum swirled through it, the scraps and shreds of dead armsmen and alien mingling with one another, torn apart as they had both been in the fiercest fighting across all the ships. The Saharduin shared a disturbing number of physiological similarities to the ancient terran shark, predators of the waters of that world when there had been oceans there. These, too, were further infected with the insidious powers of Chaos, their connection to slaughter and destruction had only inflamed those instincts beyond their natural limits. There would be no retreat. There was only the killing, unto the last. The water began to drain from certain sections, revealing whole decks utterly strewn with wet gore, but also those Saharduin who still lived, those who had not yet been forced away into other compartments so that bulkheads could slam down and block them off in permanence.

“And that,” Brother Ambros grunted as he withdrew his combat knife from the corpse of one of the remaining xenos. “Is that, praise the Emperor.”

“There are still thousands of Saharduin left alive on the ship, but they are dying at a precipitous rate,” a tech-priest noted. “We have control of all primary and secondary systems. We know where they are, and where they are moving. Praise the Omnissiah, for this foul alien technology was no match for us.”

============================================================================

One hour. That was how long it took to reduce ten Saharduin cruisers to floating hulks, their guns and engines powered down.

In that single hour, there were tens of thousands of casualties amongst the void armsmen. Thousands upon thousands of fatalities. Several wounds, only a handful of them minor, amongst the few handfuls of space marines that had been scattered amongst them. A tremendous expenditure of ammo on all sides. In the void, watching protectively, were the ships of the Blood Ravens and the Grand Cruiser Sword of Reckoning. It was they who had continually punctured the shields of the alien cruisers, pulling back and covering one another whenever they were in danger of losing their own shields. All to allow more boarding assaults, to allow teleportation between the ships. Alien designs aside, the fact remained that the alien cruisers were peers in tonnage to the Lunar-class cruiser, and as such despite more automation and the unique internal environment, they possessed up to two thirds the crew compliments of said Lunars.

Which was unfortunate, because a single Lunar-class cruiser could retain at nominal full compliment anywhere between ninety and one hundred thousand crew members.

Continued Cleaning: 92

On the other hand, the Imperial Navy had a rather massive glut of armsmen thanks to taking on the compliments of many of the destroyed ships in the battle thus far. It was by sheer numbers alone that they were able to maintain a pace of continued combat that was traditionally utilized by space marines. Endless cycling in and out, wounded platoons and squads being replaced within minutes, all while the Blood Ravens threw themselves into the fighting as well. No longer fighting to claim the vital systems of the ships, but to simply kill, to destroy, to wage a war of total annihilation. With the control of the tech-priests, the Saharduin could not hide. They could not maneuver. They could not prepare themselves, as doors and bulkheads shifted, as waters were stolen from them or over-pressurized before psychic bioelectric lightning filled both said waters and their bodies. For all of that, the Chaos-corrupted aliens fought on, they could do nothing less, for they had fallen not only into frenzy but beneath the influence of Khorne.

It would not be enough.

“Based on the estimates of the armsmen, your battle brothers, and the storm troopers, we’ll have those ships emptied of alien life within twenty four to twenty five hours,” Admiral Graves said, hand on his chin.

Once more, the commanders had met in a joined vox and holo-projected call. Well, most. Inquisitor Adrastia had finally succumbed to her wounds and medical treatment and was currently in a restive coma being watched over by her private medicae staff. She was now being represented by the two leaders of her personal forces. Captain Maria Carlyle commanded the ship and its naval staff proper, while Colonel Hun’kai commanded not only the storm trooper regiment permanently assigned to the ship but its expertly trained and equipped void armsmen as well. The left half of the former’s face was replaced with bionics, while the Colonel still bore their helmet, the lenses a deep but dull red.

“Then we should discuss what we will be doing with the ships,” Colonel Derosa said, blinking a bit blearily.

As they had not been involved in the fight, the old adage of soldiers taking their rest whenever they could had held true amongst the Meridian Regiments.

“Indeed. We don’t have nearly enough crew, even with our overstuffed compartments, to try and crew them. Let alone the fact that it’s xenos tech, furthermore it is corrupted by Chaos,” Graves warned with a shake of his head. “Either fire ships or rams. Both could be intensely valuable…but we don’t have the sheer explosives or promethium to make the former, not really.”

“We could place some of the Litany’s bombardment shells in them, but that would take more time as well.”

Grave’s bushy eyebrows rose.

“Now there’s an idea,” the Admiral mused, rubbing at his chin. “Though some of the tech-priests had the idea of trying to turn the ships into mini-Dominius Astras, as they do still use warp engines.”

All went silent for a moment as they contemplated the fate of that legendary ship. The Dominius Astra had not only been a venerable Emperor-class battleship, but the flagship of the entire Battlefleet Tempestus. At the same time, it’s sacrifice, the deliberate overloading of its warp engines after plunging into the bulk of the tyranid fleet had created an utterly devastating vortex which had torn them all into pieces and cast the scraps into oblivion. Vortex grenades were already some of the most dangerous infantry weapons around. With each upwards scaling of such effects, the potential damage grew exponentially.

“Creating such Warp vortexes can cause significant disruption to the Warp itself,” Justinius warned. “With this star system constrained as it is, I am wary of the effects that such things could cause, especially if it is more than one.”

“The Navigators warned of such things as well,” Graves nodded, “But they also brought up that the Dominus Astra was a battleship. These are but cruisers. Alien cruisers, but cruisers.”

“And there are ten of them,” Justinius rejoined, making Graves’ head knock back.

“Hmm. True. Perhaps not all.”

“We should discuss the next target,” Captain Carlyle spoke up, her voice cool and dispassionate. “There remain other worlds and other enemy ships within this system. The Sword shall spend the intervening period of total ship preparation by boiling the waters of Aeterna."

"Aye, we'll join you in that. Let this world boil away," Graves said, motioning to someone off screen.

Three more worlds remained.

“What news of Croxnov? Any movement from the Kroot?” Colonel Hun’kai asked.

“Plenty, but mostly amongst themselves. Our long range probes have detected a massive sigil effectively carved into the planet surface,” Gabriel answered. “We could not see it before due to the planet’s rotation and distance. But now we can. I dare not display that symbol openly, but suffice to say that they too have chosen a Dark God to follow. The patron of the traitorous Emperor’s Children.”

Most present made soft noises of acknowledgement, though the Inquisitorial commanders simply nodded firmly.

“Hate fighting those sorts,” Graves grumbled. “I’ll make sure to get the tech-priests to try and secure our vox channels as best as possible. Don’t need any off-tune choruses bleating into the speakers and driving crews mad.”

He said it casually, but all knew they would be doing the same. Memetic eradication of the will and mind through forced broadcast were a common tactic of ships that fell to Chaos, though the effects could change. Some could drive the crews to frothing bloodthirsty ruin, hacking each other to pieces. Others could cause directionless madness. The more esoteric effects of vessels given fully over to Nurgle were especially disturbing. The same could be said of ships that followed Slaanesh. All such things were dire, in their own ways. Crews collapsing into giggling indolence, deafened and maddened by ear and soul-splitting concertos and rapturous gasps, these could be just as if not worse than the others, depending on the situation.

“For the moment, though, the Kroot seem wholly involved with hunting creatures and each other across the surface of Croxnov, but we have no idea of what is going on inside their Warsphere.”

“I would prefer not to contemplate it too hard - especially with who knows what modifications they may have made,” Graves snorted. “Runao is still running food and supplies to New Meridian, but they don’t have a defensive fleet capable of ranging beyond the planet itself. Is it…time?”

Another silence spread.

Was it time?

The Kroot seem utterly self-absorbed, but how long could that last?

The ships over Runao were bound there, but so long as their planet shipped food to New Meridian, the enemy would be freshly fed for far longer than the forces of the Imperium.

And yet, all the while, New Meridian itself appeared to be further fortifying itself. Twisted mirrors of the PDF were rallying up, the populace itself seemingly being armed if the long range probes were correct in their projected imagery. Masses of citizenry were heading to the manufactorums and certain mustering points, taking up arms to defend their world against the coming invaders. There was little doubt in anyone’s mind that more was going on, but there was only so much the probes could do against a watchful defensive fleet replete with orbital defense stations. How long would be too long? Would advancing now prove a fatal mistake?

“If we can take the Warsphere, that could be a ram or fireship as well, far in excess of the cruisers,” Gabriel mused out loud. “If we take out Runao, one way or another, the sheer population of Vandis’ precious Hive World will begin to starve within days.”

“What are you thinking, Chapter Master?” Justinius glanced over at Gabriel.

What Are You Thinking, Chapter Master?:
Voting Moratorium 24 Hours

[] Turn The Ten (10) Saharduin Ships Into:
-[] Rams: Minimal effort, possibly devastating results if the aiming is done at a stationary target such as a space station or a planet. (Write-In How Many)
-[] Fire Ships: The enemy may have disabled the Litany's bombardment cannon, but she may yet contribute her thunder. Place bombardment shells and torpedoes into the ships, with long-range transmitters ready to trigger them at the right moments. (Write-In How Many)
[] Vortex Ships: The lesson of the Dominius Astra is that properly overloaded warp engines can be devastatingly effective. Enough to tear the heart out of Hive Fleet Behemoth. Enough, perhaps, to help tear huge holes in an enemy fleet? There may be side effects of tearing the Warp up, of course, especially in a system so constrained by the gravity reef. (Write-In How Many)

AND

GM NOTE: This list is from nearest-to-farthest in terms of distance in the system. I.E. New Meridian is furthest away from the fleet ATM

[] Choose the next target of the combined fleet:
-[] Croxnov: Slaanesh worshipping Kroot, and a still unmoving Warsphere. Perhaps consumed with alien debauchery, perhaps preparing to arrive behind the fleet at whenever target they next engage.
-[] Runao: The system's Agriworld, vegetation and crops long tainted by Chaos. It feeds New Meridian's massive population. Defended by ten system monitors, each potentially matches for cruiser ships in armament if not propulsion, as well as ten well armed orbital stations.
-[] New Meridian: Ex-Governor Vandis' bastion. Well defended. It's defense fleet is made up not just of monitors, but of warp-capable ships as well. A bevy of orbital defense stations hang about it as well, while its shipyard keeps them all running. They are clearly fortifying, preparing for the arrival of the Imperium.

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+12 Codiciers, 10 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
37 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Minor Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
4 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [Extremely Minor Casualties]

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Thirteen)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[] Turn The Ten (10) Saharduin Ships Into:
-[] Rams: Minimal effort, possibly devastating results if the aiming is done at a stationary target such as a space station or a planet. (3)
-[] Fire Ships: The enemy may have disabled the Litany's bombardment cannon, but she may yet contribute her thunder. Place bombardment shells and torpedoes into the ships, with long-range transmitters ready to trigger them at the right moments. (6)
-[] Vortex Ships: The lesson of the Dominius Astra is that properly overloaded warp engines can be devastatingly effective. Enough to tear the heart out of Hive Fleet Behemoth. Enough, perhaps, to help tear huge holes in an enemy fleet? There may be side effects of tearing the Warp up, of course, especially in a system so constrained by the gravity reef. (1)

[] Choose the next target of the combined fleet
-[] New Meridian: Ex-Governor Vandis' bastion. Well defended. It's defense fleet is made up not just of monitors, but of warp-capable ships as well. A bevy of orbital defense stations hang about it as well, while its shipyard keeps them all running. They are clearly fortifying, preparing for the arrival of the Imperium.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

“Are you absolutely sure?”

“Deadly, Admiral. Every battle weakens what remains of our forces further, for all that they also inflame our faith and fury. Meanwhile, they rally strength from the merciless sacrifice of their own,” Gabriel said as he looked upon the system produced by the actuality sphere’s projectors.

“I cannot deny that,” Graves nodded, rubbing at his chin. “Hmph. Well,” he shrugged, the image flickering as he did so. “Admiral is as high as I’ll ever get, so why not?”

“Better to die in the cause of the Emperor than flee,” Captain Carlyle said calmly, her eyes as dead speaking to them now as they had been when she discussed boiling all of Aeterna.

At that very moment, the venerable Grand Cruiser was doing just that, as were a great many of the other functional ships. Aeterna, so-called by the claimants of the system, could not necessarily burn due to its existence as an ocean world. Vast amounts of salt water were in that moment being boiled away, the atmosphere of the planet wracked and shredded by the environmental changes being wrought by concentrated plasma and lance bombardment. Craters opened deep beneath the waters, displacing it further, resulting in tidal waves and clouds of steam the size of cities erupting and spinning about. At one point, sensors detected what must have been the underwater dwellings of the Saharduin upon the planet, as well as the death and destruction of multiple massive biological entities within the depths. The Imperials cared little, for all below was tainted not just by the alien but by the taint of Chaos as well.

It was, by all accounts, a quite casual apocalypse for the planet in question.

“Mmph, perhaps for some,” Admiral Graves raised an eyebrow at the woman. “I personally plan to reach retirement age in another fifty years.”

Something ugly flickered through the now slightly narrowed dead eyes of Captain Carlyle.

“Indeed?”

“Oh yes, Captain,” Graves said, carefully enunciating the technically lesser ranked naval commander. “As such, to reach that retirement, I intend to win here. I wasn’t raised in a Death Cult, you know.”

“Moving on,” Gabriel said, not quite glaring at either of the two. “How long shall it take the Tech-Priests to do their work?”

“A little less than twenty four hours,” Graves answered. “Xeno technology it may be, the Saharduin are not so advanced as to make it hard to tell what buttons to press to make them go and turn. They’ll not be too responsive, we don’t have the sheer servitors to spare to try and work with the other fire ships with arrived with, but then, they don’t need to be.”

“Very well. Let us rearm and prepare ourselves for the fighting ahead,” Gabriel nodded to each of the conference call’s members before shutting down the projector, leaving him and Justinius standing alone.

“I shall retire to the Librarium. The Lexicani are not generally meant for combat as dire as this,” Justinius said tiredly. “Even we space marines require rest, for the mind and spirit if nothing else, on occasion.”

“I do not disagree,” Gabriel waved him away. “Rest. Recuperate. Be ready.”

The Chief Librarian inclined his head respectfully before turning and leaving. Gabriel, however, remained. They had no senior Tech-Marines to aid him, to restore the battered bionics that made up so much of his body to full form. The Tech-Priests were busy with repairs of the Imperial Navy ships as well as the ships of the Saharduin. With each shift of weight, each movement, he felt the metal grind ever so quietly within him, at levels that only he could hear. But he did not focus upon that, and instead closed his eyes to listen to the Litany herself, as best he could. She had been under his command when he was but a Captain, and he had traveled upon her as a sergeant and a lower battle brother before that. Her outer skin had been scorched and melted, but her engines and shields once more held strong.

Still.

He had little else to do but listen, and feel the shift of the ship beneath his feet on occasion.

===============================================

“DIE IN FLAMES, XENOS! DIIIIIIIIIIIEEEEEEEEEEE IIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIN FLAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMES!”

With that said, the Sister of Battle slammed her feet down, wrenched the controls about, and sent the immolator tank’s mounted weapon system whirring like a top as its twin heavy flamers engulfed the surrounding area in presumably holy fire. The dozens of hormagaunts leaping this way and that, some of them even trying to climb atop the tank, were scorched black by the heat, many of them dying instantly. Other nearby immolators did the same, the entire wedge halted by sheer weight of biomass now responding in the most appropriate manner. Just behind the now halted wedge, the rest of the Sisters of Battle immediately began firing as the tyranids burst from the ditches next to the road, some of them appearing from the cold mists which obscured the slopes of the valley, and still others exploding out of the ground in the form of raveners and tyranid warriors. The entire column was engaged in the fight within ten seconds of being halted.

“An ambush? AN AMBUSH!?” Screamed Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum as she triggered her power fists and backhanded a tyranid warrior into death while stepping out of her rhino transport. “Foolsih xenos! You have only delivered yourselves into our hands! Into the hands of the God-Emperor! DIE!” She screamed as she triggered her jump pack and went flying forwards across the battlefield directly at another tyranid warrior, both power fists forward.

Bolters chattered as loud as bio-plasma bursts, meanwhile celestian squads set their feet and began trigging their heavy flamers, multi-meltas, and heavy bolters. Seraphim slashed and shot from the skies against flying tyranid bio-forms that came screeching out of the mists. Over a thousand Sisters of Battle sang hymns of faith and hatred, their depth of their grudge against the aliens attacking them as bottomless as the hive fleets themselves. Sisters Repentia hauled their chainswords back and forth across the hides of the enemy, mono-molecular tips shredding chitin even as the unarmored penitents were in turn swarmed and shredded to pieces by alien fangs and claws. One squad of sisters was reduced to little more than melted armor and flesh when an enormous blast of bio-plasma was fired from the flesh-molded cannon of a carnifex as the large creature burst through a low ridge that it and two others had been hidden behind. Even as it stomped closer, however, two penitent engines with buzzing saw blades and heavy flamers fell upon it, tearing and cutting even as they were splashed with acid which burned down past the bone of the exposed pilots.

“This is why I suggested the route I did,” Cyrus muttered as he watched it all through the scope of his rifle. “We had not scouted this hive as the others. Damn it.”

“These Lost Rosetta, they were close allies of your Chapter once?” Captain Manin asked, looking at the Blood Raven askance.

“Yes. They took the betrayal of Kyras as poorly as we did. Now, despite everything, their faith does not allow them to forgive, or even see past the blood of the traitors we slew,” Cyrus grunted. “I’m told that in the distant past, the Chapter was able to discover some clues as to the location of the Lost Rosetta for which their Ordo gains its name, and gave it to them.”

“Mmm. Should we aid them? They have deployed across the planet.”

Cyrus pursed his lips, checking through the scope again to watch as the Sisters of Battle struggled to survive the ambush that had fallen upon them.

“…yes. That,” he pointed in their vague direction, “Specific column is led by their Canoness Superior, Margaret Tenenbaum. She is…,”

Insane. Ferocious. Zealous.

“Better alive than dead. The Lost Rosetta lost much to the tyranids many years ago, they have sworn to combat them wherever they can be found. With the Odaken gone, they’ve dedicated their full strength to this fight.”

“Very well. Rescue it is,” Captain Manin slid his helmet back onto his face.

=================================================================

“Here we go,” Admiral Graves said as the combined fleet began to pass by Kroxnov.

There was absolutely no chance of them attempting a short-range warp jump, not as the Warp itself of the system was increasingly chaotic. They had nowhere near enough navigators to even begin to think of such a thing, either, given how many of the xeno ships that they had managed to capture. Even so, it itched at the back of his skull to simply let another ship sit behind him. It wasn’t even close to the right kind of uncomfortable, rather more like trying to avoid the pointiest parts of the wall carvings and decorations in a palace while at a dance than he’d like. Warspheres, based on the records, were slow. But records could be wrong, and the insanity that was Chaos could allow the bending of perfectly good laws of reality into unwholesome positions without consent.

“Status on the Warsphere?” He barked.

“Still immobile, Admiral!”

“Hrrng,” he grunted, feeling beads of sweat form onto his forehead and back. “Tell Captain Benedict and Captain Arnold to shift more to the rear.”

“Aye, Admiral, orders sent!”

Neither of the Captains would appreciate being told to shield the Saharduin ships more obviously, but it needed to be done, just in case. All of them were being dragged along at the center of the bedraggled formation, and if the enemy had anything approaching serviceable auspex systems, they’d know that something was up. It was only prudent. Furthermore, the troop transports were in an equally vulnerable position towards the rear, carrying the precious forces that would be required for what would surely not be an easy fight on New Meridian itself.

“Come on, come on,” Graves muttered as he glared at the actuality sphere. “Keep your eyes shut, you alien mongrels…,”

The worlds of the blasted system weren’t all lined up like a bar game, but it still didn’t make Graves feel too much better that they didn’t actually have to pass within the gravity well of Kroxnov. It was still there, after all.

“Final course is set, Admiral. All ships are responding green. We’re on our way,” the helmsman said, his voice shaking only a little bit with nervousness.

So they were.

=======================================================

“Cannoness! DOWN!” The call was male and unfamiliar.

Only a few priests and emissaries had traveled with the column, and she had known them all. This was none of those. Still, Margaret did so, dropping to one knee just in time to hear something whizz past and impact into something directly behind her.

There should have been nothing directly behind her.

“Nnnnraaagh!” She snarled as she spun about on her knee, digging a divot into the dirt with the same movement, and punched upwards the moment she saw the blood splattered outline of a tyranid lictor as it attempted to reel backwards. “No you DON’T!” She grasped the bulk of the feeder tentacles and tore, ripping them all of in the same move as she captured the rest of its head in the palm of her other power fist and squeezed.

The beast died immediately, and violently.

All around her, the battle was ongoing, but she could see the tide shifting as space marines arrived. Some by teleport, but most by jump pack, burning out of the skies to drop down amongst her sisters and began tearing into the enemy. She, however, turned to face the one who had warned her, her lips twisting as she gazed upon the symbols engraved in his armor and the coloration of his armor.

“Blood Raven,” she did not quite spit.

“Canoness Tenenbaum,” the space marine said with a nod. “We told you that we hadn’t scouted this area out yet.”

He pivoted and fired his sniper rifle again, killing a tyranid warrior instantly as it loomed over a fallen sister who hadn’t managed to get to her feet in time.

“We used the data you provided, Blood Raven,” she snorted, “Five other columns such as this, each led by a canoness, are proceeding into tyranid territory. What you and the Ebon Claws could not, we shall.”

The Blood Raven blinked his one eye, the other a bionic piece with an unblinking red lens, glanced around at the battlefield, now that the battle itself was thoroughly dying down.

“I see,” he said noncommittally, which in turn made Margaret narrow her eyes, nose flaring in anger.

“Force Commander Cyrus,” an Ebon Claw said as he flew over, inclining his head to her. “Canoness Tenenbaum. We’re getting reports that the hive is showing a lot more activity.”

“Of course it is,” the Blood Raven said, looking away from Margaret. “They’ve been provoked and are going to be on high alert. We won’t be able to take down the Shadow Tower in the manner as before,” he then turned to Margaret again. “We deliberately didn’t approach this area, Canoness, so that with the other hives distracted, we could have attempted to reach the Shadow Tower in stealth.”

Margaret sneered.

“A cowardly tactic, Blood Raven.”

“A successful one,” the Ebon Claw shook his head. “How do you think we took the other Shadow Towers down that let reinforcements into the Sector? Now…now all will suffer until we can remove it with more ‘conventional’ methods.”

The Canoness glared at the two of them, eyes narrowed, looking for some sign of deceit. Finding none, however, she could only grit her teeth.

“And you could not have told us this?!?”

“Lictors, like the one I saved you from, have a tendency to seek out commanders and consume their brains for information,” Cyrus tilted his chin towards the still warm corpse. “This splinter leans heavily on such tactics. Generals, quartermasters, sergeants, priests…,” he looked at her dispassionately, “Canonesses. It hardly matters now. If we don’t strike the hive now, we might not get another chance before their ships can deliver more spores to the surface with the Navy reeling like it is.”

“Indeed.” The Ebon Claw nodded before the rest of the space marines began extricating themselves from the ambush site, treating the Sisters of Battle just as warily as they themselves were being treated. “We’ll have to move out and try to destroy it from here.”

“What, by yourselves?” Margaret raised an eyebrow. “I know that neither of your Chapters are at full strength. And…Force Commander, that is not…where is Angelos, then?”

Cyrus glanced back at her.

“You’re free to fight alongside us if you wish, Canoness. And the Chapter Master is seeing to the hunting of a heretic and a traitor to the Imperium.”

Margaret glanced between the two, then back at the ruins of the column. At least a hundred sisters were dead, the tyranids sacrificing what had to be thousands of bodies in the attack, with many more wounded.

“If you think we are too weak to kill tyranids, you both underestimate the power of our hate and our faith,” she snarled. “SISTERS! PREPARE TO MOVE OUT!”

=================================================================

“New Meridian. What a pustule of a place,” Adrastia declared as the call opened, the vox scratchier than normal the closer they got to the Chaos-born Hive World.

The Inquisitor seemed only moderately recovered compared to when last seen. The hololith was from only the neck up, but the interference could do nothing to disguise the total lack of eyes. She’d wound a black cloth over the empty sockets, a silver Inquisitorial Rosette in the middle, but other than that there was not even the slightest hint of a tremble in her voice. Joining her on the call was Captain Carlyle and the Colonel in command of her storm trooper regiment. Admiral Graves had managed to get a few hours of sleep at some point, but the bags beneath his eyes were still deep. This time, too, the Colonels Derosa were attending the call, seeing as they were coming upon what might well be the death of them all one way or the other.

“I won’t deny that. Even for a Hive World it isn’t particularly pretty.”

The closer they’d gotten, the more the scans and probes had been able to detect. Massive cathedrals and edifices dedicated not to the worship of the God-Emperor, but to the blasphemous faith of Chaos. Population estimates ran well into the billions. It was grossly well established, continually pushing cogitator calculations on the age of the planet’s settled history further and further backwards, which therefore only increased the weight of the heresy standing them all in the face. Possibly over a thousand years, the world had been held in the throes of House Vandis, and it was frustratingly unknown at which point Chaos was introduced into the matter, or if even in fact it had been at the beginning.

“Do we have anything on Vandis himself?” Colonel Gabriel Derosa asked.

“Oh, plenty,” Admiral Graves rolled his eyes. “Have a listen from what our probes have picked up.”

There was a click, and then the hateful voice of Vandis himself could be heard by all, just as it had when they first entered the blasted system.

“Beloved brothers and sisters, the enemy our family has been preparing against for generations has, finally, come for us all! Do not let yourselves falter before the Gods, however, for we have now been given the chance, the glorious opportunity, to prove ourselves before them! The traitors and chaff have been weeded out, and now only the strong remain! Only you, people of New Meridian, remain! Our mighty vessels wait in orbit to strike their battered and broken ships to scrap! Should any survive to make planetfall, our Vandian Legions are ready to tear them to pieces, prepared! In the name of the Dark Gods, hallowed be they, we-,”

Another click, the voice was gone.

“It goes on like that,” Graves said with a roll of his eyes. “Speeches upon speeches upon speeches. Exhorting the masters he has sold his eternal soul to. Praising his people. Decrying all others as weak or traitors. And so on. So far, as best we can tell, he’s holed up somewhere on the planet. Where, precisely, I cannot say.”

“Charming,” Adrastia said with a sniff. “And the planet’s defenses?”

“This fleet,” Gabriel forwarded the sensor records. “These orbital stations. Anti-orbital lasers, hive spire strength void shields. We had hoped that the toxic wastelands outside the main hives might be better, but the environment there is…severe.”

“I’ve reviewed them, the Chapter Master speaks the truth,” Gabriel Derosa said while shaking his head. “There are numerous anti-orbital defenses there as well, likely specifically in case one wished to attempt planetary bombardment or crust cracking away from the main hives.”

“The Blood Ravens were close to Meridian for a long time,” Justinius spoke up, his arms crossed, “I suspect this may well be because House Vandis knew what a response from a space marine Chapter might take the approach of.”

“Either that, or Exterminatus,” Admiral Graves replied, tapping a finger to his chin. “Could we not still try to deploy down there?”

“Only the space marines could survive in that environment, and while the scans are confused, I suspect there are more than void shield generators and anti-orbital emplacements down there,” Colonel Derosa shook his head.

“We have to take orbit first,” Gabriel declared, “After that, we can try to see to landing. Us Blood Ravens might manage to make landing, but we have several troop transports that cannot afford such aggressive behavior.”

“Fair enough,” Graves nodded. “The defense stations are somewhat spread out, but they're mostly concentrated over the two thirds of the planet that's hive, rather than the wasteland. We've got a little bit of time left before we hit the planet proper."

Auspex scans swiftly confirmed what the probes had hinted at before. The enemy fleet was not too large, not insurmountable by numbers alone, but it was far fresher than the vessels of the Imperials. They had loosely arranged themselves in front of the orbital shipyard, which looked capable of servicing only two cruisers at a time, or perhaps the Grand Cruiser the enemy possessed on its lonesome. Though it was smaller by far than the shipyard over Opus Maxima, it nevertheless weapon batteries of its own that could not be discounted.

New Meridian Orbital Defenses
1 Retaliator-class Grand Cruiser
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
2 Devastation-class Cruisers
10 Iconoclast Destroyer Escorts
10 Orbital Defense Stations (5 Laser, 5 Torpedo)
1 Small Orbital Shipyard

What Is Your Plan, Chapter Master? Choose One:
Moratorium 12 Hours
GM NOTE: You have 3 Rams, 6 Fire Ships, 1 Vortex Ship To Use At Your Discretion

[] Try To Remain At Range: Focus on using lances, attack craft, and the like to try and deal with the enemy ships at a distance, rather than risk getting in close.
[] Try To Close In: It may be punishing, but what ships are better at close range and danger than those of the space marines?
[] Try Something More Nuanced: Write-In

AND

[] Hold Back On Using Saharduin Ships
[] Use Saharduin Ships: Write-In Which Ships Go After Which Targets

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed]
SC Rage of Erudition
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+12 Codiciers, 10 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
37 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Minor Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 1/3)
4 Lunar-class Cruisers (Minor Damage)
5 Frigates (Minor Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

3 Saharduin Ram Ships
6 Saharduin Fire Ships
1 Saharduin Vortex Ship

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [Extremely Minor Casualties]

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Fourteen)

Spoiler: Plan: Scourge the Heretic and Cast Down His Works (Simpler Fire Ships and Avoiding Scuttling Charges Revision)

-[] Use Saharduin Ships: Write-In Which Ships Go After Which Targets
--[] 1 Fire Ship will lead to try to wipe out the first wave(s) of attack craft from the Devastation-classes and clear the way.
--[] 3 Ram Fireships target Shipyard.
--[] 1 Vortex Ship targets Retaliator-class Grand Cruiser, unless the Grand Cruiser is separate from the rest of the enemy fleet for some reason in which case it will target the center of the enemy fleet instead. Vortex Ship follows the Ram Ships in as the trailing member of their formation before letting them pull ahead to enact their mission without getting swallowed up in the detonation. However the key priority is ensuring a successful and effective detonation of the Vortex Ship, even if the Ram Ships get swallowed up in that too, so if there appears to be any serious risk to the Vortex Ship from waiting for them it should detonate right away instead.
--[] 2 Fire Ships will target the flanks of the enemy fleet formation (1 to each flank) as the Ram Ships and the Vortex Ship plunge into the middle of it, again prioritizing Cruisers, especially the Devastation-Classes.
--[] 3 Fire Ships are held back for targets of opportunity or later planetary bombardment if nothing sufficiently attractive presents itself.
-[] Try Something More Nuanced: the Strike Cruisers and Battle Barge will split from the Imperial Navy elements of the fleet.
--[] SCs, Battle Barge, and Adrastia's custom Vengeance-class Grand Cruiser will load up on void armsmen and inquisitorial stormtroopers again as we did when capturing the Saharduin ships, and will close in following the Saharduin ships being used as per above. The SCs will fire bombardment cannons at the orbital defense stations, prioritizing the Torpedo Defense stations. After whatever happens with the Ram/Vortex/Fire Ships they will assess the remaining targets and launch boarding operations, priority order on surviving enemy as follows: Retaliator-class Grand Cruiser, Lunar-class Cruisers, Devastation-class Cruisers, Small Orbital Shipyard, Laser Defense Stations. Priority for weapons fire is: Torpedo Defense Stations, Retaliator-class Grand Cruiser, Lunar-class Cruisers, Devastation-class Cruisers, Small Orbital Shipyard, Laser Defense Stations. Except that the Torpedo/Laser Defense Stations and the Shipyard (if it survives the Ram Ships with enough weapons to be threatening) will take immediate priority for bombardment cannon fire. The SCs and Battle Barge may pull away to merge with the rest of the fleet after disgorging boarders as may be advisable to preserve the ships.
--[] Imperial Navy and Blood Ravens escorts will hang back at long-to-medium range but will launch as many attack craft to accompany the SCs and Battle Barge, and to shoot down torpedoes etc. targeting the Saharduin ships (while "safe" to do so, i.e. it's not a suicide mission) as feasible. Priority will be given to defending the Vortex Ship out of the converted Saharduin ships being used.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

“God-Emperor watch over us as we strive through the void,” Graves intoned, his voice carried through the fleet-wide vox. “For we are his Imperial Navy, and we bring his fire through, to, and to surpass the darkness!”

Opposing them, the guardian fleet of New Meridian spread out, the blasphemous iconography scrawled across their hulls proudly on display. The very sight of them made Graves sick to his stomach. Some of those ships had surely had to have been built in some sacrilegious shipyard or another, perhaps in some of those in the very system they now fought to purge, but some were not so lucky. No, it was the others, though by now the corruption within and without made it impossible to tell, that had once been noble vessels of the Imperial Navy which infuriated him most. Who had faltered, there? The Mechanicus, in building them with some unforeseen faults in their Gellar generators? The lower deck crews, corrupted in the darkness there in their dreams? Or was it the officers themselves, they who should have been the stewards of their ships, not just in the matter of the body but of the soul? Some. None. All. It didn’t matter. The Imperial Guard here came from Meridian, and their grudge was plainly with those on the planet below. The Blood Ravens too, winnowed and a thimble of what they used to be, no doubt glared with gimlet eyes upon the current head of the disgraced traitor House of Vandis.

Personally, the Admiral didn’t particularly care about any of that, insomuch as he felt all the righteous hate and disgust for heretics and traitors in a general sense that any loyal man of the Emperor should.

But those ships?

Those…facsimiles of true vessels, those barges of corruption, those mirror falsehoods given steel and gun and engine?

“Absolutely disgusting,” he murmured to himself before straightening in his command throne. “All hands! Prepare for long range bombardment and continual salvos. I don’t want to see a single lance stop firing until I say so! Pilots, get to your ships, deck crews, ensure continual rotation!” He slammed a fist down onto the armrest. “I want every single one of those foul amalgams of metal and corruption destroyed!”

Engines flared, turrets rotated, and the Blood Ravens surged ahead as agreed upon beforehand, stuffed full of every additional armsmen available. The Saharduin ships, vile as they were, clustered within the Astartes naval formation.

===============================================================

Saharduin Vanguard: 48 vs. 53

The strike craft that boiled out of the Chaos ships crowded like insects before rushing forward, all four squadrons carried by each Devastation-class ship launched at once. Bombers and interceptors flew forward heedlessly, and whether it was because of their own speed or because of the slowness of transmission and follow through on the part of the slaved controls of the Saharduin ships, the first of the captured xeno ships erupted into a fireball of flames that only caught a small amount of them. Instead, the cloud of strike craft flew on, and immediately availed themselves upon the ships of the Blood Ravens and the Grand Cruiser of the Inquisitor Adrastia. Only a modicum of them struck at the Saharduin ships, the damage dealt non-negligible but non-fatal as well. The damage, however, threatened the continued functionality of the ships. It was not, of course, to say that the Imperial-controlled ships were defenseless. Automated point defenses activated and fired, joined by the more accurate and heavier fire from the Blood Raven ships and the Grand Cruiser that moved with them.

Up Close 1: 72 vs. 54
Long Range 1: 73 vs. 63

Both fleets shot past long and medium range at high speed, even as some of the Chaos vessels attempted to adjust their courses to remain distant. For all that they were crewed by heretics and madmen, the simple fact of the matter was that some of the enemy ships were less capable when it came to short range combat. This, of course, was precisely what the Imperials were counting on as they plunged directly into the enemy formation. The Devastation-class cruisers had allowed their peers to move forward, leaving them more safely behind and able to fire their lance arrays at will. All of this, however, was accomplished in the blink of an eye as bombardment shells landed on the static orbital defense arrays, weapons meant to crack planetary fortresses or destroy army formations instead erupting amidst the many tons of metal that made up the enemy defenses.

Saharduin Vanguard 2: 40 vs. 28
Ramming Effectiveness: 70

Perhaps it was this that allowed some of the Saharduin ships to slip away from the fierceness of the ongoing battle, the heavy plasma barrages by the Grand Cruiser so bright as to obscure the auspex with sensor bloom. Or perhaps it was the work of the Imperial Navy remaining at range with long range macrocannon and lance salvoes, their addition of their own strike craft to the ongoing battle ensuring that none of the enemy squadrons could be split off. Regardless, even as the defenses of the enemy shipyard came online. Defense laser blasts from the planet below shot upwards, striking the underside of the Saharduin ships, but though some of them were openly damaged, their engines were not. As such, all three managed to forge forward at full speed, burning fuel reserves and overloading reactors beyond safety levels to accomplish the last task they would ever perform.

They struck, in the end, like a barbed and heavy trident, digging deep and tearing through bulkheads and decks by simple virtue of weight and speed. The New Meridian shipyard was not the magnificent creation that had once hung over the now crumbling world of Opus Maxima, it was indeed smaller by far. Nevertheless, in order to service the defense fleet as well as regularly perform maintenance on the orbital stations there, it had been intended as a doughty strategic emplacement. That time, within approximately five minutes of the battle’s true beginning, was ended forever as it was shorn almost in half, with a mere scattering of piping and tortured sheets of metal keeping its pieces together. The Saharduin ships assigned to the task did not survive the impacts, their strained reactors detonating violently, which in turn set off those of the shipyard itself.

The resulting chain reaction was considerable, a sight that would have been visible from almost anywhere on New Meridian were it not for the toxic smog and clouds which clung to its upper atmosphere.

Up Close 2: 84 vs. 45
Long Range 2: 21 vs. 87
Flanking Ramming Effectiveness: 15
Vortex Ramming Effectiveness: 71
Warp Tear Consequences: 50

Torpedoes and physical munitions twisted through space, storms of fire erupting when they managed to strike true against hulls rather than erupting against void shields. The ships of the Blood Ravens never ceased moving, never ceased adjusting their positions, rotating upon the axis of their flight paths. The sheer intensity of the close-range fighting resulted in several frustrated gunners remaining at long range on the part of the Imperial Navy rapidly and continually having to readjust firing solutions or cancel fire missions outright. The shifting of the void battle meant that the risk of friendly fire was not only present but acted upon more than once to the detriment of those who were immediately hauled off of their consoles and places to be disciplined and replaced by others. The enemy ships, however, were far less caring about this, and so willingly burned holes through the hulls of some of their own ships in order to accomplish a strike upon one Imperial ship or another. A few metric tons of armor plating upon the Sword of Reckoning were blasted apart, the venerable Grand Cruiser somewhat more static in her positioning than the Blood Raven ships. This, however, was merely so that targeting solutions could be acted upon, and thus allow Battleship-grade plasma volleys to tear through void shields and into the ships beneath. Still, despite remaining back to reduce risk, it could not be avoided that further damage was dealt to the Imperial ships, a number of hangar decks of Admiral Graves’ vessel exploding and killing hundreds of operating crew and strike craft pilots. One frigate, unfortunately targeted by chance a significant number of the remaining orbital stations and some lance fire out of nothing more than momentary opportunity, was destroyed outright. Two of the remaining Saharduin ships mindlessly plowed into all of this, and exploded before reaching their destination, nothing more than large blooms of flame and scrap metal that momentarily were noted in auspex logs before being discarded.

All of which, however, was overshadowed by the impact of the last of the initially deployed Saharduin ships. Its Gellar fields had been shut off, life support disabled, reactor burning forward on a timer to go critical. The enemy Retaliator-class Grand Cruiser had focused its efforts on assaulting the more stationary Sword of Reckoning, its cursory fire towards the Saharduin ship almost destroying it regardless. However, what might have crippled a living ship could not end a revenant in time. When the warp drives overloaded, the resulting tear in the fabric of reality was visible to all. Even those who were not psykers could no avoid being affected. Whole platoons of armsmen fell to the ground mid-battle with blood pouring out of their ears at a sound they could not hear. Others felt a burning itch explode in the fatty tissues which preserved their organs, violent enough that they plunged knives and fingers into themselves to try and scratch it away, tearing their innards apart in the process. Some went deaf, blind, and dumb as neurological connections within their brains snapped. The resulting warp vortex swallowed not just the enemy flagship, but the two Devastator-class cruisers that had remained at its side.

It then continued to expand.

As shields fell and rose again, boarding torpedoes and assault rams speared into the thick hides of Chaos ships, flush to the point of being almost overburdened by void armsmen and handfuls of Blood Ravens here and there. On one of the enemy’s Lunar-class cruisers, Sergeant McKinna rammed her chainsword into the back of a gene-hound, the hulking cybernetic monstrosity screaming as she carved it in half. On another, the terminators of the Blood Ravens’ 1st Company stormed the bridge, assault cannons and storm bolters ending the lives of the crew there, mutilated, maddened, and half-absorbed into their consoles and stations as they were. The fighting was fierce as ever, and for all that no Chaos Space Marines were sighted, the enemy were nevertheless resisting mightily. More than one commander reported encountering platoons of the foe equipped entirely with Hellgun-pattern lasguns and plasma guns, as well as increasing numbers of the gene-hounds, in excess of those encountered up until that point. While preliminary studies of slain gene-hounds proved that the creatures could quite literally not live up past a year out of stasis due to the eventual fatal breakdown of their organic matter and over-spliced genetics mixed with steadily rejecting their forcibly grafted bionics, in that time they were proving considerably…difficult to manage. Something that hundreds of men and women of the Imperial Navy would come to fatally realize. In one substantially disturbing case, one pack of gene-hounds had the monstrous humanoids nearly overwhelm Sergeant Stromahn and his terminators, outright picking up and throwing the elites of the 1st Company about before they could be killed.

And then the remaining Lunar-class Cruisers were overtaken by the still expanding warp tear. Fifteen thousand void armsmen disappeared into the madness of the Warp, unable to evacuate a single soul after boarding the ships in the thirty seconds it took for the tear’s edges to reach them. The entirety of the deployed strike craft from all Imperial ships disappeared, only a small percentage of them managing to use their service weapons to kill themselves before the daemons could reach them. The other two Lunar-class ships were not spared. Sergeant McKinna could only watch as half of the enemy ship she was on disappeared into the Warp, then shrieked in terror as her mind broke from staring directly into the Warp shortly before she, Pavus, and the rest of her armsmen disappeared as the line between reality and Immaterium disappeared. Battle Brother Michael, one of the most recent promotions of the 10th Company given to the 5th, muttered a benediction of faith before the wave overtook him.

He lasted ten entire seconds in the Warp.

Most were lucky enough to die faster.

The minds of the Blood Ravens in command of the teleportariums were swift enough to begin immediate emergency recall, a benefit that could not be expanded to the many, many armsmen who had been sent forth on boarding torpedoes and assault rams. Most of the Blood Ravens were ripped away from the ships they had boarded swiftly enough, but not all. Brother Gelemon’s transponder signal disappeared as the wave swallowed the Lunar-cruiser he was on, having personally led a heroic effort to shut down the ship’s engines ensuring that he was closer to the warp tear’s expanding edge than any other. Brother Damian simply never returned from the warp, despite successfully being teleported off of the fourth and final Lunar-class approximately seven seconds before it too was overtaken. Meanwhile, engines burned at emergency speeds as the Blood Raven ships and the Sword of Reckoning desperately attempted to escape the still expanding warp tear. The enemy escorts attempted to do the same, but rather than try and avoid the certain destruction at their back, they forged forwards, firing all the while at the Imperial ships they were now interspersed with. Gellar fields flickered across every ship present, screeching in protest under pressures far in excess of what they had suffered up until that point. Crews reported hearing songs, sounds, cries of delight and rage, even voices that were of loved ones. Others swore they saw people who were meant to be dead back at their stations, including a crew chief who had died of a heart attack mere hours into the landing at Opus Maxima.

The warp tear’s expansion was unbridled, and entire shoals of lesser daemons numerous enough to be visible not by sensor array but by the naked eye when looking out of a view port spewed out of the Immaterium above New Meridian. The destroyed remnants of the enemy shipyard was taken, as were the remaining orbital stations and the wrecks of those that had been rendered nonfunctional. The whole of the Imperial fleet was forced to perform blisteringly rapid turns and burn their engines at full, redlining reactors simply in order to remain ahead of it. Hundreds of thousands of winged half-malformed things screeched and cackled at feeling the light of the star upon their newly summoned flesh. Many dissipated immediately afterwards from a lack of sustaining possibilities, but many other did not. The fleeing souls running away were escaping, yes, and had fields to protect them, yes, but there were others who could not do so. And so they descended to the planet beneath, its billion inhabitants long having invited the darkness into their souls, for they knew no other path. Summoning arrays in the hive spires meant for the personal usage of the nobility there activated in tandem, then shattered as they were overloaded from the other side, geysers of daemons exploding in the upper levels. Below, shrines to the Dark Gods covered in filth and grime by the commoners who slaved there glowed so bright as to scorch eyeballs from the sockets, and the corpse fields began to shift and move with glorious decaying unlife. The Vandian Legions responded accordingly, sorcerers and practitioners working as swiftly as they could even as weapons fire began to light up across the entire hive.

The Imperial Navy, on the other hand, had something else to deal with entirely, even as alarms began to blare about Gellar overloads.

Hunter Striking Prey: 16 vs. 85

Unseen by all, utilizing speeds and stealth not meant to be possible on vessels of such size, the Warsphere had arrived at the rear of the battlefield. Its own warp travel had been missed as the warp tear roiled in place, and by the time the fleeing ships of Admiral Graves and the Blood Ravens had realized it, the troop ships had already made the desperate decision to fly forwards as swiftly as possible, forced in turn to place the enormous warp tear at their backs so that the Imperial ships could guard them from the Warsphere. There was no proclamation of battle, no announcements, no braying calls from the xenos, contrary to usual assumptions of Slaaneshi worshippers. But then, the hunter did their level best to not announce themselves to the prey, if one was in search of the absolute most perfect hunt. The moment the Imperial ships came into range, they opened fire, tearing the shields from one of the remaining Lunar-class cruisers in but a few seconds before the ship itself was shot to pieces.

“Redeploy, redeploy!” Graves was shouting on his bridge, sweat soaking his brow as he thought furiously to himself.

“All ships, drive forward, beat that Warsphere back!” Chapter Master Angelos boomed in the chapter-wide vox.

Rapid Redeployment: 72 vs. 79

To the credit of the captains present, they did not hesitate before following their orders. Gellar warnings screamed of incursions, hundreds fought to ignore the words being whispered in their minds as priests shouted out their litanies of faith and protection, reactors burning and shuddering, engines noting warnings of damage from strain, and yet they did not fail to spread out in protective formations. The frigates, undamaged due to remaining at range and able to swiftly turn and maneuver, fired what weapons they could. Torpedoes launched in single concerted arrays, striking at the massive target waiting in front of them. The Kroot Warsphere, in turn, responded with its own massive weapon banks, striking half a dozen ships simultaneously, shattering shields and breaking armor plating in the same moments. The already battered Litany of Fury suffered once more, a great many holes punched into her already riddled hide. The battle barge now trailed fire from so many points on its hull that the number of lights eclipsed that of its engines.

The Warsphere: 65 vs. 46
Fireship Ramming: 74

Perhaps it was providence that the remaining Saharduin ships had not been utilized until that point. They had remained behind with the troops transports, and despite the slowness in response to orders transmitted to their slaved systems, had managed to escape the warp tear. The Warsphere, for all of its sheer amount of armament, was glutted for targets. The hardened ships of the Blood Ravens, the now thoroughly battered Sword of Reckoning, and the ever fewer ships remaining under the command of Admiral Graves – who by that point was contemplating just how low he might be struck in rank for the loss of so many ships – filled the targeting arrays of the slavering Kroot. Just which prize might be best to take and display? Which was filled with the best prey, ones that might be let loose to run in the corridors before the hunters could bring them down? Or, perhaps, to the maddened aliens, it would be better to grant the prey the homefield advantage, and instead disable engines and reactors, letting them choose between choking as the air turned stale and empty or dying at their hands?

Such contemplations were ended in fire as all three remaining Saharduin ships impacted into their vessel. All three struck the very center, the first managing to cause a break in the void shields, the second penetrating into the hull before letting loose its fire, and the third going even further. Within moments, an ocean of fire spread into both port and starboard halves of the ship. Kroot burned and died before they could even realize what was happening. Oxygen, that glorious fuel, fed the fire further, the open corridors, vegetation, and cattle compartments providing much to the flame. What had been an implacable foe that was in danger of destroying the entire fleet stuttered and outright halted in its movements, weapons ceasing fire in multiple sections due to the crews being vaporized in fire. All the while, the Imperials had not been idle, firing with all weapons available, managing two more torpedo volleys from all ships before the Warsphere was reduced to a floating hulk, with perhaps only a few hundred Kroot left alive in certain sealed compartments.

Finally, for the briefest of moments, there was time enough to pause and reassess.

================================================

“Let’s agree, here and now, to not do that again,” Graves wiped at his face as the hololith flickered to life. “Ever, preferably.”

In the background, mechadendrites twitching nervously, the Magos of his flagship that had come up with the idea of a ship-sized vortex bomb stood.

“The yield of the vessel’s explosion was estimated-,” they began, vocoder scratchy.

“IN THE EMPEROR’S NAME I DO NOT WANT TO HEAR IT!” He bellowed at them, sending the servant of the Omnissiah scuttling away.

“Admiral…,” Gabriel paused as Graves held up a hand.

“Chapter Master Angelos, I have just lost every one of my pilots who was not in the middle of refueling and rearming,” the Admiral sighed before he sat back heavily in his command throne. “Where before we were overburdened with those souls we managed to save from other ships, we now don’t even have enough to patrol the corridors.”

Gabriel bowed his head in acknowledgement.

“Not all were lost, Admiral. Many remained yet to be sent forth in boarding actions, but I do regret the losses taken,” he eventually said. “I can have the remainder transferred back to your ships immediately.”

“I…yes, do it,” Graves briefly drew his hand down his face. “Now I’m being told that the Warp is even more chaotic than before. As if I needed the astropaths to come scream at me about it, what with the bloody miniature warp storm we made right bloody there.”

Only then did the Chief Librarian speak up, limping slightly from where a daemonic manifestation had attempted to tear his leg off, thin tracks of dried blood marking where it had come weeping out of his eyes and ears.

“It is a bittersweet thing, but it is the opinion of myself and the Librarium that the warp tear will, is, already beginning to recede slightly. It is not being sustained by any ritual or sacrifice, and given that it has taken much not just from us but the forces of Vandis, they may well not wish it present either."

Graves simply raised an eyebrow before turning back to Gabriel.

"Will the Inquisitor be joining us? She no doubt lost a few of her stormtroopers as well."

As if summoned by his words, the image flickered to life, revealing Captain Carlyle, who despite the damage sustained by her ship seemed unaffected.

"The Inquisitor is recovering after her implant surgery was interrupted," she began promptly, looking all three of them in the eye one after another. "A daemon manifested in the operating theater, seeking to slay her."

"Is Adrastia," Gabriel began rapidly before the Captain shook her head.

"The Inquisitor had only just taken the anesthesia, and retained enough mental focus to summon her powers forth and banish it. The strain, however, has rendered her unconscious for a longer period than initially assumed. With the Colonel taken by the Warp along with a third of our available stormtrooper regiment, I am temporarily in total command of all Inquisitorial forces present."

It was the longest sentence that they'd heard the woman speak, the tone drier than the deserts of Calderis.

"I'd say I'm sorry for your losses, if I thought you'd appreciate it," Graves huffed.

"The only things certain in life are death and the Emperor," Carlyle gave the barest of shrugs. "What are our next steps?"

"Well," Graves sighed as he listened to someone on his bridge, "Defending ourselves again, it seems."

"Oh?"

"Sensor reports show that the defense fleet over Runao is on the move. They're ragged, and no doubt their little geas' are tearing their minds apart, but they're coming towards us regardless," he said with remarkable calm. "I'm sure Vandis called them up in a panic."

Ten defense monitors. Each quite possible equal to a cruiser in armament, speed, and strength.

"Hmm. This is unwelcome news," Carlyle said with slightly narrowed eyes. "The Sword of Reckoning has taken moderate damage to prow sections, many point defenses are gone. We retain shields, plasma batteries, and engines, however. Blood Raven, the condition of your ships?" She asked, turning to Gabriel's projected image on her deck.

Gabriel bowed his head for a moment before looking back up.

"The Litany of Fury is dangerously close to being rendered inoperative for combat purposes, but our strike cruisers and escorts can yet fight."

"Admiral?"

"I lost another two bloody ships, but those of us that remain still have a few lances here and there," the man grunted.

"Then our course is clear," Carlyle stated calmly, "We must move to intercept them before they can even begin to potentially be a threat to the troop transports, while allowing them to follow us so that they are more distant from the warp tear. Unless," she blinked once, "One of you has a better idea?"

"I'm for it," Graves flapped a hand at the air, "Angelos?"

Decision, Chapter Master?:
Moratorium 3 Hours

[] Carlyle's Plan: Advance in strength and try to overtake the defense monitors. Their weapons are dangerous, yes, but their crews are guaranteed to be operating under less than optimal conditions.
[] Something Else: Write-In [Subject To Graves/Caryle Agreements]

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury [Minor Damage]
1 Gladius
1 Hunter Destroyer
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed, Shield Arrays At 15%, Extreme Hull Damage] DANGER: Litany of Fury will require significant attentions at a Mechanicus Shipyard for repairs. Any notable damage may disable ship in permanency.
SC Rage of Erudition [Minor Damage]
SC The Great Father’s Fist
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova)

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+12 Codiciers, 10 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
37 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (+2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (+18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (+50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (+10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)
3 5th Company Marines (6 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 90%)
3 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
4 Frigates (Minor Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

All Void Armsmen Utilized In Boarding Lost (Remaining Void Armsmen Now Depleted To Severely Understrength Levels)

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [1/3 Casualties Sustained]

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified) (Minor Damage)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
6 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

100,000~ New Meridian Vandian Stormtroopers
1,000,000~ New Meridian Vandian Guard
5,000,000~ New Meridian Conscripts
10,000,000~ New Meridian Menials
500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Grand Hunter Hraxe, Slaaneshi Alien Warlord
Admiral Maximilian Vandis, New Meridian Defense Fleet Commander
New Meridian Defense Defense Fleet: Estimated Crews At 10,000,000 (Including All Ships, Orbital Stations, Shipyard)
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Masters of Forge-Hives, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

050.M42 Interlude: A Tide Of Pain And Pleasure

GM NOTE: Just realized I never posted this. Welp, here's some retroactive content.

050.M42 Interlude: A Tide Of Pain And Pleasure

A black sun blazed with light, almost seeming to scream as it was dragged downwards into the infinite tide of flesh and emotion. Millions perished, an entire swathe of cityscape was burnt to ashes and beyond, before the sun itself began to flicker and die. Not through any natural means, but by those who followed no laws but their own. Once ripped from its celestial cradle, the burning half-light that it had emitted since its capture began to ripple and gutter out. A great and raucous laugh went up, audible to all, sparking terror and a thousand other unknowable emotions to flutter through even the most deadened of hearts. A swarm of daemons strong enough in number to overrun entire worlds appeared from thin air with nothing but the crackle of lightning to herald their arrival. Such was their gorging hunger, their gluttonous desire, that the sun itself and all the power it once held and still gave out was eaten away. Reality itself died as the daemons feasted, dark and unknowable things from the darkest depths of the immaterium itself.

It was not the first of the Ilmaea to die, and it would not be the last. It’s capture array fell soon after, from where it had been used first to capture the dying orb in the long distant past and now used against the foe. Another section disappeared completely beneath the tide, its defenders screaming in terror as they were dragged back and away to horrific fates that even the most labyrinthine minds could not imagine. Some of the most malicious and terrible Haemonculi screamed with honest terror they had not felt for thousands of years as they were dragged beneath the tide. Stoic incubi who had fought since the birth of the Dark City itself died screaming to the delight of their killers. Hellions, who had once ruled those streets and great spires alike, darted ever higher and higher, no longer willing to even chance dipping low enough to be caught despite the roared commands of a hundred and more Archons.

Another sub-realm burst, squeezed from all sides as a child’s delight in crushing insects, killing some and dooming more as the Warp throttled the untouched space within. An ocean rushed forth again and again, filling gaps and spaces that had been bereft of its touch for far too long. Slave and master alike died, as multiple cables connecting to the greater mass were taken and corrupted, those who had welcomed the new territory in the past now being taken away for their folly and ambition. A city the size of a realspace Craftworld which had in the past carefully swept back and forth within its own subrealm was abruptly surrounded by shoals of daemons and their masters, great sonic cannons formed out of entire dead species’ bones firing to bring it low into the waiting grasp of the warp.

That too, might have been avoided, for none were as paranoid and focused on preparation for the oncoming death which attempted to grasp all as the masters of this place. But they had been betrayed from within, as once before, now again. In the past, Nurgle had managed to corrupt and sway a great many of the shadow-eaters, the monstrous half-life bearing mandrakes. They had been broken once, and perhaps some thought they might be broken again. Save that this time the new god they had sworn to had supported them greatly for their aid in breaking that barrier which had in the past prevented all of this and more. It showed on them already, the sharpening of their features, the appearance of mottling flesh which showed scintillating shades of shadow in a reversal of a kaleidoscope. They owned their own realm, now, it was said, a great and terrible section of the depths they had once been forced into now transformed into a gateway in and of itself to the realm of their kind. Kheradruakh ruled there, it was whispered, from a throne of darkness and flesh piled atop and melded with one another. In his chest was engraved the symbol of his new God, one he worshipped heartily. The corruption was welcomed in, and yet in turn he was no mere container to be devoured from within. He had become…more. The first and perhaps only of his kind to ascend, and yet he was still served by strange daemon-things which every day more mandrakes seemed to be becoming.

A fourth of Commorragh, Vect could see from his dreadnought which hung at the ‘highest’ point remaining, was completely in the grasp of the warp. Vast portions of bone and steel were twisting even now, to the naked eye, into shapes and symbols that only emphasized the one who had come to take his due. Another sub-realm, he saw on one screen, blinked frantically more and more before finally winking out entirely. The vast web of knowledge and connections, marked by the most sophisticated of indicators that could be crafted, all of which had been needed to make a map in real time that only one such as he could possibly comprehend without going mad. He silently acknowledged the arrival of a new bevy of ships, one more Kabal, which had fallen to shocked stillness at the sight of the Dark City’s state, and ordered them forth. They would serve or die. By this point, he knew to his vast displeasure that at least part of it was motivated not by fear of him, but by the most simplistic of prides. How dare any infringe upon the eternal sovereignty of Commorragh? It was meant to be inviolate from everyone and everything.

Another two sub-realms began blinking in frequency, their codes and signals given meaning more than they knew. Without a sliver of mercy or hesitation in his heart, he swept a hand across the console, and consigned them to oblivion through yet another deliberately triggered the collapse of those places. For one, it worked, for the other, the minor dysjunction had already gone too far, and added its quaking ripples across he Webway to join with what was already going on in the depths of his city. He did not bother wasting the breath on cursing the infantile pride of the Kabal who had waited too long, and thus now had allowed another great burst of warp energies to be added to what was already present, heralded by another vast legion of daemons coming into being.

Weapons to shatter solar systems, shatter sectors, had been unleashed without a care once the daemons had managed to force their way up through half of the Dark City, and yet they were replenished with ease. How could they not, when the greatest dysjunction to have ever been suffered was occurring? If was almost a daemonworld in concept, but more than that as well, the combined misery, pain, and delirious pleasures that had been felt and teased out with ever greater concentrations since the Fall itself long having soaked into the very foundations. The daemons fed on that, fed on the legacy of the eldar, as easily as they did upon the souls of the eldar. Even now, the shattered remains of lesser Kabal strongholds were being rebuilt as new bastions for their new masters.

Then, then he felt it. Everyone could. Ten million slaves felt it, across all of the Dark City and its remaining sub-realms, some dying instantly, others screaming in fear, others for salvation. One who had first arrived, breaking through Khaine’s Gate from one side while traitorous mandrakes shattered the other, and then disappeared again into the morass heedless of any tactical sense in favor of pleasure seeking. And it had found it, in every iota, every minute section, every breath of puffed air which had become charged over millennia with combined pain and pleasure of truly inhuman heights. Yet now, its mercurial attentions shifted once more, and Vect grit his teeth hard enough to crack them as he felt its presence rise up and gather itself once more from where it had once dispersed.

A vast serpent rose from the sea of warp and daemon, letting loose a shrill laugh from six thousand throats. Some had formed inside its very mouth, others in the air, others upon its great snaking length. Six great arms, pulsing with power and perfect musculature that had grown and looped in and on itself in a never-ending display of perfection given over to insane excess, flexed and twitched. Blades held in each flickered in shape, from one design to another, never staying the same for longer than a moment, each the most desirous of its kind to have ever been seen. A thousand of the most veteran incubi fell to their knees before it, and died in supplication, swept away with their souls devoured with happy glee. Others fought, and died just as well with just as much happiness on its twisting and flickering face.

At its feet, attendant insects all, came a Legion unified. It was not the first to do so, no, for that had been the masterful acts of another who had done so, but it was no less horrifying to see. At their forefront, Lucius the Eternal danced amongst the blades who had up until that point never faced an equal. Telemachon Lyras, thought dead a dozen times over, had been found again leading a warband of mutants and what remained of his warband. Julius Kaesoron, a Daemon Prince himself, was nothing but a speck compared to the one he served with unrelenting delirium. All of them served, for glory in the eyes of their god but more importantly for the pleasures that had awaited them. Supping from the cask which the Dark Eldar had been maturing since the Fall was – for most – the most wondrous of excesses in existence. They could not have stopped even if they wanted to, which they never would. How could they, when their master had returned?

The Daemon Primarch Fulgrim screamed in pleasure, shattering a morass of eardrums and stopping hearts alike, and shifted forward in the blink of an eye. The remaining shards of Khaine’s Gate, even now, had been churlishly transformed into a massive talisman hung along the daemon primarch’s chest, mocking Vect even now. Fulgrim had never spoken once, throughout his relentless and never-ending pounding against the Gate from the side of the immaterium, yet his thoughts had been easily heard. If one had managed to journey down to the epicenter of the gargantuan rift which even now grew further, they would see the words engraved in the shattered remains of stone and bone there. ‘Let us in’, the mad and insane had chanted to their deaths, sheer proximity being more than enough. ‘Let us in’. The mandrakes had, and everything had changed.

An entire shoal of hellions, led by Baron Sathonyx, died as they tried to flee. Some were thrown into Fulgrim’s great maw, others to his reunited legion to do with as they pleased. A ship was torn apart as the serpent coiled around it and squeezed. It was uncaring of the forces unleashed upon it, even some from Vect’s own dreadnought, despite the destruction being enough otherwise to break entire fleets of other such ships. Perhaps, in realspace itself, it might have been different, but the dysjunction had been more than enough that the warp itself surged in response and was greedily consumed by the great daemon to heal their wound. Even if it hadn’t, there was no sign of pain from Fulgrim as he withstood the wounds with glee at the new experiences offered to him.

“Your bastions remained unbreached, oh Supreme Overlord,” came the toneless voice of a harlequin. “As ever, we would ask that you retreat to them, and leave this doomed place to its fate.”

Vect had not seen it enter, nor would he likely see it leave. But he certainly saw it now, and felt his already flaring hatred grow further at the sight of its masque. A curled lip, a sardonic and mocking expression given unto it, in worship and symbol of their precious Laughing God. Whatever expression the harlequin held beneath it, he would never know. Still, he turned, and loomed over the shorter eldar, and snarled. His hand shot out, and wrapped around its neck, squeezing lightly. Any other would be dead as they made the motion, yet for a wonder the harlequin, no, the solitaire, let him. As was befitting his power and status, and yet…

He released the solitaire, and let their feet touch the ground once more without a sound.

“Why are you here. I have a war to win,” he said calmly.

“You cannot. The moment the daemon primarch broke Khaine’s Gate, the greater portion of Commorragh was surely lost, Vect,” the solitaire replied tonelessly. “He leads a re-unified Legion, diminished though it is by its insanities. He brought the lost Craftworld of Kher-Ys here, and even now it drifts from sub-realm to sub-realm. The fleet of the corrupted monkeigh Miriael Sabathiel has broken the fleet of Kabal after Kabal. You. Cannot. Win.”

Vect twitched and smashed a hand into a cowering slave nearby, breathing in the pain as a desperate drink as the child died. A noise rumbled through his chest as he turned upon the solitaire, openly brandishing his scepter. The solitaire, in turn, did not react at all.

“Do you think me a fool, slave of the Laughing God?” Vect sneered and turned away from the ongoing apocalypse. “That I cannot see your machinations? Leave me be and return to skulking in the shadow of our failed pantheon, to beg for scraps and favor from that empty well. I, and Comorragh, are not so weak.”

The solitaire stiffened and then stepped away.

“If you are certain in victory,” it bowed slightly, “Then we shall leave you to your course.”

And then it was gone.

Vect scoffed and turned back to the console and the running of a battle across the whole of the Dark City and beyond, banishing the thoughts the solitaire had tried to implant behind.

“I have not yet begun to fight,” he whispered, eyes burning with hatred as he stared unflinching at the daemonic tide. “Commorragh is eternal,” he sneered before keying up several preplanned messages to be sent out. “

A single press of a finger was all it took to order two dozen of the larger Kabals to move. Enough power to threaten minor stellar nations, to inspire nightmares in billions, all with the single tap of his finger. A near negligible act of his will. Slaves, spoils, riches, all would be needed to fuel the defense. And he would have it, one way or another. The lesser races of the galaxy were too embroiled in conflict with one another to stop any of them, in any case.

070.M42 Interlude: Green Sparks

070.M42 Interlude: Green Sparks

Their wildest projections had not possibly prepared them for this. Their most advanced, most masterful, most powerful defenses had not been built with what they faced in mind. How could they have been? How could they have possibly have been capable of such a thing? Their greatest minds, their most powerful intelligences, their greatest military forces, had all been prepared and geared towards other things. To shift as they had been thrust unto was not impossible, of course, not at all, but the speed and organization required was not capable of being willed into existence despite how desperately some of them might have wished it to be so. Some realized, in the moments before their mightiest and most thorough defenses were overwhelmed, that it might even have been arrogance. Something that they would never have otherwise ever suggested that their people could possibly have possessed compared to all those elsewhere in the galaxy. Not them, surely? Surely not.

Yet they came. They came on and on and on. Previously destroyed foes, thought to have been near exterminated, had returned, flush in strength and numbers that had plainly been impossible. Or so it was thought of at first by so many. It was mind-boggling, it was something that had far more demanding that their own sensor systems be triple-checked for errors, that those who had come in ships that were barely capable of making the trip to supposed safety be questioned again for surely they were lying or were delusional. The grand edifice of believed security and safety that had been built up since the beginning of their civilization was being stomped down with uncaring brutality and as the first of the fires began to become blazing pyres to millions they still struggled to comprehend that very fact. How could they be drowned in such, when they had risen above the tide again and again?

When it came, many had pointed wildly too-long-laughed at surveillance and espionage reports which had stated the utterly laughable and simply impossible, that the Imperium which had always and clearly overstated its strength and power, would be possible of putting the whole of them to the torch with but a single one of their precious and oh so vaunted ‘Crusades’. But they had crushed such things before, had they not? Thus, lies, all lies. Foolish and preposterous propaganda that they likely told their poor unwashed masses who had not seen the greater truths. But this was not them, not them at all. Even worse, it was a foe that they had fought and won against before. The shattered remains of their remarkably well pronounced Empire of Aslanta were proof enough, were they not? Had not vast swathes of them gone west, deep into the supposed territories of the Imperium?

But then their sensors had begun to shudder, their latest and furthest out perimeter stations had begun to spark and squeal as emanations of those strange forces that they had just barely begun to understand yet were by now somewhat aware of rippled through the void. From the galactic north and west and south they had come, and of Fi'rios which had become a true fortress world after so desperately wresting it from its former brutish master, there was only the screams and garbled reports of simplistic yet utter devastation. Of so many bodies that roared their way into every gun pointed in their direction that it was not the tide that shrank back but instead of their own weapons fired unto the point of overheating and failure before the wielders were hacked limb from limb and in some cases openly devoured. Then those cameras that remained after the initial chaotic landings either by mechanical systems or those who held them were destroyed as well.

At first, they had thought they could battle and win like they had so many times in the past barring a smattering of failures and setbacks. Fleets were redirected, yet in the beginning they had not yet pulled back from their farthest ranges and most distant conquest efforts. Why would they? The threat would surely be contained and pushed back. It had always been done so before, what could have changed by now? Such thoughts were ash, as the solar years passed over. The first fleets killed so many more than their own number yet were simply ground down and away. So more were recalled, and then more, and then finally as the true scope of the threat was finally comprehended by their leaders the entire whole of their military drew back from every other purpose. Vast sums were desperately promised to their allies to come to their aid, and so they came as well.

It amounted, to their mounting horror, to almost nothing.

====================================================

Atop a shattered Riptide did stand a monstrous pile of blades and spinning hacksaws that stuck out at wild angles in all directions. Barely any of the actual meat of the one within could be seen, save for a thin strip of flesh and maddened red eyes. Around him over a dozen cadres lay dead, their corpses and technologies being looted for meat and bits that those of their kind who could somehow comprehend a use for them while the last screaming colonists were torn apart by being liberally thrown onto its body for sport. With one titanic foot did he stomp down upon the once fine but now soot and blood soaked robes of the one who had attempted to beg for surrender to save all of the peoples under her protection. An entire continent set aflame around him, hundreds of thousands of tons of promethium setting the ground, the seas, the very atmosphere alight in places.

“Don’t you’ze get it! Are you’ze dumb?! Are you’ze all idiots!? AH’M DA ARCH-ARSONIST OF CHARADON! DERE AIN’T NO SURRENDERS!”

He then spat, and grunted slightly as he luxuriated in the feel of more blood being sprayed across him as the fire caste warrior was shredded limb from limb by his armor.

“Oh just them shadow beakies and ‘ard deff boys wait until we get the gubbins we’ze need to go after ‘em again.”

=========================================================

“I’ze GORBAD! GORBAD!! You fink dat we’ze nuffin just cuz me world got gotten by dem buggies?! Well NUFFIN DOIN DIS WORLD IS MINE NOW! Cause dem’ deff boyz and dem beakies is gonna regret not killin ‘me!”

The harsh voice screamed into their minds from thousands of rusty speakers that had been dropped or installed at random across the planet as they were hunted down by cackling parties of buggy riders. Ramshackle vehicles exploded as they ran into mines left behind by the retreating fire caste, each other, buildings, and more. They cared little, even as meks ran rampant and happily harvested the many, many ‘shiny bits’ for their own gear and technologies if they could be called such from across the planet. From broken and rent star ships above which had come first to defend and then desperately evacuate was even more pulled. High above, a space hulk spat more and more of its innards onto the planet, while throughout the entire star system did more ships do the same as orbital stations were alternatively taken over, looted, destroyed, or any order of such again and again.

“Da Prophet said dat I could do dat, roight?” the voice came again, though clearly not meant for all those listening and more because the speaker had clearly just not gone through the effort of turning the system off.

If they had even known how in the first place.

“He said I cud take dere worlds? Right? Yeah! YEAH!”

=====================================================

Hive Fleet Leviathan swarmed the Realm of Ultramar, as it had in the past. But unlike before, the veterans of the Tyrannic War were there. Unlike before, significant numbers of not just Ultramarine successors but many other astartes had come, putting themselves under the battlefield command of the Chapter Master Marneus Calgar. The revitalized Raven Guard, and those of Segmentum Tempestus not enforcing the cordon around the still embattled territories being fought over by the Maynarkh Dynasty of Necrons and the remains of the so-called Great WAAAGH!!!, had come as well. Thus, though the Eldar had ensured that Leviathan would be drawn away from Ulthwe and instead towards Octarius and Ultramar, the Imperium was not without its own strength. From Ryza, freed from the predations of WAAAGH!! Urgok as they had fallen behind Ghazghkull in attacking Deliverance, came legions of Skitarii and tanks. From Catachan, multiple regiments of their most elite troops who had fought tyranids in close combat and survived, a feat even some space marines could not claim. More, and more. The tyranids, vile as they were, continued to adapt to those changing circumstances, ensuring a rolling wave of destruction and warfare was spread throughout Ultramar, but for all of that…

There were only minor reports of greenskins within that conflagration of conflict.

=============================================================

“Uh…sorry boss, I dun geddit. They'ze just humies!”

The sparking flame-ridden power klaw of the Prophet snapped out and closed around the nob’s torso, large enough to cut them to pieces with just the faintest application of force. But, even as the skin began to catch flame, the nob did not wriggle in that terrible grip, lest it’s master deem to finish the act.

“I don’ care if you geddit,” Ghazghkull rumbled, his hot breath almost scorching as spittle dripped down his maw. “The buggies and the humies are foightin’, meanin’ they’re busy with dat scrap. But what we need, da boyz need, is new flash and new gubbins since they let themselves get thumped before. And I ain’t fought no Tau boyz before. S’called a win-win, ya grot. So!”

The power klaw closed, tearing the lesser warboss apart and then twitched, one point tapping an inch into the chest of another nob.

“You’ze in charge o dem boyz now, Zagrop, and iffin I hear of you’ze leading a raid on humie areas instead’a’my orderz, you’ze gonna die next! Got it!?”

“Uh, yes boss!”

"'Sides, we ain't gonna be here forever. Dere is plenty other foights ta get ter, and I ain't plannin' on missing out."

==================================================================

In the end, the Fourth Sphere Expansion died not at the hands of the Imperium, nor from the machinations of Chaos, neither the byzantine manipulations of the Eldar, nor cold calculations of the Necron, but by the sheer and unbridled brutality of the greenskins. Flags newly planted were burned down or used as loincloths or scraps. Tens of millions of settlers from a number of races under the auspices of the Tau Empire died. Even some of the worlds taken, settled, and fortified in the Third Sphere were torn, bloodily, from the grip of the Tau. Troves of technology, of ‘gubbinz’, of wiring, were ripped from battlesuits, from tanks, from starships, from the very cities themselves, all for the benefit of the greenskins and their meks. On over a dozen worlds, new ships, new factories, new gargants were being built.

He had fought his way free of Deliverance. Had crushed the Deathmarks that the Maynarkh Dynasty had sent after him. Had barely even been aware of the killing of a dozen Vindicare by kommandos, had stomped the Callidus that close enough into paste, and had happily torn apart the Eversors that he allowed to get close. With his own jaws, he had bitten the Lictors sent after him apart. The daemons had been fun, for a time, even. It had taken decades for the Great WAAAAGH!! to finally collapse, but it had.

However.

There yet remained many, many orks left in the galaxy.

And the Prophet still lived.

And so long as he did, he would never stop preaching for unending war.

=============================================================

Over Armageddon, a terribly battered Gloriana-class battleship tore out of the warp. It bore heavy damage in almost every section, entire decks crushed under some unknown impacts, and there were even marks of claws that must have been kilometers long that had scored its hull.

"I...I don't believe it. By the God-Emperor, we're free! I...wait, distress hymnals in all directions, we're...we've reached Armageddon, but...,"

"Synching chronos with outbound signals...,"

"Speak, Tech-Marine."

"I..."

On the deck of the Eternal Crusader, High Marshal Helbrecht and Comissar Yarrick stared down at the wasteland that had become more than a third of Armageddon. Below, oceans of greenskins boiled and fought against the Imperial defenders. Even now, despite their new arrival, they were receiving both hails and broadcast insults and threats from Imperial and greenskin ships respectively.

"It has been decades, High Marshal. Decades."

070.M42 Interlude: Burning Red, Burnished Gold

070.M42 Interlude: Burning Red, Burnished Gold

Subiaco Diablo was lost. The simple fact of the matter was that, regardless of the sacrifices of the Convent of the Ermine Mantle, and the celebrated Canoness Astra of the Adeptas Sororitas who had reinforced them, the world was indefinitely irrecoverable. Half of it had become overwhelmed by the Warp, and an endless tide of daemons born of the Blood God marched across its surface. They, in turn, met and fought against the twisted splinter of Hive Fleet Leviathan which had become so malformed after their travails within the warp. Imperial observers were unable to get close, and the eyes of others were far busier scrying other things that mattered more. In the end, only the Gods would know what occurred in that place. The Gods, and those that served them.

For upon a mound of corpses that could have dwarfed the lost Himalazian Mountains of Terra in its scope, dripping an ocean’s worth of alien blood into the battle-wracked earth, did the Red Angel stand. His campaign of slaughter had been long, and bloody, and the splinter fleet had never actually managed to manifest feeder tendrils. Instead, all biomass had been put towards combatting the daemons of Khorne, enough biomass to take entire Imperial sectors thrown into the charnel pits. For all of that, however, they scored victories. Blasts of bio-plasma launched by titan-sized aliens wiped out hundreds of Bloodletters, Lictors and Warriors clashing and coming out victorious over juggernauts. The psychic blasts of zoanthropes proved most effective indeed, scorching the landscape in the Materium and in the Warp simultaneously.

To those who had once attempted to hold there, to the thousand Sisters of Battle that had long ago died, it had seemed a hellscape of unimaginable proportions. A world half-eaten, half-possessed, fallen in every way that mattered and more. Perhaps it would have been even more incongruous for them to have seen the Daemon Primarch of the World Eaters Legion, the Traitorous Son, the Red Angel, stand in silence and without motion save for releasing approximations of slow steady breaths that in form were far closer to toxic furnace heat released in gusts than anything else. His enormous weapons dug into the corpses beneath him, grips tight but arms held remarkably loosely at his sides. Before Angron, shying away as it bled from a hundred wounds, was none other than the legendary Swarmlord, an increasingly infamous and monstrously powerful tyranid bio-form.

Below, a tide of tyranids met a tide of daemons, but upon that mountain of the dead the two champions stood alone.

Or, at, least, they seemed to.

“I see you there,” Angron chuckled deeply, the rumbles of his bloodstained amusement enough to crack the sanity of most mortals had they heard it.

The Swarmlord reeled before charging forward over metric tons of chitin and dead flesh, boneswords swinging at speeds even most space marines would struggle to perceive properly. It amounted to little as Angron deflected each blow without shifting his stance, his wings barely even twitching, the winds caused by so much movement rattling the metallic tendrils that ran from his head.

“Did you think us unaware?” The daemon hissed, knocking the Swarmlord back once more. “Every daemon slain, every soul taken, every essence absorbed!”

Twin beams of searing red fury made physically manifest out of naught but hatred shot from Angron’s eyes, digging deep cauterized gouges into the Swarmlord, gaining another screech of pain. Only then did Angron move again, an engine of destruction in motion once more. His axes flashed across the alien’s body, hooves cracking through chitin and bone alike. The very air burned around the fallen Primarch, flames manifesting not just around them but within the Immateirum as well. The Swarmlord’s wounds healed sluggishly, and it was a testament to the utterly alien strength of the Hive Mind that one of it’s greatest creations could survive even this much.

“DID YOU THINK US BLIND, BEL’AKOR!?”

At that, finally, the invisible lines that hung throughout the Warp were set aflame. A deep bellow of pain could be heard throughout the Immaterium for an infinity and more, for a mile and less. In less than an eyeblink, all was revealed such that those long-dead Imperial agents might have been shocked and horrified. The bountiful not-quite-daemonhosts shed their alien disguises, sprouting so many more arms, claws, and mouths. The daemonic legions of Khorne cared little, committing to the fight just as eagerly as before. The laughter of the thirsting Dark Gods boomed in the ears of all throughout the entire planetary system. Those last few vestiges of loyal Imperial souls that had clung to their holy places, their temples and churches and shrines, winked out as they too were washed over by a now boiling Warp.

And thus, did the mask of alien intelligence behind the Swarmlord’s eyes fade.

The façade was over.

“…how…,” rasped the First-Damned, the words guttural and wrenched through an alien mouth not meant for speech.

Angron’s laughter was so bright, so loud, that its heat liquified many of the corpses he stood upon. Even portions of the Swarmlord’s flesh puckered and cracked as it was scorched black, but its nerves had long been overridden to the point that it did not move other than the narrowing of its eyes.

“Your machinations were foreseen long before you arrived,” Angron sneered, liquid brass dribbling down his rictus grin and through his needle teeth. “The slaves of the Corpse-Emperor would have realized nothing. They would even applaud it. Their failure in Octarius would be overcast by a glorious change here. But you,” he gestured at the possessed alien with one of his axes, “And them,” he used the second axe to gesture towards the stars themselves, “Are pathetic brothers in idiocy. Using xenos as tools.”

Bel’akor snarled, the Swarmlord’s body breaking down by the essence within it, now fully expressing itself rather than remaining concealed for so long.

“A tool is a tool, slave,” Bel’akor spat, letting the Swarmlord’s body be buffeted by the instant wave of hatred and heat that erupted from Angron’s daemonic flesh. “Through my puppets, I have swallowed millions of souls! Even now,” a grey-black arm burst from the Swarmlord’s midsection that pointed to the battle going on all around them. “I feast upon your legions, and their strength becomes my own!”

The Swarmlord exploded, revealing the Daemon Prince that had hidden within. Wings expanded and beat once, then twice, as Bel’akor stood tall upon the fallen world. A massive blade rested in his right hand. In an instant, their combined hatred for one another struck, a tolling death knell for the world that rang out for miles distant. The Blade of Shadows rose up. In that moment, Angron could perceive the favor of hated Tzeentch hanging about his frame. It was a shadowy thing, befitting the one wielding it in that moment. Plots within plots within schemes wound about through the skein of fate.

“Perhaps I shall devour yours, slave!”

“I AM NO SLAVE!” Angron roared.

It had, in the end, been inevitable. The puppets of Bel’akor would continue to commit their full strength to the fight, and so too would the legions of Khorne fight forever. From the void of space beneath the galactic plane where the splinter had originated, from the Warp, they would expend themselves until one or the other were exhausted. As the latter died, they gave of themselves to the one who had stolen control over them. As the latter killed, they gave of what they did to the one who owned them. Blood would flow, the shaped essences of the Warp that were not quite souls would be drunk deeply of.

Subiaco Diablo was lost.

=================================================================

Cadia stood.

Shakily, on legs bloody and broken, on feet crushed and mashed to pulp, with bloody and bruised knuckles on weakly raised fists, Cadia stood.

Warbands of all of the Traitor Legions had been sighted around the Eye of Terror, striking as far as Chinchare to Belial to Caliban and beyond. The entire Agrippina Sector was considered effectively fallen save for the home system where the eponymous Forge World itself remained. Chaos Warbands that had been thought rendered extinct long ago had reappeared, as well as literal dozens of accounts of lost and disappeared ships positively identified beneath the banners and gruesome iconography of Chaos. Every day, more cultist troops arrived out of the Eye of Terror, howling mad and eager for glory in the name of the Dark Gods. Traitorous Guardsmen came on their own fleets of traitorous ships from the Imperial Navy, drawn out of hiding by the bushel from the lure of Chaos. Alien mercenaries of all kinds had been recruited at some point, further supplementing the forces commanded by the Warmaster. Chaos incursions, presences, and holdouts throughout Segmentum Tempestus, Segmentum Solar, Segmentum Pacificus, and Segmentum Ultima were at an all-time historical low – leaving in turn those areas to the predations of the still thousands of minor xeno kingdoms and empires which sought to take advantage of a distracted and overstretched Imperium. The Cadian Sector and all its peers were teetering, collapsing. Daemons were beginning to manifest in greater and greater number as well, to the point that many were beginning to manifest without a sorcerer or psyker summoning them forth. Entire tides of them had begun appearing where the fighting was thickest, driving many of their victims mad before killing them. The Dark Mechanicus was able to exhort their vision of the Omnissiah upon the battlefield, unleashing not only Titan Legios that had turned to Chaos during the Horus Heresy, but those that had been built in the time since, every inch of their bodies formed within the daemonic forges deep within the Eye from the foundation up. Fallen Imperial Knights, either individual renegades or entire Houses holding to some twisted form of fellowship, descended upon the worlds barely held by Imperial fingertips.

Every day, more arrived. More traitors. More madmen. More corrupted xenos. More daemons. More daemon-engines. More Titans. More Knights.

The well of evil seemed without end.

It was whispered, howled, dreamed, and spoken of amongst their misbegotten kind – and extracted in hundreds of Inquisitorial interrogations – that the Cadian Crucible held the Dark God’s attentions like little else had in quite some time.

By now, tens of thousands had witnessed the Living Saint Celestine fall, and tens of thousands had seen her rise, time and again. She was an idol of holy might, a presence that hardened the weakest heart and inspired the most cowardly into ferocious zealots. The Living Saint Sabbat had arrived with her many millions of devoted troops raised out of the Sabbat Worlds, joined by comprehensively massive detachments of all of the Orders Majoris of the Adeptas Sororitas. More space marines had fallen in the 13th Black Crusade than in any of the previous twelve combined, both those loyal to the Emperor and perfidious traitors, and yet more arrived all the time. Over two hundred separate Chapters of Adeptus Astartes were represented in the annals by now, all of them at least once in the casualty reports. More Guardsmen were arriving on a regular basis, from emergency raised regiments from Mordian, to a dozen separate full regiments raised of Ogryns, to a shockingly total redeployment of almost all functioning Death Korps of Krieg regiments throughout the entire Imperium to the Cadian Sector – the latter only possible with titanic effort on the part of the Administratum, Commissariat, the Lord Commander Militant and all five subordinate Lord Commanders of each Segmentum.

It wasn’t enough.

More than half of Cadia was enemy territory. Worlds throughout the Cadian System were in similarly dire straits. The nearest Forge Worlds of Demios Binary and Kantrael were under assault once more. Agri-Worlds were in danger of become salted and blackened spheres of death. Alpha Legion infiltrators had claimed credit for crippling the shipyards of Belis Corona and unnatural Warp turbulence was swiftly beginning to strangle any and all travel to or from Cypra Mundi. Many worried that a strike was soon to come to assault the Segmentum Fortress. The Imperial Navy was stretched thin, Battlefleet Gothic and Battlefleet Cadia thoroughly shredded. Incursions throughout the Eye of Terror’s surrounding territories had drawn much of Battlefleet Scarus and Battlefleet Coronus’ strength elsewhere, while Battlefleet Agrippina was bottlenecked in a desperate defense of their home system. The foundries of the Dark Mechanicus had been churning for quite a while, it seemed, for despite the loss of the Planet Killer and the Terminus Est the enemy seemed to possess more ships than the most extreme estimates previously.

However.

The attentions of Chaos being so focused upon a single point had borne them strengths and weaknesses both. They had foreseen the latest attempt of Bel’akor to empower himself further without paying to them all in equal tandem. They came ever closer to permanently ending the hated Living Saints. Every hour, another mind, another soul that had been shuttled to the battlefield surrendered to the glory of Chaos, be they mere Guardsmen, or Astartes who finally had the veil torn from their eyes. Champions of the Dark Gods swelled with power, for their deeds here, and now, within the Cadian Crucible, gained them even greater favor than any distant world or act far and away. Much to the horror of the loyalist scum, of course, who suffered under those so further empowered. Even alien champions were proving worthy, so long as they slaughtered enough Imperials, shattered enough tanks, sacrificed enough souls. The friction that had so often proved the end of such alliances between Chaos-worshippers seemed ameliorated as the Dark Gods grew ever more pleased. It was not to say they did not see all, of course, that they were not aware of other matters in the galaxy. It was simply that they had rarely been so totally entertained.

It was that, and that alone, that provided enough time and space to do what came next.

=========================================================================

Over Cadia, the Warp trembled. It was enough that both of the Living Saints could not help but look up in wonder, for they saw before any others the beacon that was now steadily pushing through the murky depths of the Immaterium. A new flotilla of Grand Cruisers bearing the marks of Khorne had just managed to shoot and ram their way closer to the planet, killing more than twice their number in Imperial Navy ships to get there. Despite the wounds dealt to those ships, it was grimly accepted by many commanders on the ground that they would soon suffer orbital bombardments of terrible power. Lance barrels glowed, macrocannons were reloaded, and the laughing mad crews prepared to unleash apocalypse onto the planet below.

And then the warp split open, and none other than the legendary Phalanx arrived. By sheer width, mass, and speed did its arrival obliterate the entire Chaos flotilla without firing a single shot. The battlefield in the void was too chaotic, all ships present already engaged with one another, and so it could not be said that everything ‘stopped for a single moment’ as some poets and historians might posit. The many ships of Battlefleet Solar that slipped out of the Warp in the shadow of the Phalanx were almost entirely forgotten, but they began immediately firing at will at all available targets. Behind them came dozens upon dozens of Mass Conveyors, each of them carrying a full capacity of a half million Imperial troops of various kinds.

The vox opened on general broadcast.

“Attention all Chaos filth. This is Chapter Master Vorn Hagan of the Imperial Fists. Today is the day you are beaten back. Today is the day that Abbadon cowers and retreats with his tail between his legs as twelve times before! Terra has come for you, treacherous dogs, in all of her fury!”

Upon the main strategium of the Phalanx, Chapter Master Hagan turned to the assembled leadership of those who had traveled hence, the crowd of them impressive by any reckoning.

“Brothers! Ready yourselves for deployment, Cadia shall not fall this day!”

Cheers answered him, and not just those from the throats of the ten Captains of the Imperial Fists. The Emperor’s Warbringers, the Knights of Dorn, the White Templars, the Red Templars, the Hammers of Dorn, the Fire Lords, Night Swords, Death Strike, Invaders, and even two Captains of the rebuilt Celestial Lions slammed fists to breastplates. All Successors of the Imperial Fists who had answered the call after the Battle Over Terra had been won. The Phalanx had once held the entirety of the Imperial Fists and their auxiliaries when they were a true Legion and had easily accommodated them all with room to spare for the rest of their allies that had come with them.

“We have not come alone, either! We come not just as the Adeptus Astartes, but more! We are the Fury of Terra!”

Hagan then looked to the Canonesses standing next to so many Brother-Captains, each of them representing members of the Adeptas Sororitas Orders Majoris as well as more than a few of the Orders Minoris. They had come in great number, called by the words of the Ecclesiarchy in order to support the Imperium at Cadia. A series of tight nods and grim looks answered him from the warrior women. They had brought veterans of many Wars of Faith, and there were more than a few of the Crusaders and more militarized members of the Ecclesiarchy amongst them that were not strictly necessary or allowed under the remit of no men bearing arms, but for the moment they had toed the line enough.

“The Sisters of Battle are prepared to unleash devastation and deliver salvation! The Fabricator-General has sent with us not just their most elite Skitarii, but the Legio Cybernetica, the Titan Legio Excruciata, and the Titan Legio Fortis! House Taranis and House Raven are even now landing their Knights alongside the Freeblades that answered the call!”

And yet all of said illustrious presences were overshadowed by one group that stood apart from them all. For it was they who had enabled this grand conveyance to occur in the first place. They who had arrived upon the Phalanx without any willing to challenge them, whose authority superseded any and all who might have dared speak against them. For it was they, who had brought forth secrets and technologies from the Dark Cells, things thought lost and forbidden that had allowed the adepts of Mars and the Tech-Marines of so many Chapters to revitalize the Phalanx like never before. Though those who had brought such things had returned to their duties afterwards, others had flown in on gilded shuttles instead. For the Phalanx, time enough had been bought to repair, to refurbish, to rearm, to resupply - and then to be flooded with troops ready for the fight.

“The Adeptus Custodes stand with us! THE EMPEROR STANDS WITH US!”

They were but a single Shield Host, and yet their presence had inflamed all upon the Phalanx with implacable fury and righteous hate towards the enemy. Even now, they did not respond to the rousing words and acts of Chapter Master Hagan, merely watched the proceedings in utter silence. But they did not need to. A whisper of their presence was as near a blade as any might carry into battle, the threat of their movement enough to threaten entire armies of Chaos troops into retreat.

“Captain Garadon,” Hagan turned to the Captain of the 3rd Company. “It is thanks to you that the Phalanx survived unto her revivification. I now entrust her to you once more as I join the battle below.”

“I shall not fail you, Chapter Master,” Tor Garadon saluted.

“In the Emperor’s name,” Hagan nodded to him before glancing out to the crowd “IN THE EMPEROR’S NAME!”

Within an hour the Phalanx had emptied itself greatly. Within an hour, the Phalanx had contributed to the reclamation of total orbital superiority over Cadia. Within a day, the reinforcements of Battlefleet Solar done much the same over half the remaining planets within the system. All the while, however, the forces of Chaos had not ceased in their arrivals, though they could no longer approach Cadia with complete impunity. Instead, they spread their attacks to planets on the outer edge of the system and others within the Cadian Sector, once more demanding that the Imperial Navy spread out to try and repulse them from other locations. The armies of Chaos upon Cadia remained stubborn, and though they were now on the retreat, they forced lakes of blood out of the Imperials for every inch retaken.

The 13th Black Crusade ground ever on…

070.M42 Through 073.M42 Interlude: Zeal And Negentropy

070.M42 Through 073.M42 Interlude: Zeal And Negentropy

It began on the world of Korolis, with the whole of the Cadian System awash in death and destruction much as the rest of the Cadian Sector. The vital atomic materials and promethium supplies extracted and refined there, as well as the facilities to transport them to battlefields across the 13th Black Crusade, had been under assault just as every other planet. In the beginning, it had been the purview of nothing more than the lost and the damned, Abbadon throwing away millions of troops of lesser worth to strangle the planet in corpses. Later on, he needed even those troops to deal with the forces the Imperium was supplying to more important planets, and instead relegated the attacks upon the world to others on a rotating basis. On some occasions, it was more elite mortal troops. On others, sorcerers summoned forth daemons to swamp the planet. The Black Legion was absent entirely in some years, instead giving over responsibility to a lesser warband or one of the other Traitor Legions, but they would always return at some time or another. Instead of wanton destruction, however, the desires of the forces of Chaos were obvious. They desired a new supply base directly on the front line.

In the monstrous length of the Black Crusade, the forces of Chaos had claimed the planet more than once, the facilities and the materials they produced switching hands at least thrice before the Blood Ravens and Salamanders had arrived alongside the 1st Company of the Angels of Vigilance, both forces responding to new distress hymnals. For five years, Aramus had fought on that blasted world. Volcanic and searing with heat, it was not fit for human life outside of the mining and refinement complexes. Either by fate or chance, it was an environment that seemed to bother the Salamanders that had traveled alongside him for so long not at all. If anything, they almost reveled in it, the environmental issues somewhat reminding the marines of the 1st Founding Chapter of Nocturne. Aramus and what little remained of the Blood Ravens were not so pleasantly inclined, and the same could be said of the Angels of Vigilance. The assaults were endless, yes, but not insurmountable.

“Brother-Captain Hector, are you well?” Aramus glanced at the stalwart astartes as he entered the command bunker.

As structures went, it was defensible enough. Salamanders and Angels of Vigilance filled it alongside the commanders of the Imperial Guard defending the world – Cadian regiments all. A vibrating sense of wonder had suffused everyone, however, when the news of the Phalanx’s arrival had come. Already, they were being told through long range astropath communiques that they would be soon receiving extremely significant levels of reinforcements and aid. The legendary Phalanx was one thing, but there were even rumors of the Adeptus Custodes being present, though of course none had seen them deploy onto the battlefield as of yet. The fact that the Captain of the Angels of Vigilance 1st Company had such a dark look on his face was, therefore, quite concerning to both Aramus and N’mul. The two friends immediately pulled away from the cogitators they were conferring with and strode over to him.

“It went well enough. Three traitor astartes dead, the rest of the Alpha Legion strike force pulled back,” the weathered veteran shook his head. “No, it is not that. I have just received a disturbing hymnal by way of the astropath.”

Aramus and N’mul paused, the two comrades exchanging dubious looks before a raised eyebrow prompted Aramus to speak.

“What, are the reinforcements Chapter Master Hagan promised not coming? It-,” Aramus paused at the look on Hector’s face. “Brother,” he clapped a hand to the man’s pauldron. “Please, speak to us.”

The Angel of Vigilance grimaced, glancing about the bunker and the now wondering eyes of too many watchers, and then jerked his head towards one of the side chambers.

“It must be grave for you to be acting like this,” N’mul frowned.

“It is,” Hector confirmed with a nod. “The hymnal is not from the Phalanx, or anyone else. Rather, it was sent from my chapter’s homeworld, Pervigilium,” he bowed his head for a moment before raising it once more. “It was a distress hymnal, utilizing emergency codes.”

N’mul and Aramus straightened in their armor.

“What?” N’mul said quickly, crimson eyes wide. “Of what sort?”

“It is a general recall order,” Hector shook his head. “For all Companies, stressing that Pervigilium itself is in danger.”

Aramus felt his pulse quicken.

“Then…,”

“The 1st Company must leave immediately,” Hector nodded. “We have already lost too many companies in this galaxy to suffer potential damage to the Fortress-Monastery. The four sent to Armageddon were wiped out by the orks, while the 3rd and 7th were lost on Cadia proper by Abbadon’s hand,” Hector growled, fingers tightening into fists on the table.

“What defenses does Pervigilium retain?” Aramus said quickly.

“We are oath-bound to retain at least one company there to defend it at all times. When I deployed into the Cadian System, it was left to Captain Agon, of the 2nd Company. One of the best in our entire Chapter’s history,” Hector replied grimly. “He would not use the codes he did unless it was truly, truly grave.”

“What could drive him to such, then?” N’mul asked.

“Nothing good,” Hector sighed and leaned back, straightening as he half-turned towards the door. “Pervigilium remains just outside the Cadian Gate proper. If it is the Great Enemy, then it could mean a backdoor right into the rear of the most recently reclaimed territories that the Phalanx took.”

Aramus looked to N’mul, who looked back. Both nodded in unison.

“Would your Chapter accept our aid, then?”

Hector paused and looked back at the two.

“I…normally, the pride of the Angels of Vigilance would demand I say no,” Hector said slowly before he raised a fist up, clenching it. “But if Agol called with such urgency…,” he looked between the two. “If you would aid us, then we would be in your debt, I think.”

“Only if we are successful in driving off whatever threat may be there,” Aramus scoffed. “Reinforcements are arriving within the day. We can begin embarking within less than an hour.”

“Very well then.”

=======================================================================

They could not have known.

“No…,”

The Angels of Vigilance had watched over the planet of Pervigilium for thousands of years. They had never ceased defending it, to the point of refusing the orders of the High Lords of Terra to commit their full chapter multiple times so that at least one Company could remain present for its defense. When the Eye of Terror waxed, they had been on the front lines every time. When it waned, they had sent out at least half their strength to combat the forces of Chaos throughout the Segmentum Obscurus. From their orbital Fortress-Monastery, they watched over the civilized planet below that they both defended and recruited from.

“NO!”

“Hector, stop!”

The Captain of the 1st Company of the Angels of Vigilance raged at the sight of a dying world. N’mul grappled with him, struggling to hold back the might of the three-century old veteran space marine, his wrath near inhuman at the sights returned by the auspex arrays of his battle barge and those of the other ships that had accompanied him. The rest of the 1st Company seemed shocked into stillness, many of them visibly frozen by the revelation that had been so gruesomely delivered. Aramus, however, bowed his head in solemnity as he looked upon the actuality sphere’s projections, as well as the various scan returns being given by the unfeeling auspex and the mindless servitors which manned it.

“How…how could Agol let this happen!?” The words were hissed through teeth grit so hard they were in danger of cracking, N’mul finally retreating somewhat as Hector came to a shaking halt.

Below, Pervigilium burned. The orbital ring, both shipyard and Fortress-Monastery both, had impacted against it through some unknown means. Hundreds of miles of shattered metal and technology lay scattered across the planet’s surface. In some areas, segments as long as continents had remained somewhat structurally intact, while others had shattered into a meteor storm of metal which had set so much of the planet aflame. The ships of the 2nd Company of the Angels of Vigilance were floating wrecks, those of them that hadn’t been similarly impacted against the planet below.

“We were not that far, that distant!” Hector insisted. “In such a short amount of time…,”

“We are receiving communications from the Angels of Vigilance 9th and 10th Company, asking what to do,” one of the serfs spoke up, flinching as Hector’s bloodshot eyes swiveled upon him.

“Hector,” N’mul said gently, shaking the 1st Captain slightly. “We need to investigate. To evacuate what survivors there might be…if we can.”

“I…yes. There…records, the preservation vaults, the…,” Hector paused. “We shall deploy to scour the…the wreck of the Fortress-Monastery,” he stumbled over the very concept before swiftly moving for the transports.

The Angels of Vigilance were swift to follow their Captain’s orders, but it was obvious that all were similarly affected. Aramus could only liken it to a nightmarish example of what might have happened to the Blood Ravens, had he not been sent out to defend Subsector Aurelia. In the 1st Aurelian Crusade, at least. Unlike the Blood Ravens, the Angels of Vigilance had only ever recruited from the world below, from the sons of the nobility. But even the most cursory look at the auspex returns showed that there were no human life signs left on the planet, despite N’mul’s words. The firestorms washing across it from a shredded atmosphere and the tectonic instability caused by the massive orbital ring smashing into it would mean the planet would become uninhabitable even by space marines within days, if not hours.

“N’mul…,” Aramus trailed off.

“I know. If the gene-seed vaults of their Fortress-Monastery were not spared from this…this apocalypse...,” the Salamander grimaced, “This might well be the death knell for their Chapter.”

“And to think we were so arrogant as to believe we could be of aid here,” Aramus spat angrily.

“We may still yet,” N’mul patted him on the shoulder. “Come, we should join the recovery efforts, what little there may be.”

Aramus looked again at the planetary projection.

“What little indeed.”

Several grim hours of sifting through the wreckage below proved even more disheartening than the arrival, much to the distress of the remaining three Companies of the Angels of Vigilance. The devastation wrought upon the planet was incalculable, as was the damage to the Fortress-Monastery when its major compartment and components could be found. The mood of the Angels of Vigilance had grown ever darker, organized search and salvage parties breaking up into individualistic paths, solitary marines tearing apart bulkheads and unearthing chambers on their lonesome with frantic movements and motions. Seemingly every armory and munition storage had detonated or cooked off at some point in the time after the Fortress-Monastery’s impact. The Chaplains were silent, no litany or sermon coming to mind. The cities of the world were lifeless, just as the ruins of the orbital ring, but something had eventually begun niggling at the back of Aramus’ mind as they went over servo skull scan reports and the auspex arrays above continued their own work.

In the end, it was the Tech-Marines who managed to pull something of worth, juicing dead and damaged cogitators with enough energy to come to life for just long enough to extract data files. The machine spirits of the Fortress-Monastery’s systems were dead. It was merely the unfortunate truth that with proper training and coaxing, their ghosts might be asked of a little bit more before being laid to rest in permanence. Thus, the assembled commanders met once again within the shattered confines of the innermost section that remained functional out of the whole of the ruined Fortress-Monastery. Here, at last, within stasis-shielded barriers that had flickered out without power, they might learn more than what their own scans were telling them. For beyond the cogitators now running off of portable generators, Sarrelen held up a battered and cracked helmet, the white paint burnt black by some incendiary or another, faint green laurel engravings along the sides stripped mostly away.

“…that is Brother-Captain Agol’s command helm,” Hector confirmed with a nod, his voice deathly quiet, the winds whipping through the creaking ruins, metal groaning and earth rumbling in the distance from quake. “But…where…?”

“I cannot say,” the Blood Raven Tech-Marine shook his head. “Having made a preliminary study of the recording, I suspect we will not find his body.”

“We haven’t found any bodies,” growled Sabin, one of the few remaining Angels of Vigilance apothecaries. “Our brothers, our serfs, our neophytes…,”

“Hence the recording,” Sarrelen took the helm, mechadendrites clicking and tapping into the helm with cords and plugs, “Please, Brother-Captain Hector, hold your questions until after you have all viewed it,” he turned and gestured, causing a hololith to flicker to life.

It took less than a second for all of the space marines present to positively identify the one’s responsible for Pervigilium’s destruction. After all, the recording began with Brother-Captain Agol killing one of them.

======================================================

Agol’s breath was ragged in his throat, even as he slammed his combat knife through the Dark Eldar’s chin and up through their head. The cruel smirk on the alien’s face did not have enough time to twist into confusion and horror before they died, their prey having slain them instead of the other way around. All around him, the rest of the remnants of the 2nd Company were falling back further into the Fortress-Monastery. His breath was also ragged due to the fact that his primary heart had been shot, and he bled from several different wounds. It was, perhaps, the Emperor’s blessings that he had survived being hit directly by a splinter cannon at all.

“Regroup, brothers! Hold these vile xenos back!”

Sharp laughter answered him rather than the calls of his brothers. Agol looked up, and to his shock saw that the rest of the 2nd Company had fallen all around him, all within the seconds it had take him to slay just one of the Incubi. Some struggled, but still others had fallen completely still. They were not, he knew, in fact dead. The despicable creatures had outright broadcast their intent. Prizes. Trophies. Emergency supplies. He knew, even now, that some of his brothers were being caged in preparation for transportation to Emperor-knew-where. Ahead, the Succubus leading the assault laughed again, her razor whip slashing into the adamantium floor with a crack. Her subordinate Wyches slowly rose from their victims and formed up behind her.

“You cannot hold back our kind, mon’keigh. You are too slow, too weak, too stupid,” she reared her head back and laughed again. “Did you not say that you would ‘break our feeble ships and burn our fragile bodies’?” She pitched her voice low as she stalked forward, heels literal spikes that drove into the deck-plates

She almost no armor at all, and yet was positively slathered in the blood of his fallen brothers, her inhumanely pale skin hidden beneath the crimson.

“Even with your pathetic distress call going out, it will be too late,” she swayed her hips as she came closer. “A miniscule whimper to make up for us shattering your pride, and yet it will amount to nothing,” she hissed as she came closer.

Agol moved, all of his enhanced strength and speed saving his life by inches as he leapt backwards from the whip slashing through where he’d lain. The Captain of the 2nd Company continually shifted backwards, combat knife held in reverse grip as his eyes darted back and forth, the rest of the Wych Coven and Incubi done with their own victims and now crowding in around him from almost all sides.

“The fear your charges shall feel as we bring their protector’s down from on high is so intoxicating, I can taste it from here!” She shrieked with more cruel laughter, now joined by the chuckles of all the other Dark Eldar.

“Merigrynn,” came a new voice, sibilant and cloying with arrogance, a voice that Agol knew from the very beginnings of the incursion.

All of the Dark Eldar stiffened, the Incubi falling into attention postures just before their subordinate warriors did the same. Agol glared angrily through his one functional eye at the one that casually swept into the chamber. His mind raced, trying to find some solution, some tactic, some measure that might yet find victory. Dark Eldar poisons burned their way through his body, fighting to bring him low, either into the embrace of death or to sedate him fully enough that he might be captured.

“Archon Endross,” the Succubus spun on her heels and fell to a kneeling position. “I…,”

“Silence,” he said, and so the Succubus quieted.

Endross himself stood a head again taller than any of the other nearby Dark Eldar. His body, unlike many of their kind, was surprisingly thickly muscled, just barely below the level of what might have been described as bulky. His herad was obscured by a concealing helm, his face specifically covered by a elaborate mask of pure white which depicted an Eldar’s face wracked by grief and pain. A splinter pistol lay in a holster on his hips, as did a sheathed power sword. Deadly weapons, yet unused and practically untouched, for Endross wielded something else entirely: a short staff of intricate work. He swung it, languidly, this way and that as he stalked closer. Its head was the bleached skull of some ancient reptile or another, clutched by what could have been a severed arm from whatever beast it might have been which formed the shaft proper.

“Captain Agol….,” Endross shook his head, tutting. “You disappoint me. I informed you of my coming, and yet you declared that you needed no aid to see us away,” the Archon turned and twitched, as if surprised, to see the fallen battle brothers spread throughout the vault. “Yet,” he tapped a single finger against his mask, “The Exquisite Fang reigns supreme. Your charges shall be fuel for my Kabal, for Commorragh, and for the arts of the Haemunculi. Your Emperor’s…’finest’,” he drew out the word, “Barely occupied us at all. Truly, the arrogance of mon’keigh is ceaseless.”

Agol coughed bloodily, stumbling backwards again as the Archon stepped forwards.

“The…the Angels of Vigilance will return here, they will stop you,” he declared weakly, coughing out another thick stream of blood. “You may kill us, but the Chapter will have its vengeance!”

Endross’ laugh was sharp enough to cut souls.

“Will they? Hmm…an interesting challenge!” the Archon genuinely sounded excited. “Can we harvest the entire populace of a so-called Civilized World before your reinforcements come? Can I drink the soul of a million mon’keigh as they scream in terror as their protector’s orbital ring descends upon their heads? Tell me, mon’keigh, how much entertainment might we extract from each and every one of you ‘Angels of Death’,” he said the title snidely, “Before you die?”

Agol snarled wordlessly, casting his gaze back and forth.

“I have slain hundreds of space marines over the past few thousand years,” Endross chuckled deeply, “It will never cease to amuse me how you hold yourselves to be peerless, peacocking and strutting about across the galaxy that rightfully belongs only to the Drukhari. You are, as ever, genuinely surprised somehow when superior warriors defeat you. I wonder…,” Endross drawled. “If we destroy every primitive pile of rocks banging together you call cogitators, every servo skull, every camera…will your precious ‘battle brothers’ even know? Even the corpses can be used by the Haemunculi, while your paltry wargear might be worth something to the mandrakes that haunt the midden heaps. They shall come running…and find nothing. All that impotent fury…,”

The Archon groaned in audible pleasure at the thought.

“Well. We shall see, won’t we?”

Agol stilled, and glanced once more at the side-chamber he had spied. By now, it was likely that the orbital ring was being destabilized. That he may well have been the last of the 2nd Company still alive.

“Yes. My brothers will see,” he growled and tore off his helmet, casting it not at any of the Dark Eldar, but instead into the chamber. “Activate stasis-lock of Chapel 19B, Eternity-Terminus!”

The Dark Eldar had frozen, prepared for violence in every aspect but surprised for just long enough for the shimmering fields to phase into being. Not that any who were watching through the helmet’s recording would see it. For in casting it so forcefully, it had struck the ground and spun about, lenses coming to a halt while facing a wall covered in purity seals and engraved oaths. Thus, it did not see what occurred next. Only weak audio was of worth at that point. To hear of the snarl of Endross which quickly transformed into a guffaw which was weakly echoed by the other Dark Eldar.

“Clever! Clever mon’keigh,” Endross could be heard, though there was a new edge there that had not been there before. “I’ve no doubt that we could cut through the walls and retrieve that helmet, if required…but you? You will never know if we choose to or not. I wondered if you would be worth making into a new grotesque by Hulmaelnok…but you’ve…you’ve actually managed to surprise me. So you shall die here and now rather than take our mercies later. Consider it…a token of my favor. A kindness from the Lord of Sorrows himself.”

Agol could be heard to spit.

“How is that for favor, xeno,” he growled wetly.

The response was something that the audio picked up by the helmet plainly could not properly articulate. Something akin to a roar and screech, a light which could be seen even on the wall that the helmet was stuck staring at. Agol's bellow of pain was barely audible at all, and yet it quickly terminated.

“Now there was a hardy soul,” Endross’ voice was filled with relish. “Now then. Back to pleasure.”

“But Archon-,”

“If these Angels of Vigilance could not defend their world, then they didn’t deserve it, did they?” Endross interrupted, his tone mild. “If they wish to lodge a complaint with natural selection, they may come find us. Let them come. At most, their paltry combat abilities might provide an amusing distraction. Now come! We have slaves and spoils aplenty to take. The mon’keigh are too busy ”

The helmet’s emergency power ensured it remained functioning even as explosions and rumbles filled the orbital ring. It was a curious thing to witness the shaking in the walls, the floors, and the ceilings as not just the chapel but the whole of the ring broke apart and was no doubt purposefully pushed down onto the planet. It flew about the chapel in the final descent, crashing down again as static washed over it upon impact, the recording cutting out soon after.

============================================================================

Sarrelen lowered the helmet, disengaging his mechadendrites.

“The helmet was severely damaged in the landing. It was a more likely possibility that it would be destroyed in the fall of the ring,” he said warily, looking across the deathly still and silent Angels of Vigilance. “It was only the noble machine spirits powering the Chapel’s stasis and void shielding which preserved this place, and the artifice of whomever crafted this helm that kept it from total destruction.”

He paused then, waiting for them to respond, and when they did not he cleared his throat and looked to the stricken Aramus and N’mul.

“The other Tech-Marines and I-,”

The general vox channel screeched to life.

“Captain!” Shouted an Angel of Vigilance scout. “Enemies in the battlezone!”

In an instant, there was commotion and life amongst the other Angels of Vigilance once more. Both because of the call, and the sound of bolter fire on the other end, as well as the fact that from seemingly nowhere amongst the wreckage burst dozens of abominable creatures. There was no time for words, for battle cries, for oaths, as the Dark Eldar grotesques came to life. Sarrelen’s personal auspex began scanning immediately, but he also had to duck away from a grasping creature of patchwork flesh and horrific Haemonculus augments. Around them, more and more of them emerged, engaging each and every space marine present, doubling and even tripling up on them.

“Damnation! Portable Shadow Field generators! They were hidden amongst the ruins all this time!” He called out at the scan’s results before batting the first of them away, jabbing the second in the face with the barrels of his left forearm mounted storm bolter and firing into its mouth.

It was the same across the ruins. An ambush prepared and waiting for just the moment that their emotions had been most heightened and furious. In the days afterward, Sarrelan would speculate that the Dark Eldar, depraved and dependent as they were on suffering, agony, and emotion from their victims, had likely ensured that at some point and at some time some sort of emotional detector had been invented by their foul kind. Psychic based or otherwise, possibly reading chemicals in the air and in the body. It didn’t really matter, in the end. What mattered more was that the Dark Eldar, who considered themselves artists of suffering and sadism, had ensured that their ambush would only be triggered when the remaining Angels of Vigilance were at their most furious and off-center at the death of their homeworld and Fortress-Monastery.

An hour later, with all of the hidden grotesques slain and the shadow field generators destroyed, Captain Hector found himself falling to his knees, holding the body of the rapidly liquifying Brother-Captain Paris of the 9th Company. The space marine managed to gasp out, but no words could be found, the acidic poisons of the grotesques melting not just his flesh, but his organs and gene-seed as well. Captain Paris managed to raise one hand, reaching towards Hector, before that too fell limp, for there was no longer skin and bone within. Only a dark liquid paste that drained out of the many holes punched through his armor. Aramus watched wearily as he glanced around the ruins, covered not just in the corpses of the slain grotesques, but of the space marines that had fallen fighting them too. Some of them had been the Angels of Vigilance, most painfully their 10th Company which had been securing the wider perimeter and had thus been more isolated and spread out.

But not all.

“How many…,” Aramus murmured.

“Five,” N’mul answered with a low growl. “Vile xenos.”

“I have only ever fought Craftworld Eldar, not this kind,” Aramus admitted, scowling at his inexperience. Perhaps, if he had known better, some of the deaths might have been prevented…?

“They are more similar than they would ever admit,” N’mul shook his head. “But even so, the Dark Eldar are by far the most depraved of aliens I have ever met. They exult and feed off of the agony and fear of others – literally, so the Librarians tell us. Tell me, in your past encounters with the Craftworld Eldar, did they speak of greater goods, of protections and the like that our minds could not comprehend?”

Aramus thought of the witch Idranel. Her claims. Her manipulations. And all the wanton destruction her kind caused before and after her death.

“Something like that.”

“The Dark Eldar, or Drukhari, have no such pretenses. All are prey to them,” N’mul, shaking his head.

“We are not prey!” Hector yelled, glaring at them from where he still held the empty armor of his battle brother.

His chest heaved in his armor, each breath heavy and ragged. His terminator armor was battered and damaged, but the marine himself had suffered no physical damage. Much of his 1st Company could say the same. The other nearby Angels of Vigilance still seemed shellshocked, but they came out of it with Hector’s words.

“We are not prey,” he repeated, this time more quietly, looking upon the armor in his hands before gently letting it down to the ground to rest in the pool of viscera that had once been a space marine. Still breathi“And I swear, upon the blood of Paris and the wreckage of Pervigilium, of our Fortress-Monastery, that in the name of the Angels of Vigilance, I will hunt this Endross down and slay him!”

An angry cheer rose up from the survivors of his Chapter.

“I as well!” One cried.

“We are with you, Hector!”

N’mul watched it play out, more and more of the Angels of Vigilance swearing to the hunt but then turned as the Salamander apothecary Fer’vel approached. A look, and a nod, gesturing towards the five reductor vials now hung on his waist, were all that was required. N’mul tilted his head, and Fer’vel bowed his, stepping back once more to see to the wounds sustained by the remainder of their own battle-brothers. Their deaths would burn at him forevermore, but he could not afford to lose himself to those fires. His mind was far more focused on other things, though it shamed him to admit it.

“Calidus-,” he near whispered into the private command channel reserved for the Salamanders alone.

“I know. I am…I am reviewing the records,” the Salamander Librarian murmured back, the psyker standing far to the side away from him. “I don’t…it seems unlikely.”

“And yet,” N’mul countered.

“And yet,” Calidus sighed. “We must investigate further, though it may prove difficult.”

“Hmm?” N’mul turned his head slightly, watching Aramus confer with the rest of his battle brothers upon the Retribution in orbit.

“A Dark Eldar Kabal capable of full planetary invasions, not mere scant raids, is a formidable one indeed. They destroyed all cogitators, but they could not eliminate weapon damages dealt to the ring, nor explosive resides – or so the Tech-Marines tell me. Furthermore, the psychic echoes of the atrocities done to the population here are near deafening, Captain.”

N’mul blinked.

“Calidus, I-,”

“Will be confirmed by the rest of the Chapter the moment you can be dragged back to Nocturne for the ceremony, brother. Do not even try to deny it.”

N’mul sighed.

“We will discuss this later. For now…,” he closed the channel and looked to Aramus. “Aramus.”

“Hmm?” The Blood Raven looked his way. “I am of a mind to aid the Angels of Vigilance in finding vengeance. What of you?”

It wasn’t even a lie.

Aramus looked at the raging and grieving Angels of Vigilance and nodded.

“It sounds like this Kabal intends to take advantage of the ongoing fighting, letting the majority of the Imperium’s forces remain focused on the Warmaster. Even if they had not done this, they would need to be stopped.”

In agreement, the two looked to Hector, who had heard their words.

“If, that is, they would have us.”

Hector glanced around his remaining brothers before gritting his teeth.

“By all rights, this should be a fight for our Chapter alone…but I cannot deny that we are weakened after their treachery. If…if the Blood Ravens and the Salamanders would aid us, I would welcome it. Vengeance must be had for this.”

=================================================================

“So. That is where we stand. I am willing to transport any who would not wish to join us in this to the nearest Imperial base, but I must ask that you decide quickly,” Aramus stepped back as he finished speaking.

For a moment, there was quiet, save for the hum of the ship. In the end, it was the Sister of Battle who stepped forward first.

“A single human soul lost to the depredations of xenos would be enough,” Palantine Katicia, her eyes bloodshot with anger. “But a hundred million of them? I could not bear to face the God-Emperor in death if I did not do this in life.”

A screech of binary conversation between the two representatives of the Mechanicus present ended with both nodding in unison.

“Affirmative,” Magos-Militant Thallrex-17 beeped. “Too much wargear has been pillaged, or worse, destroyed. The loss of the Pervigllium Ring is great. The Omnissiah weeps.”

“The Exquisite Blade must be punished,” Magos Dominus Pelliad’s mechadendrites spasmed angrily.

Aramus looked at them all and nodded, a ghost of a smile on his lips.

“I give you my thanks, then. May we find victory.”

====================================================================

Even knowing their quarry, it was not an easy or simple matter to chase them. The Dark Eldar were a powerful force on the battlefield, and swift beyond belief. By the time that the Retribution had reached Pervigilium, it had been over a week since their departure. Scans were made, reports collected, information scoured and collated as they dove back into the Cadian Sector. In between fighting in outer systems, seeking out reports of disappearances and missing regiments and groupings, they hunted. On most occasions, they discovered that the culprits were servants of Chaos. Either because they had been driven mad by the ongoing fighting, or had been corrupted more directly by the hands of sorcerers and infiltrators. There were other instances, however, of total disappearances, not just of Imperial citizens either. Minor bands of greenskins, irritants compared to the superlative strength and numbers being thrown about by the Imperium and the forces of the Warmaster, disappeared from their huts and outposts without seemingly having managed to fire a shot. An Imperial Guard regiment on garrison duty, as well as the Traitor Guard that had been laying siege to them, the basilisks artillery tanks left running.

Then they began finding evidence of something else entirely.

“What sort of weapon could do this?” Aramus asked as they stared at the shredded daemon-engine in front of them.

They had come together, the Tech-Marines deployed in full with Angels of Vigilance and Salamanders both scouring the battlefield. Sarrelen held a hand up to the hull, which had once been infused with the energies of the warp, but did not dare outright touch it. His skull probes and auspex were scanning well enough, the other Tech-Marines doing similar analytic work. Truth be told, however, Sarrelen didn’t need to wait for the results. He had served with Captain Thule’s forces, maintaining bases built across the surface of Kronus, and in one notable instance, below.

“Necron, Force Commander,” he stated after a moment. “Gauss weaponry flays molecule by molecule in rapid fashion, rending flesh and metal alike with the same ease.”

“I concur,” Cendium, the Senior Tech-Marine of the Salamanders, nodded. “This daemon-engine was of the Defiler classification, a walker sub-category. Often artillery, but when let off their leashes they can prove deadly up close. It would have died easily, in most cases. And yet,” he gestured to the three severed pieces it had been cut into, “I would suspect this is the work of some of the more powerful weaponry the Necrons possess. Gauss blasters, and the like.”

“Agreed,” Sarrelen nodded, looking then to Aramus. “There were confirmed reports of Necron vessels swarming the Blackstone Fortresses several years ago, almost a fifth of Abbadon’s estimated naval strength at the time was guarding them, and it wasn’t enough. Since then, however, nothing.”

“Well,” Aramus glanced around the battlefield. “Clearly that has changed. Any idea why that might be?”

The Salamanders did not respond immediately, but Aramus noted how they glanced amongst themselves. He didn’t comment on it, much as he had not when the Space Wolves had abandoned the entire battlefield despite the rumors of monstrous and mutated space marines bearing their colors. That did not mean that it did not sting. He had fought alongside the Great Wolf for only a short time, and the 1st Founding had more secrets than he would ever know. But N’mul and the 7th Company had been his close allies for a good number of years, at this point. He had fought alongside them for longer than the 1st and 2nd Aurelian Crusades combined. His lips thinned behind his helmet, but he shook the maudlin thoughts from himself, for now at least. One way or another, he knew, the truth of the matter would come out before the hunt for Endross was done.

“I see. Well, any clues as towards Endross’ next move, then?” He offered them a change in subject, one they leapt upon easily.

“The Dark Eldar are fast, but every time they stop to raid and take prisoners, they must slow themselves. From each of those points, they must then consider the Webway, to relieve their cargo holds, as well as what targets to take next. Based on previous struck planets and battlefield conditions present on those worlds…,”

Aramus let the information wash over him, examining it detachedly as he looked to where Hector stood. The forlorn 1st Captain of the Angels of Vigilance had grown ever more taciturn and quieter, only to explode into violence on every battlefield they found themselves on. Aramus counted the man as an ally, they had sworn to hunt Endross together after all, but some days he could not tell if it was Hector the space marine who he was talking to, or a grenade with the pin pulled that walked.

“There is little else for us here. Let us return to the ships and keep moving as surely as our quarry must be,” he said after the Tech-Marines wound down.

It would not be the last time they found evidence of Necron involvement. There were never any bodies left behind, though Aramus knew from the records that this was usual for their kind. Only the barest few fragments of inert necrodermis, and evidence of weapons fire could be found, every now and then, on the same steady path that they themselves were already following. Which was, of course, quite disconcerting. The last times the Necrons had involved themselves in the fighting going on in the 13th Black Crusade and its various battlezones, they had carved their way through the forces of Chaos and fired on any Imperial ships that came too close before, during, and after the retrieval of their prizes. This, more than anything, seemed to enflame the Salamanders as much as the Angels of Vigilance.

Eventually, it would all come to a head, just as Aramus had thought it would.

He would not have predicted Vorga Torq as the planet for it.

================================================================

“Warp transition complete in three, two, one…,”

The warp tore, and their combined fleet entered realspace once again. They were almost immediately committed to an ongoing fight in the void, macrocannon fusillades and lance blasts striking void shields across the fleet as they appeared on the perimeter of it all. Aramus gripped the actuality sphere’s projector as the Retribution rumbled from enemy fire, auspex systems already picking out the identity of multiple Chaos ships in the battlezone. More than that, however, were a notable number of thin, razor sharp ships festooned with spikes and xeno sails aplenty. It was these that Hector and the remains of his Chapter most obviously focused on, despite Aramus sighting the third and fourth parties that were also present.

“THERE!” Hector roared across the vox. “Dark Eldar ships! The same emblems of the aliens from the recording! It’s the Exquisite Blade! All ships, forward!”

“Hector wait!” Aramus shouted. “There’s an ork fleet and a necron fleet in the way!”

Nearby, N’mul was hurriedly speaking onto his Chapter’s vox.

“ANGELS OF VIGILANCE, FORWARD!”

“HECTOR!”

Vorga Torq had been little more than a Penal World for almost its entire existence. The criminal elements throughout the Cadian Sector had been sent, in no small amounts, to the world. But at the start of the 13th Black Crusade, the Iron Skulls titan legion had burned the world in the name of the Warmaster and Chaos. Though much of it had been reduced to ash, not all of it had. In the many decades since, the roaming feral prisoner gangs had combined, broken, and most importantly – bred. Other than the bodies of those on the planet below, there quite simply was no strategic value in taking it, or trying to rebuild the prisons so long as the war was going on. But then, Aramus knew by now, all those bodies and the souls within them were precisely what the Dark Eldar had been looking for.

Now the space above it was filed with battle once more.

Aramus shook his head as he watched the Angels of Vigilance fly directly into the middle of it all. The numerous Chaos ships were clearly of the Black Legion, but the symbols etched into their ships which even now made the auspex shriek were those that followed Tzeentch. Their shots were frustratingly unerring, and struck out at all of their foes, the new ships that Hector brought forth included. The ork ships did the same, though their fire was more significant in amount and far lesser in accuracy. It did not stop several blasts of lightning from stabbing at the void shields of some of Hector’s ships, stripping the void shields of some of the smaller vessels. At which point the necron ships joined their own fire. A brace of Scythe-class Harvest Ships seemed practically inviolable, despite the weapons being fired at them, and Aramus could not help the shout of outrage as an Imperial frigate was shot to pieces almost casually by secondary weapons.

And the Retribution was right alongside them.

“Thaddeus,” he looked to his friend and battle brother, armor gleaming and twin chainswords for the moment silent holstered on his waist. “Are you ready?”

“Of course, Aramus.”

“Then may the Unknown Primarch watch over us. Kogal,” He called to the apothecary who was currently sitting the command throne, who in turn looked to him. “You have command, then.”

“Very well, Aramus. Don’t make me have to come over there to retrieve your bodies,” the apothecary tilted his head, tone deadly serious.

=============================================================

Despite decades and decades of war across the Aegis Occularis, Aramus had never yet invaded an Eldar vessel in his time as a space marine of the Blood Ravens. That came to an end as the boarding torpedo crashed successfully into part of the ship’s innards, jumping and jarring as it shattered its way through the hull and then the first deck, terminating in a halt halfway through the second and third. The doors slammed open, and immediately a splinter cannon nearly him directly in the torso. Sarrelen stepped forward in front of them all, his custom panoply whirring as every individual weapon spun or otherwise powered up.

“DIE XENOS!” The Tech-Marine declared, voice deepened and louder through the terminator armor’s speakers.

Two combi-assault cannons and two storm bolters began firing all at once, a riotous eruption of sound and fury which filled the ears to overflowing. Rather than stopping, however, Sarrelen simply stepped forward and continuing firing down the corridor they had landed in, allowing Aramus and N’mul to swiftly emerge from the boarding pod. All around them, the Dark Eldar danced, fought, and killed the various boarders that had come to invade them. Orks bellowed and fired their shootas, power klaws snapping and slashing. Chaos Space Marines prayed aloud to the Dark Gods, cackling daemons spewing flame and individual fangs as if they were bullets from their many mouths. And, striding fearlessly and steadily through it all, were the Necrons. Aramus’ first impression of them was disgust, seeing as how at least some of them were draped in the bloody flayed skins of who knew how many victims. The flat and unchanging expressions on their faces, as well as those of other kinds firing glowing green rifles and cannons, only disturbed him further.

“Aramus, watch out!” One of the Salamanders in N’mul’s command squad shouted, and he whirled, hammer swinging, only to be shocked as his blow came to a sudden halt, bouncing off of a large shield wielded by a particularly ornate looking Necron. In its other hand was a large humming blade.

“Hmm! Fascinating!” An incongruously cheery voice echoed from behind it.

Even as the Necron champion, a lychguard if Aramus did not miss his guess, continued to strain against his own weapon, he looked to the speaker. They walked forward slowly; an especially elaborate staff held in one hand. It almost looked as if he wore a cloak and hood, made of the same necrodermis material as everything else. A roar of fury came from nearby, but Aramus could not take a moment to turn his head away from his foe. Especially as they bent backwards, off-balancing him and then began a punishing assault with its weapon, forcing him on the backstep like he had rarely ever been throughout his lifetime. At the same time, whenever he successfully struck a blow, the damage that had shattered bones and armor alike of his foes wriggled and writhed upon the alien’s body. And, much to his anger despite knowing it was coming, it was on the path to repairing itself.

“You are Aramus, the Blood Raven,” the Necron continued to speak, a hand clutching at their chin. “But…no. You are not worth it. I have a surplus of fallen heroes seeking redemption,” an oddly organic tutting sound emerging from that unmoving mouth. “A hundred and one permutations of ‘doing what had to be done and feeling sorry afterwards’ is quite enough, I think.”

“Who…are you…,” he gritted out.

The Necron stopped as it had begun walking past him, absentmindedly forming a gauss blaster with his free hand and firing it through the chest of a charging Chaos Raptor and forced them to their knees. They lowered their staff, firing it once at the barely living Chaos worshipper, who then exploded. At least a dozen nearby Chaos troops screamed out as they were lashed with pain.

“I? Why, I am none other than the curator and archivist of the grandest gallery in all the galaxy,” the Necron swept their now reformed free hand up to their chest. “I am seeker, collector, and protector of the unique. I am-,”

“TRAZYN!” N’mul shouted, firing his multi-melta directly at the Necron.

Rather than striking them, however, a second lychguard appeared from the melee going on all around them, blocking the blow with their shield. It began to glow, quickly, but for the moment, held.

“Yes, that,” the Necron seemed almost put out at being interrupted. “Though, Salamander, I would note that my full title is Trazyn the Infinite,” he added with a projected sound of a clucking tongue. “It is best to be accurate when speaking, I find.”

Rather than respond verbally, N’mul and the rest of his command squad simply attacked once again, despite the fact that Aramus was nearby. They were joined in this effort by another squad of Salamanders. Sarrelen had advanced ahead and was now firing upon every enemy he could find. Thaddeus was engaged in combat with a mutated Chaos Champion. Trazyn, for his part, simply twitched his body in a manner that Aramus would normally associate with rolling one’s eyes, save for the fact the Necron possessed no such thing. In an instant, the Necron was torn apart by the combined fire, melted and blasted apart, pieces going flying. In the instant afterwards, the various pieces began to flicker and shift, until they resembled their exact former existence not at all. The distraction was also enough for Aramus to slam the lychguard down to the ground, hitting it thrice with the Sunderhammer before it stopped moving, shattering its torso to pieces.

“ENOUGH!,” Aramus bellowed despite the fighting going on all around him, stomping up to N’mul and grabbing him by the gorget of his armor to drag him close. “N’mul! I will have answers. Who was that, and why-,”

“We don’t have time for this!” N’mul shouted back, shoving backwards from him. “That wasn’t him. Just another copy. He has done such duplicitous things before. We must hurry!”

And then, to Aramus’ stark disbelief, N’mul turned and ran from him. All of the Salamanders did, in fact, forming up and forming a tight closed-ranks formation that bulled through the ongoing fight across the deck. Aramus boggled at it before ducking away from a charging ork meganob, power klaw sparking and custom shoota sending solid slugs dancing up his power armor.

“N’mul!”

Thaddeus was embattled now, a pair of Dark Eldar wyches practically cartwheeling around him with their power swords. Sarrelen was ducking behind some fallen pieces of wall, multiple alien warriors firing at him.

“N’MUL!”

But the Salamanders did not turn back, and instead disappeared from sight. Aramus snarled in anger as he battered the ork to death and then moved to aid Thaddeus. The cackling of the alien women ended when he slammed Sunderhammer into one’s head, while his battle brother drove his chainswords into the stomach and chest of the other and pulled in opposite directions. The two moved, in silence, to Sarrelen, who had taken out more orks, eldar, and necrons combined than either of them. By sheer weight of fire he had shattered dozens of necrons to pieces, and while some of them were literally pulling themselves back together, others were phasing out entirely in muted swirls of green.

“We need to move,” he growled, both nodding in acknowledgement. “With me!”

He turned, then, and flipped the thunder hammer in his grip around, his knees bending low.

“FOR THE EMPEROR!” He roared the battle cry and then thundered forward, servos in his power armor whirring as he did so, every effort and iota of strength he possessed put into the charge.

None could withstand the charge. The mass and speed were simply too great. Orks were spent flying away, many struck down by Thaddeus and Sarrelen as they moved behind him. Several Dark Eldar died outright as he slammed into them, kabalite armor and the bodies within shattered to meaty chunks by sheer violent kinetic force. Even the Necron warriors were not spared, though being more durable than the two former sort of xenos meant that they were simply knocked aside outside of the one warrior that was struck by his body head on, metal torso breaking away from metal legs. And yet Aramus did not stop. His stamina propelled him forwards, the deck below crunching and shattering in a shallow trench that he formed with naught but his own motion, building the momentum further and further until he finally reached the end of the corridor. An ork meganob burst forth, streaming blood from several wounds, only to laugh with glee at an opponent reaching him. It’s laugh died as he finally unleashed the Sunderhammer, swinging upwards and then downwards with all his might directly upon the orks face. The energy field triggered, releasing the blast of concussive force, and the ork’s face, head, and innards simply ceased to be.

Only then did Aramus pause glance at the ruinous fighting still going on behind them for a few seconds before turning and moving on.

The entire battleship seemed to be possessed by madness. But, he realized within seconds of thought, it was not being destroyed. This was for a reason, whether good or ill remained to be determined. The Angels of Vigilance, he understood. Hector wished to strangle, to crush, to obliterate Endross with his own hands. In person, rather than risk destroying the ship from afar and never be entirely certain that the duplicitous alien was truly dead. This was understandable. Yet the orks were far less restrained. The Necron, he had no such certainties about, but the few reports that existed of their weapons seemed to make certain that if they wished the ship destroyed, they could do so. But they did not. Nor did the servants of the Chaos Gods, who seemed pleased to send forth their daemons, their champions, their cultist servants and slaves. Instead, all had chosen to board, to fight amongst themselves.

“For the Emperor!” Thaddeus shouted as he leapt ahead, chainswords whirring as his jump pack ignited, firing the veteran forward in a fatal horizontal line.

The monomolecularly-edged teeth shredded almost all they touched. The sheer force aided by the jump pack ensured that by kinetic strength alone that what Thaddeus went through were hacked apart. Those that managed to avoid the flashing pair of chainswords were struck and sent flying, bowling others apart or dying outright as bones crunched and broke. Those that survived, or were simply not directly in that path, suffered from the sheer weight of fire that Sarrelen could manage. An amount of ammo expenditure in spent shells that was more appropriate to a pair of razorback tanks fell to the ground, the barrels of every weapon glowing a dull red, well on its way to yellow and white. Aramus, meanwhile, now brought up the rear, keeping Sarrelen’s flanks and rear clear.

Such was how the trio fought through the ship, following the transponder signals from the Salamanders and Angels of Vigilance, from the middle deck where they had landed, right to the bridge.

By the time they reached it, the doors, and portions of the walls, had outright been blown apart, with the dead of all forces present littering the ground. Aramus grimaced at the sight of unmoving Salamander and Angels of Vigilance bodies, scattered amongst the xenos and traitors. But the fighting within the bridge was still clearly ongoing. They did not have more than a few seconds to pause, regroup, and then forge in, this time with Sarrelen in the lead with Thaddeus and Aramus flanking. As such, while Sarrelen began firing the moment he sighted enemies, the other two could step into the bridge and observe, watching with anger and confusion at the morass of anarchy.

More dead littered the ground. Numerous possessed marines spewed blue and pink fire, claws and fangs flashing through the air, all of them bearing the sigil of Tzeentch somewhere on their bodies. Ork nobs and meganobs bellowed and laughed, power klaws snapping and various kustom shoots firing all over the place, only some vaguely towards their enemies. Necron warriors dispassionately fired at everyone present, uncaring when one of theirs was struck down in turn. Power swords and chainswords swung back and forth, held in the hands of the Angels of Vigilance, even as the Salamanders fired upon what foes they could. Neither, however, could risk getting close to the central melee which was taking place in the very middle of the bridge. Over and through shattered consoles and seats, individual slave posts and torture stations, Endross bent and danced through the fight, staff in one hand and slim power sword in the other. A possessed marine which had five arms and three legs bellowed as it struck out not just at the Archon, but at the other opponents as well. Hector was silent, face a rictus of fury, his two-handed power sword swinging back and forth, punctures in his armor leaving blood upon the ground. Also joining them was an especially thickly muscled ork, an enormous cleaver that might possibly have been called a cutlass in one hand which crackled with crude ork technologies. A hat that a small man might have been crushed under was outright stapled to the orks’ head.

“Right,” Aramus stated before a bright flash of green light washed over the entire bridge.

And a quartet of tyranid warriors appeared, just as did what looked exactly like Trazyn the Infinite.

“Ah! And so we are all here, ready for the finale performance,” the Necron drawled, and this time when weapons were fired at him, a scintillating sphere of energy surrounded him, blocking out even multi-melta beams. “Endross! You’ve been the steward of that staff for long enough, don’t you think? Yes, yes, you stole it from the one who stole it from the one who looted it and so on down the lines,” he rolled his free hand in lieu of his eyes. “But as evidenced by, well, all this, I rather think it deserves are more proper steward.”

“Never!” Endross snarled through needled teeth.

“Da shiny stick is mine!” The ork Kaptin bellowed, turning his double barreled shoota on Trazyn ineffectually, even while he kept slashing at Endross.

“Die!” Hector cried aloud.

“Enough of this!” Endross spat before dropping a sphere at his feet which exploded in light and sound as well as concussive force.

Hector, the ork, and the larger possessed marine all went flying, striking the walls. As Aramus and Thaddeus moved in, however, Endross remained almost exactly where he’d previously stood. The mask upon his face prevented any hint of the emotions that might have been roiling within from being exposed, and yet he gestured with the staff once more. This time, everyone was able to see what happened as it fired. A beam of purest scarlet bloomed out of the skull which capped it washing over fully half of the bridge, including a handful of the remaining Dark Eldar within its reach. Within seconds, rust and wear appeared upon the armors of almost all present. Several died outright, shriveling where they stood. The mighty green thews of the ork decayed, skin tightening around rapidly decaying musculature and organs, flesh drooping and greying out even as all armor and weapons ceased functioning. The lines upon Hector’s face deepened, and then deepened again, wrapping his skin tight against his skull, his very teeth beginning to yellow and then depart from his drying gums. His eyes were wide, and then shrank, the very moisture and liquid itself being reduced away.

“HECTOR!” Aramus shouted, horror on his face as the Captain of the 1st Company struggled to his feet before stumbling forward, skin tearing to reveal the yellow and already chipping and breaking bone beneath.

Initially, he tried to reach into the red field, only to tear his left arm back as he felt the incredibly unsettling sensation of it weakening unto near uselessness before he removed it, leaving him to watch helplessly as Hector was reduced to a pile of bone dust inside his armor which – almost mockingly – remained largely pristine, all in the span of a few seconds. Endross laughed into the ensuing silence, starting with a low chuckle that rapidly let loose into a full blown guffaw drenched in inhuman cruelty.

“It is not the aging which might do it, for some creatures,” the Archon said almost conversationally. “It is the lack of air in the lungs. The nutrition in the stomach, the blood, circulating with nothing in it. Starvation. Suffocation. Dehydration. All in quantities that almost all living things must combat, centuries of it all at once.”

Aramus growled, turning on the alien, as did the remainder of the Angels of Vigilance present. Trazyn had simply wrapped his chin lightly in his fingers, as if a contemplative philosopher.

“I will kill you,” Aramus promised, the fingers of his left hand twitching more weakly than they ever had in his time as a space marine.

Endross…laughed.

“No, I think not. This has been amusing enough, a delectable distraction, but I have a quota to meet,” Endross made as if to wave away a gnat.

“I don’t think you shall be escaping so easily,” Trazyn shook his head once. “Is the arrogance of the Eldar truly so limitless?”

“Hah! I should say the same of the Necron!” Endross declared before a series of vox calls began sparking to life.

“Captain Hector! New Dark Eldar ships entering the battlezone! It’s…it’s so many!” The call came through the prematurely aged systems still intact in Hector’s wargear.

“Aramus, you need to get out of there right now. There’s a new Dark Eldar fleet, twice the size of the first!”

“Uh, boss! We’ze gotta go!” A call came to the deceased Kaptin, loudly broadcasting from a crude speaker welded into his gorget.

The glow in Trazyn’s eyes grew brighter before he fired out a lance of deadly energy from his own staff towards Endross, only for the Dark Eldar Archon to drag and then throw a dead Incubi in the way. The Incubi almost looked to dissolve at rapid speed. Behind them, however, Endross was surrounded in a flicker of light before disappearing into a wall which shimmered away to reveal what looked to be a Webway portal. One that shut off less than a second after the Archon’s departure. Rage and outcry followed from many of those present at seeing their target get away, but none were so loud as the few remaining Angels of Vigilance and the Salamanders.

“Oh! Clever. A bit of sport then, is it?” Trazyn spoke calmly. “Well, it seems the race is on.”

Even as N’mul and his Salamanders turned their weapons about, it was too late. Trazyn, along with every other Necron present, faded away with faint green glows marking their spots.

“Kogal,” Aramus seethed. “Activate emergency teleport. Retrieve all Blood Raven and Salamander transponders. And…tell the Angels of Vigilance they need to do the same,” he finished as he looked over Hector’s power armor, dust trickling out of the gorget to rest upon the ground. “Then open a channel to the Angels of Vigilance for me.”

He paused long enough for the light of teleportation to wash over him, planting him in the teleportarium along with a number of others. A blip appeared in the far right corner of his visor’s vision, a note of acknowledgement from Kogal and a notification that

“Attention all Imperial ships. Endross has escaped. We must make a tactical retreat and continue the hunt from a stronger position.

“Never! We must have vengeance for Pervigilium! Cowards! You swore an oath to aid us!”

He groaned, slamming a fist against a wall as his head hung. He knew it was likely, more than likely, but he had held hope that some reason might prevail.

“Captain Menon,” Aramus pleaded, “We are in a precarious position precisely because we ran ahead without proper consideration of the battlefield. We can win, but not here. Not now!”

“Commander, the Dark Eldar ships have already wiped out most of the Chaos fleet, the remainder are fleeing. The orks are in similar straights, though they seem less inclined to retreat,” Kogal said hurriedly through the Blood Raven command vox, driving Aramus to grind his teeth. “The Necron ships are gone already, we can’t seem to track where they went.

“Brother Menon think! Do you genuinely think that our ships can withstand the enemy in time for us to figure out whichever ship Endross might have transported to? Without surely dying long before!?” Aramus yelled now. “There will be no vengeance taken here if you all die within the next few minutes because you were too foolish to pull back! I will continue the hunt for Endross without you, if you choose to make a pyre of yourselves here, but do not dare call me an oathbreaker for wanting to actually succeed in fulfilling it rather than commit suicide!”

Several seconds passed by, each one seeming longer than the next, before Menon spoke again.

“We shall retreat…for now, and take stock of what we have lost here,” Menon sounded pained beyond belief as he said it.

“Thank you, Menon,” Aramus sighed. “Set coordinates to Kantrael, we can make repairs at the Forge World.”

“…Acknowledged.”

Aramus inhaled deeply and then swept Sunderhammer up to block the passageway that the Salamanders had begun approaching once they’d regrouped after the emergency passageway. He turned and glared at them with enough heated intensity that even the sons of Nocturne had to take pause. Their expressions were an indeterminate mix of frustration, anger, and shellshock, all of which swiveled now to focus on his own bared teeth. A rumbling shook throughout the ship as automatic warnings of warp transition went out, the Gellar fields flickering to life to gird it as it fled the battlefield. Aramus, however, kept his glare steady throughout the process.

“I am done with waiting on answers and explanations. We just cost the Imperium a good man, and many more besides!” He snarled. “N’mul! Calidus! We shall have words. Not tomorrow. Not an hour from now. Right. Now.”

Only then did he lower Sunderhammer, gesturing into the depths of the Retribution with a curt gesture. The two called out Salamanders glanced between once another for a moment before N’mul exhaled sharply through his nose and nodded.

“I owe you that much, Aramus,” he said quietly.

“I think we both know you owe me more than that,” Aramus snapped. “But it seems that this will have to suffice.”

==================================================================

“The Song of Entropy,” Sarrelen repeated. “Quite a name.”

The meager thimble’s worth of Blood Ravens had all come at Aramus’ call, all save for their Tomb-Epistolary who was being allowed to slumber. For all that a psyker could, dreadnought or otherwise, when passing through the Warp. The Salamanders, for their part, had not asked for others of their number to come with them save for their own Senior Tech-Marine, leaving N’mul and Calidus and Cendium at a numerical advantage. Almost all of them still bore wet blood and battle damage across their power armor, the stink of battle and near over-heated metal filling the air. Even as they looked across the table at one another, the barrels of Sarrelen’s various weapons tinged and popped as the metal cooled.

“It is more than that,” Calidus said slowly. “The Song of Entropy is not of alien make. It is one of the legendary lost artifacts of Vulkan himself.”

A collective intake of breaths came across the Blood Ravens, save for Nereus, who was utterly silent as ever.

“But…how did…,” Aramus began and then stopped himself. “How could…?”

“It is a tragic tale,” the Librarian cupped at his chin before shaking his head. “And yet, it must be told.”

So it was, though Aramus could tell there were a great many parts edited out. Whether for brevity or secrecy, or some other third thing, he could not quite decide. Either way, the Blood Ravens listened as the Librarian told of T’kell, of the Chalice of Fire, and so much more. The hunt, the artifacts found, and the prophecies supposedly surrounding them. Of what it might mean, truly, with that most dangerous of all things – hope – that might somehow lead to the return of a Primarch. To say that the Blood Ravens were not swept up in that same momentous hope would be an understatement. Thought they knew not their own Primarch, they could not help but heartily commiserate in their hearts of such a possibility. Not only for themselves, for the Salamanders, but for the Imperium as a whole. None, however, showed it on their faces. Only Aramus left his face bare, the others concealed by helms and rebreathers, the latter in Nereus’ case.

“The latest, before this, was the Gauntlet of the Forge,” Calidus concluded, voice slightly hoarse. “It was torn from the Eldar Pirate Lord, Iath Bloodweaver by our Forgemaster Vulkan He’Stan.”

“It has to be the Song of Entropy in Endross’ foul grip,” N’mul jumped in, his red eyes almost literally burning in their sockets. “The size, the shape, the look, the effects. We have examined and re-examined every helmet recording a dozen times each. It has to be the Song of Entropy,” he repeated, nearly vibrating in his armor.

“More than once in the past, Trazyn the Infinite has attempted to steal from the Salamanders,” Calidus said calmly, a hand coming to rest on N’mul’s pauldron. “In 878.M41 and again in the Tochran Crusade. He sought to steal the artifacts that the Chapter Master bears, but in both occasions Vulkan He’Stan defeated him in personal combat and crushed him. But every time,” Calidus shook his head, aggrieved. “He re-emerged, or escaped, or…his title as ‘the Infinite’ seems dangerously appropriate. It does not matter how many times he is struck down, he just reappears again in a new body.”

Aramus raised an eyebrow, his arms still crossed across his chest as they had been since the start.

“Aramus, you must understand, we had to be sure. We could not-,”

“Tell me?” He interrupted, looking between the two. “Trust me? How many decades has it been since we,” he gestured at his fellow Blood Ravens, “Rescued you from certain death, N’mul?”

The obsidian skin of N’muls face pinched as he ducked his head.

“Aramus-,”

“No,” Aramus slammed a hand down on the table, wincing at his still weakened left arm rattled with it. “You’ve both talked enough. Now it is my turn to speak. We have fought alongside you across more than five sectors. We have…have ferried you in all that time,” his voice trembled with his anger. “You know our shame, as a Chapter. You know my shame, as a space marine of the Imperium. I have no more secrets!” He slammed a hand against his chest and his many purity seals. “I have been scoured, laid bare before the flames of war and burnt again and again. This penitence, that I have been sent forth on by my Chapter Master, was and is deserved. The lies, the machinations of xenos and traitors alike I have dealt with. But…this?” He swept his hand out. “How many of your brothers died on that ship? How many Angels of Vigilance?”

His chest heaved with emotion, and it took a considerable amount of will to calm himself somewhat.

“Why, N’mul? I called you all my brothers. After all we’ve been through, all we have fought against and survived? Why would you not simply…tell me?” He could not hide the pain in the question.

N’mul and Calidus flinched.

“We had to be sure,” N’mul eventually said, but his voice was dull and he did not look up. “There have been presumed sightings before. Incorrect interpretations of the Tome of Fire.”

“I don’t care!” Aramus scoffed. “Hector is dead because he did not know what he faced. I could be dead,” he pointed at his weakened arm. “Because I did not know. Terminator armor can gird against almost anything, save – apparently – from such a field as cast by your Primarch’s workings. Hector did not have the agility or speed to move out of the way, because he did not know he needed it!”

It was almost a physical blow, the words rocking the Salamander’s heads back.

“We could have adjusted our tactics, tried to land somewhere else on the ship, altered wargear loadouts. But we did not, because we didn’t know,” Aramus growled. “There are casualties in war, there always will be, but you will have to forgive me for the fact that we were able to preserve Salamanders for so long, when I could not for my own battle brothers, only to start losing them precipitously the moment we became involved in this hunt!” His bitterness was so acrid it nearly burnt the air itself.

Finally, Aramus fell silent.

“…so what do we do now, Aramus?” N’mul whispered.

“I don’t know, Salamander,” Aramus said coldly, foregoing any of the more familiar terms. “Aside from finishing this hunt. Which may very well be the last thing we do with you on my ship. Now. If you will excuse me, Kogal dearly wishes to see just how badly I may have harmed myself through ignorance.”

It was not a direct dismissal, but it didn’t need to be to get the two Salamanders to leave the chamber. In the days that followed, retreating to the nearest Forge World for repairs, there was much cooling in the previously warm relations between the two Chapters. For the first time since they had first arrived, the Salamanders felt almost unwelcome on the Retribution which had housed them for decades. The Blood Ravens, so few in number upon their own ship, became almost as recluses. Wounds were seen to, maintenance of wargear was seen to, and tallies were made of both material and physical losses. Aramus spent much of his time in the ship’s Apothecarium, his left arm up to halfway past the elbow suffering from near fatal nutrient loss, decayed and nearly dead from what tests proved was near a century of rapid entropic abuse. If he had not removed his arm so swiftly, Kogal declared, he would have lost the arm entirely. As it was, it would take possibly weeks of treatment to return to form, time they would not necessarily have.

Over Kantrael less than a week later, the folly of rushing in so unprepared and blinded by fury were made manifest. Of the collected Angels of Vigilance fleet, every ship had suffered damage. The escorts for their entire Chapter had been blown to pieces by so many opposing forces, even when just taking minor attacks of opportunity. The speed and deadliness of the new Dark Eldar fleet had shown, managing to destroy other ships even as they tried to flee. The Angels of Vigilance were not immune to this, and the venerable battle barge Shield of Pervigilium had been cored and cut to pieces by powerful Dark Eldar weaponry. They had but one battle barge, and two strike cruisers, left now. A significant force, compared to the lonesome Retribution, but the Kabal had shown definitively that it possessed strength far in excess of what any of them had wished to believe. They were no mere raiders, picking and cutting in thousands and hundreds without warning. The Exquisite Blade were capable of outright planetary invasions, and their fleet had displayed this in violent excess.

“So. We are now all agreed, yes?” Aramus grunted, glancing at N’mul and Menon. “We know now how powerful a force that Endross can bring to bear. He willingly sacrificed over half of a powerful enough fleet to draw in his various pursuers into a trap. We must proceed more cautiously.”

Menon, now the last of the Captains of the further depleted Angels of Vigilance, struggled to nod. The fury of his chapter was as bright as ever, but their numbers were even fewer after the debacle of their last battle. Worse, the Shield of Pervigilium had carried the majority of their remaining gene-seed, the stores on their now lost homeworld stolen and likely utilized for horrific purpose by the Dark Eldar. N’mul, for his part, seemed to have settled somewhat from the reckless heated fury that had driven him and his Salamanders almost berserk when chasing after the Song of Entropy. All of the Salamander had, for which Aramus was dearly thankful. The veteran sergeant nodded swiftly and simply, saying nothing.

“We don’t know precisely where he is going next. But Endross cannot remain in the Cadian Sector any longer, not with us reporting on his whereabouts and activities to Sector Command,” Aramus continued. “Not if he wishes to keep up with his ‘quota’, whatever monstrous number that might end up being.”

“His forces outnumber us greatly. Too greatly to try and meet in open battle without ensuring our own deaths,” Menon ground out. “How can we catch and kill a quarry that outmatches us?”

“He doesn’t outmatch us,” Aramus made a cutting motion through the air. “Not truly. He simply has too many bodies and ships to prevent us from reaching him successfully. The moment the struggle against him grows to be too much, he falls back upon the Song. Remember that. As it is, the Librarians of our three Chapters have conferred, and they believe through the Emperor’s Tarot that he will head to a place of such madness that even we could not follow.”

“Not the Eye, surely,” N’mul pulled his head back.

“No,” Menon shook his head, eyes unblinking. “The Agrippina Sector.”

“Correct,” Aramus nodded. “Every major star system outside of Agrippina proper has been lost to Chaos forces. Everything else is anarchy, whole populations of worlds given over to Chaos or more mundane madness, the majority of the Great Enemy’s strength focused on actual hard targets now – they don’t have the numbers to spare for garrisons.”

“Hive Worlds. Agri-Worlds. Without protectors or abusers, just the masses themselves,” N’mul whispered, eyes wide with horror. “They will be swept through like grain crops before a hurricane.”

Finally, however, Aramus grinned. It was a grim, dark thing, but a smile all the same.

“As ever, the alien underestimates humanity.”

Both marines looked at him with tilted heads and slightly opened mouths.

“We just received a communication from Sector Command. The Phalanx is holding position over Cadia itself. But massive portions of the reinforcement fleet from Terra are assembling not just to aid in the defense of the rest of the Cadian Sector, but to reclaim all of Agrippina – or at least enough to keep safe the vital supply lines between the two Sectors.”

Aramus straightened, feeling that kindled flame in his heart growing stronger not just within himself but in the hearts of the other two as well.

“And we shall be joining them.”

=======================================================================

They came together with the rest of the Imperial fleet, battleships and cruisers and escorts aplenty, over the world of Exeltra Minor. The Agri-World was non-functional, at this point, but it served as a staging ground nonetheless. Though the fight between the Night Lords and Relictors Chapter had been decades ago, a passing battlegroup of Chaos ships had decided to casually burn much of the planet with their weapons while waiting for new orders. As such, what had once been a planet filled with plants meant to be processed into nutrient blocks was now a mostly blackened orb that hung in the void with a stripped atmosphere. In truth, the presence of a number of other Chapters made it so that by the time the meager fleet of the Angels of Vigilance and the Retribution reached them they were more of a foot note.

Or so they had thought.

“Commander?” The serf’s voice was strained. “We…we have a boarding order.”

Aramus paused and looked way from the actuality sphere.

“Boarding…order? Not a request?”

“Commander,” the serf coughed. “They are identifying as the Adeptus Custodes. The cogitators have automatically verified their authenticity. The…the machine spirits are already preparing bay 9A.”

A pin could have dropped across the entire strategium.

“Accept the…the order,” Aramus said hoarsely before tapping into the shipwide vox. “Attention all hands. The…the Adeptus Custodes are coming to board the ship.”

To try and describe the frantic activity that took place across the ship would be impossible. To say that servo skulls were released in their totality to begin cleansing and scrubbing procedures would not truly encapsulate what the cloud of white floating probes looked like flooding the hallways. Serfs scrubbed and cleaned armors, the docking bays were swept through, and all and sundry on the ship began attempting to prepare their finest wargear. Within an hour, those that could filled into the docking bay where the incoming ship. It was not, in fact, a Thunderhawk. Rather, the aurumite and gold gleamed upon a Stormbird, one of the legendary transports utilized throughout the Great Crusade that had become as myth in the current era. All of the Blood Ravens, the Salamander leadership, as well as those of the Angels of Vigilance, the two Magos and the Palantine with her Celestian Squad had formed up. Despite everything, they were a remarkably powerful force, wielding advanced and deadly wargear, that had seen some of the worst the galaxy had to offer throughout the 13th Black Crusade.

They, universally, felt as fumbling primitive children when the Adeptus Custodes emerged from the Stormbird. With crackling guardian spears by some, an unknown sort of bolt weapon held by others, all draped in individualized auramite power armor, the least of which made the greatest ceramite masterpieces worn by those present seem lesser, the Custodes marched in two-by-two out of the Stormbird. Aramus could barely bring himself to breathe, something that seemed to be true across all the others throughout the docking bay. The Sisters of Battle looked close to passing out entirely, if he didn’t miss how they were purposefully locking the legs of their power armor to keep themselves standing. Finally, the Shield-Captain emerged, conical helm and mask expressionless at the very end. Escorted by none, and likely needing none, he stalked forwards with the rest of the Custodes bracketing him on both sides, facing outwards in something a second away from assuming deadly defensive posture.

Aramus, along with all of the others, fell to their knees in kneeling positions well before the Custodes reached them.

The greatest of sorceries, the most powerful of alien trickery, could not possibly – Aramus hoped – ever come close to matching the true presence and power of the Adeptus Custodes. It was a pressure, a weight, that seemed to fall upon them all in unison from physical closeness and gaze alone. They were utterly breathless now, waiting for the first word. The Custodes had not spoken a single word other than silent informing them of their approach.

“Where is the Blood Raven known as Thaddeus?” The voice was deep and rich and…tinged with something that sounded like but could not possibly be annoyance.

All felt frozen as the Custodes looked left and right.

“You,” he pointed, correctly as it turned out, directly at Thaddeus as he knelt. “Yes. Your face matches the recordings.”

“My lord, I-,”

“We would see the armor that you claim to possess,” the Shield-Captain interrupted. “The armor that you claim was once worn by one of the 10,000.”

The blood could not have drained out of Thaddeus’ face faster than if a Dark Eldar Haemonculus had forced it from him with machines. He had chosen to wear a plain and unadorned set of power armor, bereft of any accolades lest they had made him look to be trying to be more self-important. Or so Thaddeus had told Aramus.

“O-of course, my lord.”

“You,” Aramus jumped as the Custodes looked to him next. “And you, the Tech-Marine. You shall accompany us to the armory.”

In the end, there was nothing they could do but accede to the Custodes commands. In total silence, the Shield-Captain following along behind them, the three Blood Ravens moved to the armory where Thaddeus stored his wargear. There, held in pride of place in the center of the secondary armory, lay the wargear which the Chapter’s records denoted as having been worn on the battle of the Vengeful Spirit that saw Sanguinius dead and the Emperor laid low. It had, through all they had been through, seemed near inviolable. All maintenance required had been performed, but it had never seemed to take harm in the manner as other equipment, even terminator armor. Nearby lay the other two weapons the records claimed were of Custodes origin, as it never seemed right to take them too far from one another when in storage.

Looking at them now, however, Aramus felt something quietly despair in his mind.

“…Hmph,” the Shield-Captain said after a moment, reaching forward to place a hand against the armor.

The look on Thaddeus face equaled his own. Sarrelen’s was concealed by his helmet, but his mechadendrites were limp in his servo-harness. Aramus knew why, as well. He felt it himself. That yawning abyss which had just opened up in front of them. Caught up in the ecstasy of the Adeptus Custodes choosing their ship to walk upon, to speak to them, and they had not realized the implications.

“Yes. It is you, isn’t it,” the Shield-Captain said quietly, leaning forward until their head lightly rested against the chest.

Slowly, they turned and placed their hands now upon the bolter and flamer. Both of incredibly archaic but undeniably potent design. Weapons that Thaddeus had rarely ever used, favoring close melee combat as he did. Aramus, Sarrelen, all of the Blood Ravens and Salamanders alike had dared not wield them in excess either. The armor had been one thing, a matter of protection and survival, but Thaddeus did not wear it often after the Bloody Hill. Out of respect, and reverence.

“I would see the records,” the Shield-Captain eventually said. “Of when the Blood Ravens supposedly…acquired these items. And how.”

Aramus cleared his throat.

“The records are incomplete, lord Custodes, but-,”

“Aristos,” the Shield-Captain said. “You may call me Aristos. It is one of my names, but the sole one you shall have of me. As for your records…I shall peruse them with my own eyes.”

Aramus bowed at the waist, again crushed beneath the authority in those words.

“At once.”

Then they were on the move again, only to startle momentarily at the presence of two more Custodes that had apparently followed them without them noticing, now taking up guard positions in front of the armory. Straight to the main cogitator bank, with Sarrelen swiftly granting complete and total access to the Custodes. A remote link opened up immediately, the source obscured but firmly identified as belonging to the Custodes elsewhere to the fleet, one not to be closed off or touched.

“Mmm. More complete than I was expecting, given the faltering of your Chapter.”

Aramus grit his teeth and looked away, shame burning in his face.

“We…were sent on our Penitent Crusade before the Chapter’s Civil War,” he replied. “Our ship’s records suffered no damage from the fighting.”

“And yet,” Aristos turned so swiftly that Aramus nearly missed it until his face was but a few inches away. “Your records do not tell us of your Primarch. It begins quite abruptly, in fact.”

Though the Shield-Captain had not adjusted his posture, potential violence flooded the entire strategium in a manner that Aramus had previously only believed vile alien technologies or powerful psykers might manage.

“That…is the shame of the Blood Ravens, yes,” Aramus said quietly, looking down.

“So many supposed exchanges. Yet the three items which matter most, are given almost nothing on their acquisition or retrievals. Only a long, long list of battles fought in, glories won. A number under the orders of your previous Chapter Master.”

“Azariah Kyras was a traitor and a madman, but we ended him, and all of the other traitors in our Chapter!” Aramus did not know why he spoke so frantically, save that instinct compelled him to.

The Custodes was silent for a moment, but it felt as if lascannons were raking across Aramus where that gaze tracked across his body. A brimming and almost otherworldly fury had suffused the Custodes in that instant, though his body language and armor showed it not, to the point that Aramus could almost smell it.

A single inhale through the nose.

“I believe you.”

Aramus did not quite slump in his armor in relief, but it was a close thing.

“It is to be expected. Every son a disappointment or failure in some way or another,” Aristos shook his head slowly. “And the sons of those sons, and so on and so on,” he grunted.

The Blood Raven did not dare reply, the indignance that should have welled up in him nonexistent. For the Custodes had witnessed it all, he knew. From before the beginning of the Great Crusade, to afterwards. The whole of the Great Crusade, and all that had come afterwards. The weary bitterness with which Aristos spoke crystallized in Aramus’ mind. How many tens of thousands of space marines had they watched over ten thousand years fall to Chaos, or falter in an infinity of other ways? They, who guarded the Golden Throne, who could not help but watch as it happened again and again. In that moment, Aramus felt more shame than he ever had before in his entire life, even when sent on Penitent Crusade, at the utter disappointment that the whole of the Adeptus Astartes must seem to the Adeptus Custodes. It burned at him so painfully that he might well have vaporized in his armor, leaving nothing behind but ash.

“My judgement is thus: The Blood Ravens did not deliberately steal or rob of the dead,” Aristos continued. “But your continued possession, rather than returning these honored arms to Terra, is not nearly so forgivable.”

Aramus could not do anything but nod. Behind him, Thaddeus and Sarrelen stiffened slightly in their armor.

“Lord Aristos, please. I was the one to wear the armor, I-,” Thaddeus pleaded before Aristos held a finger up, which proved more than enough to silence him.

“Your deeds are minor legends across the 13th Black Crusade, Aramus of the Blood Ravens. Fighting alongside the Great Wolf himself. The Battle of the Bloody Hill, though rumor and speculation abound about it. Stopping the Green Kroosade and being crucial to the reclamation of Mordax Prime. Killer of champions, defender of the Imperium,” Aristos drawled, each deed somehow reduced in magnitude and importance simply by passing through his lips. “By the inkling of the Inquisition, by your association with the Salamanders and Adeptas Sororitas, you are judged pure enough by others.”

But not, necessarily, by the Custodes, it went unsaid.

“If you must kill me, kill me, but leave the rest of my brothers, please,” Aramus inhaled deeply, holding himself at attention. “It was my responsibility.”

“It was the responsibility of your Chapter to return this wargear to its proper owners immediately, rather than parade around in it as if you had ever done anything to deserve them!” Aristos shot back, his yell a sickle that cut through the rest of the barely existent chatter on the strategium. “Every second that it remained in your Chapter’s armories is a near blasphemy against the whole of the Adeptus Custodes and the Emperor!”

Aramus rocked back on his heels from those words, but Thaddeus was the one who fell to his knees.

“Lord Aristos. Please-,”

“It was your commander’s decision to not deliver it unto the Custodes. And his commander’s decisions. And so on, stretching back not just through your time under the so-called leadership of Azariah Kyras, but the Chapter Masters and Chief Librarians before them,” Aristos seethed.

Then, suddenly, he stopped.

“There is no point in demanding that your Chapter give us their necks,” Aristos said, voice suddenly filled with bone-deep exhaustion. “It would merely be hundreds of corpses that would not be pointed – for a time at least before inevitably failing again – at the enemies of the Emperor. At a crucial time such as this, upon the crux, with Abbadon’s strength waxing despite all efforts to the contrary.”

A shaky breath came from Thaddeus, and he did not rise from where he’d fallen to his knees.

“This shall remain in your records for eternity. And in ours, in case your records end up…damaged,” Aristos moved to the cogitators, entering new data. “A black mark upon your Chapter, for hoarding like greedy children that which you did not deserve. All the Custodes shall know of you for your blasphemy.”

Shame burned the souls of all who heard him speak.

“We shall reclaim that which is ours. None shall spend a moment more in your hands,” he continued on, voice as hard as adamantium. “I could demand that all of you Blood Ravens present your necks, but…,” he sighed, releasing that ancient exhaustion into the air once more. “There wouldn’t be a point.”

The Custodes shook his head.

“Another Chapter would simply rise up and disappoint us in your wake. Such are the failures of the Primarchs,” he sneered, seemingly coming close to spitting if he were not still wearing his helmet.

There was a beat before Aramus spoke again, steeling himself to look the Custodes in the eyes once again.

“Then…what shall happen to us?”

Aristos scoffed.

“The Ten Thousand shall know and scorn your entire Chapter. Do you wish to lay your neck before my blade?”

When he was but a sergeant, he had been struck by a moment of crystallized realization during the Hadrian Campaign. After viewing the tactical maps, listening to reports and recon, he had seen the single thread which led him behind enemy lines and to the supermassive artillery emplacement which had stymied the entire campaign. It had happened again in the first and second Aurelian Crusades. It had led him across the whole of the 13th Black Crusade. Information collected, analyzed, and stored with conclusions drawn from them. Amidst the burning shame of what had been done, what had been said, that moment of realization appeared once more. It took everything Aramus had not to react outwardly.

It was an out.

A mercy couched in thousands of years of weariness and disappointment, in exhaustion and frustration.

For in truth, had the Adeptus Custodes demanded the Blood Ravens punished punitively and fully for their transgressions, theirs, and their past brothers, then no force in the Imperium would have granted them succor. Not even the Emperor himself. Aramus knew for a fact that it was entirely possible that most of the Chapter would simply kneel and present themselves to the Custodes for execution. How could they not? Even now, some part of him strained to do exactly that. Thaddeus had gone even further, falling to his knees, pride and worth torn from them in less than half an hour since the Custodes arrival.

“No, Lord Aristos. I can only swear to work until my dying breath to try and expunge this shame.”

“You will die failing to do so,” Aristos said coolly. “But that you will at least strive to be better than you are is somewhat commendable. Perhaps you might prove something of worth in the reclaiming of the Agrippina Sector.”

It happened in a split second. Before Aramus and Thaddeus could even begin to think of looking at one another, the Shield-Captain seemed to sharpen while standing still. How he realized it, Aramus would never know.

“You are not here to fight in the reclamation,” Aristos declared. “Astonishing. You’ve managed to disappoint even faster than I thought was possible.”

“We are,” Aramus said quickly. “We are, but there is more to it as well.”

Aristos thumped the butt of his guardian spear.

“Speak, Blood Raven.”

Aramus inhaled deeply. There was no possibility hesitation.

“A short time ago, the Imperial world of Pervigilium was rendered barren of human life…” he began.

Throughout it all, the Shield-Captain did not shift. He did not even appear to breathe. But, neither did he interrupt.

“The Emperor’s Tarot, as best our foresight can tell, the signs point to him descending to a den of madness as it is scoured clean by light,” Aramus said. “We believe it to be Agrippina. More than a hundred million human souls have been lost to the Exquisite Blade, and their possession of the Song of Entropy is an insult besides. We aim to journey into Agrippina, and hunt down the Exquisite Blade as well as battle the forces of Chaos. This, I swear to you, is the truth.”

Aristos was silent.

“It is not the worst excuse I have ever heard for lying about one’s purposes.”

“Lord Aristos-,”

“Enough,” the Shield-Captain raised a hand, silencing Aramus. “I have had enough of this ship, this Chapter. We are done here.”

Abrupt and coarse as their arrival was, the departure of the Adeptus Custodes was even worse. The serfs wept out of sight, not knowing they could still be heard. The Sisters of Battle whispered amongst themselves as they looked on. The Tech-Priests glanced at one another and returned to their own cadres. The Salamanders, sons of Vulkan, of the 1st Founding, were not spoken to by the Custodes at all. In the end, the ancient stormbird lifted off and flew back out of the Retribution, leaving those on the strike cruiser shellshocked, shamefaced, and staggering back to their quarters. The Blood Ravens, one and all, felt as if they had been flayed open and scraped with a sharp blade on the innards of their minds, bodies, and souls. Thaddeus more than any, however, for it was he who had worn the golden armor even once, now knowing that once was too many.

The cloud of despair which had sprung upon them all in the departure of the shining light of the angered Custodes seemed to cling to the very walls. It would take much to banish. As such the next arrivals, only a day later as the last of the Imperial strike force finished assembling over the ruins of Exeltra Minor, proved even more shocking.

================================================================

Fist slammed on chests in resounding salute from every member of the Salamanders 7th Company.

“Hail, Chapter Master Tu’Shan!” The call echoed out from every throat.

Now it was the Blood Ravens who stood off to the side, the Salamanders taking the forefront. The trio of thunderhawks that had landed in the Retributions docking bay had released their full compliments. It was impossible to mistake the legendary Firedrakes for any other Salamander Company. Behind them, hanging in the void at a distance that could prove dangerously close if they had any cause for conflict, close enough for Aramus to see through the void shields, was a tremendous fleet of vessels. Battle barges and strike cruisers blotted out the stars visible from within the bay, escort ships flitting this way and that as well. N’mul bowed his head as the Chapter Master of the Salamanders approached, his mighty honor guard flanking him and the Forgefather just behind him and to the right. Their mighty and legendary wargear gleamed under the lights of the docking bay.

“N’mul,” the Chapter Master said, voice warm through his helmet. “It has been too long.”

“I am honored by your presence,” N’mul bowed further.

“If what you have found is true, if you have truly found the Song of Entropy,” Tu’Shan shook his head, “Then it is we who are honored by you.” The Chapter Master then turned to the Blood Ravens. “And these, then, must be the Blood Ravens who have fought by your side for all these years.”

Aramus saluted, feeling the weight and power of the Chapter Master of a 1st Founding Chapter fall upon him.

“Chapter Master Tu’Shan, you honor us with your presence. I am Force Commander Aramus, of the Blood Ravens. With me are Sergeant Thaddeus, Scout Nereus, Apothecary Kogal, and Tech-Marine Sarrelen. Our sixth brother is, unfortunately, interred within a dreadnought and currently slumbers.”

Tu’Shan shook his head.

“The honored dead should be allowed to rest. Fear not, young Blood Raven. N’mul reports you a trustworthy ally and friend, and I intend to believe his words until you should prove otherwise,” the elder Salamander nodded, clapping him on the pauldron. “Your deeds elsewhere in the Black Crusade have proven you are stalwart and trustworthy enough, I should think. Still,” he slipped his hand off and looked upon them all. “I know that this began as a hunt for justice, for the deaths of all of Pervigilium’s citizens and for those of the Angels of Vigilance. And know this, then,” Tu’Shan straightened further, his helmet’s lenses almost glowing with some inner light. “The Archon Endross and his Exquisite Blade shall die for their crimes. The Angels of Vigilance will have their vengeance before this is done. And the Song of Entropy shall return to the Sons of Vulkan.”

Less than a day later, the orders came through.

The task force was moving into Agrippina.

==================================================================

The first re-encounter with the Exquisite Blade was at accursed Lelithar. The world that had held host to the so-called Voice of the Emperor, which had broken out in rebellion following the false prophet. In the decades since the total loss of Imperial control over the system, it had only grown worse. Hundreds of millions of humans driven to madness. Many of them fell to worship of Chaos, others following false conceptions and visions of the Emperor that would have seen even the mildest of priests burning them for heresy. The lattermost were left alive for sport, for sacrifices, by the forces of Chaos who reigned over the world. The void above was heavily fortified, for the planet marked one of the most stable warp lanes leading between the two sectors. For the forces of Chaos, who desired to claim all of Agrippina, all of Cadia, and all of the galaxy for themselves, keeping said route secured was within their best interests. As such, when the Imperial fleet appeared on the edges of the system, it was to watch the forces of the Iron Warriors and the Black Legion battling back against the fleet of the Exquisite Blade. Already, dozens of fast-moving alien transports were quite liberally scooping up whole chunks of the human populace below. Worshippers of Chaos or madmen they might have been, but that the aliens would benefit from their capture was unacceptable.

As one, the Angels of Vigilance, the Retribution, and the assembled Chapter Fleet of the Salamanders advanced. With them, though pursuing different targets, were detachments of other Chapters. Several of them were Imperial Fist Successors, but others were of more distant origins. The actuality sphere was as busy as it had ever been, even over Cadia in the initial days, that left Aramus having to work to take in all of the data streams and interpret them all. Behind astartes ships flying into close range, dozens of cruisers fired lance arrays at long range, supported by nova cannon blasts and salvoes shot from numerous battleships.

To the howls of fury of many, however, the Exquisite Blade utilized their superior speed and maneuverability to simply withdraw steadily as the planet rotated, enslaving, and capturing all the while, until the forces of Chaos were a bulwark to the Imperium’s ships. An advance could not be made without either sustaining critical damage from Chaos ships and planetary defenses or stopping to remove such things in the first place. By the time that the latter could be done, however, the Exquisite Blade ships had escaped the system, though they had left a smattering of cruisers in broken pieces by the end of it. Meanwhile, landings had to be done on the planet below, to shatter the bastions there and take on the millions of Chaos worshippers that had been born into their faith, knowing only hatred for those who had come to ‘liberate’ them. Another week would pass before pacifications enough could be performed that the fleet would move on. Legends such as the Chapter Master of the Salamanders, and of course the Custodes, distinguished themselves above every other group.

========================================================

Yayor, once an Agri-World that was a major contributor to the entire Sector and beyond, had been malformed by the touch of Chaos after too long. Not unto the point of being a Daemon World, but it was certainly on its way to such things. The crops now walked, and hungered for blood and gristle to feed themselves. The groves screamed, every fruit an explosive sphere that erupted in toxic smoke and fire. Of those unfortunates who had survived the initial battles there, who had at one point been saved by the Dark Angels and Space Wolves before they were taken under the yoke of Chaos once again, the decades had not been kind. No longer were they the tenders of life, they were the prey. The tribes that had formed in the aftermath of the two apocalypses that had fallen on them painted themselves in the sigils of Chaos out of fear, in hopes of protection. It didn’t work, in truth, neither against the malevolent landscape or from the Dark Eldar.

Again, the forces of Chaos had fortified the system’s void, preparing for the inevitable day that the forces of the Imperium would attempt to reclaim what had once been theirs. Again, they battled the Dark Eldar. Again, the Imperial fleet fought both head on. What was different from before, however, was the appearance of a large fleet of orks, seemingly chasing rumors either of whatever it was that Endross carried, or more likely simply chasing the next satisfactory battle.

In the end, another world burned in the fires of war, hundreds of thousands dying as ships were torn apart in the void. Boarding was done, boarding was countered, and over the course of a single day Aramus stepped foot on the decks of two separate ork ships, three Chaos ships, and one more Dark Eldar ship. It was then, embattled on all sides, that Aramus of the Blood Ravens fought alongside the Firedrakes and elements of other companies of the Salamanders upon the flagship. To speak of that battle would be to tell of blinding firestorms of weapons fire, and of reaching the bridge. Again, Endross was confronted, and yet again, Endross escaped – this time by sacrificing a host of hundreds of horribly powerful grotesques to bar the hunters from their quarry. It was one thing to face grotesques. It was another to face those that had been crafted by the Exquisite Blade’s haemonculus contacts.

For these were grotesques that bore the remnants of power armor, and purposefully crude brands and carvings which marked them out as once being true Angels of Vigilance. Bolt pistols had been surgically implanted into their chests and shoulders, and chainswords, power swords, and combat knives were attached across their limbs. Litanies of cowardice and pain had been etched with acid into their hides and exposed bone, an extended joke and barb by the Dark Eldar for the space marines to find once they had killed the wailing wretches. It was a battle of horrors, of desecration, of beings that outright demanded extermination for their crime of existence. Here, the Angels of Vigilance, Salamanders, and Blood Ravens were joined in battle by none other than the Custodes, if only for a short amount of time. The small host was ceaseless in their movements, seemingly inviolable as they moved from ship to ship, from battlefield to battlefield.

=======================================================

Strategists on both sides knew the truth – the battle for the sector came down to none other than the Agrippina system itself. The forces of Chaos throughout the whole of the sector realized that they must break the lynchpin of Imperial efforts once and for all – to take the system now was to shatter the purpose and effort of the Imperium in the sector, to remove a blemish and defiant spot that had remained since the beginning. To lose would be to allow the Imperium to gain all the momentum required to overwhelm the rest of the Sector in the name of the Corpse-Emperor, especially with the newly retaken warp route back into the Cadian Sector. For years, the fleets of Chaos had successfully resisted Imperial probes from without, but with supply lines stretched as thin as they were they could not withstand a fight from within as well. For the part of the Imperium, they knew as well that victory could bring a wave of success, whilst failure could end up causing knock on effects from Cadia to Terra considering how much of Battlefleet Solar had contributed to the fight going on in Obscurus.

For the Dark Eldar, the hunters had become so glutted with prey that they could not see that two separate predators were closing in on both sides. A breakout attempt was possible, but not attempted. In the end, Aramus could only posit it was down to the inhuman and inexhaustible pride and arrogance of the Dark Eldar. Their ships could slip away into the Webway, surely, if ever the danger became too great for them all to handle. There yet remained more prey they could take, just one more, for the aliens were forever in need of more souls to drink from to remain alive. It was a supposition supported by the Librarium’s records of past encounters with the Eldar, one concurred by the Salamanders and their own lengthy years encountering Eldar here and there. Personal experience against fighting Eldar had proven to Aramus that it seemed as if each and every one of them, whether Craftworld-loyal or otherwise, actively denied the possibility of a 'mon'keigh' killing them right up until it actually happened.

In any case, what followed shortly afterwards, in what historians would term the Third Battle for Agrippina of the 13th Black Crusade, was a battle in the void of simply epic proportions, featuring the third highest amount of ships for both Imperium and Chaos fleets featured within a single star system in the enterity of the length of the 13th Black Crusade up to that point. The second most had been over Mordax Prime, when the massive fleet of the Green Kroosade met with the combined fleets of multiple nearby Forge Worlds, and the first was in the Cadian System itself. Battleships long thought lost or destroyed revealed themselves flying the banner of Chaos. Grand Cruisers and battlecruisers filled the void, joined by whole squadrons of cruisers and escorts of numerous types. Macrocannon ammo expenditure cost the tithes of whole Mining Worlds elsewhere in the Imperium to replace. Lance arrays nearly burnt out from the sheer amount of targets. There was no retreat. There was no surrender.

Millions died in the course of a handful of days, as ships that had existed for hundreds of years on both sides suffered from total war in the void.

The casualties on the ground were worse.

Chaos invaded with its madmen, its traitorous guardsmen, its militias and citizens who had been raised within the territories of Chaos and granted accursed arms to bear. They faced the hardened PDF and isolated regiments of the Imperial Guard, as well as the legions of skitarii and warrior tech-priests of Agrippina. Daemons swarmed temples, where priests and Sisters of Battle fought them with faith and fire. Continents were set ablaze by the fighting. And yet, through it all, the Dark Eldar flitted here and there, garbled reports and sudden silences in parts of the battlezone marking their presence. Then there were the reports of orks, because of course the greenskins would arrive at a time of highest inconvenience for everyone else. But so too were there reports of mysterious metallic figures scouring their way through the battlefields here and there, disappearing and reappearing at random leaving utter destruction behind.

On the Hive World of Narsine, a planet overpopulated even by the extensive standards of its categorization, the hunters found their prey, the Dark Eldar flitting this way and that to avoid the fighting between Imperials and traitors. The bloodshed was thick enough for the enemy to begin summoning daemons in great number, and a tide of bloodletters and juggernauts began to emerge within the rivers of blood spilled by the unwashed masses being slaughtered in the streets.

It was there, on Narsine, that once again, three Chapters presented themselves, and there they won glory for their deeds.

Of smashing through an artillery emplacement filled with basilisks and daemon-engines alike, saving the advance of three separate Imperial Guard regiments. Chapter Master Tu’Shan personally brought down a truly monstrous Forgefiend daemon-engine in a single blow, an act of pure strength and skill that few could boast to have accomplished.

Of facing down an enormous warband of the Black Legion, with Aramus facing the Chaos Lord leading them in a duel whilst the rest of their force fought their equal in number in Chaos Space Marines supplemented further with daemons and traitorous guardsmen wielding heavy weapons.

Of advancing on the Dark Eldar with such speed that they could not spread their terrofex gasses over an entire hive, preventing hundreds of millions of being so touched with fear and horror that the Dark Eldar could drink of them from afar.

Moments of heroism that were, in the end, only some of many.

But they were theirs, at least.

It was on the highest spire of Narsine, the palace of the Planetary Governor, that Chapter Master Tu’Shan, Commander Aramus, and Captain Menon saved the life of the governor and his family from the Dark Eldar who had wished to take them as prizes. Recordings from numerous cameras secreted throughout the palace by the paranoid governor – ever wary of infiltrators from the forces of Chaos or others – provided footage from a hundred angles as the one known as Endross of the Exquisite Blade was confronted once more, along with several more grotesques, and true elites of the Incubi and Wych Cults of Comorragh.

A blow from Sunderhammer had chipped and broken part of the mask that the Archon wore, revealing a withered and black-veined thing which barely seemed to look akin to the seemingly ageless Craftworld Eldar. There was no smile, no smirk, only alien fury on the Archon’s face. Was, Aramus was heard to ask, the ‘game’ still proving as fun with the aliens on the backfoot for once? The Archon’s reply was to cast forth a red energy field which spilled from the staff he bore, but the space marines were faster, jump packs activating with his gesture and remaining nanoseconds away from being struck by the light. It lasted, just long enough, for a sniper round from somewhere that the cameras did not see to strike the Archon in wrist, severing the hand wielding the staff entirely. At which point the rest of the assembled space marines and aliens all charged for the device as one.

The result of that clash ended with the Archon escaping, clutching the staff in his remaining hand, but almost all who had followed him dead.

And the hunters would follow.

======================================================================

It ended on the world of Aurent, the whole of the Agrippina System on fire, fleets and squadrons of ships wheeling about and firing upon one another in complete chaos. Every formation save for the gunline in the rear had broken down, as any ship not at the most extreme range possible was thrust into the fighting. It was not something intended or planned, and in fact went against the capabilities and usual methods of most of the ships involved, and yet it had devolved into such as the hours had gone on. To try and extract from that was to invite death. To try and pause and regroup was to die. Either side could be run over and crushed by whichever faltered first. As it was, no other sort of ship in the arsenal of the Imperium or in the patterns stored by the Adeptus Mechnicus were better suited for such punishing fighting than the ships of the space marines. Which was, in turn, known by the forces of Chaos. And so once again, space marine fought directly against space marine, while it seemed like the stars themselves around them burned.

And there, over Aurent, powered by bloodshed and spite and stolen secrets by daemons, was a ritual cast. One of grand proportions, waves of foul Warp energies spilling throughout the Materium. But for once, while it drove many loyal sons and daughters of the Imperium mad, and caused minor warp tears from which daemons emerged on many ships with shattered void shields, that was not its intended purpose. Instead, an entire host of battered Dark Eldar ships was revealed over Aurent, having arrogantly trusted that their shadow fields were utterly inviolable to the efforts of idiotic blind mon’keigh.

For though almost any on both sides would kill one for suggesting it, there were in fact some things that the Imperium and the Traitor Legions shared: a hatred for the xeno.

And so it was that the Black Legion Sorcerer Zemerath the Twice-Annointed tore the veil of the Dark Eldar. For in his earliest days, so long ago, before the Long War had begun, he had witnessed too many battle brothers die during the Great Crusade from Eldar weapons, and so had hated them as fiercely as the Corpse-Emperor to that very day. The Dark Eldar ships, completely unprepared for being exposed so completely, had not formed any defensive posture whatsoever. The broadsides fired by Imperial and Chaos ships at will, shots of pure opportunity, were more than enough to shatter some of the alien vessels, blowing apart soul-tortured metal and crystalline matrix alloys. The world of Aurent itself, which had suffered Eldar assaults in the past to the point that the legendary and mourned Creed had seen to creating new defenses and planned tactics, fired its own defense lasers. Close enough to raid the populace below was more than close enough for the powerful anti-orbital emplacements.

In an instant, from the spite of a sorcerer steeped in evil and atrocity, the Exquisite Blade was broken.

But they were not yet defeated.

The auspex tracked numerous transports fleeing to the planet below, even as their ships were destroyed. It was, at that point, mutually agreed that the tenacious Archon Endross would surely not have died in the initial bombardment. As such, the hunters followed their quarry down, their ships remaining above to hold cordon and provide what aid could be given. Already, the armies of the Imperium and those of Chaos clashed across the hive world, its defenses far more considerable than those with Narsine. The world was a shield for Agrippina itself, and thus a world that had to be broken before the lash of the Dark Gods, or one saved by the benediction of the Emperor. The coming days would tell which of the two would occur instead.

For over a month did they hunt and chase, fighting the forces of Chaos all the while. On some days, they found scattered bands of Dark Eldar, fighting no longer for plunder, but for survival. Every time the combined force struck them, the aliens would lose that fight. On other days, it was all they could do to withstand the assaults of the forces of Chaos. The presence of the entire Salamanders Chapter upon the field was both threat and prize both to the servants of the Dark Gods, the prestige for ending them a prize enough to make almost any of such treacherous dogs to make the attempt. Daemon-engines. Champions. Assassins. Sorcerers. Hordes drawn by the whispers in their minds. All of these and more came upon the hunters as they sought out their prey. More than once, Endross himself was sighted, only for the Exquisite Blade to ambush their pursuers with double-backed and hidden troops, allowing the Archon to escape.

Until, finally, the hunt ended.

======================================================================

In a collapsing hive, battered by Chaos artillery for days, the skull probes found them. Within a Guard base, its permacrete walls chipped and broken in multiple places, the remnants of the Exquisite Blade had slowly collected themselves from across the surface where they had initially scattered. It was an army. One that, battered and wearied as they might have been, was still one of the deadliest forces on the planet. Grotesques and wracks aplenty roamed back and forth. Warriors patrolled, as did skimmers of light and heavy varieties. Talos Pain Engines floated back and forth, exploding into violence at the nearest possible threat before returning to twitching silence. Dark lances sprouted from across the entire base, weapons built specifically to tear through the heaviest of armors. But all of that paled before the thing which stood at the center.

Once, long ago, it might have been an elegant creation, a beautiful weaving of wraithbone and weaponry. Now, however, the Eldar Titan, for that was what it had to be, had been transformed by the workings of the Dark Eldar. Soul-tortured metal had been welded to its wraithbone frame, no doubt causing agony through the psychically sensitive material. Spikes and blades had been driven through its limbs in places, becoming defense and offense in one. Its weapons glowed, then dimmed, as if constantly being activated and reactivated. The whole of it, spindly and shaped like an Eldar in body with a completeness that Imperial Titans did not quite manage, twitched badly.

By the words of the Librarians, it was akin to staring into the heart of a star, if a star was made of screams. It did not help that it was constantly speaking, each groaned and tortured word that escaped it causing pleasured shivers amongst the Dark Eldar.

“Sister…sister I cannot hear you…you are so quiet…so quiet…please, sister, in the name of Asuryan, I can’t hear you! I’m sorry, please, speak to me…,” the Titan’s voice rumbled through the air.

It was, without a doubt, the grand trump card of the Kabal. A weapon fit to topple not just hives, but worlds. A single Titan was a weapon worth an army and in and of itself.

“Sarrelen,” Aramus said calmly as he viewed the skull probe’s recording. “Is it ready?”

The Tech-Marine paused.

“It…has never been tested in the field.”

“This may well be the time, then.”

“What do you speak of, Aramus?” Tu’Shan had looked at him.

“A project of Sarrelen’s. He started it near the very start of our Penitent Crusade.”

All eyes now turned to the Tech-Marine, now, from three separate chapters, two separate orders of the Adeptus Mechanicus, and a Palantine of the Sisters of Battle. Only some of those present knew of what was being said.

“It started with small scavenging. Parts, here and there,” Sarrelen cleared his throat. “Purifying rituals performed for each one, every time, consistently, every single day when I was not on the battlefield. With regular testing from the Epistolary when he could be awakened for it. But after Mordax Prime…I received considerably more potent aid from the Adeptus Mechanicus. But-,”

“It is a Land Raider,” Aramus interrupted. “One painstakingly constructed over the decades, piece by piece, each one ritually blessed and purified. Your own Tech-Marines have aided us in this, Chapter Master, if you will forgive my impertinence.”

“It is they who deigned not to speak to me of it,” Tu’Shan waved it off. “Something we shall discuss later. But for now, tell me Tech-Marine, what pattern is it?”

Sarrelen did not fidget. Such a thing was impossible for a space marine.

“It is a Terminus Ultra, Chapter Master,” he said softly. “It has been a personal project of mine. We possess anti-infantry weapons in excess, through our heavy bolters and assault cannons and storm bolters. But the Terminus Ultra would aid us in making up the difference on the field.”

“Truly?” Tu’Shan took the revelation in stride, but then for such a Chapter as the Salamanders vehicles that were rare to the Blood Ravens were far more numerous. “That is an impressive feat, considering the circumstances.”

“I am sure that the Salamanders possess many of their own vehicles,” Aramus demurred, “Land Raiders besides.”

“We do, but deploying the Shadowswords and Fellblades is a lengthy procedure, waking and preparing their machine spirits more no easy task. Furthermore, I will not risk orbital fire into the hive, much of it remains inhabited by citizens of the Imperium. This Terminus Ultra, can it be deployed promptly?” Tu’Shan asked Sarrelen, his helmet doffed such that the pure crimson of his eyes could be seen directly.

“I…yes, Chapter Master Tu’Shan. It can be,” Sarrelen said stiffly.

“Then let us do so! The Song of Entropy must not remain in Endross’ possession for a second longer!”

=====================================================================

“Sarrelen?”

“Weapons charging. Capacitors holding steady. Lascannons aligned!”

“Then fire.”

From out of the darkness of the hive came a column of pure light. The tortured soul of the Eldar Titan, whose sister had long ago been devoured body and soul into the maw of Endross, was granted the barest of reliefs as the strike from the Terminus Ultra blew it apart. Less than a second, however, was all that was granted, for the blow had also destroyed the soulstone, and thus the soul of the pilot was swiftly devoured by Slaanesh who barely acknowledged the meal. The servants of the Imperium did not know any of this, and would largely not care if they did. What mattered more was that the Titan careened backwards and then collapsed.

“CHAAAAAAARGE!” Tu’Shan bellowed, rising up out of cover, brandishing his weapons. “INTO THE FIRES OF BATTLE, UNTO THE ANVIL OF WAR!”

“WE ARE THE SHIELD AND THE SWORD!”

“FOR THE UNKNOWN PRIMARCH!”

“FOR THE GOD-EMPEROR!”

“GLORY TO THE OMNISSIAH!”

Over a thousand space marines, sisters of battle, and tech-priests with their retinues charged twice their number in Dark Eldar elites in an entrenched position. Predator tanks and whirlwind tanks unleashed their payloads, battle cannons and lascannons firing as missiles screamed overhead. Heavy bolters opened up as well as hand-held lascannons fired by devastator squads. Assault marines and assault terminators activated jump packs and teleporters respectively, landing explosively in the middle of the enemy base. The next moments were filled to the brim with violence and chaos. In one moment, Aramus was grappling with a grotesque, in another Chapter Master Tu’Shan was striking down a Talos Pain Engine, and in a third N’mul and his own squad were bringing down an entire charge of Wyches with weight of fire. Myrmidons unleashed the highest level of human technologies against the blasphemous techno-sorcery of the alien. The faintest of golden auras seemed to suffuse the members of the Adeptus Sororitas, their fury literally made manifest in fire without visible source.

Then the shrieking of the Song of Entropy began.

For all the terror and devastation the weapon was capable of, it was impossible to hide its usage. As such, within seconds, they had advanced to the Archon’s position upon a short rise within the base itself, where once in the past officers might have given speeches to their troops. And it was there that Aramus felt another spike of impotent failure and shame drive its way into his chest, as he watched Captain Menon, last of the Angel of Vigilance leadership, fade to dust. A combat knife had been driven into the Archon’s stomach, but it was all that would remain.

“ENDROSS!” Aramus bellowed.

A mad laugh burst from the Archon as he faced them.

“You…you! All of you. Mon’keigh! Stinking primitives! Do you realize how much this will set back my quota?! Vect will tear me asunder when I return to Commoragh so late!”

Aramus’ fury was stoppered, if only momentarily, by confusion and shock.

“You…you really think that you will survive this?” He said incredulously.

Endross’ mask had been broken again, now revealing the hideous thing he was beneath, the skin stretched so tight against the bone beneath as to make him nearly skeletal. Chapped and torn lips peeled back to reveal needle point teeth and gums the color of midnight, stained from ingesting any number of possible substances. The Archon swayed slightly where he stood, even as his Kabal fought to the death all around him. His power sword flickered in what looked like a grafted replacement of some sort, still discolored compared to the rest of his body. The Song of Entropy was clutched in a death grip in the other.

“Of course I will! I am ENDROSS! THE LORD OF SORROWS! I will not be killed by the likes of you. Of any of you! I am of Commorragh! I will always survive! Always!”

“Mad xenos,” Aramus spat.

And the fight began.

Whether or not his sanity would permit him to consider the possibility of loss, the simple fact of the matter was that the Lord of Sorrows became a whirlwind of death in those final moments. Against the Chapter Master of the Salamanders and Aramus, a great many foes would fall. Not so, the Archon of the Exquisite Blade. Chemical injectors activated, bulging his musculature, and ballooning his strength enough to send them flying with kicks and punches. His power sword hacked and carved across their armor, cutting his way through Aramus’s cheek, and nearly gutting him more than once. The venerable power armor of Tu’Shan was similarly scored and damaged. It strained Aramus like almost nothing had in the entire 13th Black Crusade to even keep up.

“I will peel your skin open and wear it as a cloak, and if you survive that I will throw you to the arena!” Endross spat globules of sizzling ichor onto Aramus’ armor.

“You will die, and we shall burn your corpse beyond ash with melta bombs,” Aramus growled back.

Blades and spears flashed, even as Sunderhammer swung continually back and forth in a desperate defensive maneuver. Twice, Endross dropped grenades that could have permanently deafened and blinded lesser mortals, a custom mixture of terrorfex and acidic gasses that ate away even at ceramite filling the air. Once, Aramus triggered Sunderhammer’s energy field, the concussive force knocking Endross just enough that Tu’Shan could cut the alien’s forearm with his own power sword. Around them, the melee continued. The Forgefather and Thaddeus were back-to-back, at one point, chainswords slashing back and forth as the Spear of Vulkan cut and stabbed, the two surrounded by mutated grotesques that were surely masterpieces of some Haemonculus or another. But all the while, Aramus could not stop a growing suspicion in his mind. He had chased after the Archon for too long, had suffered his tricks too many times, and now his instincts were starting to speak. Suspicions that were proven right when the Archon ducked away from the both of them and let a group of Incubi confront them instead.

“Stupid mon’keigh!” Endross laughed, voice cracking and dipping, a bit of blood spurting from between his lips. “How can you fall for the same ploy again and again and again!”

But whatever the Archon expected to happen…didn’t. Aramus battered down Incubi alongside Tu’Shan, and the Archon stared not at the two closest to killing him, but rather into the distance. And as they came closer, the whole of his body began to shake and shudder with unconcealed fury. Wyches fell upon the duo, and all the others, eyes alight with the knowledge that death was upon them but with absolute refusal to go down with anything less than maximum effort towards the contrary. More grotesques in all sorts of shapes and sizes burst from the earth. A pair of predators dueled with raider skimmers, dark lances cutting deep before lascannon blasts cut a skiff entirely in half.

The violence did not cease, but it certainly did slow somewhat as another Pain Engine was heaved out of the shadows, accompanied by a literal rain of broken Dark Eldar bodies all around the perimeter.

“The response, I believe,” Shield-Captain Aristos called out as he withdrew his guardian spear from the Talos with a wet squelch, “Is that perhaps you should not rely on the same ploy again and again and again.”

From the shadows did not come another overwhelming force of Dark Eldar, ready to crush their prey between themselves.

Instead came but fifty Adeptus Custodes, splattered heavily with the blood of the slain would-be-ambushers. How those in such auramite power armor had managed to overcome the stealth and speed of the Dark Eldar as well as their far greater numbers, all in the shadows without revealing either group to the combatants up to that point, was unknown. Suffice that they were the Adeptus Custodes, of the Ten Thousand, and had managed it without issue.

“No,” Endross said, the word quiet and nearly throttled by the anger that caused a black flush to spread up his neck and face.

Ancient and withered black veins pulsed.

“NO!” He bellowed, pupils now blown out from the combat drugs he was injecting through his armor.

“Yes,” Tu’Shan roared.

There was no more room for words. Even before the Adeptus Custodes joined the fight, the battle was turning against the Dark Eldar. Which was not, of course, to say that they were not without their own small victories. Space marines fought, and space marines died. Whether by quirk of fate, or deliberate cruel decision, the Angels of Vigilance would not see out the day. Their losses over Armageddon would never be recovered, their gene-vaults in their Fortress-Monastery lost along with all their brothers. With every battle, they had driven themselves on in the search of vengeance, and they died for it. The weapons of the Dark Eldar were often such that even when bodies remained, the gene-seed within was destroyed. So it was that, even at the end, the Exquisite Blade managed to end the legacy of one of the longest standing Chapters that had stood watch over the Eye of Terror. The spite that the two groups had held towards one another had began as little more than basic enmity by cause and course, but in those final moments it became inflamed to an all-consumed hatred which eclipsed all reason.

Blood dripped from a number of wounds, with alien toxins clogging veins and attempting to liquify organs, and yet the space marines fought on. Impaled and battered, armor and bone alike breaking, the Archon fought on.

Finally, however, the Archon twisted his body such that he nearly severed his own spine, just so that he could slam his power sword through Tu’Shan’s thigh and pin him to the ground. Long enough, it seemed, for him to bring the Song of Entropy to bear. Many Salamander’s hearts stopped at the sight of it, even as Tu’Shan struggled to free himself. The crimson field began to erupt from the head of the staff, only for Aramus to clasp his left hand over the head of the staff entirely, and with the last of the strength in his rapidly decaying arm as the entropic energies washed over the limb, forced the staff’s head towards the sky. A whispered word locked the armor of the arm in place, even as skin and blood and bone became dust and then even less than that within it. Sunderhammer dropped to the ground.

For with his right hand Aramus was finally close enough to wrap fingers and hand around the Archon’s throat.

And with a vicious tear, the Lord of Sorrows who had swallowed millions upon millions of souls, who had brought billions more to Comorrragh, who had lived since the fall of the Eldar Empire, had his neck squeezed with such force as to separate head from torso entirely. Pinched and thin skin tore, muscle and gristle ripped, and spinal cord was crushed to fragments.

His head did not bounce upon hitting the ground, for in that same instant Aramus brought his boot down to crush it to pulp.

=======================================================

From a distance, the Salamanders forming up ranks, a strange glow and whirring sound emerged from the center. There, Aramus knew, would stand the Forgefather and Chapter Master, along with all seven of the Captains of their Chapter. A whisper began next, starting inaudible, but swiftly growing in sound. It was a mixture of cheer, prayer, and giving of thanks, as near as Aramus could tell. For the Song of Entropy had been confirmed to be true, no imitation of any sort, and as such it meant that one more of the Artifacts of Vulkan had finally been returned to the Salamanders thousands of years after the search had begun. Slowly, but completely, the assembled 1st Founding Chapter began to stomp their feet in unison at some beat that apparently resided in all of their hearts.

A ghost of a smile passed across Aramus’ lips as he watched it, the Blood Ravens standing just apart.

“…why?” He asked next, turning to look at the inscrutable Shield-Captain. “I had thought us never to meet again, after…before.”

“It is not within the remit of your sort to question where, when, or why a Custodes goes,” Aristos replied, tone once more a mixture of tired and disappointed that nearly blasted Aramus off his feet. “As it is, however…,” the Custodes gestured toward excited gathering of Salamanders, the corpses of all the dead Exquisite Blade members carelessly crushed underfoot. “For all their failings, the works of the Primarchs may well be of some aid to the Imperium’s survival.” Aristos turned back to Aramus. “Perhaps. Do not mistake us, thief, we came to aid them. Not you.”

“I had thought so,” Aramus nodded, “But even so, I give you my thanks.”

“Worthless as it is,” Aristos sniffed. “A question, in turn, Blood Raven. Why did you sacrifice your arm, and potentially yourself, to save the life of Tu’Shan?”

Aramus blinked.

“Do you truly think so little of me?”

“Yes,” Aristos replied bluntly. “Your Chapter has a tendency. On Tartarus, your current Chapter Master released a powerful daemon. Your previous Chapter Master fell to Chaos, and managed to conceal it for centuries. On Kronus, your Chapter willingly brutalized the Imperial Guard on the orders of said heretic. In Kaurava, your Chapter spent more time fighting the Sisters of Battle and now Lord Subsector Stubbs than anything else, and lost five companies for it. In the first Aurelian Crusade, you nearly lost your worlds to the tyranids because you could not understand the implications of their coming save for Captain Cyrus. In the second Aurelian Crusade…,” the Custodes trailed off, Aramus having already looked down with red flushing his neck in shame. “Well, I suspect you are more familiar with your failings there than any other."

It took a moment for Aramus to marshal the strength to speak.

“You’re right,” he admitted. “We have made…many mistakes. We do not know our Primarch, a shame no other Chapter I can immediately think of can share. We are distaff shadows compared to ones such as they,” he made to gesture to the Salamanders before realizing his left arm was gone, the armor now hanging limply at his side. “Which is why it was all the more important that he live. Earlier, you said it would be pointless to execute the Blood Ravens for our theft, as it would deprive the Emperor of some small hundreds of space marines to fight for him.”

“I did,” Aristos nodded.

“The loss of one such as Tu’Shan would deprive the Emperor of one of far more worth,” Aramus declared. “The Salamanders have taken losses in this campaign, but they can recover, and likely will swiftly enough. And they have now regained one of the Artifacts of Vulkan. If the cost of that was my arm,” he grabbed his limp left arm armor with his right, raising it up before letting go to let it swing back down, “Or even my life, I think that such a thing would be worth it.”

“You would claim that Chapter Master Tu’Shan is worth more than your entire Chapter?”

Aramus snorted, looking away again.

“I was overflowing with indignant pride when Gabriel sent me here. In the decades since, it was carved and burnt and beaten out of me. I had begun to rebuild it, believing myself purified by – to use the Salamander terms – the anvil of war and the fires of battle. Our meeting proved that I was still not yet ready to return to my brothers – which, I suppose, is very much the purpose of penitence.”

He paused, then, and looked back to the Custodes.

“Gabriel is likely doing his best to rebuild the Blood Ravens into a Chapter worth its pride. I can do no less than to rebuild myself to better serve the Emperor. In mind, in spirit, and, it seems,” he glanced at the empty portion of his armor again, “In body as well. Is Chapter Master Tu’Shan worth more than all of the Blood Ravens combined? Perhaps not.”

Then Aramus looked Aristos in the eyes.

“I do know that he is worth more than one such as me.”

The Shield-Captain was still for a lengthy moment before nodding.

“Hmm. There might be something of worth in you after all.”

“Aramus!” Tu’Shan boomed as he strode to them with a slight limp, the Salamanders now breaking up to maintain the perimeter. “Honorable Custodes,” he bowed his head to Aristos, who nodded curtly back. “It is confirmed and done. The Song of Entropy is ours. And you, young Blood Raven, have my personal thanks.”

“Lord Tu’Shan, I-,”

“Nonsense. If you hadn’t sacrificed your arm, and possibly your life had you not been able to fully push the staff away, I would have died standing there,” the Chapter Master of the Salamanders shook his head, a smile on his lips. “I owe you and yours a debt.”

“Not so. We began this all in the name of the Angels of Vigilance, who we failed,” Aramus shook his head, causing Tu’Shan to bow his with a look of bitterness crossing his face. “We have killed their killers, but the defenders of lost Pervigilium remain dead.

“This is true,” Tu’Shan sighed, “A regret that cannot ever be fully expunged. We slew the Exquisite Blade, yes, but the Bell of Lost Souls shall toll long on Terra after this day.”

“It has not stopped ringing since this Black Crusade began,” Aristos added, making both look at him askance. “Furthermore, our time is done here. We have other places to bring the Emperor’s fury to in this Sector and in others.”

As abrupt as ever, the Custodes all departed in silence without another word.

“The credit should be given more to N’mul,” Aramus continued afterwards. “He is the one who-,”

“Has fought alongside you for too long for you to be able to deflect so easily,” Tu’Shan shook his head. “And yet, for all my thanks, I must apologize to you now.”

“There is no need. I figured it was coming,” Aramus quirked his lips for a moment. “N’mul must return to Nocturne.”

“What!?” N’mul said, overhearing and turning to them even as Tu’Shan nodded. “Chapter Master, no! I am needed here!”

“The 7th Company needs a Captain,” Tu’Shan countered. “A proper one, not simply a veteran sergeant who has not undertaken the proper rites.”

The argument between the two was fierce, at least on the part of one, as Aramus let the bittersweet knowledge that N’mul could not resist Tu’Shan telling him to his face to report to Nocturne pass through him. He had known it was coming. It was, in fact, inevitable. It truly wasn’t proper for an entire company of space marines to be forced to reside on the strike cruiser of another Chapter entirely, after all.

“Aramus?”

He blinked and looked up to find a shame-faced N’mul looking at him.

“Yes?”

“I…,”

“I know. It’s all right. If you are swift, then perhaps we will see another again before the 13th Black Crusade ends.”

Aramus’ smile died as he saw the look on N’mul’s face worsen.

“What is it?”

“The Salamanders will not be returning, Aramus.”

“What?” Aramus’ eyes widened in shock.

“The whole of the Chapter was already deployed at Armageddon. Had many promises to defend it. They left, quite abruptly, to reclaim the Song of Entropy,” N’mul looked away. “In their absence, Imperial losses have escalated considerably, even with the return of the Eternal Crusader. We must return. And Tu’Shan says that it has been long since the 7th Company has fought alongside its brothers.”

Aramus squeezed his eyes shut and sighed.

“I see. Well then,” he clapped his remaining hand to N’mul’s shoulder. “Fight well, brother,” he gave him as full a smile as he could, which was more of a struggle than he had anticipated.

“I will, brother,” N’mul’s look was fierce. “We shall break the orks at Armageddon, and then we shall return. This is not the last time that the 7th Company shall fight alongside the Blood Ravens. This, I swear.”

This time, Aramus’ smile was more genuine.

“Then I look forward to it. I shall endeavor to survive until that day, if you do the same.”

The resulting wrist-clasp terminated oddly for the Blood Raven as N’mul drew Aramus closer to wrap his second arm around his shoulder and back. The sensation it brought was faintly and distantly familiar, from something that almost felt like a memory of his life before being taken as an initiate into the Chapter.

“I will. Fight on, brother,” N’mul told him with a nod.

“See to your company, N’mul,” Tu’Shan said quietly, having waited for them to finish before speaking up again.

“Of course, Chapter Master,” N’mul looked one last time at Aramus before nodding to Tu’Shan and striding away.

“…should you be walking? The power sword struck you clean through,” Aramus spoke up.

“The apothecaries saw to both of us. The toxins are neutralized,” Tu’Shan waved the concern away. “The bleeding has ceased. More in-depth treatment can wait for later.”

“I…suppose.”

“Now, as to the debt,” Tu’Shan began.

“Chapter Master-,”

“My gratitude in this instance is irrefusable, Aramus,” Tu’Shan cleared his throat.

“If this must be so,” Aramus sighed, “Then…I do have a request.”

“Name it.”

Aramus inhaled deeply before speaking.

“The battlefield is growing ever fiercer. Upon the Retribution we carry a goodly portion of gene-seed.”

Tu’Shan’s gaze sharpened considerably.

“There is no guarantee,” Aramus looked to where N’mul was speaking to the assembled 7th Company, “That we will survive the next battle, let alone the next year. Should it come to pass that the Retribution is destroyed, I would not have it be so that the gene-seed is lost with us. My request is thus,” Aramus looked back to the now grave expression on Tu’Shan’s face. “Sarrelen can see to a bionic replacement for my arm. But the gene-seed cannot be replaced. Forgive my impertinence, Chapter Master, but I would ask of you to safely transport what we possess to our Chapter, or at least to Governor Derosa of Meridian in the Aurelian Subsector to hold for the Chapter until the Blood Ravens may take possession of it.”

“This is no small task, Aramus,” Tu’Shan murmured. “Subsector Aurelia is in the Eastern Fringe, almost the other side of the galaxy from the Eye, a great distance indeed from Armageddon and Nocturne besides.”

The Blood Raven winced.

“I would expect nothing less,” Tu’Shan grinned, teeth white and gleaming. “If you had tried to defer to some small measure of recompense I would have been insulted. To ask us to forgo our duties on Armageddon I would have been furious. Instead, you ask of us to take up a grave and honorable duty, one worth doing regardless. Yes, Aramus of the Blood Ravens. It may take us some time, but yes.”

“Thank you, Chapter Master,” Aramus said gratefully. “Thank you.”

“Of course,” Tu’Shan patted him on the shoulder. “Now, let us regroup and do what needs to be done to free this world.”

In the grand scheme of things, it was a minor battle on Aurent, all told. The fate of Agrippina was decided, however, with a thousand of such things. The back of the forces of Chaos were broken, and the Imperium triumphed on mountains of dead and broken ships. All the same, the shipyards of Agrippina were more than happy to aid in repair and restoration of those who had freed them from the constant pressure of Chaos assaults. Within the day, the battle in the void was over, and within the year, all planets within the system were scoured clean. The fleet would go on to restore the Sector to the Imperium, and in that time more victories and glories were won by the Salamanders than all others.

And none would forget the Blood Ravens that strode alongside them, for the tale of the Hunt for the Song of Entropy would become a legend of its own.

In time, however, the Salamanders did depart to Nocturne, so far flung away. Their fleet bolstered, at that point, by a battered battle barge and pair of strike cruisers, late of the lamented and lost Angels of Vigilance, of whom their last Captain – Brother Menon – had left behind a recording leaving the ships to those who had fought alongside him in the case of his death in the course of the hunt. Alas, the Penitent Crusade of Aramus could not accept such aid, and so the ships went to the Salamanders instead, to become the fleet that would replace the ships of the 7th Company that had been lost decades ago. The Retribution would remain in Agrippina for a time, before rapidly reappearing elsewhere, from the Scarus Sector to the Cadian Sector and even Belis Corona at times. In those places, the Blood Ravens deployed no longer alongside Salamanders, but others instead, fighting the enemies of the Imperium and contributing as best they could wherever they could.

All the while, the 13th Black Crusade ground on…